import{_ as m,o as i,c as t,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as j,f,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},x={class:"review-content"};function T(e,a,u,d,o,r){return i(),t("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(u.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",x,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(u.poem.answer),1)])])])}const S=m(q,[["render",T],["__scopeId","data-v-1bbd2d89"]]),C=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Responde esto: El cáncer se describe mejor como Opciones disponibles: [a] un tipo de ingeniería genética; [b] la fusión de las células sexuales; [c]. división celular anormal; [d]. tejido que deja de crecer;","answer":"[C] es la respuesta correcta "},{"question":"انقر على أيقونة التطبيق. انقر على أيقونة الترس ثم انقر على زر الخروج من التطبيق . احذف التطبيق بعد ذلك عن طريق النقر عليه بزر الفأرة الأيمن واختيار نقل إلى سلة المهملات، أو عن طريق سحب التطبيق إلى سلة المهملات. انقر بزر الفأرة الأيمن على المجلد ثم انقر على خيار النقل إلى سلة المهملات، أو اسحب المجلد إلى سلة المهملات. لاحظ أن حذف المجلد سيؤدي إلى حذف محتوياته أيضًا. يجب نسخ الملفات إلى مجلد آمن آخر قبل حذف مجلد دروب بوكس إن لم تكن الملفات محفوظة في ذاكرة التخزين السحابية خاصة حساب دروب بوكس. افعل ذلك عن طريق النقر بزر الفأرة الأيمن على اسم التطبيق واختيار حذف من الشريط الجانبي.اكتب ملخص باللغة العربية:","answer":"ابحث عن تطبيق دروب بوكس في شريط قوائم نظام ماكنتوش. اخرج من تطبيق دروب بوكس. ابحث عن تطبيق دروب بوكس في مجلد التطبيقات. ابحث عن مجلد دروب بوكس لحذفه أيضًا حال الرغبة بذلك. احذف اختصار دروب بوكس من الشريط الجانبي إن احتجت لذلك."},{"question":"Wat voor belangrijke tekst beschrijft de volgende tekst: Tijdens het Conclaaf van 1922 gold hij andermaal als kanshebber, maar de kardinalen kozen Achille Ratti als paus Pius XI. In 1925 schreef kardinaal Maffi een felle herderlijke brief, die tegen het fascisme was gericht. De autoriteiten hielden de publicatie ervan tegen.","answer":"Het gaat over het conclaaf van 1922."},{"question":"Huraikan pendapat anda tentang kelebihan mempelajari seni mempertahankan diri. ","answer":"Cadangan jawapan:1. Mempertahankan diri1.1 menyelamatkan diri apabila diserang oleh penjahat.1.2 tidak mudah diperlakukan sewenang-wenangnya oleh pihak lain.1.3 dapat menjaga maruah diri.2. Mendisiplinkan diri2.1 mematuhi waktu latihan2.2 taat pada etika sesuatu seni pertahanan diri yang dipelajari2.3 menggunakan seni pertahanan diri untuk kebaikan.3. Menyihatkan badan3.1 melibatkan pergerakan fizikal3.2 mengeluarkan peluh3.3 melancarkan pengaliran darah"},{"question":"Tôi là nữ, làm nhân viên văn phòng với lương tháng gần 20 triệu đồng. Một mình nuôi con nhỏ, tôi có số tiền tích lũy hơn 500 triệu đồng.Tôi chưa có kinh nghiệm kinh doanh nhưng rất muốn đầu tư hoặc kinh doanh để tăng thêm thu nhập mỗi tháng. Mua đất cũng không biết bắt đầu từ đâu, chứng khoán từng tham gia nhưng không thành công, thậm chí bị lỗ.Tôi yêu hoa và ấp ủ có cửa hàng hoa cho riêng mình. Tuy nhiên, công việc văn phòng chiếm hết thời gian và tôi cũng không có kinh nghiệm kinh doanh. Bản thân đang cảm thấy khá rối ren, hy vọng nhận được lời khuyên của chuyên gia.","answer":"Chắc hẳn là không chỉ riêng bạn, đây là mối quan tâm lớn của nhiều nhân viên văn phòng hoặc làm việc có nguồn thu nhập ổn định. Phần lớn đều loay hoay trong việc tìm hướng ra cho đầu tư, kinh doanh để tăng trưởng tài sản tốt hơn.Riêng trường hợp của gia đình bạn, khi chỉ có một nguồn thu duy nhất, nhu cầu đầu tư an toàn và tăng trưởng ổn định cần được lưu ý. Tuy nhiên, trước khi tính đến việc đầu tư, bạn cần có cho mình những phương thức quản trị rủi ro.Thứ nhất, mua bảo hiểm nhân thọ và các sản phẩm bổ trợ. Là trụ cột gia đình, bằng việc chuẩn bị cho mình một hợp đồng bảo hiểm nhân thọ, bạn đã chuyển giao rủi ro mất thu nhập toàn bộ hoặc một phần cho công ty bảo hiểm, khi bị tử vong, thương tật hay mắc bệnh hiểm nghèo. Mức phí bảo hiểm 5-8% thu nhập mỗi năm là phù hợp, để đảm bảo bạn có thể an tâm hơn trong cuộc sống và không bị áp lực đóng phí quá cao.Thứ hai, lập quỹ dự phòng khẩn cấp. Với thu nhập bình quân 20 triệu đồng mỗi tháng và có một người phụ thuộc là con, bạn nên phân bổ như sau: tiết kiệm ít nhất 10-20% thu nhập, dự kiến ở mức 3 triệu đồng mỗi tháng; chi phí hưởng thụ ở mức 10% thu nhập, tương ứng 2 triệu đồng mỗi tháng; chi phí thiết yếu, đã bao gồm phí bảo hiểm, khoảng 15 triệu đồng mỗi tháng.Từ khoản tiền 500 triệu đồng hiện có, bạn trích ra 50 triệu để lập quỹ dự phòng. Bạn nên chia ra vài khoản nhỏ, gửi tiết kiệm một tháng. Khi cần thiết sẽ có ngay nguồn dự phòng để chi tiêu trong trường hợp khẩn cấp.Về đầu tư, danh mục của bạn cần đảm bảo đạt các yếu tố sau: đa dạng sản phẩm đầu tư, từ đó tối ưu hiệu suất lợi nhuận; đảm bảo tính thanh khoản, khi cần thiết có thể quy đổi khoản đầu tư sang tiền mà vẫn đảm bảo toàn giá trị; có phương án quản trị rủi ro.Trước khi chọn sản phẩm đầu tư, bạn cần xem xét các mục tiêu ngắn, trung và dài hạn của mình. Với những mục tiêu ngắn hạn cần chi tiêu trong tương lai, bạn cần đầu tư an toàn, như gửi tiết kiệm với lãi suất tốt ở các ngân hàng. Khoản vốn dành cho đầu tư dài hạn cần xác định rõ, tránh thanh lý tài sản sớm hơn dự tính, tại điểm rơi về giá trị sẽ không đạt hiệu quả về hiệu suất đầu tư.Bạn có thể tham khảo hai sản phẩm đầu tư có tính dài hạn gồm bất động sản và chứng khoán.Về bất động sản, bạn nên dành một khoản vốn để đầu tư vào kênh này vì chúng thường neo giữ giá trị tốt, miễn mua đúng giá trị. Việc định giá và chọn đúng khu vực có tiềm năng tăng trưởng rất quan trọng. Bạn nên tìm đến các dịch vụ tư vấn uy tín để nhận được lời khuyên giá trị.Các khu vực vùng ven hoặc lân cận các thành phố lớn vẫn luôn có những bất động sản nằm ở mức giá thấp, phù hợp với nguồn vốn hiện có của bạn và khả năng tăng trưởng lợi nhuận tốt. Bạn có thể tham khảo các khu vực ở Đồng Nai, Bình Dương, Đăk Lăk, Cam Ranh, Phú Yên, Mỹ Đức, Đông Anh đang có các sản phẩm dưới 300 triệu đồng.Với nguồn thặng dư ổn định 3 triệu mỗi tháng, bạn có thể cân nhắc sử dụng đòn bẩy tài chính khi lãi suất về vùng ổn định, nhằm gia tăng cơ hội tăng trưởng tài sản. Tôi ví dụ khoản vay 100 triệu đồng, lãi suất 8,5% mỗi năm, thời hạn 15 năm, mỗi tháng bạn phải trả trung bình 1,2-1,3 triệu đồng, nằm trong phạm vi an toàn.Về chứng khoán, với hạn chế về kiến thức, kinh nghiệm cũng như thời gian, bạn nên chọn một trong hai phương thức đầu tư sau: mua chứng chỉ quỹ tại các quỹ đầu tư lớn và có uy tín về năng lực quản lý quỹ; hoặc đầu tư tích sản cổ phiếu bằng cách mua đều đặn một vài mã chứng khoán đã chọn lọc.Bạn có thể tìm hiểu hai phương thức đầu tư này từ nhiều kênh khác nhau, hoặc có thể sử dụng dịch vụ tư vấn chứng khoán uy tín để có thể hạn chế rủi ro thua lỗ. Bạn cần xem xét chu kỳ kinh tế để chọn lựa thời điểm mua - bán phù hợp. Khẩu vị rủi ro và kinh nghiệm đầu tư cũng nên tính đến khi chọn lựa sản phẩm. Ngoài ra, bạn cũng nên dành một tỷ trọng nhỏ nguồn vốn, từ 5-10% cho tiền gửi tiết kiệm để đảm bảo thanh khoản cho danh mục đầu tư.Đối với kế hoạch kinh doanh cửa hàng hoa, bạn cần xem xét và đánh giá các yếu tố sau.Thứ nhất, công việc văn phòng chiếm hết thời gian và bạn cũng không có kinh nghiệm kinh doanh. Vậy khi mở cửa hàng hoa, ai sẽ là người quản lý? Bạn có thể gọi vốn hay có đối tác cùng kinh doanh không? Theo tôi, việc tìm kiếm một đối tác kinh doanh có cùng sở thích, có thời gian và kinh nghiệm là điều không dễ.Thứ hai, bạn cần có một kế hoạch kinh doanh cụ thể, chi tiết về vốn ban đầu, vốn lưu động cho cửa hàng hoạt động, nguồn vốn dự phòng cho trường hợp lỗ trong 3-6 tháng; dự kiến nguồn khách hàng, doanh thu và chi phí, kế hoạch marketing cũng cần được lưu ý. Chắc chắn, bạn cũng cần có kiến thức quản lý tài chính.Ngoài ra, các phương án quản trị rủi ro đối với cửa hàng hoa cũng cần được thiết lập. Hoa là sản phẩm có hạn sử dụng ngắn và mang tính mùa vụ nên cần được tính toán cách thức xử lý phù hợp. Kế hoạch cắt lỗ cũng nên được cân nhắc. Bạn cần dự tính trước sẽ chấm dứt hoạt động khi khoản lỗ vượt quá mức dự kiến hay sẽ vay mượn thêm để chờ kinh doanh khởi sắc."},{"question":"Inona no tena mampiavaka ny diplaomasia dolara, ary ahoana no ampiasan’i Etazonia izany amin’ny fifandraisany iraisam-pirenena?","answer":"Ny diplaomasia dollar dia manondro ny fampiasana ny fahefana ara-toekarenan'i Etazonia, ao anatin'izany ny volany (dolara), mba hisy fiantraikany amin'ny fanapahan-kevitra sy ny politikan'ny firenena hafa. Ny Etazonia dia afaka mampiasa izany amin'ny alalan'ny fametrahana sazy ara-toekarena, fanomezana fanampiana ara-bola, na fampiasana ny toerany amin'ny andrim-bola iraisam-pirenena mba hampisy fiantraikany."},{"question":"කම්පාලා  නගරය කිනන් රටක අගනුවරද ?","answer":"කම්පාලා  නගරය උගන්ඩාවේ අගනුවරයි. "},{"question":"Remplissez le \\"_\\" de la phrase suivante : \\"Dupont a visité la tombe de Dubois en 1765. A cette date _ était peiné depuis cinq ans.\\" Choix : - \\"Dubois\\" - \\"Dupont\\" Réponse :\\"","answer":"Dupont a visité la tombe de Dubois en 1765. A cette date Dupont était peiné depuis cinq ans."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Richard Dawkins para a biologia?","answer":"Richard Dawkins é um renomado biólogo evolucionista, escritor e comunicador científico. Suas principais contribuições para a biologia estão relacionadas à divulgação da teoria da evolução e ao entendimento do papel da seleção natural na evolução das espécies. Aqui estão algumas das principais contribuições de Richard Dawkins para a biologia:a. Gene Egoísta: Em seu livro \\"O Gene Egoísta\\" (The Selfish Gene), publicado em 1976, Dawkins introduziu o conceito de \\"gene egoísta\\". Ele argumentou que os genes, e não os organismos individuais, são as unidades fundamentais de seleção natural. Dawkins propôs que os genes têm uma motivação \\"egoísta\\" para se replicar e passar para as gerações futuras, e que isso explica muitos aspectos da evolução e do comportamento animal.b. Memes: Dawkins também popularizou o conceito de \\"meme\\" em seu livro \\"O Gene Egoísta\\". Ele definiu memes como unidades de cultura, ideias ou comportamentos que se propagam de pessoa para pessoa por imitação, assim como os genes se propagam por replicação. Embora a ideia dos memes seja mais aplicada ao estudo da cultura e do comportamento humano, ela influenciou o pensamento sobre como as ideias e a cultura evoluem.c. Extensão da Teoria da Evolução: Dawkins desempenhou um papel fundamental na divulgação da teoria da evolução e na explicação de como a seleção natural atua para moldar as características das espécies ao longo do tempo. Ele usou uma linguagem acessível para explicar conceitos complexos, tornando a teoria da evolução mais acessível ao público em geral.d. Promoção da Ciência: Dawkins é um comunicador científico prolífico e autor de vários livros populares de ciência, incluindo \\"O Fenótipo Estendido\\" (The Extended Phenotype) e \\"O Maior Espetáculo da Terra\\" (The Greatest Show on Earth). Seu trabalho tem contribuído para promover o pensamento crítico e científico e para combater o obscurantismo e o criacionismo.e. Advocacia do Ateísmo: Embora seja mais conhecido por suas contribuições para a biologia, Dawkins também é um proeminente defensor do ateísmo e do secularismo. Seu livro \\"Deus, um Delírio\\" (The God Delusion) critica a religião e promove uma visão secular do mundo.Portanto, Richard Dawkins é conhecido por suas contribuições para a biologia, particularmente pela popularização da teoria da evolução, suas ideias sobre os \\"genes egoístas\\" e os \\"memes\\", bem como por sua habilidade de comunicar conceitos científicos complexos ao público em geral. Suas obras têm influenciado significativamente o campo da biologia evolucionária e a compreensão da evolução."},{"question":"Xakameeynta miisaanka.","answer":"Hadii aad kamid tahay dadka faraha badan ee isku dayaaya in aay dhimaan misaankooda waxyaabaha ka qeeyb qaadan kara markii uu doonaayo qofka in uu dhimo,ama uu saxo miisaanka waxaa kamid ah:1) waa in aad qaadato go,aan kama danbeeys ah, waa inaad sameeysato jadwal maalinle ah,waa inaad sameeysato jadwal jimicsi oo joogte ah saacado cayiman,sidoo kale in aad cuntadada iska saxdo isbuuc walba hal mar taasi waxa aay kaa caawineeysaa inaad ka hortagto misaankaaga oo siyaada, iyo in aay sara uqaado bad qabka iyo caafimaadka jirkaaga."},{"question":"සිංහල ඇතුළු බොහොමයක් භාෂාවල මුල් අකුර \\"අ\\" ශබ්දය ලිවීමට යොදාගන්නා අකුර වන්නේ ඇයි!එසේ නොමැති භාෂා සහ එම භාෂාවන් පටන්ගන්නා මුලකුරු මොනවාද?","answer":"ඔක්කොටම කලින් කට අරින්න එපැයි. .කෝ \\"ආ\\" කියන්න. ..මතකද පොඩි කාලෙ කවනකොට එහෙම අම්ම කියනව. .මනුශ්‍ය කටහඩේ මුලින්ම පිටවන ස්වරය විවෘත \\"ආ ස්වරය. නමුත් \\"ආ\\" ලෙස ඇදෙන්නෙ \\"අ\\" අක්ශරය නිසයි ඕනෙම ශබ්ද මාලාවක හෝ ලිඛිත අක්ශර මාලාවක මුල්ම ස්වරය \\"අ\\" ලෙස යෙදෙන්නෙ. ,මට නම් \\"අ\\" ස්වරයෙන් පටන් නොගන්න බසක්(අක්ශර හෝඩිය) මොනම බස් පවුලකවත් දකින්න ලැබිල නැහැ. ලොව පැරණිම බස් වන සංස්කෘත, ද්‍රාවිඩ, හෙළ, ලතින්, මැන්ඩරින් ආදි බස් ඕනෙ එහෙක අරැඹුම \\"අ\\" ශබ්දය පිටවෙන ස්වර අකුරක්."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berat tangan\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud pemalas atau seorang yang enggan bekerja. Contoh ayat: Saedah memang berat tangan. Dia hanya tidur dan tidak mahu menolong kakaknya di dapur."},{"question":"ශ්‍රි ලංකාවේ පළමු පොලිස්පති කවුද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු පොලිස්පති වන්නේ රොබට් කැම්බෙල් මහතාය."},{"question":"చక్రీయ ఆదాయ ప్రవాహం గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"ఒక ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థలో సంస్థల నుంచి గృహ రంగానికి, గృహ రంగం నుంచి సంస్థలకు నిరంతరం ఆదాయం ప్రవహించడాన్ని చక్రీయ ఆదాయ ప్రవాహం అంటారు."},{"question":"Neden keçi sütü daha beyazdır?","answer":"Keçi sütünde A vitamini miktarı fazladır. Bundan dolayı keçi sütleri ve keçi tereyağı inek sütlerinkine gö- re daha beyazdır."},{"question":"Arizona offers more than just deserts and canyons. What cultural experiences and hidden gems can surprise and enrich my travel experience?","answer":"Native American Heritage: Visit the Hopi Cultural Center in Tuba City, learn about Navajo art and weaving traditions, or attend a traditional powwow for a deeper understanding of the region's vibrant cultures.Art in Unexpected Places: Explore the murals and street art scene in Phoenix, visit the quirky galleries in Bisbee, or witness the annual Desert X art installations across the state.Foodie Delights: Savor authentic Sonoran cuisine in Tucson, discover hidden taco stands along dusty highways, or enjoy farm-to-table restaurants in Sedona.Stargazing Paradise: Escape light pollution and experience breathtaking night skies in dark sky parks like Cherry Springs or Kitt Peak Observatory.Unexpected Adventures: Take a hot air balloon ride over Sedona, go spelunking in Kartchner Caverns, or kayak through the calm waters of Lake Powell."},{"question":"Ijọba o gbọdọ fun ẹnikẹni labẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona ni tipatipa-Ile-ẹjọ lo sọ bẹẹ","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ giga apapọ kan to fikalẹ siluu Port-Harcourt, nipinlẹ Rivers, ti sọ pe ọrọ gbigba abẹrẹ ajẹsara arun Koronafairọọsi ni Naijiria, ẹni to ba fẹ, to si nifẹẹ si gbigba abẹrẹ naa lo le lọọ gba a, ki i ṣe ọrọ tulaasi, bẹẹ nijọba o gbọdọ fipa fun ẹnikẹni labẹrẹ ọhun.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, nile-ẹjọ naa gbe aṣẹ yii kalẹ ninu idajọ lori ẹjọ kan ti nọmba rẹ jẹ FHC/PH/FHR/266/2021, eyi ti Ọgbẹni Charlse Godwin fi pe ijọba ipinlẹ Edo, Gomina Ọbaseki, atawọn mẹrin mi-in lẹjọ si kootu naa.Gomina Obaseki lo ti kọkọ paṣẹ laipẹ yii pe dandan ni ki gbogbo awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Edo lọọ gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona, aijẹ bẹẹ, ijọba le ma jẹ ki wọn ṣejọsin ni ṣọọṣi ati mọṣalaṣi, awọn banki ati awọn ile-ijọba, wọn si tun le padanu awọn anfaani ati ẹtọ kan lọdọ ijọba ti wọn o ba ṣe bẹẹ.Ipinnu yii ni olupẹjọ naa lọ pẹjọ le lori, o ni kile-ẹjọ ba awọn da si i, boya ijọba laṣẹ lati sọ gbigba abẹrẹ arun Korona di kan-n-pa bẹẹ.Ninu alaye rẹ, agbẹjọro olupẹjọ rọ ile-ẹjọ lati da ijọba lọwọ kọ na, ki wọn si faaye gba a pe kawọn oniroyin ati iwe iroyin gbe gbogbo bi ẹjọ naa ba ṣe lọ si sojutaye.Adajọ Adamu Turaki Mohammed to bojuto ẹjọ yii sọ pe oun fọwọ si ẹbẹ olupẹjọ, o ni kijọba Edo ma ṣe mu ẹnikẹni nipa lati gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona titi ti igbẹjọ yoo fi pari lori ẹjọ naa, o ni ẹnikẹni to ba nifẹẹ si i le lọọ gba a tabi kọyin si i.Adajọ naa sun igbẹjọ to kan si ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii."},{"question":"Inona avy ny karazana fitiavana?","answer":"Ny karazana fitiavana dia ahitana ny fitiavan' olon-droa, ny fitiavana ny fianakaviana, ny fitiava-namana ary ny fitiavana tsy misy fitiavan-tena. "},{"question":"In one sentence, explain the concept of mindfulness and its benefits for mental well-being.","answer":"Mindfulness is the practice of being fully present in the moment, without judgment. It has been shown to reduce stress, improve focus, and enhance overall mental well-being."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Sanadkii uu Soo Islaamay halyeey-gii Cumar Bin Khadaab Rc?","answer":"Wuxu Soo Islaamay Sanadkii 6-Aad ee nabinimada Rasuulka NNKH loo Soo Saaray."},{"question":"XORIYADDA CARUURTA WAA HALKA AY KA BILAABATO TARBIYADOODA!!!","answer":"XORIYADDA CARUURTA WAA HALKA AY KA BILAABATO TARBIYADOODA!!!.In la siiyo Caruurta wax badan oo Xoriyadda Noloshooda ka mid ah,waa qaybta ugu Muhiimsan ee Tarbiyada koriimadooda. Rasuulka scw Caruurtii uu tarbiyeeyay kuwii uu dhalay iyo kuwii uu koriyayba waligii gacan uma qaadin,ma canaanan oo hadal kulul kuma oran,kaliya Nasteexo ayuu siin jiray,caqligoodana wuu baraarujin jiray,wuxuuna u muujin jiray Ixtiraam. Rasuulka scw kolna lagama soo warin in uu Canug wax fahmi kara Amar qayaxan dul dhigay ama ku qayliyay. Saxaabiga Anas oo ka mid ahaa Caruurtii Nabiga scw uu tarbiyeeyay wuxuu CadeeyayToban Sano oo uu Nabiga scw u khidmeynayay in uusan kolna afaarihiisa gaarka u ah soo dhex galin nabiga scw. \\"خدمتُ رسولَ اللهِ صلَّى اللهُ عليهِ وسلَّم عشرَ سنينَ ، فما قال لي أُفٍّ قطُّ ، وما قال لي لشيٍء صنعتُه : لِمَ صنعتَه ، ولا لشيٍء تركتُه : لِمَ تركتَه ، وكان رسولُ اللهِ من أحسنِ الناسِ خُلُقًا ،\\"أخرجه البخاري (6911،3561) ومسلم (2309، 2330)“Waxaan u khidmeeyay Rasuulka scw oon la noolaa Toban Sano,waligii iima Caayin wax aan ku foognahay oo Uf ima oran,wax aan Sameeyay maxaad u samaysay ima oran waligii,wax aan ka tagay oon sameyn waayayna ima oran maxaad oga tagtay,Rasuulku wuxuu ahaa midka dadka ugu Dhaqanka iyo Akhlaaqda wanaagsan. Xadiiskaa waxaa laga qaadanayaa in Caruurta oo la siiyo Xoriyad tasaruf oon kol walba Amar iyo Diidmo iyo qaylo lala daba taagnaan in ay ka mid tahay waxyaabaha ugu Muhiimsan ee Tarbiyada Awlaadda caawiya abuurana Jawi kalsooni iyo Jacayl ay Caruurta u qaadaan waalidka ixtiraamaya wax badan oo doonistooda ka mid ah."},{"question":"සිංහරාජ වනාන්තරයේ ඇස්තමේන්තුගත වෘක්ෂලතා ඝනත්වය කොපමණද, එය ආසියාවේ අනෙකුත් වැසි වනාන්තර සමඟ සැසඳෙන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"සිංහරාජ වනාන්තරයේ ඇස්තමේන්තුගත වෘක්ෂලතා ඝනත්වය හෙක්ටයාරයකට පැල 240,000 ක් පමණ වන අතර එය ආසියාවේ වඩාත්ම ඝන වැසි වනාන්තරය බවට පත් කරයි. ආවේණික විශේෂයන්ගෙන් සමන්විත මෙම නිධානයට ගස්, කෘමීන්, උභයජීවීන්, උරගයින්, පක්ෂීන් සහ ක්ෂීරපායින් ඇතුළත් වේ."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੨ ॥ਮੰਤ੍ਰੀ ਹੋਇ ਅਠੂਹਿਆ ਨਾਗੀ ਲਗੈ ਜਾਇ ॥ ਆਪਣ ਹਥੀ ਆਪਣੈ ਦੇ ਕੂਚਾ ਆਪੇ ਲਾਇ ॥ਹੁਕਮੁ ਪਇਆ ਧੁਰਿ ਖਸਮ ਕਾ ਅਤੀ ਹੂ ਧਕਾ ਖਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਸਿਉ ਮਨਮੁਖੁ ਅੜੈ ਡੁਬੈ ਹਕਿ ਨਿਆਇ ॥ਦੁਹਾ ਸਿਰਿਆ ਆਪੇ ਖਸਮੁ ਵੇਖੈ ਕਰਿ ਵਿਉਪਾਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਏਵੈ ਜਾਣੀਐ ਸਭ ਕਿਛੁ ਤਿਸਹਿ ਰਜਾਇ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 148 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅੰਗਦ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਅਠੂਹਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਮਾਂਦਰੀ ਹੋ ਕੇ (ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਸੱਪਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾ ਹੱਥ ਪਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਹੀ ਹੱਥਾਂ ਨਾਲ (ਮਾਨੋ,) ਚੁਆਤੀ ਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਧੁਰੋਂ ਮਾਲਕ ਦਾ ਹੁਕਮ ਹੀ ਇਉਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਅੱਤ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਸ ਅੱਤ ਦੇ ਮੂਰਖਪੁਣੇ ਕਰ ਕੇ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਧੱਕਾ ਵੱਜਦਾ ਹੈ । ਮਨਮੁਖ ਮਨੱੁਖ ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਨਾਲ ਖਹਿਬੜਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਰਤਾਰ ਦੇ) ਸੱਚੇ ਨਿਆਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਉਹ (ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਵਿਚ) ਡੁੱਬਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਹਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਬੇੜੀ ਗ਼ਰਕ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ।ਪਰ (ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਦੋਸ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ, ਕੀਹ ਗੁਰਮੁਖ ਤੇ ਕੀਹ ਮਨਮੁਖ) ਦੋਹੀਂ ਪਾਸੀਂ ਖਸਮ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ (ਸਿਰ ਤੇ ਖਲੋਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ) ਹੈ, ਆਪ ਹੀ ਨਿਰਨਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਵੇਖ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਅਸਲ ਗੱਲ) ਇਉਂ ਹੀ ਸਮਝਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਹਰੇਕ ਕੰਮ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਰਜ਼ਾ ਵਿਚ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।\\""},{"question":"Kodi ndi maboma ati omwe ali mumphepete mwa Nyanja ya Malawi ?","answer":"Karonga, Rumphi, Nkhata bay, Nkhota Kota, Salima. Dress ndi Mangochi ndi omwe ali mumphepete mwa nyanjayi"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo vanim-potoana nandalovan'ny literatiora malagasy?","answer":"Ireo vanimpotoana nandalovan'ny literatiora malagasy dia:-Ny vanim-potoana Kristiana-Ny vanim-potoana Mitady ny very-Ny vanim-potoana Fiforetana anaty-Ny vanim-potoana Fakantahaka-Ny vanim-potoana Nahamoana ny Literatiora-Ny vanim-potoana Fitakiana fahaleovan-tena na fanarenana-Ny vanim-potoana saritsarim-pahaleovantena-Ny vanim-potoana ankehitriny"},{"question":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा घुम्न लायक मुख्य ठाउँहरू के के हुन्?","answer":"काठमाडौं, पाटन, भक्तपुर काठमाडौं उपत्यकाका प्रमुख घुम्नलायक स्थल हुन् ।"},{"question":"ಕನ್ನಡದಲ್ಲಿ ಒಂದು ತಮಾಷೆಯ ಜೋಕ್ ಬರೆಯಿರಿ","answer":"ಭೀಮ: ನಿಂಗೆ ಎಷ್ಟು ಮಕ್ಕಳುಸೋಮ: ಹನ್ನೆರಡು, ಹೆಂಡ್ತಿ ಗರ್ಭಿಣಿಭೀಮ: ಅಷ್ಟೊಂದು ಮಕ್ಕಳಾ?ಸೋಮ: ಹೆಂಡ್ತಿನ ಖಾಲಿ ಹೊಟ್ಟೆಲಿ ಇರಲು ಬಿಡೋಲ್ಲ ಎಂದು ಮಾವನಿಗೆ ಮಾತುಕೊಟ್ಟಿದ್ದೇನೆ.."},{"question":"*متى كانت أول حملة صليبية على القدس ؟","answer":"عام 1099 م"},{"question":"Inona no teny ilazana ny fampitsaharana tanteraka ny asa ataon'ny mpampiasa?1-Ny fandroahana2-Ny fametraham-pialana3- Ny fisotroan-dronono","answer":"Valiny: 1. Fandroahana"},{"question":"'මූලධර්මවාදී සෛවවාදියෙක්' යන්නෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"හින්දු ( සිව) අාගම පිළිබඳ දැඩි මතධාරියෙක්"},{"question":"बॅगिंग\\" (Bagging)","answer":"\\"बॅगिंग\\" (Bagging) हे मशीन लर्निंग आणि अल्गोरिथमिक प्रक्रिया आहे ज्यामध्ये एका मॉडेलच्या प्रवृत्तीवरील तक्रारींच्या समस्येच्या परिस्थितीत काम करण्याच्या प्रक्रियेच्या एक संख्यात्मक नियोजनाची प्रक्रिया आहे. बॅगिंग म्हणजे \\"बूट्स्ट्रॅप आणि अग्रेगेटिंग\\" च्या आकलनाच्या संक्षिप्त रूपाची प्रक्रिया आहे.बॅगिंगचा मूळ काम असा आहे की त्याच्या मूळ मॉडेलस काही प्रक्रिया घेतली जाते आणि त्यातल्या प्रत्येक मॉडेलसला तयार केलेल्या डेटासेटमध्ये एकाधिक किंवा एकाधिक तरंगाने डेटा नक्कीपूर्वक प्रशिक्षण दिला जातो. नंतर, सर्व मॉडेल्सच्या पूर्वगणनेच्या परिणामांची सारणी तयार केली जाते आणि त्या सारणीतील प्रत्येक प्रवृत्तीसाठी औद्योगिक निर्णय घेतला जातो.आपल्याला बॅगिंगच्या मदतीने अधिक स्थिर आणि अधिक मजबूत मॉडेल मिळवायला मदतील. असा मॉडेलस तयार केल्यास, तो किंवा अधिक स्थिर आणि अधिक व्यक्तिगतिकृत होतो. बॅगिंगच्या वापरामुळे आपल्या मॉडेलसमध्ये विचाराच्या वर्गाच्या संवेगाच्या दृढीकरणाची अधिक मान्यता मिळते आणि त्याचे दुरुस्तीकरण केले जाते.संक्षेपक, बॅगिंग हे एक संख्यात्मक प्रक्रिया आहे ज्यामध्ये अनेक मॉडेल्स तयार केल्या जातात आणि त्यांना विचाराच्या वर्गाच्या संवेगाच्या दृढीकरणाच्या विचारासाठी एकत्र आणण्यात मदतीला येते."},{"question":"Qual a função da ONU?a) Zelar pela cultura em todas as naçõesb) Unir as nações com o objetivo de manter a paz e a segurança mundialc) Financiar países em desenvolvimentod) Regular o funcionamento do sistema financeiro a nível internacionale) Gerenciar acordos de comércio entre os países","answer":"A resposta correta é a alternativa b) Unir as nações com o objetivo de manter a paz e a segurança a nível internacional.A Organização das Nações Unidas (ONU), criada em 1945, tem como objetivos:- Manter a paz e a segurança;- Proteger os direitos humanos;- Distribuir ajuda humanitária;- Promover o desenvolvimento sustentável;- Defender o direito internacional."},{"question":"Manana ity teny manaraka ity ianao:\\"mitsiky\\", vinavinao ny fotonteny.","answer":"Ny fotontenin'ny teny hoe \\"mitsiky\\" dia \\"tsiky\\""},{"question":"Kí ni Uba Sani àti Isa Ashiru ń sọ nípa ìdájọ́ ìgbìmọ̀ tó ń gbẹ́jọ́ awuyewuye èsì ìdìbò Gómìnà ní Kaduna","answer":"Lọjọbọ yi ni igbimọ to n gbẹjọ lori awuyewuye to jẹyọ ninu esi idibo Gomina ipinlẹ Kaduna gbe idajọ kalẹ.Wọn wọgile atako ti oludije ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP gbe wa pe oun ko faramọ ijaweolubori Uba Sani oludije ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC/Amọ nibi ọrọ de bayii, awọn igun mejeeji lo n sọ pe awọn ni idajọ naa gbe lẹyin.Awọn aṣoju ẹgbẹ mejeeji lo wa ni ile ẹjọ lỌjọbọ nibi tawọn adajọ ko ti yọju lati gbe idajọ kalẹ.Yala, niṣe ni wọn kede idajọ wọn loju opo ayelujara Zoom fawọn to peju si ile ẹjọ.Ko si alaye kan pato lori idi ti wọn fi ka idajọ wọn loju opo Zoom amọ awọn eeyan sọ pe o ni ohun ṣe pẹlu aabo nitori bara awọn eeyan ko ṣe balẹ ṣaaju ikede yi.Ko fẹ ẹ si eyi ti ko lawọn jaweloboiri ninu igun ti ọrọ yi kan amọ bi Uba Sani ṣe n kesi awọn to tako ijaweolubori rẹ lati pawọpọ pẹlu ijọba rẹ, bẹẹ ni Isa Ashiru ọun ṣe n sọ pe o n jiroro pẹlu awọn agbẹjọro rẹ lori igbesẹ to kan bayii.Nkan tokan bayii ku sọwọ Isa Ashiru-Gomina Uba SaniNinu ọrọ tirẹ, Gomina Uba Sani sọ pe idajọ igbimọ lori esi idibo tunbọ fidi ododo mulẹ pe oun loun jaweolubori nitori lọkan toun, ko si magomago kankan nidi idibo to waye.''Ki Allah gbe aṣeyọri fun wa.Fawọn alatako ẹgbẹ PDP to fidirẹmi, mo fẹ ki wọn gba pe ẹni to ba wu ni Ọlọrun maa n gbe agbara fun.Mo fẹ fi da awọn eeyan Kaduna loju pe a ko ni ṣe jamba fẹnikankan''''Ko buru bi Isa Ashiru ṣe gba ile ẹjọ lọ nitori ile ẹjọ naa leeyan ti le beere fun ẹtọ rẹ labẹ ofin''O tẹsiwaju pe awọn eeyan kan gbe iroyin ẹlẹjẹ kaakiri loju opo ayelujara pe Isa Ashiru lo jaweolubori.O ni ''awa kii tẹle ahesọ ọrọ nitori gbogbo eeyan naa lo ti gbọ idajọ igbimọ. O ku sọwọ Ashiru lati fi igbagbọ rẹ sọdọ Ọlọrun.''Gomina Uba Sani sọ pe awọn ko foya koda ki oludije PDP gba ile ẹjọ lọ lọjọ iwaju.O ni ohun to jẹ awọn logunbayii ni kawọn tẹsiwaju mimu awọn adehun tawọn ṣe pẹlu araalu ṣẹ nipinlẹ Kaduna.Esi ree lati ẹnu Isa AshiruDidakẹ ko tunmọ si pe a ko ni ku.Bẹẹ ni oludije ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ninu ibo Gomina Kaduna ṣe fesi lẹyin idajọ igbimọ to n gbẹjọ gbe ọrọ wọn kalẹ.O sọ pe 'igbimọ sọ pe ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC kuna lati faaye gba Uba Sani lati dije du ipo ninu idibo to waye.\\"Meji ninu awọn adajọ to gbe idajọ kalẹ sọ pe ki wọn gba iwe ẹri moyege ti Inec fun Uba Sani padda lọwọ rẹ ki wọn si tun idibo ṣe lawọn ibudo idibo kan ni ipinlẹ Kaduna''Lafiku o ni ''a ti sọ fun agbẹjọro wa wi pe ko wo idajọ yi daada ki a baa le mọ nkan to kan ti a o ṣe bayii''Ashiru sọ pe oun ko tori ara oun tako idajọ igbimọ bi kii ṣe tori awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Kaduna.O lawọn yoo wo idajọ igbimọ ti ko ba si tẹ awọn lọrun awọn yoo tẹsiwaju lọ ile ẹjọ to tun kan lati tako ọrọ yi.O ni igbesẹ akọkọ ree tawọn yoo gbe.Ki gaan ni igbimọ sọ ninu idajọ wọn?Igbimọ ẹlẹni mẹta to gbọ igbẹjọ awuyewuye labẹ idari adajọ Victor Oviawe sọ pe awọn olupẹjọ kọ lati tete gbe ẹjọ wọn wa laarin ọsẹ kan ti iwe ofin Naijiria la kalẹ.Bẹẹ naa ni wọn sọ pe Uba Sani jare lori idahun rẹ pe ọrọ ti Isa Ahiru gbe wa siwaju igbimọ ko fẹsẹ mulẹ rara.Wọn tun sọ pe kani awọn ko fọwọ rọ ẹsun ti Ashiru gbe wa danu ni, awọn ki ba sọ pe ki wọn ṣe atundi ibo lawọn aaye idibo mejlelogun kan ni Kaduna laarin aadọrin ọjọ ninu idajọ ipilẹ awọn."},{"question":"Pemandangan di kawasan sawah itu ______ pada waktu pagi.","answer":"indah nian"},{"question":"வினா:‘சுப்புரத்தினம் ஒர் கவி ’ என்று பாரதிதாசனை அறிமுகிப்படுத்தியவர் ?","answer":"விடை: பாரதியார்"},{"question":"वित्तीय स्थिरता मा काम सन्तुष्टि को प्रभाव अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"जागिरको सन्तुष्टिले क्यारियर वृद्धि र जागिर कायम राख्ने गरी वित्तीय स्थिरतालाई सकारात्मक रूपमा प्रभाव पार्न सक्छ। काममा सन्तुष्टिले प्रायः आम्दानी क्षमता र राम्रो आर्थिक नतिजाहरू बढाउँछ।"},{"question":"احساس سرماخوردگی دارم. چه توصیه‌ای برایم داری؟","answer":"سرما خوردگی یک بیماری ویروسی است بهترین توصیه برای بهبودش استراحت و استفاده از مایعات گرم و غداها و میوه های  ویتامین‌دار است. همچنین بهتر است برای اطمیتان از نوع بیماری خود و گرفتن توصیه‌های تخصصی‌تر به پزشک مراجعه کنید."},{"question":"Manomeza tenina mpanidinika iray momban'ny vintana .","answer":"Ity misy tenina mpandinika iray momban'ny vintana :   “Lahatra tsy azo iolahana na ifidiana ny vintana.”nosoratan'i EDA."},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: 2017 sezonunda Mercedes F1 takımına geçen Bottas ilk yarış galibiyetini 2017 Rusya Grand Prix'inde kazanmıştır.Ayrıca o sezon","answer":"2017 Avusturya Grand Prix ve 2017 Abu Dabi Grand Prix'lerini kazanıp 305 puanla 3. olarak bitirmiştir."},{"question":"ஒகேனக்கல் என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள் _________பவளப்பாறைவழுக்குப்பாறைபனிப்பாறைபுகைப்பாறை","answer":"விடை : புகைப்பாறை"},{"question":"懐かしの人気漫画『キャッツ・アイ』で活躍した三姉妹とは、泪（るい）、瞳とあと一人は誰でしょう？","answer":"愛"},{"question":" السؤال: شنو هو النوع ديال الصلاه ديال الجمع اللي ممكن المسلمين يصليوها فوقت الشتا؟","answer":"الجواب: جمع التقديم فقط."},{"question":"inona ary izany ny soa tsy fangalatra?","answer":"ny vadin'olona no soa tsy fangalatra"},{"question":"பரிணாம கோட்பாட்டின் தந்தை யார்? ","answer":"விடை: சார்ஸ் டார்வின்"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da tamanin da bakwai a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 187"},{"question":"Манас эпосуЖазгыч манасчылара) Дункана Кочуке уулу, Чоңдуб) Мамбет Чокмор уулу, Ш. Рысмендеевв) Ыбырайым Абдырахман уулу, Тоголок Молдо","answer":"Манас эпосув) Ыбырайым Абдырахман уулу, Тоголок Молдо"},{"question":"كمل الحكي:\\"رامي، شو رأيك نروح رحلة ؟ أنا وإنت لحالنا ؟\\"آه، ليش لأ؟ وين نروح؟\\"","answer":"\\"ع البترا\\"\\"متى نروح؟\\"\\"يوم عيد ميلادي.\\""},{"question":"Wat voor trivia vraag hoort bij SpaceX?","answer":"We gaan naar de maan! Niet enkel figuurlijk, maar NASA heeft te kennen gegeven om tegen 2025 weer een mens op de maan te willen zetten.Voor deze maanmissies gaat NASA in zee met een commercieel bedrijf om de maanvluchten uit te voeren. Dat bedrijf bewees in 2020 al dat het in staat was om succesvol astronauten af te leveren in het Internationaal ruimtestation. Hoe heet dit bedrijf dat we ook kennen van de satelliettreintjes die regelmatig te zien zijn?"},{"question":"林黛玉对后世的影响是什么？","answer":"林黛玉是古代文学作品中极富灵气的经典女性形象。她对后世产生了深远的影响，成为了人们心中的理想女性。"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഇന്ത്യയുടെ വിഭജനം എന്തായിരുന്നു?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: 1947-ൽ നടന്ന ഇന്ത്യയുടെ വിഭജനം, ബ്രിട്ടീഷ് ഇന്ത്യയെ രണ്ട് വ്യത്യസ്ത രാഷ്ട്രങ്ങളായി വിഭജിക്കുകയായിരുന്നു: ഇന്ത്യയും പാകിസ്ഥാനും. ഈ വിഭജനം മതപരമായ അടിസ്ഥാനത്തിലായിരുന്നു, ഇന്ത്യ പ്രധാനമായും ഹിന്ദു ഭൂരിപക്ഷ രാഷ്ട്രമായതിനാൽ പാകിസ്ഥാൻ മുസ്ലീം ഭൂരിപക്ഷ രാഷ്ട്രമായി സൃഷ്ടിക്കപ്പെട്ടു."},{"question":"भारत की पहली महिला प्रधानमंत्री कौन थीं?","answer":"श्रीमती इंदिरा गांधी भारत की पहली महिला प्रधानमंत्री थीं।"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపుగా ఒక పేరా రాయండి:చిందు భాగోతం ప్రదర్శన : చిందు భాగవతం ప్రదర్శించడానికి ముందు నాలుగు గుంజలు, వెనక రెండు గుంజలు పాతి పందిరి వేస్తారు. ఆ పందిరి కిందనే భాగోతం ప్రదర్శిస్తారు. పందిరి లేకుంటే భాగోతం ఆడరు. పందిరిని చాందిని అని కూడా అంటారు. పందిరికి మూడుపక్కల ఎడ్లకు కట్టే పగ్గాల కంటే లావుగా ఉండే జనుముతో చేసిన తాళ్లను కట్టేవారు. భాగోతం చూడడానికి వచ్చిన వారు మీద పడకుండా ఈ తాళ్ళను కట్టేవారు. దొమ్మరి బిడ్డ గడ (రెండువైపులా కర్రలు పాతి వాటి మధ్యలో తాడు కట్టేవారు. ఆ తాడుపై పెద్ద వెదురు కర్ర పట్టుకొని నడిచేవారు) ఎక్కి సాలా పులిగోలిగా అని బియ్యం సల్తది. మాదిగ చిందోల్లు ఎల్లమ్మ యేషం గట్టి చెరువులు మొకం కడిగితేనే మోక్షం, బరుకతు అని భావించే వారు. అట్లాంటిది మారిపోయి నడి ఊర్లో భాగోతం ఆడటం ఎల్లమ్మ తాతల కాలంలోనే ప్రారంభమైంది.","answer":"“ఇవ్వాల చిందు భాగోతం ఆడుతుండ్రట, పోవాలరా” అనేవారు. ఇవ్వాల “ఎల్లమ్మ ఆట ఆడుతున్నరు. గావు పట్టేదున్నదట పోవాల” అని ఊరివాల్లు వచ్చేవారు. పాత రోజుల్లో రాత్రులు ఊర్లో భాగోతం ఆడుతున్నపుడు మంగలోల్లు దివిటీలు పట్టేవారు."},{"question":"கேள்வி: ஒளி பரவலுக்கு சில தினசரி வாழ்க்கை உதாரணங்களைக் கொடுங்கள். ","answer":"சரியான பதில்: பின்வரும் இடங்களில் சிதறலைக் காணலாம்: வானவில் உருவாக்கம் - காற்றின் ஒளிவிலகல் குறியீடு மற்றும் நீர் துளிகளின் ஒளிவிலகல் குறியீடு வேறுபட்டது, இதன் காரணமாக நீர்த்துளியின் மூலம் ஒளிவிலகல் வெள்ளை ஒளியின் கதிர் ஏழு வண்ணங்களாகப் பிரிகிறது. குறுவட்டு மூலம் பிரதிபலிப்பு - குறுந்தகடு பளபளப்பான மேற்பரப்பில் விழும் வெள்ளை ஒளியானது விலகலுக்கு உள்ளாகி பல்வேறு அல்லது ஏழு வண்ணங்களாகப் பிரிகிறது. முப்பட்டைக் கண்ணாடி மூலம் ஒளிவிலகல் - வைரம் அல்லது முப்பட்டைக் கண்ணாடி பல்வேறு ஒளிவிலகல் மேற்பரப்புகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளது, இதன் காரணமாக வெள்ளை ஒளி வளைந்து விலகுகிறது மற்றும் இறுதியாக வெவ்வேறு வண்ணங்களாகப் பிரிகிறது."},{"question":"ලඝු ගණක චක්‍රය ඉදිරිපත් කළේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"සර් ජෝන් හේපියර්"},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Espanha?","answer":"Madrid."},{"question":"영단어 ketchup의 유래가 궁금해요.","answer":"1680년대, catsup로도 철자가 나타났으며, 이 철자는 조너선 스위프트의 1730년 시 A Panegyrick on the D--n.에서 처음 등장했다. 이 철자는 미국에서 아직도 사용되며, cat과 sup의 영향을 받았다.초기 사용에서는 과일과 향신료로 만든 동인도 소스로 묘사되었으며, catchup로 철자가 되었다. 이 기원이 맞다면, 툴루어 kajipu에서 유래된 것으로, \\"커리\\"를 뜻하는 kaje에서 비롯된 것으로 알려졌다. 그러나 이 단어는 보통 ketchup로 철자가 되며, 초기 사용에서는 멸치나 간장과 비슷한 것으로 묘사되었다. 현대의 소스에서는 말레이어(오스트로네시아어) kichap에서 유래된 것으로 알려져 있으며, 중국어 koechiap\\"물고기의 염수\\"에서 비롯된 것으로, 이 경우 북베트남의 중국계 커뮤니티에서 유래된 것일 수 있다 [Terrien de Lacouperie, \\"Babylonian and Oriental Record,\\" 1889, 1890].Lockyer의 1711년 책 \\"An Account of Trade in India\\"는 \\"소이는 일본에서 통에 담겨 오고, 최고의 케첩은 통칭 [베트남]에서 나온다. 그러나 두 종류 모두 중국에서 매우 싼 가격에 만들어 판매된다\\"고 말한다. 이는 영국인들이 인도에서 케첩이라고 부르는 소스를 수입해왔으며, 이것이 다른 국가의 레시피와 다를 수도 있다는 것을 시사한다.이 재료는 1680년대 영국 요리책에 등장했으며, 1720년대에는 버섯 소스를 모방한 집에서 만든 소스가 등장했다. 윌리엄 키카이너의 \\"Apicius Redivivus; or, the Cook's Oracle,\\" 런던, 1817에서는 호두, 버섯, 굴, 조개, tomata, 흰색 (식초와 멸치가 들어간다) 오이, 푸딩 케첩을 비롯한 다양한 종류의 케첩 레시피가 7 페이지에 걸쳐 소개되었다. Chambers's Encyclopaedia (1870)에서는 버섯, 호두, 토마토 케첩이 \\"가장 존경받는 세 가지 종류\\"로 나열되어 있다. 토마토 케첩은 미국에서 1800년경에 등장하였으며, 20세기 초반부터 우세해졌다. \\"토마토 케첩\\"을 뜻하는 ketchup이라는 단어는 1921년에 사용되기 시작했다."},{"question":"COVID - 19 මරණ 50 000 ඉක්මවූ , පළමුවැනි යුරෝපා රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"COVID - 19 මරණ 50 000 ඉක්මවූ , පළමුවැනි යුරෝපා රට,මහා බ්‍රිතාන්‍යය"},{"question":"Nisha Kalema","answer":"Nisha Kalema (bíi ni ọdún 1993) jẹ́ òṣèré, akọ́wé àti olùgbé jáde eré lórílẹ̀-èdè Uganda. Ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré bìnrin to dára jù lọ láti ọ̀dọ̀ Uganda Film Festival Award ní ọdún 2015, 2016 àti 2018 fún ipa tí ó kó nínú eré The Tailor, Freedom àti Veronica's Wish.Kalema di gbajúmọ̀ òṣèré nípa eré Galz About Town. Ó kó ipa olórí àwọn aṣẹ́wó tí orúkọ rẹ̀ jẹ́ Clara nínú eré náà. Ní ọdún 2015, Hassan Mageye fi Kalema ṣe Grace nínú eré The Grace. Eré náà sì ló jẹ́ kí ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ òṣèré bìnrin to dára jù lọ tí ó kọ́kọ́ gbà. Ní ọdún 2016, ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ kejì gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèrébìnrin to dára jù lọ fún ipa Amelia tí ó kó nínú eré Freedom. Eré náà sì gba àmì ẹ̀yẹ mẹ́fà. Ní ọdún 2016, ó ṣe Prossy nínú eré Jinxed. Ní ọdún 2018, ó kó ipa Veronica nínú eré Veronica's Wish. Ó ṣe bí èèyàn tó ní àrùn jẹjẹrẹ nínú eré náà. Eré náà sì ló jẹ́ kí ó gbà àmì ẹ̀yẹ kẹta gẹ́gẹ́ bí òṣèré bìnrin to dára jù lọ. Eré náà sì ti gba àmì ẹ̀yẹ mẹ́ẹ̀sán.Kalema lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ St Charles Lwanga Primary School àti Kainabiri Secondary. Ó gboyè nínú ìmò ìròyìn láti ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí Buganda Royal Institute of Business and Technical Education ní ọdún 2013."},{"question":"යුනෙස්කෝ  ලෝක උරුම වැඩිම ප්‍රමාණයක් අයත් රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"යුනෙස්කෝ  ලෝක උරුම වැඩිම සංඛ්‍යාවක් ඇත්තේ  ඉතාලියටයි. ඉතාලිය එහි පොහොසත් සංස්කෘතික හා  ඓතිහාසික උරුමයන් සඳහා  ප්‍රසිද්ධ  වන අතර, ඒවායේ කැපී පෙනෙන විශ්වීය වටිනාකම සඳහා  පිළිගත් ඓතිහාසික නගර, ස්මාරක, කලා  එකතු කිරීම් සහ භූ දර්ශන වැනි පුළුල් ස්ථාන ඇතුළත් වේ. ඉතාලියේ ඇති ලෝක උරුම ස්ථාන ගණන රෝම අධිරාජ්‍යය, පුනරුදය සහ ඉන් ඔබ්බට ඇතුළු විවිධ කාල පරිච්ඡේද තුළ කලාව, ගෘහ නිර්මාණ ශිල්පය සහ ඉතිහාසය සඳහා  රටෙහි සැලකිය යුතු දායකත්වය පිළිබිඹු කරයි."},{"question":"Sino-sino ang miyembro ng Apo Hiking Society?","answer":"Ang Apolinario Mabini (APO) Hiking Society ay isang banda na kadalasang itinturing na isa sa mga haligi ng Original Pilipino Music (OPM). Sila Danny Javier, Jim Paredes at Boboy Garovillo ang miyembro ng grupong ito. Nagretiro ang grupo noong 2010. Namatay si Javier noong 2022 dahil sa komplikasyon, habang patuloy na tumutugog at umaawit pa rin sina Paredes at Garrovillo bilang mga indibidwal na artista."},{"question":"கேள்வி: சுமந்து இச்சொல்லின் பொருள் ________தாங்கிபிரிந்துசேர்ந்துவிரைந்து","answer":"பதில் : சுமந்து இச்சொல்லின் பொருள் __தாங்கி__"},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahanao mijery ny ao anaty boaty fitaovana?","answer":" Azonao atao ny mijery ny ao anatin'ny boaty fitaovana amin'ny fanokafana fotsiny ny saron'ny boaty."},{"question":"පන් වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටියක් වන මොට්ලූ ගැන කරුණු කියන්න.","answer":"පන් වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටියක් වන මොට්ලූ (Small flower umbrella plant) ගැන කරුණු පහත දැක්වේ.විද්‍යාත්මක නම : Cyperus difformis Linnකුලය : Cyperaceaeලක්‍ෂණ  : මෙය වාර්ෂක පන් ශාකයකි. මි.මී. 1-4 ක් පමණ මෙහි කඳ මහත්වන අතර මෘදුය. බීජ මඟින් ප්‍රචාරණය සිදු වේ. මඩ සහිත කුඹුරුවල බහුලව දක්නට ලැබේ."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన గద్యానికి కొనసాగింపు రాయండి:పూర్వం తెలుగువారి వేడుకలు వినోదములు ఎలా ఉండేవో ఆధారాలు కూడా దొరకటం లేదు. ప్రబంధములలో చెప్పబడిన వసంతోత్సవాలు, శరదోత్సవాలు వేడుకలుగా కనిపిస్తున్నాయి. ప్రతిగ్రామంలో, గ్రామ సామూహిక మాన్యములుండేవి. దానిపై వచ్చే ఆదాయంతో వసంతోత్సవాలలో, శరదోత్సవాలలో పాల్గొనే కళాకారులకు వినియోగించేవారు. భాగవత మేళములు, తోలుబొమ్మలాటలు వేడుకలుగా ఉండేవి. వసంతోత్సవములు, శరదోత్సవములతోపాటు మకర సంక్రమణము కూడా ఒక పండుగే! మకర సంక్రమణమంటే సంక్రాంతి.తెలుగు దేశము వ్యవసాయ ప్రధానమైన దేశం అవటం చేత మేలుజాతి పశుసంపదను తయారుచేసేవారు. సంక్రాంతి, కనుమ పండుగనాడు పశుప్రదర్శన, ఎద్దుల పందాలు, కోడిపందాలు, పొట్టేళ్ళ పందాలు నిర్వహించేవారు. గ్రామాలలో గెలు పెద్దుల మాన్యములుండేవి. ఎడ్లపందాలలో ఏ ఎద్దు గెలుస్తుందో ఆ సంవత్సరమంతా ఆ భూమి ఆ ఎద్దు యజమాని ఆధీనంలో ఉంటుంది. ఇది ఈనాటి రోలింగ్ కప్ వంటిది.","answer":"సంక్రాంతినాడు జరిగే వేడుకలలో కోడిపందముల ఆట ఒకటి. కోడిపందాలు మన దేశంలో వేయి సంవత్సరాలకు పూర్వం నుండి వాడుకలో ఉన్న ఆట. ఇది దక్షిణ హిందూదేశములోనే కాక జావా, సుమిత్ర వంటి ప్రాంతాలలో కూడా ఉన్నట్లు తెలుస్తుంది. కోడిపందాలు సంస్థానాధీశులకు చాలా ప్రియమైన వేడుక. పలనాటి యుద్ధము కోడిపందెముల కారణంగానే జరిగిందని చరిత్ర చెప్తుంది.క్రీడాభిరామం, భోజరాజీయం మొదలగు గ్రంథములలో వృషభ, మేష, దున్నల, గజముల, పొట్టేళ్ళ పోరులు వర్ణించబడ్డాయి. కుంతలదేశాధిపతి అయిన భూలోక మల్ల సోమేశ్వరభూపతి తమ ‘మానసోల్లాస’ కావ్యమునందు ఒక ప్రకరణమంతా వీటిని గురించే వ్రాశాడు. వీటితోపాటుగా నాటి రాజుల ఆట వేట. ఈ వేటలో పాదివేట, లిడివేట, తెరవేట, దామెనవేట అను పలురకముల ఆటలున్నాయి. ప్రబంధములలోని అష్టాదశ వర్ణనలలో ‘వేట’ కూడా ఒకటి. ఇలా పూర్వకాలమున ఆటలు, వేడుకలు, వినోదాలు, పోటీలు, యుద్ధాలు ప్రజలకు వినోదాన్ని అందించేవని కవి పేర్కొన్నారు."},{"question":"वाराणसी  शिक्षा","answer":"== शिक्षा ==वाराणसी के उच्चतर माध्यमिक विद्यालय इंडियन सर्टिफिकेट ऑफ सैकेंडरी एजुकेशन (आई.सी.एस.ई), केन्द्रीय माध्यमिक शिक्षा बोर्ड (सी.बी.एस.ई) या उत्तर प्रदेश माध्यमिक शिक्षा परिषद (यू.पी.बोर्ड) से सहबद्ध हैं। === उच्च शिक्षा ===वाराणसी में तीन सार्वजनिक एवं एक मानित विश्वविद्यालय हैं:बनारस हिन्दू विश्वविद्यालय जिसकी स्थापना १९१६ में पं.मदन मोहन मालवीय ने एनी बेसेंट के सहयोग से की थी। इसका १३५० एकड़ (५.५ वर्ग कि॰मी॰) में फैला परिसर काशी नरेश द्वारा दान की गई भूमि पर निर्मित है। इस विश्वविद्यालय में भारतीय प्रौद्योगिकी संस्थान (आई.आई.टी-बी.एच.यू) एवं आयुर्विज्ञान संस्थान विश्व के सर्वोच्च तीन एवं एशिया सबसे बड़े आवासीय विश्वविद्यालयों में से एक हैं। यहां १२८ से अधिक स्वतंत्र शैक्षणिक विभाग हैं।संपूर्णानंद संस्कृत विश्वविद्यालय: भारत के गवर्नर जनरल लॉर्ड कॉर्नवालिस ने इस संस्कृत महाविद्यालय की स्थापना १७९१ में की थी। ये वाराणसी का प्रथम महाविद्यालय था।इस महाविद्यालय के प्रथम प्रधानाचार्य संस्कृत प्राध्यापक जे म्योर, आई.सी.एस थे। इनके बाद जे.आर.बैलेन्टियन, आर.टी.एच.ग्रिफ़िथ, डॉ॰जी.थेवो, डॉ॰आर्थर वेनिस, डॉ॰गंगानाथ झा और गोपीनाथ कविराज हुए। भारतीय स्वतंत्रता उपरांत इस महाविद्यालय को विश्वविद्यालय बनाकर वर्तमान नाम दिया गया।महात्मा गांधी काशी विद्यापीठ एक मानित राजपत्रित विश्वविद्यालय है। इसका नाम भारत के राष्ट्रपिता महात्मा गांधी के नाम पर है और यहां उनके सिद्धांतों का पालन किया जाता है।केन्द्रीय तिब्बती अध्ययन विश्वविद्यालय सारनाथ में स्थापित एक मानित विश्वविद्यालय है। यहां परंपरागत तिब्बती पठन-पाठन को आधुनिक शिक्षा के साथ वरीयता दी जाती है। उदय प्रताप कॉलिज, एक स्वायत्त महाविद्यालय है जहां आधुनिक बनारस के उपनगरीय छात्रों हेतु क्रीड़ा एवं विज्ञान का केन्द्र है। वाराणसी में बहुत से निजी एवं सार्वजनिक संस्थान है, जहां हिन्दू धार्मिक शिक्षा की व्यवस्था है। प्राचीन काल से ही लोग यहां दर्शन शास्त्र, संस्कृत, खगोलशास्त्र, सामाजिक ज्ञान एवं धार्मिक शिक्षा आदि के ज्ञान के लिये आते रहे हैं। भारतीय परंपरा में प्रायः वाराणसी को सर्वविद्या की राजधानी कहा गया है। नगर में एक जामिया सलाफिया भी है, जो सलाफ़ी इस्लामी शिक्षा का केन्द्र है।इन विश्वविद्यालयों के अलावा शहर में कई स्नातकोत्तर एवं स्नातक महाविद्यालय भी हैं, जैसे अग्रसेन डिगरी कॉलिज, हरिशचंद्र डिगरी कॉलिज, आर्य महिला डिगरी कॉलिज, एवं स्कूल ऑफ मैंनेजमेंट।== संस्कृति ==वाराणसी का पुराना शहर, गंगा तीरे का लगभग चौथाई भाग है, जो भीड़-भाड़ वाली संकरी गलियों और किनारे सटी हुई छोटी-बड़ी असंख्य दुकानों व सैंकड़ों हिन्दू मंदिरों से पटा हुआ है। ये घुमाव और मोड़ों से भरी गलियां किसी के लिये संभ्रम करने वाली हैं। ये संस्कृति से परिपूर्ण पुराना शहर विदेशी पर्यटकों के लिये वर्षों से लोकप्रिय आकर्षण बना हुआ है। वाराणसी के मुख्य आवासीय क्षेत्र (विशेषकर मध्यम एवं उच्च-मध्यम वर्गीय श्रेणी के लिये) घाटों से दूर स्थित हैं। ये विस्तृत, खुले हुए और अपेक्षाकृत कम प्रदूषण वाले हैं।=== रामनगर की रामलीला ===यहां दशहरा का त्यौहार खूब रौनक और तमाशों से भरा होता है। इस अवसर पर रेशमी और ज़री के ब्रोकेड आदि से सुसज्जित भूषा में काशी नरेश की हाथी पर सवारी निकलती है और पीछे-पीछे लंबा जलूस होता है। फिर नरेश एक माह लंबे चलने वाले रामनगर, वाराणसी की रामलीला का उद्घाटन करते हैं। रामलीला में रामचरितमानस के अनुसार भगवान श्रीराम के जीवन की लीला का मंचन होता है। ये मंचन काशी नरेश द्वारा प्रायोजित होता है अर पूरे ३१ दिन तक प्रत्येक शाम को रामनगर में आयोजित होता है। अन्तिम दिन इसमें भगवान राम रावण का मर्दन कर युद्ध समाप्त करते हैं और अयोध्या लौटते हैं। महाराजा उदित नारायण सिंह ने रामनगर में इस रामलीला का आरम्भ १९वीं शताब्दी के मध्य से किया था।=== बनारस घराना ===बनारस घराना भारतीय तबला वादन के छः प्रसिद्ध घरानों में से एक है। ये घराना २०० वर्षों से कुछ पहले ख्यातिप्राप्त पंडित राम सहाय (१७८०-१८२६) के प्रयासों से विकसित हुआ था। पंडित राम सहाय ने अपने पिता के संग पांच वर्ष की आयु से ही तबला वादन आरम्भ किया था। बनारस-बाज कहते हैं। ये बनारस घराने की विशिष्ट तबला वादन शैली है। इन्होंने तत्कालीन संयोजन प्रारूपों जैसे जैसे गट, टुकड़ा, परान, आदि से भी विभिन्न संयोजन किये, जिनमें उठान, बनारसी ठेका और फ़र्द प्रमुख हैं।आज बनारसी तबला घराना अपने शक्तिशाली रूप के लिये प्रसिद्ध है, हालांकि बनारस घराने के वादक हल्के और कोमल स्वरों के वादन में भी सक्षम हैं। घराने को पूर्वी बाज मे वर्गीकृत किया गया है, जिसमें लखनऊ, फर्रुखाबाद और बनारस घराने आते हैं। बनारस शैली तबले के अधिक अनुनादिक थापों का प्रयोग करती है, जैसे कि ना और धिन। बनारस घराने में एकल वादन बहुत इकसित हुआ है और कई वादक जैसे पंडित शारदा सहाय, पंडित किशन महाराज और पंडित समता प्रसाद, एकल तबला वादन में महारत और प्रसिद्धि प्राप्त हैं। घराने के नये युग के तबला वादकों में पं॰ कुमार बोस, पं.समर साहा, पं.बालकृष्ण अईयर, पं.शशांक बख्शी, सन्दीप दास, पार्थसारथी मुखर्जी, सुखविंदर सिंह नामधारी, विनीत व्यास और कई अन्य हैं। बनारसी बाज में २० विभिन्न संयोजन शैलियों और अनेक प्रकार के मिश्रण प्रयुक्त होते हैं।== पवित्र नगरी ==वाराणसी या काशी को हिन्दू धर्म में पवित्रतम नगर बताया गया है। यहां प्रतिवर्ष १० लाख से अधिक तीर्थ यात्री आते हैं। यहां का प्रमुख आकर्षण है काशी विश्वनाथ मंदिर, जिसमें भगवान शिव के बारह ज्योतिर्लिंग में से प्रमुख शिवलिंग यहां स्थापित है।हिन्दू मान्यता अनुसार गंगा नदी सबके पाप मार्जन करती है और काशी में मृत्यु सौभाग्य से ही मिलती है और यदि मिल जाये तो आत्मा पुनर्जन्म के चक्र से मुक्त हो कर मोक्ष पाती है। इक्यावन शक्तिपीठ में से एक विशालाक्षी मंदिर यहां स्थित है, जहां भगवती सती की कान की मणिकर्णिका गिरी थी। वह स्थान मणिकर्णिका घाट के निकट स्थित है। हिन्दू धर्म में शाक्त मत के लोग देवी गंगा को भी शक्ति का ही अवतार मानते हैं। जगद्गुरु आदि शंकराचार्य ने हिन्दू धर्म पर अपनी टीका यहीं आकर लिखी थी, जिसके परिणामस्वरूप हिन्दू पुनर्जागरण हुआ। काशी में वैष्णव और शैव संप्रदाय के लोग सदा ही धार्मिक सौहार्द से रहते आये हैं।वाराणसी बौद्ध धर्म के पवित्रतम स्थलों में से एक है और गौतम बुद्ध से संबंधित चार तीर्थ स्थलों में से एक है। शेष तीन कुशीनगर, बोध गया और लुंबिनी हैं। वाराणसी के मुख्य शहर से हटकर ही सारनाथ है, जहां भगवान बुद्ध ने अपना प्रथम प्रवचन दिया था। इसमें उन्होंने बौद्ध धर्म के मूलभूत सिद्दांतों का वर्णन किया था। अशोक-पूर्व स्तूपों में से कुछ ही शेष हैं, जिनमें से एक धामेक स्तूप यहीं अब भी खड़ा है, हालांकि अब उसके मात्र आधारशिला के अवशेष ही शेष हैं। इसके अलावा यहां चौखंडी स्तूप भी स्थित है, जहां बुद्ध अपने प्रथम शिष्यों से (लगभग ५वीं शताब्दी ई.पू या उससे भी पहले) मिले थे। वहां एक अष्टभुजी मीनार बनवायी गई थी।वाराणसी हिन्दुओं एवं बौद्धों के अलावा जैन धर्म के अवलंबियों के लिये भी पवित तीर्थ है। इसे २३वें तीर्थंकर श्री पार्श्वनाथ का जन्मस्थान माना जाता है। वाराणसी पर इस्लाम संस्कृति ने भी अपना प्रभाव डाला है। हिन्दू-मुस्लिम समुदायों में तनाव की स्थिति कुछ हद तक बहुत समय से बनी हुई है।=== गंगा नदी ===भारत की सबसे बड़ी नदी गंगा करीब २,५२५ किलोमीटर की दूरी तय कर गोमुख से गंगासागर तक जाती है। इस पूरे रास्ते में गंगा उत्तर से दक्षिण की ओर यानि उत्तरवाहिनी बहती है। केवल वाराणसी में ही गंगा नदी दक्षिण से उत्तर दिशा में बहती है। यहां लगभग ८४ घाट हैं। ये घाट लगभग ६.५ किमी लं‍बे तट पर बने हुए हैं। इन ८४ घाटों में पांच घाट बहुत ही पवित्र माने जाते हैं। इन्हें सामूहिक रूप से 'पंचतीर्थी' कहा जाता है। ये हैं अस्सी घाट, दशाश्वमेध घाट, आदिकेशव घाट, पंचगंगा घाट तथा मणिकर्णिक घाट। अस्सी ‍घाट सबसे दक्षिण में स्थित है जबकि आदिकेशवघाट सबसे उत्तर में स्थित हैं।=== घाट ===वाराणसी में १०० से अधिक घाट हैं। शहर के कई घाट मराठा साम्राज्य के अधीनस्थ काल में बनवाये गए थे। वर्तमान वाराणसी के संरक्षकों में मराठा, शिंदे (सिंधिया), होल्कर, भोंसले और पेशवा परिवार रहे हैं। अधिकतर घाट स्नान-घाट हैं, कुछ घाट अन्त्येष्टि घाट हैं। कई घाट किसी कथा आदि से जुड़े हुए हैं, जैसे मणिकर्णिका घाट, जबकि कुछ घाट निजी स्वामित्व के भी हैं। पूर्व काशी नरेश का शिवाला घाट और काली घाट निजी संपदा हैं। वाराणसी में अस्सी घाट से लेकर वरुणा घाट तक सभी घाटों की दक्षिण की ओर से क्रमवार सूची इस प्रकार से है:"},{"question":"కింది వాటిలో ఏ పరమాణువు నిర్మాణంను ‘నీల్స్ బోర్’ సిద్ధాంతం సరిగ్గా వివరించింది?A) హైడ్రోజన్ పరమాణువుB) హీలియం పరమాణువుC) కార్బన్ పరమాణువుD) అన్ని పరమాణువులు","answer":"A) హైడ్రోజన్ పరమాణువు"},{"question":"கேள்வி:ஈ. வெ. இராமசாமி மேற்கோள் சிலவற்றைத் தருக.","answer":"பதில்:ஒருவன் தான் விரும்பும் நலன்கள் அனைத்தும் பிறருக்கும் உண்டாகச் செய்வதுதான் நாகரீகம்.ஆத்மா, மோட்சம், நரகம், மறுப்பிறப்பு, பிதிர்லோகம் ஆகியவற்றைக் கற்பித்தவன் அயோக்கியன்; நம்புகிறவன் மடையன்; இவற்றால் பலன் அனுபவிக்கிறவன் மகாமகா அயோக்கியன்.இல்வாழ்க்கை என்பது தனிப்பட்ட ஓர் ஆணுக்கோ ஒரு பெண்ணுக்கோ மட்டும் சொந்தமில்லை. இருவருக்கும் சொந்தமானது.நரகத்திற்குப் பயந்தவனால் ஒன்றும் செய்ய முடியாது. அதுவும் சமதர்மக் கொள்கைகளைப் பரப்ப வேண்டுமானால் நாத்திகனால்தான் முடியும்.சிந்தனைதான் அறிவை வளர்க்கும்; அறிவுதான் மனித வாழ்வை உயர்த்தும்.பார்ப்பனர்கள் நம்மைச் சூத்திரர்கள் என்று கூப்பிட்டால் நாம் அவர்களை மிலேச்சர்கள் என்று கூப்பிட வழக்கப்படுத்தவேண்டும்.ரயிலும், மோட்டாரும், ஆகாய கப்பலும் போக்குவரவு சாதனங்களும் இல்லாத காலத்தில் புளுக ஆரம்பித்தால் ஜனங்கள் கண்டு கொள்ள மாட்டார்கள் என்று கருதிப் பூலோகத்தில் இமயமலையை கைலயங்கிரி (வெள்ளிமலை) என்றும், பால்கடல், தயிர்க்கடல் சிரஞ்சீவிகளும் சித்தர்களும் இங்கு இருக்கிறார்கள் என்றும், மற்றும் இதுபோல் ஆசைதீரப் புளுகிவைத்தார்கள்.பேராசை இல்லாவிட்டால் எந்த மனிதனும் தனது புத்திக்கும் அனுபவத்திற்கும் ஒவ்வாததை ஒரு காலமும் நம்பிப் பின்பற்றமாட்டான்.முட்டாள்கள் உள்ள வரை அயோக்கியர்கள் ஆட்சி செய்வார்கள். இதுதான் ஜனநாயகம்.மதத்தையாவது, ஜாதியையாவது, கடவுளையாவது உண்மை என்று நம்பி அவைகளைக் காப்பாற்ற முயற்சிக்கும் எவனாலும் மக்களுக்குச் சமத்துவமும், அறிவும், தொழிலும், செல்வமும் ஒருக்காலும் ஏற்படவே ஏற்படாது.சூழ்ச்சியில் அடைந்த வெற்றி மனிதனை, சதா சூழ்ச்சியிலேயே இருக்கச் சொல்லுமே ஒழிய, வெற்றியை அனுபவிக்கக் கூட நேரமளிக்காது."},{"question":"Quel concept psychologique le chien de Pavlov l’a-t-il aidé à décrire ?","answer":"L'expérience canine de Pavlov l'a aidé à décrire le concept psychologique du conditionnement classique. Ivan Pavlov, un physiologiste russe, a mené des expériences avec des chiens pour étudier le processus d'apprentissage associatif, dans lequel un stimulus neutre est associé à un stimulus significatif pour produire une réponse comportementale spécifique.Dans l'expérience de Pavlov, les chiens ont été exposés à un stimulus neutre (une cloche) avant de recevoir de la nourriture, ce qui a naturellement déclenché une réponse salivaire. Au fil du temps, les chiens ont commencé à associer le son de la cloche à l’arrivée de la nourriture, ce qui les faisait saliver même lorsque la nourriture n’était pas présente. Le stimulus neutre (cloche) est devenu un stimulus conditionné qui a suscité une réponse conditionnée (salivation) similaire à la réponse originale à la nourriture. Ce processus d’apprentissage par association est devenu connu sous le nom de conditionnement classique et a jeté les bases de la compréhension de la manière dont les comportements peuvent être appris et modifiés en fonction d’indices environnementaux."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਸੁਣਿ ਮਨ ਭੂਲੇ ਬਾਵਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਚਰਣੀ ਲਾਗੁ ॥ਹਰਿ ਜਪਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇ ਤੂ ਜਮੁ ਡਰਪੈ ਦੁਖ ਭਾਗੁ ॥ਦੂਖੁ ਘਣੋ ਦੋਹਾਗਣੀ ਕਿਉ ਥਿਰੁ ਰਹੈ ਸੁਹਾਗੁ ॥੧॥ਭਾਈ ਰੇ ਅਵਰੁ ਨਾਹੀ ਮੈ ਥਾਉ ॥ਮੈ ਧਨੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਨਿਧਾਨੁ ਹੈ ਗੁਰਿ ਦੀਆ ਬਲਿ ਜਾਉ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤਿ ਪਤਿ ਸਾਬਾਸਿ ਤਿਸੁ ਤਿਸ ਕੈ ਸੰਗਿ ਮਿਲਾਉ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਘੜੀ ਨ ਜੀਵਊ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਮਰਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ਮੈ ਅੰਧੁਲੇ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਵੀਸਰੈ ਟੇਕ ਟਿਕੀ ਘਰਿ ਜਾਉ ॥੨॥ਗੁਰੂ ਜਿਨਾ ਕਾ ਅੰਧੁਲਾ ਚੇਲੇ ਨਾਹੀ ਠਾਉ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਨਾਉ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਕਿਆ ਸੁਆਉ ॥ਆਇ ਗਇਆ ਪਛੁਤਾਵਣਾ ਜਿਉ ਸੁੰਞੈ ਘਰਿ ਕਾਉ ॥੩॥ਬਿਨੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਦੁਖੁ ਦੇਹੁਰੀ ਜਿਉ ਕਲਰ ਕੀ ਭੀਤਿ ॥ਤਬ ਲਗੁ ਮਹਲੁ ਨ ਪਾਈਐ ਜਬ ਲਗੁ ਸਾਚੁ ਨ ਚੀਤਿ ॥ਸਬਦਿ ਰਪੈ ਘਰੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਨਿਰਬਾਣੀ ਪਦੁ ਨੀਤਿ ॥੪॥ਹਉ ਗੁਰ ਪੂਛਉ ਆਪਣੇ ਗੁਰ ਪੁਛਿ ਕਾਰ ਕਮਾਉ ॥ਸਬਦਿ ਸਲਾਹੀ ਮਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੁਖੁ ਜਲਿ ਜਾਉ ॥ਸਹਜੇ ਹੋਇ ਮਿਲਾਵੜਾ ਸਾਚੇ ਸਾਚਿ ਮਿਲਾਉ ॥੫॥ਸਬਦਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੇ ਨਿਰਮਲੇ ਤਜਿ ਕਾਮ ਕ੍ਰੋਧੁ ਅਹੰਕਾਰੁ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਸਲਾਹਨਿ ਸਦ ਸਦਾ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਖਹਿ ਉਰ ਧਾਰਿ ॥ਸੋ ਕਿਉ ਮਨਹੁ ਵਿਸਾਰੀਐ ਸਭ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥੬॥ਸਬਦਿ ਮਰੈ ਸੋ ਮਰਿ ਰਹੈ ਫਿਰਿ ਮਰੈ ਨ ਦੂਜੀ ਵਾਰ ॥ਸਬਦੈ ਹੀ ਤੇ ਪਾਈਐ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੇ ਲਗੈ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਸਬਦੈ ਜਗੁ ਭੂਲਾ ਫਿਰੈ ਮਰਿ ਜਨਮੈ ਵਾਰੋ ਵਾਰ ॥੭॥ਸਭ ਸਾਲਾਹੈ ਆਪ ਕਉ ਵਡਹੁ ਵਡੇਰੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਬਿਨੁ ਆਪੁ ਨ ਚੀਨੀਐ ਕਹੇ ਸੁਣੇ ਕਿਆ ਹੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਬਦਿ ਪਛਾਣੀਐ ਹਉਮੈ ਕਰੈ ਨ ਕੋਇ ॥੮॥੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 57 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ-ਪਏ ਕਮਲੇ ਮਨ ! (ਮੇਰੀ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ) ਸੁਣ (ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨੀ ਪਉ (ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈਤੂੰ ਭੀ ਉਹ) ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮ ਜਪ, (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਸੁਰਤਿ ਜੋੜ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਿਆਂ) ਜਮਰਾਜ (ਭੀ) ਡਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਜੜ ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਪਰ ਜੇਹੜੀ) ਭਾਗ-ਹੀਣ ਜੀਵ-ਇਸਤ੍ਰੀ (ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਿਮਰਦੀ, ਉਸ) ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਦੁੱਖ-ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਵਿਆਪਦਾ ਹੈ (ਦੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਜੜ ਤਦੋਂ ਹੀ ਪੈ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ, ਜੇ ਸਿਰ ਉਤੇ ਖਸਮ-ਸਾਈਂ ਹੋਵੇ, ਪਰ ਜੋ ਖਸਮ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਕਦੇ ਚੇਤੇ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੀ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਿਰ ਉਤੇ) ਖਸਮ-ਸਾਈਂ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਤ ਹੋਵੇ ? ।੧। ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! (ਨਾਮ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ) ਮੈਨੂੰ (ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ) ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ ਥਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਧਨ ਹੈ, ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਹੈ (ਇਹ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਜਿਸ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ (ਹੀ) ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਹਾਂ ਸ਼ਾਬਾਸ਼ੇ ਉਸ (ਗੁਰੂ) ਤੋਂ ਜਿਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਮਿਲਿਆਂ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ । (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ) ਮੈਂ ਉਸ (ਗੁਰੂ) ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਰਹਾਂ (ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਦਾਤਿ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੇ) ਉਸ ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਇਕ ਘੜੀ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿ ਸਕਦਾ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੇਰੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹ(ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮੈਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ) ਮੈਨੂੰ ਅੰਨ੍ਹੇ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਨਾਹ ਭੁੱਲ ਜਾਏ, ਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਪਰਨਾ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਹਾਂ ।੨। (ਪਰ ਗੁਰੂ ਭੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਸੁਜਾਖਾ ਹੋਵੇ) ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੁਰੂ (ਆਪ ਹੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ) ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੋਵੇ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਚੇਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ (ਆਤਮਕ ਸੁਖ ਦਾ) ਥਾਂ-ਟਿਕਾਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ (ਪੂਰੇ) ਗੁਰੂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ, ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ (ਸੁਚੱਜਾ) ਜੀਵਨ-ਮਨੋਰਥ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਤੋਂ ਵਾਂਜਿਆ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਿਚ ਆਇਆ ਤੇ ਤੁਰ ਗਿਆ, ਪਛਤਾਵਾ ਹੀ (ਨਾਲ ਲੈ ਗਿਆ, ਖਾਲੀ-ਹੱਥ ਹੀ ਜਗ ਤੋਂ ਗਿਆ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਸੁੰਞੇ ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਕਾਂ (ਆ ਕੇ ਖ਼ਾਲੀ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੩। ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ (ਚਿੰਤਾ ਆਦਿਕ ਇਤਨਾ) ਦੁੱਖ ਵਿਆਪਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਸੱਤਿਆ ਇਉਂ ਕਿਰਦੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ) ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਲਰ ਦੀ ਕੰਧ (ਕਿਰਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ) ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਣ ਲਈ) ਤਦ ਤਕ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ) ਮਹਲ (-ਰੂਪ ਸਹਾਰਾ) ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ, ਜਦ ਤਕ ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਜੀਵ ਦੇ) ਚਿੱਤ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਜੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਮਨ ਰੰਗਿਆ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਹਜ਼ੂਰੀ (ਦੀ ਓਟ) ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਲੱਭ ਪੈਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਕੋਈ ਵਾਸਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੋਹ ਸਕਦੀ ।੪। (ਸੋ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਇਸ ‘ਨਿਰਬਾਣ ਪਦ’ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਾਂਗੀ, ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛ ਕੇ (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਦੱਸੀ) ਕਾਰ ਕਰਾਂਗੀਮੈਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਕਰਾਂਗੀ, (ਭਲਾ ਕਿਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮੇਰੇ) ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਵੱਸੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਹੋਵੇ, ਮੇਰਾ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦਾ ਦੁੱਖ ਸੜ ਜਾਏ, ਸਹਜ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨਾਲ ਸੋਹਣਾ ਮਿਲਾਪ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ, ਸਦਾ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਮੇਰਾ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਮੇਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ।੫। ਜੇਹੜੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹ ਕਾਮ ਕੋ੍ਰਧ ਅਹੰਕਾਰ (ਆਦਿਕ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ) ਨੂੰ ਤਿਆਗ ਕੇ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ (ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲੇ) ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਲਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੀ ਯਾਦ) ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਜੇਹੜਾ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ (ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ) ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਭੀ ਮਨੋਂ ਭੁਲਾਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ।੬। ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜ ਕੇ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਲੋਂ) ਮਰ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ (ਇਹ ਮਰਨੀ) ਮਰ ਕੇ ਇਸਥਿਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਟਾਕਰੇ ਤੇ ਤਕੜਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਢਹੇ ਚੜ੍ਹ ਕੇ) ਮੁੜ ਕਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਰਦਾ (ਇਹ ਅਟੱਲ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ) ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਜਗਤ (ਜੀਵਨ-ਰਾਹ ਤੋਂ) ਖੁੰਝਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਭਟਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਮੁੜ ਮੁੜ ਜਨਮ ਮਰਨ ਦੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੭। ਸਾਰੀ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਲਾਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਾਡੀ ਵਧੀਕ ਤੋਂ ਵਧੀਕ ਵਡਿਆਈ-ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਹੋਵੇ (ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਦੀ ਸੂਝ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਇਹ ਲਾਲਸਾ ਬਣੀ ਹੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, ਗਿਆਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਿਰੀਆਂ ਕਹਿਣ ਸੁਣਨ ਨਾਲ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣਦਾ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੀ ਆਪਣਾ ਆਪ ਪਛਾਣਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ (ਜੇਹੜਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਆਪੇ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦਾ ।੮।੮।\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਜੈਸੇ ਕਿਰਸਾਣੁ ਬੋਵੈ ਕਿਰਸਾਨੀ ॥ਕਾਚੀ ਪਾਕੀ ਬਾਢਿ ਪਰਾਨੀ ॥੧॥ਜੋ ਜਨਮੈ ਸੋ ਜਾਨਹੁ ਮੂਆ ॥ਗੋਵਿੰਦ ਭਗਤੁ ਅਸਥਿਰੁ ਹੈ ਥੀਆ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਦਿਨ ਤੇ ਸਰਪਰ ਪਉਸੀ ਰਾਤਿ ॥ਰੈਣਿ ਗਈ ਫਿਰਿ ਹੋਇ ਪਰਭਾਤਿ ॥੨॥ਮਾਇਆ ਮੋਹਿ ਸੋਇ ਰਹੇ ਅਭਾਗੇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਕੋ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਜਾਗੇ ॥੩॥ਕਹੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਈਅਹਿ ਨੀਤ ॥ਮੁਖ ਊਜਲ ਹੋਇ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਚੀਤ ॥੪॥੧੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 375 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਾਣੀ! (ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਕੋਈ ਕਿਸਾਨ ਖੇਤੀ ਬੀਜਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਜਦੋਂ ਜੀ ਚਾਹੇ) ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਢ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਚਾਹੇ ਉਹ) ਕੱਚੀ (ਹੋਵੇ ਚਾਹੇ) ਪੱਕੀ (ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਤੇ ਮੌਤ ਕਿਸੇ ਭੀ ਉਮਰੇ ਆ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ) ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਯਕੀਨ ਜਾਣੋ ਕਿ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਜੀਵ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਮਰਦਾ ਭੀ (ਜ਼ਰੂਰ) ਹੈ ।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਭਗਤ (ਇਸ ਅਟੱਲ ਨਿਯਮ ਨੂੰ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਮੌਤ ਦੇ ਸਹਮ ਵਲੋਂ) ਅਡੋਲ-ਚਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਦਿਨ ਤੋਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਰਾਤ ਪੈ ਜਾਇਗੀ, ਰਾਤ (ਭੀ) ਮੁੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਫਿਰ ਮੁੜ ਸਵੇਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ (ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜਨਮ ਤੇ ਮਰਨ ਦਾ ਸਿਲਸਲਾ ਤੁਰਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੨।(ਇਹ ਜਾਣਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਕਿ ਮੌਤ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਆਉਣੀ ਹੈ) ਬਦ-ਨਸੀਬ ਬੰਦੇ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ (ਫਸ ਕੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਮਨੋਰਥ ਵਲੋਂ) ਗਾਫ਼ਿਲ ਹੋਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ (ਮੋਹ ਦੀ ਨੀਂਦ ਤੋਂ) ਜਾਗਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਆਖ—(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਸਦਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਏ ਜਾਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ (ਇਸ ਉੱਦਮ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ, ਇਕ ਤਾਂ, ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ) ਮੁਖ ਉਜਲਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਦੂਜੇ) ਮਨ (ਭੀ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੯।\\""},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Eagraíocht Dhomhanda Sláinte. ","answer":"Gníomhaireacht a bunaíodh taobh istigh de na Náisiúin Aontaithe i 1948 chun comhoibriú idirnáisiúnta i bhfeabhsú shláinte na ndaoine a chur chun cinn is ea an Eagraíocht Dhomhanda Sláinte (World Health Organization nó WHO). "},{"question":"自分には痛くもかゆくも感じない物事をたとえて、「対岸の何」というでしょう？","answer":"火事"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਕਰਿ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਹਰਿ ਪਰਗਟੀ ਆਇਆ ॥ਮਿਲਿ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਧਨੁ ਪੂਰਾ ਪਾਇਆ ॥੧॥ਐਸਾ ਹਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਸੰਚੀਐ ਭਾਈ ॥ਭਾਹਿ ਨ ਜਾਲੈ ਜਲਿ ਨਹੀ ਡੂਬੈ ਸੰਗੁ ਛੋਡਿ ਕਰਿ ਕਤਹੁ ਨ ਜਾਈ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਤੋਟਿ ਨ ਆਵੈ ਨਿਖੁਟਿ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥ਖਾਇ ਖਰਚਿ ਮਨੁ ਰਹਿਆ ਅਘਾਇ ॥੨॥ਸੋ ਸਚੁ ਸਾਹੁ ਜਿਸੁ ਘਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਸੰਚਾਣਾ ॥ਇਸੁ ਧਨ ਤੇ ਸਭੁ ਜਗੁ ਵਰਸਾਣਾ ॥੩॥ਤਿਨਿ ਹਰਿ ਧਨੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਿਸੁ ਪੁਰਬ ਲਿਖੇ ਕਾ ਲਹਣਾ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਅੰਤਿ ਵਾਰ ਨਾਮੁ ਗਹਣਾ ॥੪॥੧੮॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 375 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਵੀਰ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਪ ਆ ਪਰਤੱਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਕਦੇ ਨਾਹ ਘਟਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਹੇ ਵੀਰ! ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਇਕੱਠਾ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਅੱਗ ਸਾੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ, ਜੋ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਡੁੱਬਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਅਤੇ ਜੋ ਸਾਥ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਭੀ ਹੋਰ ਥਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ।੧। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਐਸਾ ਧਨ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਵਿਚ) ਕਦੇ ਘਾਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਜੋ ਕਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਮੁੱਕਦਾ । ਇਹ ਧਨ ਆਪ ਵਰਤ ਕੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੰਡ ਕੇ (ਮਨੱਖ ਦਾ) ਮਨ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਧਨ ਦੀ ਲਾਲਸਾ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਜਮ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਸਾਹੂਕਾਰ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਉਸ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਧਨ ਤੋਂ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਲਾਭ ਉਠਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। (ਪਰ, ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਉਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਹਰਿ-ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ ਹਾਸਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪੂਰਬਲੇ ਕੀਤੇ ਭਲੇ ਕਰਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਲਿਖੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਦਾਸ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਧਨ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਜਿੰਦ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਅਖ਼ੀਰਲੇ ਵੇਲੇ ਦਾ ਗਹਣਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੮।\\""},{"question":"Facelight kime yakışır?","answer":"Facelight saç modeli en çok açık saçlara yakışıyor. Bu yüzden saçlarını facelight yaptırdıktan sonra sıkı toplamak yerine daha çok açık bırakmalısın. Editörün önerisi: İşlem gören saçlarını açık şekillendirmek için sağlıklı saç uçlarına ihtiyacın var. Yıpranmış saç uçları saçlarını çok bakımsız gösterebilir."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Cập nhật giá đơn vị quỹ Prulink của Prudential Việt Nam","answer":"Xem thêm thông tin tại website: https://www.prudential.com.vn/vi/thong-tin-cac-quy-dau-tu/quy-lien-ket-don-vi-prulink/"},{"question":"న్యాయానికి గల మూడు ఆధారాలను పేర్కొనండి.","answer":"న్యాయం – నిర్వచనాలు:ప్లేటో: “వ్యక్తి తన పని తాను చేసుకుంటూ, ఇతరుల వ్యవహారాలలో జోక్యం చేసుకోకపోవడమే న్యాయం”.అరిస్టాటిల్: “న్యాయం అంటే సమాజంలో ప్రతి వ్యక్తీ తన నైతిక బాధ్యతలను నిర్వర్తించడం తప్ప మరేదీకాదు”.కెఫాలస్: “న్యాయం అంటే ప్రతి ఒక్కరూ సత్యాన్ని పలకడం, ఇతరులకు ఇవ్వాల్సింది ఇవ్వడం”. న్యాయం ఆధారాలు: ఎర్నస్ట్ బార్కర్ న్యాయానికి నాలుగు ఆధారాలున్నాయని పేర్కొన్నాడు. అవి: 1) ప్రకృతి 2) నైతికత 3) మతం 4) ఆర్థిక అంశాలు. వాటిని క్రింది విధంగా వివరించవచ్చు.1) ప్రకృతి: గ్రీకు యధేచ్ఛావాదులు ప్రకృతిని న్యాయం ఆధారాలలో ఒకటిగా భావించారు. వారి దృష్టిలో ప్రకృతి అనేది నైతిక తాత్వికత, మత విశ్వాసాల సమ్మేళనం. ప్రకృతి, దైవం, హేతువులనేవి అవిభాజ్యాలు. ప్రకృతి నియమాల ప్రకారం జీవనం సాగించే వ్యక్తులు భగవంతుడు, హేతువులపట్ల ఒకే విధమైన భావాలను కలిగి ఉంటారని వారు ఉద్ఘాటించారు. ప్రకృతి మూడు ప్రధాన అంశాలను సూచిస్తుందని వారు పేర్కొన్నారు. అవి: 1) మానవుడికి స్వాతంత్ర్యం ఉండాలి. 2) మానవులందరూ సమానమైన గుర్తింపును కలిగి ఉండాలి. 3) మానవులందరూ తోటి మానవులతో హేతువు ఆధారంగా స్నేహ సంబంధాలను కలిగి ఉండాలి. పైన పేర్కొన్న మూడు అంశాలు కాలక్రమేణా స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం, సౌభ్రాతృత్వం అనే మూడు భావనలకు ఆధారాలయ్యాయి.2) నైతికత: ఆదర్శవాదులైన ప్లేటో, ఎమ్మాన్యుయెల్ కాంట్, థామస్ హిల్లీ గ్రీన్, ఎర్నెస్ట్ బార్కర్లు న్యాయం అనేది నైతిక సూత్రాల అవలంబన ద్వారా అవతరించిందని ఉద్ఘాటించారు. కాలానుగుణంగా సమాజం |ఆమోదం పొందిన విలువలే సంవర్ధక న్యాయభావనకు ఆధారమయ్యాయని వారు పేర్కొన్నారు. తరువాత కాలంలో రాజ్యం సంవర్ధక న్యాయాన్ని అమలులో ఉంచేందుకు చర్యలు తీసుకొన్నదన్నారు.3) మతం: న్యాయానికి గల మరొక ఆధారమే మతం. మధ్యయుగం నుంచి మతం న్యాయానికి ఆధారంగా కొనసాగుతూ వచ్చింది. న్యాయం, మంచి, చెడులకు సంబంధించిన భావనలను భగవంతుడు ప్రవచించాడని క్రైస్తవమతాధిపతులు పేర్కొన్నారు. మతం ద్వారా న్యాయభావనలకు అంకురార్పణ చేసి, బలవంతుడే రాజ్య పాలకుడిగా ఉంటాడనీ వారు ఉద్ఘాటించారు. థామస్ అక్వినాస్ అనే మతాచార్యుడిగా మారిన తత్వవేత్త మతాన్ని క్రైస్తవచర్చికి ప్రతిరూపంగా విశ్వసించాడు. ఇతని ప్రకారం చట్టం ఆధారంగా కొనసాగే జీవనం ఉత్తమమైందిగా భావించాడు. రాజు ఎల్లప్పుడు ప్రజలను సన్మార్గంలో నడిపించాలన్నారు. రాజు తన అధికారాలను మతాధిపతి ఆధిపత్యానికి బద్ధుడై వినియోగించాలన్నాడు."},{"question":"\\"हकिङ विकिरण\\" सिद्धान्त र ब्ल्याक होलको लागी यसको प्रभाव व्याख्या गर।","answer":"हकिङ विकिरण एक सैद्धान्तिक भविष्यवाणी हो कि ब्ल्याक होलले विकिरण उत्सर्जन गर्न सक्छ र अन्ततः पिण्ड गुमाउन सक्छ। यसले सुझाव दिन्छ कि ब्ल्याक होलहरू बिस्तारै समयको साथ वाष्पीकरण हुन सक्छ।"},{"question":"ਤੀਰ ਸਾਨ੍ਹ ਦੀ ਅੱਖ ਦਾ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨਾਂ ਲਗਾਉਣ ਤੋਂ ਖੁੰਝ ਗਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਆਦਮੀ ਦਾ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨਾ ਨਹੀ ਲਗਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਆਦਮੀ ਖੇਡ ਹਾਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਆਦਮੀ ਦਾ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨਾ ਨਹੀ ਲਗਿਆ।"},{"question":" புவியியலின் தந்தைஎன  அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார் ?","answer":"பண்டைய கிரேக்க அறிஞர் எரடோஸ்தீனஸ் \\"புவியியலின் தந்தை\\" என்று அழைக்கப்படுகிறார். புவியியல் என்ற வார்த்தையை முதன்முதலில் பயன்படுத்தியவர் அவர், மேலும் அவர் கிரகத்தைப் பற்றிய சிறிய அளவிலான புரிதலையும் கொண்டிருந்தார், இது பூமியின் சுற்றளவைக் கணக்கிடுவதில் அவருக்கு உதவியது. எரடோஸ்தீனஸ் பரந்த அளவிலான திறன்களைக் கொண்டிருந்தார். கிமு ஐந்தாம் நூற்றாண்டில் வாழ்ந்த கிரேக்க கணிதவியலாளர், புவியியலாளர், கவிஞர், வானியலாளர் மற்றும் இசைக் கோட்பாட்டாளர் ஆவார்.புவியியல் துறையில், இன்றும் பயன்படுத்தப்படும் சொல்லகராதிக்கு அவர் முன்னோடியாக இருந்தார். பூமியின் விட்டத்தை நிர்ணயித்த முதல் நபராக அவர் மிகவும் பிரபலமானவர். நூலகத்தில் தனது வேலையின் ஒரு பகுதியாக அவர் அணுகிய கணிசமான ஆய்வுக் கண்டுபிடிப்புகளைப் பயன்படுத்தி இதை அவர் நிறைவேற்றினார். அவரது கணக்கீடு வியக்கத்தக்க வகையில் துல்லியமாக இருந்தது. அவர் பூமியின் அச்சு சாய்வை முதன்முதலில் தீர்மானித்தார். இது மிகவும் துல்லியமானது என்பதை நிரூபித்தது. அவரது நாளின் அறியப்பட்ட புவியியல் அறிவின் அடிப்படையில், அவர் பூமியின் முதல் உலகளாவிய திட்டத்தை உருவாக்கினார், இதில் இணைகள் மற்றும் நடுக்கோடுகள் அடங்கும்.எரடோஸ்தீனஸ் விஞ்ஞான காலவரிசையைக் கண்டுபிடித்த பெருமைக்குரியவர். அவர் அரை-புராண ட்ரோஜன் போரின் முக்கிய சம்பவங்களின் தேதிகளை மாற்றியமைக்க முயன்றார். எண் கோட்பாட்டில் பகா எண்களைக் கண்டறிவதற்காக எரடோஸ்தீனஸின் சல்லடையை பிரபலப்படுத்தினார்.அவரது விமர்சகர்கள் அவரை இகழ்ந்து, அவருக்கு பீட்டா என்று பெயரிட்டனர். ஏனெனில் அவர் தனது அனைத்து முயற்சிகளிலும் தொடர்ந்து இரண்டாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார் என்று சுடாவில் உள்ள ஒரு பதிவின் படி. எவ்வாறாயினும், அவரது ரசிகர்கள் அவரைப் போட்டியாளர்களாக இருந்த ஒலிம்பியன்களுக்குப் பிறகு பென்டாத்லோஸ் என்று அழைத்தனர். அவர்களுக்கான படிப்பின் ஒவ்வொரு துறையிலும் ஒரு நிபுணராக தன்னை நிலைநிறுத்திக் கொண்டார். எரடோஸ்தீனஸ் உலகின் அனைத்து நுணுக்கங்களையும் புரிந்து கொள்ள விரும்பினார்."},{"question":"如何在\\"喜马拉雅学乖\\"上注册和购买课程？","answer":"用户可以通过下载\\"喜马拉雅学乖\\"的手机应用，或者访问其官方网站进行注册和购买课程。"},{"question":"வினா:  முதன் முதலில் பத்மஸ்ரீ விருதை பெற்றவர் யார் ?","answer":"  விடை:  அன்னை தெரசா1.  அன்னை தெரேசா  அல்பேனியா நாட்டைப் பூர்வீகமாகக் கொண்டவர். 2.  இந்தியக் குடியுரிமை பெற்ற உரோமன் கத்தோலிக்க அருட்சகோதரியும் ஆவார். 3.  இவரின் இயற்பெயர் ஆக்னஸ் கோன்ஜா போஜாஜியூ ஆகும். 4.  1950 ஆம் ஆண்டு, இந்தியாவின் கொல்கத்தாவில் பிறர் அன்பின் பணியாளர் என்ற கத்தோலிக்க     துறவற சபையினை நிறுவினார். 5.  நாற்பத்தைந்து வருடங்களுக்கு மேலாக ஏழைஎளியோர்களுக்கும், நோய்வாய்ப்பட்டோருக்கும்,      அனாதைகளுக்கும், இறக்கும் தருவாயிலிருப்போருக்கும் தொண்டாற்றியவர் இவர். 6.  முதலில் இந்தியா முழுவதும் பின்னர் வெளிநாடுகளுக்கும் பிறர் அன்பின் பணியாளர் சபையினை      நிறுவினார்."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو أول الأنبياء؟","answer":"الإجابة: آدم عليه السلام "},{"question":"Kusvitsa dama kuita sei?","answer":"Kupira nyaya"},{"question":"Merhaba Türkçe kökenli mi?","answer":"Merhaba kelimesi Arapça kökenli bir kelimedir ve dilimize Arapçadan geçmiştir. Türkçede yaygın olarak kullanılan bir kelime türüdür. Anlamı ise selam ya da selamlaşma olarak ifade ediliyor."},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um assistente social?","answer":"Um assistente social ajuda indivíduos e famílias a enfrentar dificuldades sociais, oferecendo suporte e recursos."},{"question":"Nahoana no miova endrika ny Volana isaky ny alina?","answer":"Miova endrika isan-kariva ny Volana noho ny toerana misy azy mihodidina amin'ny Tany sy ny Masoandro, izay miteraka fiovaovan'ny habetsahan'ny tara-masoandro hita taratra eo amin'ny velarany."},{"question":"Hatagi ko ug listahan sa pinaka tsada na exploration-focused na video games.","answer":"Kani ang mga examples sa mga dula na ang main goal kay exploration:- Subnautica- Outer Wilds- Journey- No Man's Sky- Stray- Astroneer- Grow: Song of the Evertree- Firewatch- Call of the Sea- ABZU- What Remains of Edith Finch\\""},{"question":"سیمان از چه موادی ساخته می شود؟","answer":"مواد اصلی مورد استفاده در تولید سیمان عبارتند از:    آهک (Limestone): یک نوع سنگ کربناته که به عنوان منبع اصلی اکسید کلسیم (CaO) در تولید سیمان به کار می‌رود.    خاکستر سیلیسیوم (Silica): معمولاً از معدن خاکستر سیلیسیوم یا شن و شیشه کوارتز به عنوان منبع اصلی اکسید سیلیسیم (SiO2) استفاده می‌شود.    خاکستر آهن (Iron Ore): جهت افزودن اکسید آهن (Fe2O3) به سیمان.    آلومینا (Bauxite): به عنوان منبع اکسید آلومینیوم (Al2O3).    گچ (Gypsum): برای کنترل زمان اتصال سیمان و جلوگیری از افت سریع آن به عنوان یک ماده افزودنی استفاده می‌شود. سیمان‌ها را می‌توان به سیمان‌های هیدرولیک و غیر هیدرولیک تقسیم کرد. سیمانی که پس از سفت شدن حتی زمانی که در زیر آب نگهداری می‌شود، استحکام آن افزایش می‌یابد، هیدرولیک نامیده می‌شود. سیمان غیر هیدرولیک در شرایط مرطوب یا زیر آب سفت نمی‌شود. بلکه در هنگام خشک شدن سفت می‌شود و با دی اکسیدکربن موجود در هوا واکنش می‌دهد. پس از سفت شدن در برابر حمله مواد شیمیایی مقاوم است.فرآیند تولید سیمان شامل دو مرحله اصلی است: خنک کردن و آسیاب کردن مواد خام تا به پودر سیمان تبدیل شوند،  سپس ترکیبات در دماهای بسیار بالا قرارمی گیرند تا سیمان تولید شود."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਜਲਿ ਹੈ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਥਲਿ ਹੈ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਸੂਤਕ ਓਪਤਿ ਹੋਈ ॥ ਜਨਮੇ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਮੂਏ ਫੁਨਿ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਸੂਤਕ ਪਰਜ ਬਿਗੋਈ ॥੧॥ ਕਹੁ ਰੇ ਪੰਡੀਆ ਕਉਨ ਪਵੀਤਾ ॥ ਐਸਾ ਗਿਆਨੁ ਜਪਹੁ ਮੇਰੇ ਮੀਤਾ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ ਨੈਨਹੁ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਬੈਨਹੁ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਸ੍ਰਵਨੀ ਹੋਈ ॥ ਊਠਤ ਬੈਠਤ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਲਾਗੈ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਪਰੈ ਰਸੋਈ ॥੨॥ ਫਾਸਨ ਕੀ ਬਿਧਿ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਊ ਜਾਨੈ ਛੂਟਨ ਕੀ ਇਕੁ ਕੋਈ ॥ ਕਹਿ ਕਬੀਰ ਰਾਮੁ ਰਿਦੈ ਬਿਚਾਰੈ ਸੂਤਕੁ ਤਿਨੈ ਨ ਹੋਈ ॥੩॥੪੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 331 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਭਗਤ ਕਬੀਰ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਜੰਮਣ ਤੇ ਮਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਸੂਤਕ-ਪਾਤਕ ਦੀ ਭਿੱਟ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਤਾਂ) ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ, ਧਰਤੀ ਉਤੇ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ, (ਹਰ ਥਾਂ) ਸੂਤਕ ਦੀ ਉਤਪੱਤੀ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਭਿੱਟਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ, ਕਿਉਂਕਿ)ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਕਿਸੇ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਜੰਮਣ ਤੇ ਸੂਤਕ (ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਫਿਰ ਮਰਨ ਤੇ ਭੀ ਸੂਤਕ (ਆ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ); (ਇਸ) ਭਿੱਟ (ਤੇ ਭਰਮ) ਵਿਚ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਖ਼ੁਆਰ ਹੋ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ।੧। ਹੇ ਪੰਡਿਤ! (ਜਦੋਂ ਹਰ ਥਾਂ ਸੂਤਕ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ) ਸੁੱਚਾ ਕੌਣ (ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ) ਹੈ? (ਤਾਂ ਫਿਰ) ਹੇ ਪਿਆਰੇ ਮਿੱਤਰ! ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਗਹੁ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਤੇ ਦੱਸ, ।੧। ਰਹਾਉ। (ਨਿਰੇ ਇਹਨੀਂ ਅੱਖੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦੇ ਜੀਵ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜੰਮਦੇ ਮਰਦੇ, ਸਾਡੇ ਬੋਲਣ ਚਾਲਣ ਆਦਿਕ ਹਰਕਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਕਈ ਸੂਖਮ ਜੀਵ ਮਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, ਤਾਂ ਫਿਰ) ਅੱਖਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ, ਬੋਲਣ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੀਭ) ਵਿਚ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ, ਕੰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ,  ਉਠਦਿਆਂ ਬੈਠਦਿਆਂ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ (ਸਾਨੂੰ) ਸੂਤਕ ਪੈ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, (ਸਾਡੀ) ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਸੂਤਕ ਹੈ ।੨। (ਜਿੱਧਰ ਵੇਖੋ) ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ (ਸੂਤਕ ਦੇ ਭਰਮਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਫਸਣ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਢੰਗ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ) ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਕਰਾਣ ਦੀ ਸਮਝ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਹੈ। ਕਬੀਰ ਆਖਦਾ ਹੈ—ਜੋ ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਆਪਣੇ) ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ (ਇਹ) ਭਿੱਟ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੱਗਦੀ ।੩।੪੧।\\""},{"question":"उत्पादन क्षेत्रात \\"टोयोटा मॉडेल\\" काय आहे?","answer":"टोयोटा प्रॉडक्शन सिस्टीम (TPS) हे जपानी ऑटोमोटिव्ह उत्पादक टोयोटा यांनी विकसित केलेले उत्पादन तत्वज्ञान आणि कार्यपद्धती आहे. याला कधीकधी \\"लीन मॅन्युफॅक्चरिंग\\" असेही संबोधले जाते. TPS उच्च दर्जाची उत्पादने आणि सेवा प्राप्त करण्यासाठी कचरा कमी करणे, कार्यक्षमता वाढवणे आणि प्रक्रियांमध्ये सतत सुधारणा करण्यावर लक्ष केंद्रित करते.टोयोटा उत्पादन प्रणालीच्या मुख्य तत्त्वांमध्ये खालील गोष्टी समाविष्ट आहे:1. जस्ट-इन-टाइम (JIT): हे तत्त्व केवळ आवश्यकतेनुसार उत्पादने किंवा घटकांचे उत्पादन आणि वितरण करण्यावर भर देते, ज्यामुळे इन्व्हेंटरी कमी होते आणि अतिरिक्त स्टॉकशी संबंधित कचरा कमी होतो.2. जिडोका: या संकल्पनेमध्ये कामगारांनी दोष ओळखल्यास उत्पादन लाइन थांबविण्याचे सक्षमीकरण करून उत्पादन प्रक्रियेत गुणवत्ता निर्माण करणे समाविष्ट आहे. हे दोषपूर्ण उत्पादनांना पुढील रेषेच्या खाली उत्पादित होण्यापासून रोखण्यास मदत करते.3. Kaizen: Kaizen म्हणजे सतत सुधारणा. यामध्ये चालू असलेल्या सुधारणेची संस्कृती वाढवणे समाविष्ट आहे, जिथे प्रत्येक कर्मचाऱ्याला प्रक्रियांमध्ये लहान, वाढीव सुधारणा सुचवण्यासाठी आणि अंमलात आणण्यासाठी प्रोत्साहित केले जाते.4. पोका-योक: हे डिझायनिंग प्रक्रिया किंवा यंत्रणांना संदर्भित करते जे प्रथम स्थानावर चुका होण्यापासून प्रतिबंधित करते. चुकांची शक्यता कमी करणार्‍या मूर्ख प्रणाली तयार करण्याबद्दल आहे.5. Heijunka: Heijunka उत्पादन प्रक्रियेच्या कोणत्याही विशिष्ट भागावर जास्त भार पडू नये म्हणून उत्पादन प्रवाह समतल करण्याविषयी आहे. हे स्थिर आणि संतुलित कार्यप्रवाह राखण्यास मदत करते.6. Andon: Andon प्रणालीमध्ये उत्पादन प्रक्रियेची स्थिती दर्शविणारे व्हिज्युअल सिग्नल किंवा डिस्प्ले समाविष्ट असतात. हे त्वरीत समस्या किंवा व्यत्यय ओळखण्यात मदत करते आणि वेळेवर सुधारात्मक कारवाई करण्यास अनुमती देते.7. कानबान: कानबान ही एक व्हिज्युअल शेड्युलिंग प्रणाली आहे जी उत्पादन प्रक्रियेतील सामग्री आणि माहितीचा प्रवाह नियंत्रित करण्यासाठी कार्ड किंवा सिग्नल वापरते. हे सुनिश्चित करते की उत्पादन मागणी आणि क्षमता यांच्याशी जुळते.ही तत्त्वे एकत्रितपणे एक प्रणाली तयार करतात ज्याचा उद्देश कचरा कमी करणे (वेळ, संसाधने आणि दोष यांच्या दृष्टीने), कार्यक्षमता वाढवणे आणि एकूण गुणवत्ता सुधारणे आहे. टोयोटा प्रॉडक्शन सिस्टीम मोठ्या प्रमाणावर प्रभावशाली आहे आणि असंख्य उद्योग आणि संस्थांनी केवळ उत्पादनाच्या पलीकडे ती स्वीकारली आणि स्वीकारली आहे."},{"question":"ليه اتسمت جزيرة سانت هيلينا بالأسم ده؟","answer":"اتسمت بالاسم دا نسبه للقديسه هيلينا.الجزيره معروفة بانها الجزيرة اللى البريطانيين نفوا نابوليون بونابارت للمرة التانيه فيها بعد ما نفوه قبل كدا و هرب من جزيرة اليبا , واللى مات فيها فى سنة 1858."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي أمره أبو بكر الصديق أن يجمع القرآن الكريم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: زيد بن ثابت"},{"question":"Cad é an GULag? Inis dom faoi. ","answer":"Seasann an giorrúchán Rúisise ГУЛаг nó GULag do Glavnoye upravleniye lagerey, is é sin, Príomhúdarás na gCampaí Géibhinn. Bhí a leithéid sin d'údarás i mbun riarachán na gcampaí géibhinn san Aontas Sóivéadach nuair a bhí Stalin i gceannas ar an tír sin. Is gnách, áfach, \\"Gulag\\" a thabhairt sa ghnáthchaint ar chóras iomlán na gcampaí géibhinn.Sa Bhéarla, tugtar gulag ar aon champa amháin, the gulags ar an gcóras iomlán. Níl an úsáid seo bunaithe ar an Rúisis, áfach. \\"An Crios\\" nó \\"an Limistéar\\" (зона/zona as Rúisis) a thugadh muintir an Aontais Shóivéadaigh ar chóras na gcampaí. De réir mar a tháinig tuiscint ag muintir an stáit Shóivéadaigh ar an mbrúidiúlacht a bhain leis an stát s'acu go hiomlán, thosaigh siad ag tabhairt великая зона/velikaya zona, \\"an Crios Mór\\" nó \\"an Limistéar Mór\\", ar an Aontas Sóivéadach féin, agus an chiall ag dul leis an úsáid seo nach raibh mórán difríochta idir saol na gcampaí géibhinn agus an leagan Sóivéadach den tsaoirse. "},{"question":"mwambi: kunena kwa ndithe-ndithe namnthabwe anadzitengera","answer":"Mwambi wakuletsa kuyankira nkhani za eni ache. Akulu ponena mlandu amakonda kwambiri kuphiphirista nkhani zao, ndipo wina akaulula chinsisi chao amamleka kuti aweruze ndiye. Iwo amangofuna kuti akaphiphiritse pakuona kuchita manyazi akumvawo kapena kuti oweruzidwawo azindikire okha nasiye chimene awatsutsacho.Mwambiwu uli ndi nthano yache ndiyo: Kale-kale namnthabwe, timba ndi mbalame zina zinali zakupha nyama ndi maukonde ao. Namnthambwe, timba ndi mbalame zina zinali zodikira maukonde. Mwa mbalame zonse woponya uta kwambiri anali timba; anaponya mubvi wache wosagwera m'dothi. Masiku onse namthbwe analikukhalira ukonde umodzi ndi timba. Iwo onse atapit ku uzimba, mbalame zina zinaka kukasaka ndipo inabvumbuluka nyama nikodwamu ukonde wa namnthabwe ndi timba. Timba anaponya mubvi nairasa nati mau apansi, \\"Atate!\\" Pakumva mamnthabwe anapfuula ndi mau okweza (adziti walasa ndiye) \\"Namnthabwe! Namnthabwe!  Namnthabwe!\\" Pakumva mbalame zina zinakhulupirira kuti ndiye walasa, pofika kufunsa zapeza nyama iri gone! Timba kulephera kunenetsa kuti ndalasa ndine, koma mbalamezo zinati,\\"Ife dzina la Namnthabwe si Timba ai.\\"Machitidwe oterewa amachitidwa pa uzimba uli onse, koma timba sanamva bwino m'mitma mwache nayese-yese njira yakumuletsera Namnthabwe mkhalidwe woterewo.Tisku lina napanga malango kuti Namnthabwe atenge mlandu. Mbalame zonse zitapanga kunka kuuzimba Namnthabwe ndi Timba anakhalaira ukonde umodzi monga mwa masiku onse. Tsiku limenelo nyama itabvumbuluka Timba m'malo molasa nyama, analasa mmodzi wa odikira nati chimodzi-modzi mau apansi monga mwamasiku onse,\\"Atate!\\" Namnthabwe pakumva anachita mwa masiku onse napfuula, \\"Namnthabwe! Namnthabwe! Namnthabwe!\\" Zitabwera mbalame zonse zinati,\\"Kodi nyama imene unkanenererayo ndi imeneyi?\\" Iye analephera kukana nayesa kutulira malanduwo pa Timba koma izo zinachitira umboni ndi kuti,\\"Walasa mnzathu ndiwe chifukwa tamva mau ako.\\" Pompo zinangogwira ndi kumupha.Mwambi umenewu ukumbutsa kuti anthu ambiri amalowa m'zobvuta chifukwa chakuulula-ulula zinsisi zaeni, natengedwa pa mlandu, mwina kulangidwa opanda kuchimwa koma chifukwa cha mau okha, monga Namnthabwe uja."},{"question":"Суроо: Россиянын борбору кайсы?","answer":"Жооп: Москва. Кыргызча Маскөө деп аталып келген"},{"question":"问题：地球上最大的陆地动物是什么","answer":"答案：非洲象"},{"question":"Ọbasanjọ gba Buhari nimọran: Ọwọ lile kọ o, lọọ pepade alaafia pẹlu awọn ti wọn fẹẹ ya kuro ni Naijiria  ","answer":"Aarẹ ilẹ wa tẹlẹ ri, Oloye Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ, ti ṣekilọ pe afaimọ ki ọrọ awọn eeyan ti wọn n pariwo pe awọn maa ya kuro lorileede Naijiria lọọ da orileede ẹya tiwọn silẹ, afaimọ kọrọ naa ma mu ijọba lomi gidi, o si le kọja ohun ti apa ijọba apapọ yoo ka, pẹlu bi wọn ṣe gun le fifọwọ lile mu ọrọ ọhun.Ọbasanjọ ni oun ko lodi si ki Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari ṣepade alaafia pẹlu awọn ajijagbara to n fọnrere iyapa yii, o ni ọna toun mọ to daa ju lọ lati bojuto awuyewuye ọhun niyẹn.Lasiko to n dahun ibeere tawọn oniroyin ilu eebo kan, tileeṣẹ Newsweek bi i l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii, lori ipo torileede Naijiria wa, l’Ọbasanjọ sọrọ naa.Ọbasanjọ ni “Mi o rohun to buru ninu ki Buhari ṣepade pẹlu Nnamdi Kanu, tabi awọn eeyan mi-in ti wọn n sọrọ yiya kuro lara Naijiria, mi o le ta ko iru igbesẹ bẹẹ, kaka bẹẹ, mo maa fun wọn niṣiiri lati ṣe bẹẹ ni.“To ba jẹ emi ni Aarẹ ni, niṣe ni ma a pe Kanu, ma a tun pe awọn mi-in ti ọrọ wọn jọra pẹlu tiẹ, awọn ẹlẹgbẹ ẹ, ma a si bi wọn leere pe: ‘Ki niṣoro yin gan-an, ki lẹ fẹ’? Ki i ṣe Kanu lati ilẹ Ibo nikan o, mo maa pe awọn ajijagbara to wa lawọn agbegbe mi-in pẹlu.”Baba naa tun sọ pe bawọn ologun ṣe fẹẹ fọwọ lile mu ọrọ yii lewu, ko le mu ojutuu wa, bẹẹ si lọrọ awọn to fẹẹ ya kuro naa ko le mu ojutuu wa. O ni ọwọ pẹlẹkutu lo yẹ kijọba fi mu ọrọ ọhun, tori iṣoro to le mu Naijiria lomi ni.“A gbọdọ pese iṣẹ to to fawọn ọdọ wa, iṣẹ gidi, ka si fẹsẹ wọn le ọna ati la, ka pese ọjọ ọla to nitumọ fun wọn, ki ireti wọn fun ọjọ ọla rere le duro. Ko sọna abayọ mi-in.”"},{"question":"ローリングスの小説『子鹿物語』に登場する、主人公の子鹿の名前は何でしょう？","answer":"フラッグです。"},{"question":"வினா:ஒரு நூற்றாண்டை எத்தனை மாதங்கள் உருவாக்குகின்றன?அ) 12ஆ) 120\\tஇ) 1200 \\tஈ) 12000","answer":"விடை:: இ) 1200 மாதங்கள். ஒரு நூற்றாண்டிற்கு மொத்தம் 100 ஆண்டுகளும், ஒவ்வொரு வருடமும் மொத்தம் 12 மாதங்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பதால், ஒரு நூற்றாண்டு 1200 மாதங்களைக் கொண்டிருக்கும் (100 × 12 = 1200 மாதங்கள்)."},{"question":"گیاهان من شاخ و برگ زیادی دارند اما تعداد گل‌های آن‌ها بسیار کم هستند. چه مشکلی وجود دارد؟","answer":"معمولاً این اتفاق به علت کوددهی نا منظم و استفاده از کود نا درست پیش می اید. کودی که استفاده می‌کنید نیتروژن زیادی دارد و بالعکس پتاسیم کمتری دارد. سعی کنید کودهایی تهیه کنید که برای گیاهان شما مناسب باشد. زیاده روی در کود دهی نیز باعث کم شدن تعداد گل‌ها می‌شود. کودهای مناسب را در فصل رشد گیاهان استفاده کنید."},{"question":"¿Qué es la astronomía?","answer":"La astronomía es la ciencia que se dedica al estudio de los astros, como las estrellas, planetas, galaxias, cometas y otros objetos celestes, así como los fenómenos que ocurren en el espacio exterior."},{"question":"Суроо: Ислам дини деген эмне?","answer":"Жооп: Ислам дини-бүгүнкү күнү жер бетинде тек акыйкат дини. Кудайдын жиберген акыркы дини.Акыркы Азирети Мухаммед Пайгамбар анын пайгамбары, акыркы Ыйык Куран анын ыйык китеби болуп эсептелет. Бүгүнкү күнү Кудай жиберген диндерден үчү гана жашап келет. Алар Иудаизм, Христиан жана Ислам диндери. Бул диндердин экөөсү тактап айтканда Иудаизм жана Христиан диндери бүгүнкү күнгө чейин адамдар тарабынан бурмаланып, нагызын сактай алган эмес. Булардан Ислам дини гана өзүнүн нагызын, аруулугун сактап келген."},{"question":" Naarta yaa ugu hor gelaya Qiyaamaha","answer":" Waxaa ugu hor gelaaya Suldaan, Madaxweyne ama hogaamiye aan cadaalad sameyn"},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Aza miady vitana ............................... \\" ","answer":"\\"  Aza miady vitana amin'ny akoho. \\" "},{"question":"Papasakok apie Lietuvos miestą Kauną. Pasakojimas turi būti platus su istoriniai faktais","answer":"Kaunas – antrasis pagal dydį Lietuvos miestas šalies centrinėje dalyje, Nemuno ir Neries santakoje. Svarbus pramonės, transporto, mokslo ir kultūros centras, Laikinoji sostinė. Kauno miesto savivaldybė, Kauno rajono savivaldybės centras, katalikų arkivyskupijos centras.Kaunas buvo vienas dažniausiai minimų miestų vokiečių ordinų kronikose (Kauen, Cawen, Kauwenpille ir kt.), dažnai minimas ir Rusijos kronikose.Šiuo metu vyrauja kalbininkų nuomonė, kad Kaunas yra asmenvardinis vietovardis, kilęs iš asmenvardžio Kaunas; tokia pavardė ir dabar pasitaiko keturkampyje Jurbarkas–Jonava–Alytus–Vilkaviškis, į kurį patenka ir Kaunas. Šią versiją dar 1925 m. pateikė šveicarų kalbininkas Alfredas Senas (1899–1978), jai pritarė Pranas Skardžius ir Petras Jonikas.[3] Kas buvo tas Kaunas – nežinoma, svarstoma, kad veikiausiai tai galėjęs būti pilies valdovas. Tokią prielaidą leidžia daryti ir dabartinis pilies pavadinimas: net kauniečiai ją dažniau vadina Kauno pilimi, o ne tiesiog pilimi, nors kitos pilies Kaune ir nėra. Pats asmenvardis Kaunas kildinamas iš būdvardžio kaunus – „kuris mėgsta muštis, kautis“. Jei taip, tai hipotetinis pilies valdovas Kaunas turėjęs būti arba „karštakošis“, arba „geras kovų meistras, gerai įvaldęs tuometinius ginklus“.Kiek vėliau už A. Seną vokiečių kalbininkas G. Študerus iškėlė hipotezę, kad Kauno pirminė reikšmė galėjusi būti „gilus, žemas, slėnyje esąs“. Jo nuomone, šaknis kaun- kilusi iš indoeuropiečių šaknies *kau-, *keu- „lenkti(s), linkti“; iš čia išsirutuliojo ir reikšmė „žemas“ bei su ja susijusios kitos reikšmės, plg. gotų hauns „žemas“, vokiečių Hohn „pajuoka“, latvių kauns „gėda“. Vadinasi, šiuo atveju Kaunas kildinamas iš spėjamai buvusio, bet išnykusio būdvardžio kaunas ar kaunus „žemas“.[4] Atvejų, kai vietovardis užkonservuoja anksčiau turėtus, bet jau nebevartojamus žodžius ar jų dalis, yra ne vienas, plg. Simnas (iš spėjamai išnykusio tokio paties ežeravardžio ar asmenvardžio), Stabingis (iš jotvingių ir prūsų kalbų žodžio stabis „akmuo“), Kirsna (iš jotvingių ir prūsų kalbų žodžio kirsnan „juodas“), Palanga, Kretinga (su kuršiškomis priesagomis -ang-, -ing-) ir kt.Liaudies etimologija Kauno pavadinimą sieja su veiksmažodžio kautis esamojo laiko trečiojo asmens forma „kaunas(i)“. Kad kautynės gali duoti vardą jų vietai, rodo Pabaisko (į pietus nuo Ukmergės) pavyzdys, kur 1435 m. vyko Švitrigailos ir jo sąjungininkų mūšis su jo priešininko Žygimanto pajėgomis. Bėda tik ta, jog intensyvūs mūšiai su kryžiuočiais ties Kaunu prasidėjo nuo XIV a. vidurio, o pats vardas yra senesnis.Kauno vardas turi ir legendinius kilmės aiškinimus. Legendoje apie Palemoną (Bychovco kronika, XVI a.) Kauno vardas kildinamas iš Palemono viduriniojo sūnaus Kuno vardo: esą šis atsikėlęs prie Nevėžio žiočių ir įkūręs miestą, kurį pavadinęs savo vardu.[5] Kita legenda pasakoja, kad Kaunu buvo pavadintas deivės Aleksotos ir medžioklio Dangeručio sūnus.[6] Istorikas Teodoras Narbutas XIX a. yra užrašęs legendą, jog lietuviai garbinę dievaitį Kaunį, primenantį graikų Apoloną. Didžiulė Kaunio statula esą stovėjusi Nemuno pakrantėje ties dabartiniu Kauno senamiesčiu; Kaunį savo globėju laikę sielininkai, todėl audros metu šiam dievaičiui degindavę auką – augalų ūglių, šaknų, porą avinų.Miestas yra beveik pačiame Lietuvos centre, Lietuvos Vidurio žemumoje, išsidėstęs didžiausių šalies upių Nemuno ir Neries santakoje. Prieš miestą, užtvenkus Nemuną, suformuotos Kauno marios. Kitoje miesto pusėje telkšo Lampėdžio ežeras.ĄžuolynasNapoleono kalnas žvelgiant iš kito Nemuno krantoKaunas iškilęs apie 70–80 m virš jūros lygio. Aukščiausias miesto taškas yra IX forte (100,1 m), žemiausias – Nemuno vagoje ties Lampėdžiais. Miesto centrinė dalis yra tarp Nemuno ir Neries upių, žemumoje, 30–35 m aukštyje virš jūros lygio, apsupta trijų – Žaliakalnio, Aleksoto ir Šilainių kalvų. Miesto centrą supančiuose šlaituose pastatyta dešimtys laiptų, kurie būtini dėl vietos reljefo ypatybių.[7] Vieni žinomiausių – Stasio Kudoko projektuoti Kauko laiptai.Miesto klimatas žemyninis, šalčiausias – sausio, šilčiausias – liepos mėnuo. Per metus iškrenta apie 630 milimetrų kritulių. Vyrauja pietvakarių krypties vėjai. Mieste yra daug saugomų teritorijų, draustinių, kuriuose aptinkami į Lietuvos raudonąją knygą įrašyti gyvūnai. Gražiausi mieste parkai – Ąžuolynas, Pažaislio ir Panemunės šilai.Pagrindiniai Kaune aplinkos teršėjai yra transportas, pramonės ir energetikos įmonės. Geriamajam vandeniui paruošti naudojamas gruntinis ir paviršinis vanduo, išgaunamas keturiose miesto vandenvietėse.2008 m. rugsėjo 16 d. Marvelėje paleisti nauji biologinio nuotekų valymo įrenginiai.Gyvenvietė Neries ir Nemuno santakoje buvo įkurta vėliausiai X a. Manoma, kad Kaunas minimas 1030 m. arabų aprašymuose. 1140 m. arabų geografas al Idrisijus šiose vietose mini Qaynu arba Qanys gyvenvietę, kuri galėjo būti dabartinio Kauno vietoje. Santakos gyvenvietės teritorijoje XIV a. viduryje buvo pastatyta mūrinė Kauno pilis. Kryžiuočių heroldo Vygando Marburgiečio kronikoje Kauno gyvenvietė pirmą kartą paminėta 1361 m. kaip Kawen. 1362 m. Vokiečių ordinas Kauno pilį užėmė ir sugriovė. XV a. pradžioje pilis atstatyta.1408 m. Vytautas Didysis miestui suteikė Magdeburgo teises. Miestas buvo prekybos kelių sankirtoje ir turėjo Kauno upių uostą, dėl to sparčiai plėtojosi prekyba ir amatai. 1413 m. Kaunas tapo Trakų vaivadijos Kauno pavieto centru. XV a. pradžioje tai buvo vokiečių pirklių miestas, 1441 m. jame įkurta Hanzos kontora. 1539 m. jis pavaizduotas Olaus Magnuso sudarytame žemėlapyje „Carta Marina“.Dėl XVII a. viduryje prasidėjusių karų ir epidemijų, Kauno plėtra labai sulėtėjo. 1665 m. miestą kelis kartus puolė Rusijos kariuomenė, 1701 m. užėmė švedai. 1657 ir 1708 m. mieste siautė maras, 1731 ir 1732 m. dalį miesto sunaikino gaisras.1795 m. po Abiejų Tautų Respublikos padalinimų miestas prijungtas prie Rusijos Vilniaus gubernijos. Napoleono karų metu 1812 m. Napoleono kariuomenė dukart praėjo pro miestą, abukart jį nusiaubdama. Miesto ekonomika atsigavo XIX a., 1843 m. tapus Kauno gubernijos centru, 1862 m. nutiesus geležinkelį ir 1898 m. pradėjus veikti pirmajai elektrinei. Miesto kultūrinis gyvenimas pagyvėjo po 1863 m. sukilimo numalšinimo 1864 m. iš Varnių atkėlus Žemaičių vyskupijos centrą ir kunigų seminariją. 1876 m. gatvės apšviestos žibalinėmis lempomis, 1899 m. – elektra. 1892 m. įkurtas teatras, 1898 m. – miesto muziejus. XIX a. pabaigoje Kaunas – miestas, gubernijos ir apskrities centras.[8]1919 m. Kaune pradėjo veikti pirmoji radijo stotis Lietuvoje. Tarpukario metais Kaunas stipriai išsiplėtė ir tapo svarbiausiu Lietuvos mokslo, pramonės, kultūros ir švietimo centru, 1920–1939 m. buvo laikinoji Lietuvos sostinė. Po to, kai 1940 m. birželio 15 d. Sovietų Sąjunga okupavo Lietuvą Kaune kūrėsi pogrindinės organizacijos. 1941 m. birželio 22 d. Kaune prasidėjo LAF organizuotas sukilimas prieš okupacinį režimą. Buvo sudaryta Laikinoji vyriausybė, kuri birželio 23 d. paskelbė atstatanti laisvą ir nepriklausomą Lietuvą. Birželio 25 d. į Kauną įžengę vermachto daliniai rado jį išlaisvintą nuo okupantų, tačiau Laikinąją vyriausybę toleravo tik pusantro mėnesio. Po Antrojo pasaulinio karo okupacinė valdžia naikino viską, kas priminė nepriklausomos Lietuvos gyvenimą, Kaunas buvo paverstas uždaru pramonės miestu. Tik prasidėjus Atgimimui mieste buvo atkurtas Vytauto Didžiojo universitetas, pradėti atstatyti paminklai, grąžinti istoriniai viešųjų erdvių, įstaigų, gatvių pavadinimai.1991 m. sausio įvykių metu sovietų kariuomenei pasikėsinus į Lietuvos valstybingumą, Kaune, taip pat prie Sitkūnų radijo ir televizijos siųstuvų, budėjo žmonės, pasiryžę paaukoti už ją savo gyvybes. Okupavus Lietuvos televizijos pastatus Vilniuje, iš Kauno buvo transliuojama vienintelė lietuviška televizijos programa. Atkūrus Lietuvos valstybingumą, 1993 m. patvirtintas naujasis Kauno herbas. Miesto ekonomika palaipsniui persitvarko į paslaugas orientuotas sritis, tokias kaip logistika, transportas, turizmas, informacinių technologijų plėtra.Šaltinis: https://lt.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaunas"},{"question":"Кыргызстандык кайсы программисттерден кимди тааныйсың?","answer":"Алия РысбекGoogle Deepmind’де программист болуп иштейт. Google’да иштөөнүн бала кезинен бери кыялданып келген. Ал жумуш издеп жүргөн учурда ар түрдүү компанияларга 100дөн ашык билдирүү калтырып, анын 70инен ашыгы жумушка ала албайбыз деп жооп берген. Ошентсе да моюн сунуп отуруп калбастан, ал өзү самаган ишке орношуу оюнан кайткан эмес.Мындай өжөрлүктүн аркасы менен Google Deepmind, Facebook, Cisco жана Bloomberg компанияларынан сунуш алган. Бирок алардын ичинен Google Deepmind’ды тандап алган."},{"question":"Algorithm-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"நெறிமுறை"},{"question":"Inona no fanambarana tsy marina momba'ny faritra arovana eto Madagasikara amin'ireto?a) I Madagasikara dia fonenan'ny faritra arovana maromaro mba hitahiry ny zavamananaina miavaka ao aminy.b) Valan-javaboary an-dranomasina ny Valan-javaboarin’Isalo.d) Ny valan-javaboahary Ranomafana dia malaza amin'ny kazanana \\"lemurien\\".","answer":"Valiny diso : b) Valan-javaboahary an-dranomasina ny valan-javaboahary Isalo. (Valan-javaboarin’Isalo dia valan-javaboary an-tenety.)"},{"question":"Kindly take the following complicated statement and make it simpler:One of 50 businesses located at the University of Virginia, TearSolutions Inc. was cofounded by Mark B. Logan and Gordon W. Laurie, a cell biologist at the university.","answer":"Gordon W. Laurie, a cell biologist at the University of Virginia, and Mark B. Logan cofounded TearSolutions Inc."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"badan boleh dimiliki, tetapi hatinya tidak\\"?","answer":"Walaupun menjadi atau bersifat seperti hamba atau orang lemah terhadap orang yang berkuasa, namun hatinya tidak begitu"},{"question":"క్రింది సామాన్య వాక్యాన్ని సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యంగా మార్చండి:బొండుమల్లెలు వేసింది తానే, పెంచింది తానే, డబ్బు చేసిందీ తానే.","answer":"బొండుమల్లెలు వేసి, పెంచి, డబ్బు చేసింది తానే."},{"question":"Completa la frase seguente: L'anno successivo prese invece parte ai primi Europei, quelli di","answer":"Torino 1934, terminando 10º nei 1500 m, dopo aver passato la sua batteria da 4º in 4'01\\"8."},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 3 ਮਾਰਚਵਿੱਤ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਅਰੁਣ ਜੇਤਲੀ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇ ਮਾੜੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਚਲਾਈ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਾਂਰਗਸ ਮਾੜੀ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰ ਦੀ ਭੂਮਿਕਾ ਨਿਭਾਅ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਨਾਲ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਭਾਵਨਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਠੇਸ ਪਹੁੰਚੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਬੇਇੱਜ਼ਤੀ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠ 21 ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਪਾਰਟੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਮਤਾ ਪਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਤੇ ਬਾਲਾਕੋਟ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਿਆਸੀਕਰਨ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਸ੍ਰੀ ਜੇਤਲੀ ਨੇ ਸੋਸ਼ਲ ਮੀਡੀਆ ’ਤੇ ਲਿਖਿਆ, ‘ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਗਏ ਬਿਆਨਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਦੇਸ਼ ਕੌਮੀ ਹਿੱਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਨੁਕਸਾਨ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਧਿਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਜ਼ਾਹਿਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਮੌਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਲੜਾਈ ਦੀ ਅਹਿਮੀਅਤ ਘਟਾ ਸਕੇ।’ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਾਬਕਾ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਨਮੋਹਨ ਸਿੰਘ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਨਮੋਸ਼ੀ ਹੋਈ ਹੈ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ ’ਚ ਅਤਿਵਾਦ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਸਿਆ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ।ਕਿੰਨੀਆਂ ਪਾਰਟੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ 'ਤੇ ਸਿਆਸਤ ਕਰਨ ਦਾ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਾਉਂਦਿਆਂ ਮਤਾ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਹੇਠ 21 ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਪਾਰਟੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਮਤਾ ਪਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਗਾਇਆ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਤੇ ਬਾਲਾਕੋਟ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਿਆਸੀਕਰਨ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"මිනිස් දිවේ පිටුපසම කොටසට දැනෙන රසය","answer":"තිත්ත රස"},{"question":"Inona izany holatafa?","answer":"Ny holatafa dia karazana holatra mafy, saiky toy ny hazo"},{"question":"உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதியின் ஓய்வு வயது என்ன?","answer":"உச்ச நீதிமன்ற நீதிபதி ஒருவர் 65 வயது வரை பணிபுரியலாம். தவறான நடத்தை அல்லது இயலாமை ஆகியவற்றின் அடிப்படையில் மட்டுமே குடியரசுத் தலைவரால் பதவி நீக்கம் செய்யப்படுவார்."},{"question":"नेपालको सिमाना जोडिएको दुई देश कुन कुन हुन ?","answer":"चीन र भारत"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన సమాచారం ఏ ముఖ్యమైన సంఘటన గురించి చెప్తుంది:  భారతీయ 2000-రూపాయల నోటు (₹ 2000) భారత ద్రవ్యమానంలోనికి కొత్తగా చేర్చబడింది. 8 నవంబర్ 2016 న 500, 1000 రూపాయల నోట్ల రద్దు తర్వాత దీనిని రిజర్వ్ బ్యాంక్ ఆఫ్ ఇండియా (ఆర్బిఐ) విడుదల చేసింది, 10 నవంబర్ 2016 నుండి ఇది చెలామణిలో ఉంది. ఇది పూర్తిగా కొత్త రూపకల్పనతో మహాత్మా గాంధీ కొత్త క్రమం లోని ఒక బ్యాంకు నోటు.","answer":"500, 1000 రూపాయల నోట్ల రద్దు,కొత్త 2000 రూపాయిల నోటు"},{"question":"Wat is een Palaemonella dijonesae?","answer":"Palaemonella dijonesae is een garnalensoort uit de familie van de Palaemonidae. De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 2010 door Bruce. "},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：巴洛克艺术运动兴起于哪个世纪？","answer":"答案：巴洛克艺术运动兴起于17世纪。"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക.ഖണ്ഡിക: പെയിന്റിംഗ്, ശിൽപം, വാസ്തുവിദ്യ എന്നിവയിലെ അസാധാരണമായ കഴിവുകൾക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട ഒരു ഇറ്റാലിയൻ നവോത്ഥാന കലാകാരനായിരുന്നു മൈക്കലാഞ്ചലോ. സിസ്റ്റൈൻ ചാപ്പലിന്റെ സീലിംഗ്, ഡേവിഡിന്റെ പ്രതിമ, വത്തിക്കാൻ സിറ്റിയിലെ സെന്റ് പീറ്റേഴ്‌സ് ബസിലിക്കയുടെ ഡിസൈൻ തുടങ്ങിയ മാസ്റ്റർപീസുകൾ സൃഷ്ടിച്ചതിലാണ് അദ്ദേഹം ഏറ്റവും പ്രശസ്തനായത്. വിശദാംശങ്ങളിലേക്കുള്ള അവിശ്വസനീയമായ ശ്രദ്ധ, മനുഷ്യന്റെ ശരീരഘടനയുടെ യഥാർത്ഥ ചിത്രീകരണം, വൈകാരിക ആഴം എന്നിവയാണ് മൈക്കലാഞ്ചലോയുടെ കൃതികളുടെ സവിശേഷത. അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ കലാപരമായ സംഭാവനകൾ കലാരംഗത്ത് അഗാധവും ശാശ്വതവുമായ സ്വാധീനം ചെലുത്തിയിട്ടുണ്ട്, അദ്ദേഹത്തെ ചരിത്രത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും പ്രശസ്തരായ കലാകാരന്മാരിൽ ഒരാളാക്കി.ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: പെയിന്റിംഗ്, ശിൽപം, വാസ്തുവിദ്യ എന്നിവയിലെ അസാധാരണമായ കഴിവുകൾക്ക് പേരുകേട്ട പ്രശസ്തനായ ഇറ്റാലിയൻ നവോത്ഥാന കലാകാരനായ മൈക്കലാഞ്ചലോയുടെ ജീവിതവും കലാപരമായ നേട്ടങ്ങളും ഈ ഭാഗം എടുത്തുകാണിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"ලෝක කම්කරු දිනය කවදාද?","answer":"මැයි 01"},{"question":"Waarom worden aardappelchips na opening van de zak muf?","answer":"Zakken met aardappelchips zijn gevuld met stikstof Veel consumenten denken dat de chipbedrijven uit zijn op je geld door driekwart van de zak te vullen met lucht, maar het is eigenlijk stikstof om je chips vers te houden. Daarom moet je, zodra je de zak opent, de chips zo snel mogelijk opeten. Nu heb je een reden om de hele zak chips in één keer op te eten zonder je schuldig te voelen."},{"question":"Find the result of 7 raised to the power of 3 (7³).","answer":"7³ is equal to 7 * 7 * 7, which equals 343."},{"question":"Ninkii Ugu Horeeyey Oo Islaam Ah Oo Yeesho Ciidan Ilaaliyo?","answer":"Mucaawiye Binu Abii Sufyaan RC."},{"question":"Узак отуруунун ден соолукка кандай коркунучу бар?","answer":"Узакка созулган отуруу ден-соолукка ар кандай коркунучтарга дуушар кылат. Анын ичинде семирүү жана жүрөк-кан тамыр оорулары көп кездешет. Тыныгуу жана үзгүлтүксүз кыймылды киргизүү жалпы ден соолук үчүн абдан маанилүү."},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد التكبيرات في صلاة الجنازة؟","answer":" الجواب: أربع تكبيراتٍ مع تكبيرة الإحرام."},{"question":"வினா:மரம் வளர்ப்பதனால் நாம் பெறும் பயன்கள் குறித்துக் கலந்துரையாடுக.","answer":"விடை :மரம் வளர்ப்பதனால் நாம் பெறும் பயன்கள் குறித்த கலந்துரையாடல்அமலன் : மரம் வளர்ப்பதனால் நமக்கு என்னனென்ன பயன்கள் உள்ளன?ராதா : மரம் வளர்ப்பதனால் நமக்கு நிறைய பயன்கள் உள்ளன.அமலன் : அப்படியா! எங்கே? சொல்லு பார்ப்போம்.ராதா : மரங்கள் கரியமில வாயுவை உள்வாங்கிக் கொண்டு நமக்குத் தேவையான உயிர் காற்றைக் கொடுக்கிறது.அமலன் : மரங்களினால் வேறு என்ன பயன் உள்ளது?ராதா : மரங்கள் நமக்குக் கனிகள், காய்கள், இலைகள், தண்டுகள், வேர்கள், பூக்கள்என்று பலவற்றைத் தருகின்றன.அமலன் : மரங்கள் மண் அரிப்பை எவ்வாறு தடுக்கிறது?ராதா : மழைக்காலங்களில் அதிக நீர் பெருக்கெடுத்து ஓடும் போது நீருடன் மண்ணும்  சேர்ந்து அரித்துக்கொண்டு ஓடும் அந்த சமயங்களில் மரங்களின் வேர்கள்  மண்ணரிப்பைத் தடுத்து நிறுத்துகிறது.அமலன் : நன்றாகச் சொல்கிறாய். இன்னும் கூடுதலாக சொல்லேன்.ராதா : மரங்கள் நமக்கு வாசனை பொருட்கள், மூலிகைப் பொருட்கள், தளவாடப் பொருட்கள், எரிபொருட்கள் என பலவகையான பொருட்களை தருகின்றன. அதுமட்டுமல்லாமல் மரம் வளர்ப்பதால் தான் மழை வரும். மரங்கள் நீராவி சுழற்சிக்கு அதிக பயனை நல்குவதால், மரம் வளர்த்தால் மழை கிடைப்பது உறுதியே. மரம் மனிதர்கள் மட்டுமல்லாமல் பறவைகள், விலங்குகள், ஊர்வன, சிறு உயிரினங்கள் என்று எல்லாவற்றிற்கும் பயன் கிடைக்கின்றன."},{"question":"Expliquez la théorie de la relativité générale d'Albert Einstein et son impact sur la compréhension de la gravité.","answer":"La relativité générale d'Albert Einstein, formulée en 1915, redéfinit la gravité en décrivant comment la masse courbe l'espace-temps. Selon cette théorie, la gravité n'est pas une force à distance, mais plutôt la manifestation de la courbure de l'espace-temps provoquée par la présence de masse. Elle a été confirmée par des observations telles que la déviation de la lumière près d'objets massifs. La relativité générale a également prédit des phénomènes tels que la dilatation du temps en présence de champs gravitationnels intenses, des aspects cruciaux pour comprendre l'univers à une échelle cosmique."},{"question":"హక్కులను నిర్వచించి పౌర, రాజకీయ హక్కులను వర్ణించండి.","answer":"పరిచయం: రాజనీతిశాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో హక్కుల భావనకు చాలా ప్రాముఖ్యత ఉంది. సామాజిక జీవనానికి హక్కులనేవి అత్యంత ఆవశ్యకమైనవి. సామాజిక సంక్షేమ సాధనగా హక్కులు పరిగణించబడినాయి. హక్కులను వినియోగించుకోవటం ద్వారానే రాజ్యంలోని పౌర వ్యక్తిత్వం వికసిస్తుంది. సమాజంలోనూ, రాజ్యంలోనూ సంపూర్ణ వ్యక్తిత్వ వికాసానికి హక్కులు అవసరమవుతాయి. రాజ్యం పౌరులకు ప్రసాదించే హక్కుల ద్వారానే దాని ఔన్నత్యం గుర్తించబడుతుందని హెచ్.జె. లాస్కి పేర్కొన్నాడు. సాధారణంగా ప్రతి రాజ్యం తన పౌరులకు వివిధ రంగాలలో అనేక హక్కులను ప్రసాదిస్తుంది.హక్కులనేవి రాజ్యం, సమాజంచేత గుర్తించబడే కనీస పరిస్థితులు, అవకాశాలుగా పరిగణించవచ్చు. వాటిని రాజ్యంలోని వివిధ చట్టాలు పరిరక్షిస్తాయి. ఆధునిక రాజ్యాలు తమ రాజ్యాంగం, చట్టాల ద్వారా పౌరుల వికాసానికి అనేక ఏర్పాట్లుగావించాయి. ఇక హక్కులు, బాధ్యతలు అనేవి వ్యక్తుల సంపూర్ణ వికాసానికి అత్యంత ఆవశ్యకమైనవి.అర్థం: “హక్కు” అంటే “కలిగి ఉండటము” అని అర్థం. సమాజ సంక్షేమం కోసం, ప్రగతి కోసం వ్యక్తులందరూ పాటించవలసిన బాధ్యతల రూపమే హక్కులు. హక్కులు మానవునకు స్వేచ్ఛను ఇచ్చి, వికాసానికి తోడ్పడతాయి. హక్కుల నిర్వచనాలు: రాజనీతి శాస్త్రవేత్తలు హక్కు అనే పదాన్ని అనేక విధాలుగా నిర్వచించారు. వాటిలో కొన్నింటిని కింద వివరించడమైనది.ఎర్నెస్ట్ బార్కర్: “వ్యక్తి మూర్తిమత్వ సామర్థ్యాన్ని పెంపొందించేందుకు అవసరమైన బాహ్యపరమైన పరిస్థితులే హక్కులు”.బొసాంకే: “సమాజం చేత గుర్తించబడి, రాజ్యంచేత అమలులో ఉంచబడే అధికారాలే హక్కులు”.టి.హెచ్. గ్రీన్: “ఉమ్మడి శ్రేయస్సుకు దోహదపడే వాటిని కోరేందుకు, గుర్తించేందుకు ఉండే అధికారాలే హక్కులు.”హెచ్.జె. లాస్కి: “హక్కులనేవి మానవుల సామాజిక జీవనానికి అవసరమైనవి. అవి లేకుండా ఏ ఒక్కరూ సాధారణంగా అత్యుత్తమమైన వ్యక్తిగా రూపొందటం సాధ్యం కాదు.”పౌరహక్కులు: నాగరిక జీవనాన్ని గడపటానికి అవసరమయ్యే హక్కులనే పౌరహక్కులు అంటారు. అన్ని రాజ్యాలు తమ ప్రజలకు ఈ హక్కులను ఇస్తున్నాయి. ఈ హక్కులపై అనేక మినహాయింపులు ఉంటాయి. ముఖ్యమైన పౌర హక్కులు ఏమనగా:1. జీవించే హక్కు: జీవించే హక్కు అనేది పౌరహక్కులలో అత్యంత ముఖ్యమైనదని టి.హెచ్. గ్రీన్ భావించాడు. ఈ హక్కు వ్యక్తుల జీవనానికి భద్రతను కల్పిస్తుంది. ఈ హక్కు లేనట్లయితే వ్యక్తులు తమ జీవనాన్ని గడిపేందుకు అనేక ఇబ్బందులను ఎదుర్కొంటారు. ప్రతి వ్యక్తికీ ఈ హక్కు ఎంతో విలువైనదే కాకుండా, సమాజం, రాజ్యం మొత్తానికి కూడా ఎంత విలువైనదనే ప్రమేయంపై ఈ హక్కు ఆధారపడి ఉంది. అందువల్ల ఈ హక్కు ద్వారా రాజ్యం వ్యక్తుల జీవనానికి ఎంతగానో రక్షణను కల్పిస్తుంది. అయితే ఈ హక్కును అనుభవించే విషయంలో వ్యక్తులపై రాజ్యం కొన్ని సహేతుకమైన ఆంక్షలను విధించవచ్చు. ఈ సందర్భంలో రాజ్యం ఏ వ్యక్తినైనా జాతి ప్రయోజనం కోసం ఎటువంటి త్యాగానికైనా సిద్ధంగా ఉండాలని ఆజ్ఞాపించవచ్చు. ఈ హక్కులలో ఆత్మరక్షణ హక్కు కూడా ఇమిడి ఉంది.2. స్వేచ్ఛా హక్కు: స్వేచ్ఛా హక్కు వ్యక్తులకు అనేక రంగాలలో స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని ప్రసాదిస్తుంది. ఈ హక్కు వారి జీవనాన్ని అర్థవంతం చేస్తుంది. వ్యక్తులు అనేక రంగాలలో వారి వ్యక్తిత్వాన్ని వికసింపచేసుకొనేందుకు వీలు కల్పిస్తుంది. సంచరించే హక్కు, వాక్ స్వాతంత్ర్యపు హక్కు, భావవ్యక్తీకరణ హక్కు, ఆలోచనా హక్కు, నివసించే హక్కు మొదలైనవి ఇందులో ఉన్నాయి.3. సమానత్వ హక్కు: సమానత్వ హక్కు అంటే చట్టం దృష్టిలో అందరూ సమానులే అని అర్థంగా చెప్పవచ్చు. వ్యక్తుల మధ్య కులం, వర్ణం, పుట్టుక, మతం, ప్రాంతం, సంపద, విద్యలాంటి పలురకాల విచక్షణలను ఈ హక్కు నిషేధిస్తుంది. అందరినీ ఒకే రకంగా ఆదరిస్తుంది. రాజ్యంలో చట్టాలను ఒకే విధంగా వర్తించుటకు ఈ హక్కు ఉద్దేశించింది. సామాజిక, ఆర్థిక, రాజకీయ రంగాలలో వ్యక్తులందరికీ సమానమైన అవకాశాలను ఈ హక్కు కల్పిస్తుంది.4. ఆస్తి హక్కు: ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం ప్రతి వ్యక్తి ఆస్తిని సంపాదించేందుకు, అనుభవించేందుకు, దానధర్మాలకు వినియోగించుకొనేందుకు లేదా వారసత్వంగా పొందేందుకు వీలుంటుంది. ప్రతి వ్యక్తి ఉన్నత ప్రమాణాలతో జీవనాన్ని కొనసాగించేందుకు ఈ హక్కు అవసరమవుతుంది. అలాగే వ్యక్తి మూర్తిమత్వ వికాసానికి ఇది ఎంతో కీలకమైనది.5. కుటుంబ హక్కు: కుటుంబం అనేది ఒక ప్రాథమిక, సామాజిక వ్యవస్థ. కుటుంబ ” హక్కు సమాజంలో వ్యక్తులకు కుటుంబపరమైన సంబంధాలను ఏర్పరచుకొనేందుకు వీలు కల్పిస్తుంది. పర్యవసానంగా ఈ హక్కు ద్వారా వ్యక్తులు తమకు నచ్చినవారిని వివాహం చేసుకొనే స్వేచ్ఛను కలిగి ఉంటారు. అలాగే సంతానాన్ని పొందేందుకు, పిల్లలను పోషించేందుకు వారికి పూర్తి స్వేచ్ఛ ఉంటుంది. అయితే జాతీయ ప్రయోజనాలను దృష్టిలో ఉంచుకొని ఈ హక్కుపై రాజ్యం కొన్ని నిర్దిష్టమైన ఆంక్షలను విధించవచ్చు. ఉదాహరణకి ఇటీవలి కాలం వరకు చైనా ప్రభుత్వం అక్కడి పౌరుల కుటుంబసభ్యుల సంఖ్యపై కఠిన ఆంక్షలను విధించింది. ఇప్పుడిప్పుడే ఈ రాజ్యం పైన పేర్కొన్న విషయంలో కొన్ని సవరణలు చేస్తున్నది.6. మత హక్కు: ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం వ్యక్తులు తమకు ఇష్టమైన మతాన్ని స్వీకరించేందుకు, ప్రచారం చేసేందుకు, ప్రభోదించేందుకు స్వేచ్ఛను కలిగి ఉంటారు. వారు ఈ విషయంలో సంపూర్ణమైన స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటారు. ముఖ్యంగా లౌకికరాజ్యాలు తమ పౌరులకు విశేషమైన మత స్వాతంత్ర్యాలను ప్రసాదించాయి.7. ఒప్పందం హక్కు: ఒప్పందం హక్కు ప్రకారం వ్యక్తులు తమ జీవనం, ఆస్తి, ఉపాధి వంటి విషయాలలో చట్టబద్ధమైన ఏర్పాట్లను చేసుకొనేందుకు లేదా ఒప్పందాలను కుదుర్చుకొనేందుకు స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటారు. ఈ విషయంలో ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం సంబంధిత వ్యక్తులు స్పష్టమైన నియమ నిబంధనలను పాటించాల్సి ఉంటుంది. రాజ్యం వ్యక్తుల శ్రేయస్సును పెంపొందించే ఒప్పందాలను మాత్రమే ఈ సందర్భంలో గుర్తిస్తుంది.8. విద్యా హక్కు: ఆధునిక కాలంలో విద్యాహక్కు అనేది ప్రతి వ్యక్తికి అత్యంత ఆవశ్యకమైనదిగా పరిగణించబడింది. విద్యలేనివారు, అమాయకులు ప్రభుత్వ వ్యవహారాలలో చురుకుగా పాల్గొనలేరు. అలాగే నిరక్షరాస్యులు తమ శక్తి సామర్థ్యాలను పూర్తిగా వినియోగించుకోలేరు. అందుచేత విద్య, అక్షరాస్యత అనేవి సమాజంలో వివిధ సామాజిక సమస్యలను అవగాహన చేసుకొనేందుకు, ప్రభుత్వ విధానాలను తెలుసుకొనేందుకు దోహదపడతాయి. ప్రజాస్వామ్య రాజ్యాలలో ఈ హక్కు ప్రతి పౌరుడికి కనీస స్థాయి విద్యను అందించేందుకు హామీ ఇస్తుంది.9. సంస్థలు, సంఘాలను ఏర్పాటు చేసుకునే హక్కు: ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం వ్యక్తులు తమకు ఇష్టమైన సంస్థలు, సంఘాలను నెలకొల్పుకొని, కొన్ని నిర్దిష్ట లక్ష్యాలను నెరవేర్చుకొనేందుకు వీలుంటుంది. వ్యక్తులు ఈ హక్కును వినియోగించుకోవటం ద్వారా తమ అభీష్టం ప్రకారం వివిధ సంస్థలు, సంఘాలలో సభ్యులుగా చేరేందుకు, కొనసాగేందుకు మరియు సభ్యత్వాలను ఉపసంహరించుకొనేందుకు పూర్తి స్వేచ్ఛను కలిగి ఉంటారు. అయితే ఒకవేళ వ్యక్తులు జాతి శ్రేయస్సును విస్మరించి సంస్థలను స్థాపించి నిర్వహించినచో, రాజ్యం వారి చర్యలపై కొన్ని ఆంక్షలను విధించవచ్చు.10. రాజ్యాంగ పరిహారపు హక్కు: వ్యక్తి హక్కుల పరిరక్షణకు ఈ హక్కు అత్యంత ఆవశ్యకమైనది. ఈ హక్కు లేనిచో పౌరహక్కులనేవి అర్థరహితమవుతాయి. ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం ఇతరుల జోక్యం లేదా దాడి ఫలితంగా నష్టం పొందిన వ్యక్తి తన స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని కోల్పోయినచో, తగిన ఉపశమనాన్ని, న్యాయాన్ని న్యాయస్థానాల ద్వారా పొందుతాడు. ఈ సందర్భంలో ఉన్నత న్యాయస్థానాలు, అనేక ఆజ్ఞలను జారీ చేస్తాయి. అటువంటి వాటిలో హెబియస్ కార్పస్, మాండమస్, ప్రొహిబిషన్, కో వారంటో, సెర్షియోరరి లాంటివి ఉన్నాయి.రాజకీయ హక్కులు: ప్రజాస్వామ్య దేశాలలో ప్రభుత్వ వ్యవహారాలలో పౌరులు పాల్గొనటానికి అవకాశం కల్పించబడింది. ఈ అవకాశాలనే రాజకీయ హక్కులు అందురు. రాజకీయ హక్కులు ముఖ్యంగా 5 అవి:1. ఓటు హక్కు: ఆధునిక ప్రజాస్వామ్య రాజ్యాలలో పౌరులు అనుభవించే అతి ముఖ్యమైన రాజకీయ హక్కు ఓటు హక్కు వయోజన పౌరులు ఈ హక్కును వివిధ శాసన నిర్మాణ సంస్థలలో తమ ప్రతినిధులను ఎన్నుకొనేందుకు శక్తివంతమైన ఆయుధంగా వినియోగిస్తారు. ఈ హక్కు వారిని నిజమైన సార్వభౌములుగా రూపొందిస్తుంది. వయోజన పౌరులందరూ వర్ణం, పుట్టుక, భాష, తెగ, మతం, ప్రాంతం వంటి తారతమ్యాలు లేకుండా ఈ హక్కును కలిగి ఉంటారు. అయితే విదేశీయులు, మైనర్లకు ఈ హక్కు వర్తించదు.2. ఎన్నికలలో అభ్యర్థిగా పోటీచేసే హక్కు: రాజ్యంలో పౌరులు వివిధ శాసన నిర్మాణ సంస్థలకు అభ్యర్థులుగా పోటీచేసేందుకు ఈ హక్కు అధికారమిస్తుంది. రాజకీయ సామర్థ్యం ఆసక్తి, శక్తివంతమైన నాయకత్వం వంటి లక్షణాలు గల పౌరులు రాజ్యానికి సంబంధించిన రాజకీయ యంత్రాంగ నిర్వహణలలో చురుకుగా పాల్గొనేందుకు వీలు కల్పిస్తుంది. దాంతో ఈ హక్కు పౌరులలో విశేషమైన రాజకీయ పరిజ్ఞానాన్ని, ఆసక్తిని పెంపొందిస్తుంది. ఈ హక్కు ప్రజాస్వామ్య రాజ్యానికి ప్రధాన ప్రాతిపదికగా ఉంటుంది.3. ప్రభుత్వ పదవులను చేపట్టే హక్కు: పౌరులు వివిధ రకాల ప్రభుత్వ పదవులను చేపట్టి, నిర్వహించేందుకు ఈ హక్కు అనేక అవకాశాలను కల్పిస్తుంది. ఈ హక్కు ప్రకారం ఏ ఒక్క పౌరుడు ఇతరులతో పోల్చినచో ఎటువంటి ప్రత్యేకమైన సౌకర్యాలను కానీ, మినహాయింపులు కానీ పొందేందుకు వీలులేదు. ప్రభుత్వాధికారాన్ని ఎంతో హుందాగా నిర్వహించేందుకు ఈ హక్కు పౌరులకు సహాయకారిగా ఉంటుంది.4. విజ్ఞాపన హక్కు: పౌరులు తమ అవసరాలు లేదా సమస్యలను ప్రభుత్వ దృష్టికి విజ్ఞప్తుల ద్వారా తెచ్చేందుకు ఈ హక్కు దోహదపడుతుంది. ఆధునిక రాజ్యంలో ఈ హక్కు ఎంతో ప్రాధాన్యత గల రాజకీయ హక్కుగా పరిగణించబడింది. ఈ హక్కు ద్వారా పౌరులు ఎంతో కాలంగా అపరిష్కృతంగా ఉన్న సమస్యలను ప్రభుత్వం దృష్టికి తెచ్చి, తగిన పరిష్కారాలను పొందుతారు. అలాగే ప్రభుత్వాధికారులు ప్రజా సమస్యలను తెలుసుకొని, వాటిని సకాలంలో పరిష్కరించేటట్లు ఈ హక్కు సహాయపడుతుంది.5. విమర్శించే హక్కు: ఈ హక్కు ప్రభుత్వానికి సంబంధించిన అనేక విధానాలు, కార్యక్రమాలను విమర్శించేందుకు పౌరులకు అవకాశం ఇస్తుంది. అలాగే వివిధ స్థాయిలలో నాయకులు, పరిపాలన సిబ్బంది పాల్పడే అవకతవకలను బహిర్గతం చేసేందుకు ఇది తోడ్పడుతుంది. అంతేకాకుండా కాలానుగుణంగా ప్రభుత్వం అనుసరించే విధానాలపై పౌరులు సహేతుకమైన, నిర్మాణాత్మకమైన విమర్శలను చేసేందుకు అవకాశమిస్తుంది. ఈ హక్కు అంతిమంగా పరిపాలనాధికారులు, విధాన రూపకర్తలు తమ విద్యుక్త ధర్మాలను ఎంతో అప్రమత్తంగా, జాగ్రత్తగా నిర్వహించేటట్లు చూస్తుంది."},{"question":"ਬਾਇਓ ਗੈਸ ਕਿਸ ਤੋਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਬਾਇਓਗੈਸ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਲ-ਮੂਤਰ ਤੋਂ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਬਾਇਓ ਗੈਸ ਵਿਚ ਲਗਪਗ 67% ਮੀਥੇਨ ਗੈਸ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਕਿ ਬਲਣਸ਼ੀਲ ਗੈਸ ਹੈ । ਇਹ ਗੈਸ ਨਾਲੀਆਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਭੇਜੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਭੋਜਨ ਪਕਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਬਾਇਓਗੈਸ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਲੰਡਰਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਭਰਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ । ਬਚਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਮਲ-ਮੂਤਰ ਖਾਦ ਵਜੋਂ ਖੇਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Cuộc đời của Elizabeth Woodville trở thành nguồn cảm hứng lớn cho các tác phẩm và tiểu thuyết liên quan đến cuộc Chiến tranh Hoa Hồng","answer":". Đáng kể nhất là phương diện sân khấu, nhà soạn kịch William Shakespeare đã làm nên hai vở kịch là \\"Henry VI, Part 3\\" cùng \\"Richard III\\" đều có liên quan đến cuộc đời bà, trong khi phần Henry VI chỉ nói về khía cạnh nhỏ về cuộc hôn nhân của bà, thì trong phần Richard III lại lấy Elizabeth Woodville làm trung tâm, với việc căng thẳng giữa bà cùng Vua Richard về vấn đề kế vị trong lịch sử. Theo sự xây dựng của Shakespeare, Elizabeth Woodville trở thành địch thủ chính trị đáng gờm và thông minh nhất của Vua Richard ngay từ khi cả hai lần đầu gặp với tư cách chị dâu em chồng. Và dù hai vở kịch này, qua bàn tay hiện đại đã gọi bà trực tiếp là [\\"Queen Elizabeth\\"], thì nguyên tác của Shakespeare lại không bao giờ gọi như vậy, mà chỉ là [\\"Lady Grey\\"] hay [\\"The Queen\\"]."},{"question":"ما اسم العضلة الأكثر قوة في جسم الإنسان؟ ","answer":"العضلة الأكثر قوة في جسم الإنسان هي عضلة الفخذ (الرباط العضلي للفخذ). عضلة الفخذ تتألف من مجموعة من العضلات، وليس هناك عضلة واحدة تحمل اسم \\"عضلة الفخذ\\". تشكل العضلات في منطقة الفخذ مجموعة كبيرة ومعقدة، تشمل العديد من العضلات مثل عضلات الكواد والمجموعة الخلفية والمجموعة الداخلية والخارجية، وغيرها.إذا كنت تقصد العضلات الكبيرة في منطقة الفخذ، فإن عضلة الكواد (Quadriceps) تعتبر واحدة من أكبر وأقوى العضلات في هذه المنطقة، وهي تشمل أربع عضلات هي الرباط العضلي الأمامي (Rectus Femoris) وعضلة السمانة الطويلة (Vastus Longus) وعضلة السمانة الوسطى (Vastus Medialis) وعضلة السمانة القصيرة (Vastus Lateralis)."},{"question":"කාර්මික විප්ලවය යුරෝපයේ ආරම්භ වීමට බලපෑ ප්‍රධාන හේතුව කුමක්ද?","answer":"කාර්මික විප්ලවය යුරෝපයේ ආරම්භ වීමට බලපෑ ප්‍රධාන හේතුව වන්නෙ වෙළෙඳාම යි.."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Lê Bống tự tin trước thềm chung kết \\"Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam\\" | Lao Động Trẻ - Tin tức mới nhất dành cho công nhân lao động trẻ","answer":"Lê Bống tung bộ ảnh quyến rũ và có chia sẻ trước thềm chung kết Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam 2022. Trước thềm chung kết Miss Fitness Vietnam 2022 (Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam), thí sinh Lê Xuân Anh (hay còn được cộng đồng mạng gọi với cái tên quen thuộc Lê Bống) gây chú ý khi tung bộ ảnh mới. Khác hẳn hình ảnh một TikToker năng động, người đẹp sinh năm 1995 có màn \\"lột xác\\" với vẻ ngoài nóng bỏng hơn. Qua những hình ảnh này, Lê Bống cho biết muốn truyền tải thông điệp tích cực cho tất cả mọi người: \\"Chỉ cần bạn biết yêu thương bản thân, rồi bạn sẽ trở thành một phiên bản tốt hơn của chính mình\\". \\"Vậy là hành trình tại Miss Fitness Vietnam 2022 của tôi chỉ còn một ngày nữa là kết thúc. Khoảng thời gian vừa qua tại cuộc thi đã giúp tôi trưởng thành hơn rất nhiều và cũng học hỏi được những điều bổ ích. Tôi thấy mình cực kỳ may mắn. Và tôi cũng tin rằng bản thân đã có thể chạm gần hơn đến phiên bản hoàn hảo của chính mình\\", cô chia sẻ. Nhìn lại hành trình dự thi Miss Fitness Vietnam 2022, Lê Bống cho biết cô đã cố gắng và nỗ lực vượt qua nhiều thử thách để bứt phá giới hạn của bản thân. Đồng thời, người đẹp sinh năm 1995 cũng gửi lời cảm ơn đến huấn luyện viên và các thí sinh khác vì đã luôn giúp đỡ mình trong suốt thời gian vừa qua. Lê Bống sinh năm 1995, ở Hà Nội. Cô được biết đến với vai trò là một Tiktoker, người mẫu ảnh và tham gia diễn xuất trong một số MV ca nhạc, phim ngắn của các nghệ sĩ Việt... Sở hữu ngoại hình xinh xắn, Lê Bống đã nhanh chóng thu hút sự chú ý của mọi người và thu về lượng khán giả trên mạng xã hội. Nằm trong Top 30 thí sinh xuất sắc nhất, Lê Bống sẽ tranh tài cho ngôi vị Hoa hậu Thể thao Việt Nam 2022 trong đêm chung kết diễn ra tối 31.7 tại TP.HCM. Hoa hậu Thúy Anh Ngô cùng ê-kíp tham gia các hoạt động cộng đồng nhằm mang yêu thương đến người nghèo, nghệ sĩ neo đơn."},{"question":"Cé hé Luciano Pavarotti? ","answer":"Ba theanór cáiliúil Iodálach é Luciano Pavarotti ( 12 Deireadh Fómhair 1935 - 6 Meán Fómhair 2007) a raibh aithne air ar fud an domhain go háirithe mar amhránaí ceoldráma. Rugadh i Modena i dtuaisceart na hIodáile é. Bhí aithne air chomh maith mar gheall ar a chuid oibre le haghaidh airgead a bhailiú do charthanais ar son dídeanaithe agus do Chumann na Croise Deirge.\\tIs síol é an t-alt seo. Cuir leis, chun cuidiú leis an Vicipéid.Má tá alt níos forbartha le fáil i dteanga eile, is féidir leat aistriúchán Gaeilge a dhéanamh."},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Tanzânia?","answer":"0,549."},{"question":"Kanti imibuzo yani leyo?Imibuzo nje yomthetho.Kulungile, ngiyezwa-ke mntanami.(Esukuma) Sengibongile mama, sengicela ukuhamba.Uma nimthola nimtshele eze azongibona bo.Ngizokwenze njalo mama. Ngizokukhonzela.Ungikhonzele kakhulu mntanami.(Avalelise uNhleko aphume. Endleleni uhamba ekhuluma yedwa.)Kungenzeka yini ukuthi nguye uSonto owadubula uMfundisi? Impelasekusobala manje. Manje ngizobenzenjani lobu bufakaziengibutholile? Kodwa akufanele ngitatazele. Kuyofanele siqoqe bonkeubufakazi esingabuthola bese siyambamba lo nkosikazi. Impelaakufuneki ukuxhamazela uma sekunje. Kuzofanele siyobhekanalapha okwadutshulelwa khona uMfundisi sibone ukuthi singetholelutho yini. He, akakhohliwe nje ehlakaniphile lo nkosikazi. Kodwangiyafunga, ngeke kugcine yena! (Aqhubeke nohambo esephikeleleesiteshini samaphoyisa.)1. Chaza ukuthi ubukhona bomlingiswa onguMthofi kwawuhlukumeza kanjaniumphakathi wakule ndawo. Bhala iphuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo: UMthofi uyathengwa ukuthi abulale abantu lokhu kwakwenza ukuthiumphakathi uzizwe ungaphephile.  Ukuhamba ehlome ngesibhamu kwenza umphakathi ungaphephi.  UMthofi wabulala abantu abaningi endaweni lokhu kwenza ukuthi isimosenhlalo endaweni singabi sihle. (Nokunye okunembayo okungashiwo umfundi) "},{"question":"Who starred as Juno MacGuff opposite Michael Cera in the 2007 film Juno?","answer":"Elliot Page (formerly Ellen Page). While presenting as female, Page came to recognition for his role in the television franchise Pit Pony (1997–2000), for which he was nominated for a Young Artist Award, and for his recurring roles in Trailer Park Boys (2002) and ReGenesis (2004). He received critical acclaim for portraying the title role, a pregnant teenager, in Jason Reitman's film Juno (2007), and earned nominations for an Academy Award, two BAFTA Awards, a Golden Globe Award and a Screen Actors Guild Award. At age 20, it made him the fourth-youngest nominee for the Academy Award Best Actress at the time.Page is also known as an outspoken activist. Describing himself as a pro-choice feminist, he has spoken out in favor of the Me Too movement, advocated for abortion rights, has called for the end of military dictatorship in Myanmar, and also practices as a vegan. In 2014 Page was included in The Advocate's annual \\"40 Under 40\\" list. In 2015 he received the Human Rights Campaign Vanguard Award. Page has strongly spoken out against discriminatory legislation towards the trans community and has become a vocal advocate for LGBTQ rights."},{"question":"Σε ποιο σημαντικο γεγονός αναφέρεται το κείμενο: Ευρέως γνωστή, έγινε το 2009, όταν συμμετείχε στο Διαγωνισμό Τραγουδιού της Eurovision, που έγινε στη Μόσχα της Ρωσίας, εκπροσωπόντας την Τουρκία με το τραγούδι \\"Düm Tek Tek\\" καταλαμβάνοντας την 4η θέση.","answer":"Στην καλλιτέχνη που συμμετείχε στο Διαγωνισμό Τραγουδιού της Eurovision με την Τουρκία. "},{"question":"Nibi tawọn eleyii ti n digunjale lọwọ n’Iju-Ọta lawọn ọlọpaa ka wọn mọ","answer":"Lalẹ, ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an aabọ ọjọ kejila, oṣu kọkanla, lawọn ọkunrin mẹta yii; Bamidele Oluwashina, Adebọwale Kẹhinde ati Oluwaṣẹgun Abayọmi, digunjale laduugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Iju-Ọta, nipinlẹ Ogun, ti wọn n fi nnkan ija gba dukia awọn eeyan lọwọ wọn.Ibudokọ Iju-Love ati Tipper Garage, gan-an ni wọn ti n pitu ọhun gẹgẹ bi DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi ṣe wi.O ni nibi ti wọn ti ko jinni-jinni ba awọn eeyan lẹni kan ti pe teṣan ọlọpaa Onipaanu, l’Ọta, pe idigunjale n lọ lọwọ ni Iju-Ọta o.Bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe debẹ ni wọn ṣina ibọn bolẹ lati dẹruba awọn ole yii, ṣugbọn niṣe lawọn naa bẹrẹ si i da tiwọn pada, wọn ko sa rara.Nigba ti ikọ adigunjale naa ri i pe ibọn ọlọpaa le ju eyi tawọn n lo lọ ni wọn dọgbọn sa, ṣugbọn ọwọ ba ọkan ninu wọn.Kia lawọn agbofinro ti gba gbogbo agbegbe naa kan, pẹlu iranlọwọ awọn eeyan ibẹ, wọn ri awọn meji yooku mu, nigba ti wọn n dọgbọn sa lọ ninu kẹkẹ Maruwa kan.Ṣaaju lawọn ole yii ti bu Tosin Ajayi ladaa lori, niṣe lawọn ọlọpaa sare gbe e lọ si ọsibitu fun itọju.Ibọn ilewọ ibilẹ kan ati ọta ibọn meji ti wọn ko ti i yin lawọn ọlọpaa ba lọwọ ikọ adigunjale yii; wọn si ti taari wọn sẹka itọpinpin labẹnu, gẹgẹ bi CP Edward Ajogun ṣe paṣẹ."},{"question":"வினா : முதலாம் பாரூக் பற்றி  குறிப்பு எழுதுக","answer":"விடை: முதலாம் பாரூக்  (11 பிப்ரவரி 1920 - 18 மார்ச் 1965) இவர் முகம்மது அலி வம்சத்திலிருந்து எகிப்தின் பத்தாவது ஆட்சியாளராகவும், எகிப்து மற்றும் சூடானின் இறுதி மன்னனாகவும் இருந்தார். இவரது தந்தை முதலாம் புவாத் என்பவருக்குப் பின் 1936 இல் பதவிக்கு வந்தார். 1952 ஆம் ஆண்டு எகிப்திய புரட்சியில் இவர் பதவிலிருந்து தூக்கியெறியப்பட்டு, பின்னர், 1965 இல் இத்தாலிக்கு நாடுகடத்தப்பட்டார்.இவர், 1920 பிப்ரவரி 11 அன்று கெய்ரோவின் அப்தீன் அரண்மனையில், சுல்தான் முதலாம் புவாத் என்பவருக்கும், அவரது இரண்டாவது மனைவி நஸ்லி சப்ரி என்பவருக்கும் மூத்த மகனாகப் பிறந்தார். அல்பேனிய வம்சாவளியைச் சேர்ந்த இவர் தனது பாரம்பரியத்தைப் பற்றி எப்போதும் பெருமிதம் கொண்டிருந்தார். மேலும் ஒரு மன்னனாக, இவர் 30 அல்பேனிய மெய்க்காப்பாளர்களை தன்னுடைய பாதுகாவலர்களாகக் கொண்டிருந்தார். ஏனெனில் அல்பேனியர்களை தனது வாழ்க்கையில் நம்பக்கூடிய ஒரே நபராக இவர் கருதினார். இத்தாலியைச் சேர்ந்த அன்டோனியோ புல்லி என்பவர் இவரது இளமைக்கால நண்பராக இருந்தார். அவர் பாருக்கின் ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில் எகிப்தின் மிக சக்திவாய்ந்த மனிதர்களில் ஒருவரானார். இவரது தந்தை இறப்பதற்கு முன்பு, இங்கிலாந்தின் வூல்விச்சில் உள்ள இராணுவக் கழகத்தில் கல்வி பயின்றார். இவர் 1965 மார்ச் 18 அன்று ஒரு உணவகத்தில் இறந்தார். எகிப்திய உளவுத்துறை இவர் விஷம் குடித்து இறந்தார் எனக் கூறினாலும், இவரது உடலில் அதிகாரப்பூர்வ பிரேத பரிசோதனை எதுவும் நடத்தப்படவில்லை. தான் கெய்ரோவில் உள்ள அல் ரிஃபாய் பள்ளிவாசல் கல்லறையில் அடக்கம் செய்யப்பட வேண்டும் என்று விருப்பினார். ஆனால் அந்தக் கோரிக்கையை அப்போதைய எகிப்திய அரசாங்கம் மறுத்து விட்டது. பின்னர், இவர் இத்தாலியிலேயே அடக்கம் செய்யப்பட்டார். "},{"question":"Vilket land ligger mellan Spanien och Frankrike?","answer":"Andorra, formellt Furstendömet Andorra (katalanska: Principat d'Andorra), är ett litet furstendöme i Pyrenéerna i sydvästra Europa, en inlandsstat på gränsen mellan Frankrike och Spanien. Huvudstad är Andorra la Vella. Andorra är en av Europas mikrostater."},{"question":"கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கேள்விக்குச் சரியான பதிலளி:சாரநாத் கல்தூணில் செதுக்கப்படாத விலங்கு?1. மாடு2. யானை3. சிங்கம்4. குதிரை","answer":"விடை: 1. மாடு. இந்தியாவின் புகழ் பெற்ற சக்கரவர்த்தியான அசோகர், சில ஸ்தூபிகளையும் தூணையும் 'சாரநாத்' எனும் இடத்தில் நிறுவினார். இதில் உள்ள அசோகச் சக்கரம்தான் இந்தியத் தேசியக் கொடியையும் அலங்கரிக்கிறது. அசோகச்சக்கரத்தின் அருகில் நான்கு பக்கமும் சிங்கம், குதிரை, எருது, யானை ஆகியவற்றின் உருவங்கள் உள்ளன. இந்தத் தூணில் உள்ள நான்கு சிங்கங்கள்தான் இந்தியாவின் தேசியச் சின்னமாக உள்ளது."},{"question":"ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਭਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੰਡੋਮ ਜਾਂ ਸੈਕਸ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰਾਂ ਲਈ ਇਹ ਹਨ ਨਿਯਮ।ਇਸ ਹੁਕਮ ਨੇ ਸਰਕਾਰੀ ਕੰਟਰੋਲ ਅਤੇ ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ਯੋਗ ਤੇ ਗ਼ੈਰ-ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ਯੋਗ  ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਰੇਖਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਚਰਚਾ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ।ਕਿੱਥੇ ਔਰਤਾਂ ਦੀ 'ਸ਼ੁੱਧੀ' ਲਈ ਸੈਕਸ ਕਰਨਾ ਰਵਾਇਤ ਹੈ?ਸੈਕਸ ਡੌਲ ਦੀ ਖਿੱਚ-ਧੂਹ: ਕਿਹੋ ਜਿਹੀ ਮਾਨਸਿਕਤਾ?ਸੈਕਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਨਕਾਰ ਕਰਨ 'ਤੇ ਪਤਨੀ ਦਾ ਕਤਲ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਭਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. 'ਤੇ ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਸਬੰਧੀ ਕੁਝ ਹੋਰ ਉਦਾਹਰਣਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਇੱਕ ਝਾਤ -ਯੂਕੇ ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ :ਯੂਕੇ ਵਿਚ ਥ੍ਰੈਸ਼ਹੋਲਡ (ਇੱਕ ਵਿਸ਼ੇਸ਼ ਸਮਾਂ) ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਨੂੰ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ। ਫ੍ਰੀ-ਟੂ-ਏਅਰ ਚੈਨਲ ਰਾਤ ਨੌਂ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਵੇਰ ਸਾਢੇ ਪੰਜ ਵਜੇ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਹੀ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰ ਜਾਂ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਪੂਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਢੁੱਕਵੀਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ। ਸੈਕਸ ਸੀਡੀ, ਸਿਆਸਤ ਤੇ ਔਰਤ ਦੀ ਮਰਿਆਦਾ :ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਪਰੋਨ ਬਾਰੇ ਇਹ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਜਾਣਨੀਆਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹਨ। ਪ੍ਰੀਮੀਅਮ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਲਈ, ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ ਰਾਤ ਅੱਠ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਸਵੇਰੇ ਛੇ ਵਜੇ ਖ਼ਤਮ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਨਿਯਮ ਉਸ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ 'ਤੇ ਲਾਗੂ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਗਾਲ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਾਂ ਹਿੰਸਾ ਆਦਿ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ।ਯੂਕੇ ਕਮਿਊਨੀਕੇਸ਼ਨ ਰੈਗੂਲੇਟਰ ਆਫ਼ ਕਾਮ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਹੋਏ ਇੱਕ ਸਰਵੇਖਣ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ 74% ਆਮ ਜਨਤਾ ਅਤੇ 78% ਮਾਪੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ 9 ਵਜੇ ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ ਜਾਂ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਲਈ ਸਹੀ ਸਮਾਂ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਹੈ ਕਿ 9 ਵਜੇ ਦੇ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ, ਘਰੇਲੂ ਚੈਨਲਾਂ 'ਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਦੇਖਣ ਯੋਗ ਹੋਣੇ ਚਾਹੀਦੇ ਹਨ। ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਦੀ ਨੀਤੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, \\"ਬਾਲਗ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸੰਵੇਦਨਸ਼ੀਲ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਕਰਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ 'ਵਾਟਰਸ਼ੈਡ' ਦੇ ਨੇੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ।\\"ਯੂ ਐਸ ਏ ਸੇਫ ਹਾਰਬਰ :ਯੂਨਾਈਟਿਡ ਸਟੇਟਸ ਫੈਡਰਲ ਕਮਿਊਨੀਕੇਸ਼ਨਜ਼ ਕਮਿਸ਼ਨ (ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ) ਨੇ ਟੀਵੀ 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਲਈ ਨਿਯਮ ਨਿਰਧਾਰਿਤ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ।ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ. ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮਾਂ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਰਾਤ ਦਸ ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਵੇਰ ਛੇ ਵਜੇ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਿਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ।'ਕੀ ਖਤਰਾ ਹੈ ਨੀਲੀਆਂ ਫਿਲਮਾਂ ਦੇਖਣ ਨਾਲ' :ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਘੰਟਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ 'ਸੁਰੱਖਿਅਤ ਹਾਰਬਰ ਘੰਟੇ' (ਸੇਫ ਹਾਰਬਰ ਆਵਰ) ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਐਫ.ਸੀ.ਸੀ. ਦੇ ਨਿਯਮ 'ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ' ਨੂੰ ਪਰਿਭਾਸ਼ਿਤ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਵੇਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਿਣਸੀ ਸਮੱਗਰੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਿਲ ਹੈ। ਅਸ਼ਲੀਲ ਭਾਸ਼ਣ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਸੋਧ (ਪ੍ਰਗਟਾਵੇ ਦੀ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ) ਦੁਆਰਾ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਅਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. 'ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਐਤਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਮੰਤਰਾਲੇ ਨੇ ਟੀ.ਵੀ. ਚੈਨਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਰਾਤ 10 ਵਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਸਵੇਰੇ 6 ਵਜੇ ਦੇ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਹੀ ਕੰਡੋਮ ਦੇ ਇਸ਼ਤਿਹਾਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਰਣ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਸਲਾਹ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Wat is contraspionage?","answer":"Contraspionage is een activiteit gericht op het beschermen van het inlichtingenprogramma van een organisatie tegen de inlichtingendiensten van een tegenstander. Het omvat het verzamelen van informatie en het uitvoeren van activiteiten om spionage, sabotage, moorden of andere inlichtingenactiviteiten uitgevoerd door, voor of namens buitenlandse machten, organisaties of personen te voorkomen."},{"question":"கணிப்பொறியின் தந்தை?","answer":"சார்லஸ் பேபேஜ்"},{"question":"参考下面的段落,然后以相同的语言回答后面的问题:  过渡:1972年,梅赛德斯-奔<unk>推出了W116系列,这是第一个正式被称为S级的车型. 产于1972年至1980年,W116系列具有四轮独立悬挂和盘式制动. 280,350和450 (4.5L版本) 的车型有SE和SEL版本. W116的生产总数为473,035台. 这是梅赛德斯-奔<unk>的开创性<unk>车, 在公司历史上, 这辆车首次有明显,公然和外在的重视安全, 而不是纯粹的造型观点. 整体设计包含了从20世纪60年代中后期到70年代初的\\"安全研究车辆\\"开发的众多安全功能.  问题:W116的生产量有多少台?","answer":"473,035台"},{"question":"Глобалдык моделдештирүү деген эмне ?","answer":"Глобалдык моделдештирүү – илимдеги Жер шарын дээрлик камтыган, ири масштабдагы социал., экономикалык, жана экологиялык процесстердин моделдерин иштеп чыгууга арналган жаңы тармак. Дүйнөнүн экономикасынын алгачкы экономикалык, математикалык модели БУУнун тапшырмасы боюнча АКШ экономисти В. Леонтьевдин жетекчилиги астында иштелип чыккан. Анда дүйнө экономикалык, 43 сектор боюнча экспорттук-импорттук өз ара байланышы бар 15 регионго бөлүнгөн. Бул моделде бүтүндөй дүйнө жүзүнүн 2000-жылга чейинки өнүгүү келечегинин бир нече варианты анализделген. Мындан тышкары Рим клубунун тапшырмасы боюнча башка моделдер да иштелип чыгууда. Кандай гана глобалдык модел болбосун аны түзүүдө илим менен техниканын жетишкендиктерин жана өнүгүү тенденцияларын эсепке алып, дүйнөдө тынчтыкты жана Жердин экосистемасын сактоону эске алуу зарыл."},{"question":"\\"Tsy mba afaka mandray anjara amin'ny fiainantsika ato an-trano ve ianao e? Isan'andro mitavana izay asa vitan'ny hafa fotsiny, manampy ny asan'olona indray ary!\\"Inona no fihetseham-po asehon'io fanambarana io?","answer":"Maheho hatezerana io fanambarana io satria miresaka momba ny hakiviana manoloana ny zava-misy ary miezaka ny mahatnga saina olona amin'ny zavatra tsy mety ataony."},{"question":"من می‌خواهم آپارتمانی را بخرم و من هم می‌خواهم آپارتمانی را بفروشم به نظر شما برای بدست آوردن قیمت مناسب از چه طریقی می‌توانم اقدام کنم؟","answer":"اگر قصد خرید کاشانه دارید، ابتدا باید متناسب با بودجه‌ای که دارید و یا پیش‌بینی می‌کنید که قادر به تهیه و تأمین آن هستید، ابتدا یک جستجوی اینترنتی را در وب سایت‌های ملکی و سپس اپلیکیشن‌های معروف موبایلی انجام بدهید و همچنین پیشنهادهای فروش در روزنامه همشهری را بررسی کنید و سپس به‌صورت حضوری در بنگاه‌های واقع در محله یا منطقه‌ای که قصد خرید کاشانه را دارید مراجعه کنید و فایل‌های مناسب با بودجه خود را مشاهده کنید و باقیمت‌هایی که از سایت‌ها و جراید به دست آورده‌اید مقایسه کنید و بعد از بررسی شرایط و امکانات به‌راحتی می‌توانید قیمت مناسب و به‌روز آپارتمانی را که از مدنظرتان است را بیابید ولی اگر قصد فروش دارید علاوه بر آنچه گفته شد، برای فروش سریع‌تر می‌توانید یک تخفیف مناسبی در نظر بگیرید و علاوه بر سپردن ملکتان به بنگاه‌های رسمی اتحادیه املاک برای فروش سریع‌تر و به‌موقع آگهی ملکتان را در وب سایت‌های معتبر ملکی و اپلیکیشن‌های موبایلی و روزنامه همشهری ثبت کنید. مطمئن باشید که اگر موقعیت ملک‌تان مناسب و قیمت آن کمی تخفیف خورده باشد، صریحاً مشتری پر و پا قرص سروکله‌اش پیدا می‌شود."},{"question":"සාමය සම්බන්ධ ශාකයේ නම මොකක්ද?","answer":"සාමය සම්බන්ධ ශාකයේ නම ඔලිව්‌ ශාකයයි. ඔලිව් ගස හෝ වඩාත් නිශ්චිතවම ඔලිව් ශාඛාවක් යනු පුරාණ ග්‍රීක මිථ්‍යා කථා දක්වා දිවෙන සාමයේ හා මිත්රත්වයේ සංකේතයකි."},{"question":"Mene ne Ashasha?","answer":"Nau’ i ce ta garma da ake amfani da ita wajen noma ta hanyar rage girman kunya, ita takan burkuce kwarin kunya ne, sannan kuma ta rage faɗin kunyar, ta yadda mai aiki zai ji sauƙin gudanar da noma. A wasu guraren ma sai dai kawai ya ɗaga ciyawar ya karkaɗe ƙasar jikinta."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny _ dia vavaka kristianina izay midera an'i Maria Virjiny.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Ny Ave Maria dia vavaka kristianina izay midera an'i Maria Virjiny."},{"question":"క్రింది వాక్యాలను సంక్లిష్ట వాక్యాలుగా మార్చండి.అ) అంబటిపూడి వెంకటరత్నం కావ్యం రాశాడు. అంబటిపూడి వెంకటరత్నం అచ్చు వేయించాడు.ఆ) గడియారం రామకృష్ణశర్మ మంచి పాండిత్యం సంపాదించాడు. గడియారం రామకృష్ణశర్మ అనేక సన్మానాలు పొందాడు.ఇ) కప్పగంతుల లక్ష్మణశాస్త్రి కర్ణసుందరి నాటకాన్ని అనువదించాడు. కర్ణనుందరి నాటకాన్ని ప్రచురించాడు.","answer":"అ) అంబటిపూడి వెంకటరత్నం కావ్యం రాశాడు. అంబటిపూడి వెంకటరత్నం అచ్చు వేయించాడు.జవాబు:అంబటిపూడి వెంకటరత్నం కావ్యం రాసి, అచ్చు వేయించాడు.ఆ) గడియారం రామకృష్ణశర్మ మంచి పాండిత్యం సంపాదించాడు. గడియారం రామకృష్ణశర్మ అనేక సన్మానాలు పొందాడు.జవాబు:గడియారం రామకృష్ణశర్మ మంచి పాండిత్యం సంపాదించి, అనేక సన్మానాలు పొందాడు.ఇ) కప్పగంతుల లక్ష్మణశాస్త్రి కర్ణసుందరి నాటకాన్ని అనువదించాడు. కర్ణనుందరి నాటకాన్ని ప్రచురించాడు.జవాబు:కప్పగంతుల లక్ష్మణశాస్త్రి కర్ణసుందరి నాటకాన్ని అనువదించి, ప్రచురించాడు."},{"question":"A que categoria pertence a seguinte questão: Quem ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Ator em dois mil e onze?","answer":"A categoria desta pergunta é: cinema. Colin Firth ganhou o prêmio de Melhor Ator por seu papel como Rei George VI em “O Discurso do Rei”. Em janeiro, Firth ganhou o Globo de Ouro de Melhor Ator - Filme Dramático.Ele já recebeu uma indicação ao Oscar por seu papel no ano passado em “A Single Man”. Ele perdeu para Jeff Bridges em \\"Crazy Heart\\"."},{"question":"البردة قصيدة في مدح الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم للشاعر…؟","answer":"كعب بن زهير"},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة رومنسيه من بحر الخفيف. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"وَغَزال كَناسِهِ المرانُما لِقَلب مِن مُقلَتيهِ أَمانُذي نَواس كَأَنَّها ظُلمة الشرك وَوَجه كَأَنَّهُ الإِيمانفَكَأَن العذار في صَفحة الخد كَفور في جيدِهِ فُرقانوَكَأَنا مِن أُنسِهِ وَمَحياهُ بِرَوض تَظلنا الأَفنانخَدُّهُ الوَرد وَالبَنَفسَج صَدغاه لِعَيني وَثَغرهُ الأُقحُوانوَكَأَنَّ النَديّ وَالكاس تَجلىفيهِ أُفق نُجومِهِ الندمانوَكَأن الأَنفاس مِنهُ نَسيموَكَأَنا إِذا شَدا أَغصانوَكَأَن الندمان في دَوحة اللَهو غُصون ثَمارها الكِتمانيَتَعاطُون أَكؤُس العَتب إِذ طافَ عَلَيهُم بِها المُنى وَالأَمانيا سَقا ذَلِكَ الزَمان وَحَياه مَلث مِن الرِضى هتانزَمَن كُلُهُ رَبيع وَعَيشغُصنُهُ يانع الجنى فينانِمر لي بِالشَئام وَالشَوق غُصنوَشَبابي يَزينهُ العُنفُوانِاِبن عَشر وَأَربَع وَثَمانهِيَ عيد وَبَعضَها مَهرَجانِ"},{"question":"\\"දෙවැට අයිනේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"දෙවැට අයිනේ මල් පිපෙන්නේ පුංචි නංගිලාටයිනංගිලා ඒ මල් නෙලන්නේ මාලයක් ගොතන්නයිසුවඳ මල් වලින් ගොතන මාලා පුංචි මල්ලිලාටයිමල්ලිලා ඒ ගෙල දමන්නේ ආදරේ ලබන්නයිසියුමැලී මල් පෙතීපාට පාටින් සැරසෙතීඇයි ලොවේ පිපුනේ කියාසුවඳ මල් නො අසතීබට ගහේ අතු අත වනන්නේ පුංචි මල්ලිලාටයිමල්ලිලා ඒ බට නෙලන්නේ බටනලා හදන්නයිහදවතේ සුසුමන් නැගෙන්නේ ඒ නලා වයන්නයිබට නලාවේ ඒ ඇසෙන්නේ ආදරේ කතාවයිබටගහේ සිදුරකින්හදවතේ සුසුමකින්ගැයෙන ගී රාවයෙන්මියුරු වී අප සවන්භද්‍රජි මහින්ද ජයතිලක, සමිතා මුදුන්කොටුවභද්‍රජි මහින්ද ජයතිලකභද්‍රජි මහින්ද ජයතිලක "},{"question":"س146- من هي ملكة سبأ في عهد سيدنا سليمان؟","answer":"ج146- بلقيس"},{"question":"ਮੇਰੀ ਬਸ ਛੁੱਟ ਗਈ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੈਂ ਕੰਮ ਤੇ ਜਲਦੀ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੰਮ ਲਈ ਲੇਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੰਮ ਲਈ ਲੇਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. සුබ ලකුණු බල බලා ඉරගල වැටෙන ඉම තුරාහෙමිහිට ඇවිද ගියේ තනිකම් දොසින් නේදමිහිකත බාර දෙවියනේපෝයෙන් පෝය ගෙවෙන්නේ","answer":"සුබ ලකුණු බල බලා ඉරගල වැටෙන ඉම තුරාහෙමිහිට ඇවිද ගියේ තනිකම් දොසින් නේදමිහිකත බාර දෙවියනේපෝයෙන් පෝය ගෙවෙන්නේදොරකඩ හීන විසිරයේමගෙ හද අගුළු හැර තියේයහනට නිදි ගෙනෙන්නරැය අඳුරින් මුදන්නකවදා කවුරුද එන්නේතනිකම් නපුර පරදවාඅණ වින දෝස හැර දමාඅඳුරට එළිය දෙන්නසිහිනය රැගෙන එන්නකවදා කවුරුද එන්නේනිරෝෂා විරාජිනීනිලාර් එන්. කාසිම්රෝහණ වීරසිංහ"},{"question":"Алыкул Осмоновтун калемине таандык ырлардан жазып бере аласыңбы ?","answer":"КАЛАМГАСен жолдошум, сен кубатым, сен бактым,Ашык болуп, издеп жүрүп мен таптым.Колуктумдун мурда сүйүп өзүңдү,Өз жанымдын жарымысынан жараттым.Чырагымсың, айсыз түндө адашпайм,Ынагымсың, жан чыкканча тарашпайм.Дүркүрөгөн дөөлөтүмсүң каламым…Вашингтон долларына алмашпайм.Командириң – эл намысы, эл анты,Сага ишенип курч куралып карматты.Ошондуктан, өрт аралап бараткан –Сен доорумдун танка минген солдаты.Заман күчтүү, күч чак келбейт алдына,Заман дайра, аккан катуу агымга.Бул турмушта: нечен кыйын жол бастык,Дагы кыйын жолдор жатат алдыда.Эгер өлкөм керек десе биз белен,Эл эрки үчүн, туулганбыз энеден,Жүрөгү чоң баатырларбыз бактылуу –Жер шарынын азаттыгын ээлеген.Мына ушундай улуу жолдо баратып,Кезек менен күндөр батып, таң атып.Күтүлбөгөн бир мезгилде, түбөлүк –Эгер өлүм, мени кетсе уктатып.Ошол замат, арта салып мойнуңа,Тез чуркап жет, кең өрөөндүн оюна.Көп ыйлабай, капаланбай көөп кой,Ысык-Көлдүн толкун чачкан боюна.Көр шарпылдап толкундарын таратсын,Толкундары мени карай баратсын.Жүр көрөлү: кыргыздын бир акыныУктап жатат… уктап жатат, деп айтсын…Биздин турмуш, биздин кылым эң кызык,Октор гана оюн кылган жол сызып,Ок күчүнөн жеңип алган өмүрлөр,Чындыгында эң бир ширин, эң ысык.Сен жолдошум, сен кубатым, сен бактым,Ашык болуп издеп жүрүп мен таптым.Колуктумдан мурда сүйүп өзүңдү,Өз жанымдын жармысынан жараттым."},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع دوله لبنان؟","answer":"لبنان هو بلد يقع في جنوب غرب قارة آسيا، ويشكل جزءًا صغيرًا من الشرق الأوسط. إليك بعض المعلومات حول لبنان في سياق قارة آسيا.لبنان هو بلد يتمتع بتاريخ غني وتنوع ثقافي في قلب الشرق الأوسط. يقع على الساحل الشرقي للبحر الأبيض المتوسط، ويحده من الشمال والشرق سوريا، ومن الجنوب فلسطين، ويحده البحر الأبيض المتوسط من الجهة الغربية. يتميز لبنان بتنوع تضاريسه، حيث يرتفع سلسلة جبال لبنان في الشمال والشرق، وتتدفق الوديان الخصبة في وادي البقاع. يشكل لبنان جسرًا ثقافيًا بين العالمين العربي والغربي، حيث تتحد فيه اللغة العربية والفرنسية بانسجام. يواجه لبنان تحديات اقتصادية وسياسية، لكنه يظل مكانًا ساحرًا يستقطب السياح بفضل جمال طبيعته وتاريخه العريق. مدينة بيروت الحديثة تعكس الحياة الحضرية، بينما تحتفظ المدن والقرى التقليدية بسحرها الخاص. إن مطبخ لبنان الشهير يتميز بأطباق لذيذة ومتنوعة، حيث يجتمع النكهات الشرقية باللمسات العالمية. في مجمله، يظل لبنان وجهة فريدة ومذهلة تجمع بين التراث والحداثة في قلب الشرق الأوسط."},{"question":"Misy karazany firy ny matoanteny?","answer":"Ny matoanteny dia azo atao anaty sokajy telo: ny matoantenin' ny mpanao sy ny matoantenin' ny atao, ary ny matoanteny tsy mitongilana. Ny matoantenin' ny mpanao dia mamaritra ny lazaina manao zavatra. Ny matoantenin' ny atao dia mamaritra ny lazaina miaritra na iharan-javatra. "},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： ウクライナでは、ロシアの攻撃で、いろいろな所に地雷が埋められています。これから地雷をどうやってさがしてなくすかが、大きな問題になっています。首都のキーウの近くのブチャでは今年4月から、日本が用意した機械を使って、地雷をさがす訓練を行っています。この機械は、レーダーを使って土の中を調べます。地雷など金属でできた物を見つけると、赤い色で知らせます。物の形もわかります。訓練をしている人は「ウクライナは世界で最も多く地雷が埋められている国の1つです。これからもいろいろな機械が必要です。日本の皆さんからの協力がとても大切です」と話していました。日本はこれから、この機械を50台ぐらい送る予定です。","answer":"ウクライナ　日本の機械を使って地雷をさがす訓練"},{"question":"Oniversitem-panjakana aiza no tsara indrindra eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny oniversite an'Antananarivo no tsara indrindra eto Madagasikara."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Từ Pháp trở về năm 1960, bà đã đến Bộ Giáo dục xin việc và được ưu ái chọn một trong ba trường Đại học Sư phạm Hà Nội, Tổng hợp hoặc Bách Khoa. Bà chọn Đại học Sư phạm Hà Nội. ","answer":"GS Hoàng Xuân Sính từng là chủ nhiệm bộ môn đại số, trưởng khoa Toán-Tin học tại ngôi trường danh giá này."},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：人类学如何研究不同文化的人类与动物关系？","answer":"答案：人类学通过研究不同文化对动物的态度、人类与动物互动方式、动物象征意义等方面来了解其人类与动物关系的文化多样性和社会影响。"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકના એક લેખનના શરૂઆતના ફકરા નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"ભાઈ મારી પાસે અંગ્રેજી શીખવા બેઠા. કહ્યું: “વાંચો; શું છે ?”⁠ભાઈએ વાંચ્યું: “ટહે”⁠મને થયું “આવો શબ્દ અને ઉચ્ચાર અંગ્રેજીમાં તો નથી.” મેં ચોપડી જોઈ. એમાં the(ટી એચ ઈ - ધી) લખેલું હતું.⁠મને થયું. “આ ગણેશ ખોટા બેઠા; ભાઈને અંગ્રેજી બેસે તો બેસે !”⁠પછી મેં એને અંગ્રેજી ભણાવવા માંડ્યું. કેમે કરી બેસે નહિ. અંગ્રેજી કરતી વખતે આંખમાં પાણી આવે. એવો રમતિયાળ અને વિનોદી છોકરો, પણ બદલાઈ જ જાય ! ગરીબ ગાય જેવો ને મરી ગયેલો લાગે.⁠પણ પડતો આખડતો એ અંગ્રેજી ચોથા ધોરણમાં આવ્યો.\\"આ માથાફોડના આગળના ફકરા લખો.","answer":"⁠સાહેબ પધારવાના હતા. છોકરાઓએ રેસિટેશન્સ (Recitations) કરવાના હતાં; ભાઈને પણ ગોખીને બોલવાનું હતું. ભાઈએ તો માંડ્યું ગોખવા; ગોખ્યું, ગોખ્યું, ગોખ્યું !⁠સાહેબ પધાર્યા. રેસિટેશનો થયાં; ભાઈનું કામ ખૂબ વખાણાયું; ઉચ્ચારો (Pronounciations) અને હલક (Intonations) માટે સ્તુતિ પામ્યા; ભાઈને પહેલું ઈનામ મળ્યું. ભાઈ મલક્યા; માસ્તર પણ મલકાયા; ને સાહેબે વીઝીટર્સ બૂકમાં છોકરાના અને શાળાના કામને વખાણ્યું.​⁠આ બધા રાજી થઈને ગયા. આ ભાઈએ ઈનામ મેળવ્યું; માસ્તરનો પગાર વધ્યો; પણ મારું મન ખેદ પામ્યું. મારે માટે તો પરાણે ને માથાઝીક કરીને ભણાવવાનું રહ્યું, ને મારી તો ચિંતા વધી; એમ જ ભાઈની અણાઅવડાત અને અણગમો પણ એ જ રહ્યાં.⁠રેસિટેશનમાં ભાઈ પહેલો આવ્યો પરમ્તુ અંગ્રેજીમાં તો ભાઈ છેલ્લો જ રહ્યો !"},{"question":"Mihodina manodidina ny masoandro ve ny tany?","answer":"Valiny: EnyNy Tany dia mihodidina ny Masoandro indray mandeha isaky ny 365.25 andro, izay mamaritra ny taona iray"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari uku da talatin da bakwai a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 337"},{"question":" શ્રાધ્ધ સ્પેશિયલ ખીર બનાવવાની રીત","answer":"શ્રાધ્ધ સ્પેશિયલ ખીર બનાવવા જરૂરી સામગ્રી4 કપ ફૂલ ક્રીમ દૂધ½ કપ ચોખા¾ કપ ખાંડ8-10 બદામ ની કતરણ10-12 કાજુ ના કટકા1 ચમચી ચિરોંજી / ચારવડી¼ ચમચી એલચી પાઉડર50 ગ્રામ મોરો માવોશ્રાધ્ધ સ્પેશિયલ ખીર બનાવવાની રીત:શ્રાધ્ધ સ્પેશિયલ ખીર બનાવવા સૌપ્રથમ ચોખા ને સાફ કરી બે ત્રણ પાણીથી ધોઈ ને સાફ કરી લ્યો ત્યારબાદ બે ગ્લાસ પાણી નાખી અડધો કલાક પલાળી મુકો. ચોખા પલળી જાય એટલે એનું પાણી નીતરવા ચારણીમાં કાઢી લ્યો.1.\\tહવે કડાઈ માં ફૂલ ક્રીમ દૂધ ને ગરમ કરવા મૂકો. દૂધ ને પહેલા ફૂલ તાપે ગરમ કરવા મૂકો દૂધ થોડું ગરમ થાય એટલે ગેસ મિડીયમ કરીને હલાવતા રહી પાંચ મિનિટ ઉકાળી લ્યો. દૂધ ઉકળી જાય એટલે તેમાં નીતરેલ ચોખા નાખી મિક્સ કરી લ્યો.2.\\tચોખા નાખ્યા પછી પાંચ મિનિટ હલાવતા રહો જેથી ચોખા કડાઈ માં ચોટી ના જાય પાંચ મિનિટ પછી ચોખાને દૂધ સાથે દસ પંદર મિનિટ સુંધી ધીમા તાપે ચડવા દયો અને વચ્ચે વચ્ચે એક બે વખત હલાવતા રહો. પંદર મિનિટ પછીચોખા. બરોબર ચડી ગયા છે એ ચેક કરવા એક બે દાણા ને આંગળી વડે દબાવીને ચેક કરી લ્યો.3.\\tજો ચોખા બરોબર ચડી ગયા હોય તો એમાં ખાંડ, એલચી પાઉડર નાખી ને હલાવી ને ખાંડ ને ઓગળી લ્યો ખાંડ ઓગળી જાય એટલે બીજી પાંચમિનિટ ચડવા દયો જેથી ખાંડ નું પાણી બરી જાય. હવે પાંચ મિનિટ પછીએમાં કાજુ ના કટકા , બદામ ની કતરણ અને ચીરોંજી અને મોરો માવોનાખી મિક્સ કરી ને ધીમા તાપે આઠ દસ મિનિટ ચડવા દયો.4.\\tદસ મિનિટ પછી ગેસ ગેસ બંધ કરી નાખો ને ગરમ ગરમ કે  ઠંડી ઠંડી મજા લ્યો શ્રાધ્ધ સ્પેશિયલ ખીર.નોંધ:1.\\tઅહી ચોખા તમે બાસમતી, રેગ્યુલર અથવા ટુકડા વાપરી શકો છો. પણ જો ટુકડા ચોખાથી બનાવશો તો ખીર વધારે ક્રીમી બનશે કેમ કે એમાં સ્ટર્ચ નું પ્રમાણે વધારે હોય છે.2.\\tમોરો માવો નાખવો ઓપ્શનલ છે.3.\\tડ્રાયફ્રુટ તમે તમારી પસંદ ના નાખી શકો છો.4.\\tખાંડ પણ તમે તમારી પસંદ પ્રમાણે નાખવી."},{"question":"CAAFIMAADKA GUUD?","answer":"Agaasinku waxa uu mas’uul ka yahay hogaaminta isku xidhka iyo qorshaynta geedi socodka cudurada faafa iyo kuwa aan la kala qaadin, oo ay ku jiraan TB, HIV, Malaria, cudurada dayacan ee laga helo wadamadda kulaylaha, Caafimaadka maskaxda, Caafimaadka indhaha, xaaladaha degdega ah iyo ilaalinta, nadaafada iyo barnaamijyada Caafimaadka Bulshada iyo sidoo kale horumarinta Caafimaadka hawlaha dalka,Khariidadeynta helitaanka barnaamijyada la xiriira xarumaha caafimaadka, isbitaallada iyo bulshada, In ay qiimeeyaan oo ay la socdaan tayada adeeg bixinta dalka.Fulinta talooyinka iyo casharrada laga bartay ee la xidhiidha barnaamijyada PH.QAYBAHA WAAXDAHorumarinta CaafimaadkaCaafimaadka DeegaankaXaaladaha Degdega ah ee Caafimaadka DadweynahaKahortagga iyo xakamaynta cudurada faafaCudur Aan Faafin"},{"question":"ஆசாரக்கோவை பற்றி ஒரு பத்தியை எழுதுங்கள்.","answer":"ஆசாரக்கோவை மனித வாழ்க்கைக்கு இன்றியமையாத ஆசாரங்களை அதாவது ஒழுக்கங்களை எடுத்துக்கூறும் ஒரு நூல். ஆசாரம்-ஒழுக்கம், கோவை-அடுக்கிக் கூறுதல். பண்டைக்காலத் தமிழ் நூல்களின் தொகுப்புகளில் ஒன்றான பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கில் ஒன்றாக வைத்து எண்ணப்படும் இஃது ஒரு நீதி நூல். வண்கயத்தூரைச் சேர்ந்த பெருவாயின் முள்ளியார் என்னும் புலவர் இதனை எழுதியவர்.ஆசாரங்கள்:தற்சிறப்புப்பாயிரம் நீங்கலாக, பல்வேறு வெண்பா வகைகளால் அமைந்த 100 பாடல்களால் ஆனது இந்நூல். இந்நூலின் பாக்கள், பத்துப்பாட்டு, சீவக சிந்தாமணி முதலிய இலக்கியங்களின் உரைகளிலும், இலக்கண விளக்கம், நன்னூல், பிரயோக விவேகம் முதலான இலக்கணங்களின் உரைகளிலும், மேற்கோள்களாக வருகின்றன. ஒவ்வொரு பாடலும் ஒவ்வொரு விடயம் தொடர்பான ஒழுக்கத்தை எடுத்து இயம்புகின்றது. இவ்வொழுக்கங்களின் பட்டியல்:1. ஆசார வித்து2. ஒழுக்கம் தவறாதவர் அடையும் நன்மைகள்3. தக்கிணை முதலியவை மேற்கொள்ளல்4. முந்தையோர் கண்ட நெறி5. எச்சிலுடன் தீண்டத் தகாதவை6. எச்சிலுடன் காணக் கூடாதவை7. எச்சில்கள்8. எச்சிலுடன் செய்யக் கூடாதவை9. காலையில் கடவுளை வணங்குக10. நீராட வேண்டிய சமயங்கள்11. பழைமையோர் கண்ட முறைமை12. செய்யாமல் தவிர்க்க வேண்டியவை13. செய்யத் தகாதவை14. நீராடும் முறை15. உடலைப்போல் போற்றத் தக்கவை16. யாவரும் கூறிய நெறி17. நல்லறிவாளர் செயல்18. உணவு உண்ணும் முறைமை19. கால் கழுவிய பின் செய்ய வேண்டியவை20. உண்ணும் விதம்21. ஒழுக்கம் பிழையாதவர் செய்வது22. பிற திசையும் நல்ல23. உண்ணக்கூடாத முறைகள்24. பெரியோருடன் இருந்து உண்ணும் முறை25. கசக்கும் சுவை முதலிய சுவையுடைய பொருள்களை உண்ணும் முறைமை26. உண்ணும் கலங்களைக் கையாளும் முறை27. உண்டபின் செய்ய வேண்டியவை28. நீர் குடிக்கும் முறை29. மாலையில் செய்யக் கூடியவை30. உறங்கும் முறை31. இடையில் செல்லாமை முதலியன32. மலம், சிறுநீர் கழிக்கக்கூடாத இடங்கள்33. மலம் சிறுநீர் கழிக்கும் முறை34. மலம், சிறுநீர் கழிக்கும் திசை35. வாய் அலம்பாத இடங்கள்36. ஒழுக்க மற்றவை37. நரகத்துக்குச் செலுத்துவன38. எண்ணக்கூடாதவை39. தெய்வத்துக்குப் பலியூட்டிய பின் உண்க40. சான்றோர் இயல்பு41. சில செய்யக் கூடியவையும் செய்யக் கூடாதவையும்42. மனைவியைச் சேரும் காலமும் நீங்கும் காலமும்43. உடன் உறைதலுக்கு ஆகாத காலம்44. நாழி முதலியவற்றை வைக்கும் முறை45. பந்தலில் வைக்கத் தகாதவை46. வீட்டைப் பேணும் முறைமை47 நூல் ஓதுவதற்கு ஆகாத காலம்48. அறம் செய்தற்கும் விருந்து அளித்தற்கும் உரிய நாட்கள்49. நடை உடை முதலியவற்றைத் தக்கபடி அமைத்தல்50. கேள்வியுடையவர் செயல்51. தம் உடல் ஒளி விரும்புவார் செய்யத் தக்கவை52. தளராத உள்ளத்தவர் செயல்53. ஒழுக்கமுடையவர் செய்யாதவை54. விருந்தினர்க்குச் செய்யும் சிறப்பு55. அறிஞர் விரும்பாத இடங்கள்56. தவிர்வன சில57. நோய் வேண்டாதவர் செய்யக் கூடாதவை58. ஒருவர் புறப்படும் போது செய்யத் தகாதவை59. சில தீய ஒழுக்கங்கள்60. சான்றோருடன் செல்லும் போது செய்யத் தக்கவை61. நூல்முறை உணர்ந்தவர் துணிவு62. சான்றோர்க்குச் செய்யும் ஒழுக்கம்63. கற்றவர் கண்ட நெறி64, வாழக்கடவர் எனப்படுவர்65. தனித்திருக்கக் கூடாதவர்66. மன்னருடன் பழகும் முறை67. குற்றம் ஆவன68. நல்ல நெறி69. மன்னன் செய்கையில் வெறுப்படையாமை முதலியன70. மன்னன் முன் செய்யத் தகாதவை71. மன்னன் முன் சொல்லக் கூடாதவை72. வணங்கக்கூடாத இடங்கள்73. மன்னர் முன் செய்யத் தகாதவை74. ஆசிரியரிடம் நடக்கும் முறைமை75. சான்றோர் அவையில் செய்யக் கூடாதவை76. சொல்லும் முறைமை77. நல்ல குலப்பெண்டிர் இயல்பு78. மன்னர் அவையில் செய்யக் கூடாதவை79. பெரியோரிடம் உள்ள முச்செயல்கள்80. சான்றோர் பெயர் முதலியவை கூறாமை81. ஆன்றோர் செய்யாதவை82. மனைவியின் உள்ளம் மாறுபடுதல்83. கடைபோக வாழ்வோம் என எண்ணுபவர் மேற்கொள்ள வேண்டியவை84. பழகியவை என இகழத் தகாதவை85. செல்வம் கெடும் வழி86. பெரியவரை உண்டது யாது என வினவக் கூடாது87. கட்டிலில் படுத்திருப்பவருக்குச் செய்யத் தகாதவை88. பெரியோர் போல் வாழ்வோம் என எண்ணுபவர் செய்கைகள்89. கிடைக்காதவற்றை விரும்பாமை90. தலையில் சூடிய மோத்தல்91. பழியாவன92. அந்தணரின் சொல்லைக் கேட்க93. சான்றோர் அவையில் குறும்பு முதலியன செய்யாமை94. ஐயம் இல்லாத அறிவினர் செய்கை95. பொன்னைப் போல் காக்கத் தக்கவை96. எறும்பு முதலியவை போல் செயல் செய்தல்97, சான்றோர் முன் சொல்லும் முறை98. புகக் கூடாத இடங்கள்99. அறிவினர் செய்யாதவை100. ஒழுக்கத்தினின்று விலகியவர்"},{"question":"inona no fomban-drazana mampalaza ny malagasy ary atao na an-kafaliana na an-karatsiana?","answer":"ny kabary no fomban-drazana mampalaza ny malagasy"},{"question":"சிவயோக சுவாமியின் கூறும் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தருக .","answer":" மேற்கோள் :  \\"நீயே உனக்கு நண்பனும் பகைவனும்\\"."},{"question":"السؤال: من قائد معركة حطّين ؟","answer":"الإجابة: صلاح الدين الأيوبي."},{"question":"පරිගනකයේ දෘඩාOග වලට සමීපතම ක්‍රමලේඛ භාෂාව කුමක්ද? ","answer":"පරිගනකයේ දෘඩාOග වලට සමීපතම ක්‍රමලේඛ භාශාව වන්නේ,ඇසෙම්බ්ලි ක්‍රමලේඛ භාශාවයි."},{"question":"競馬場で、レースに出走する馬の下見をする場所のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"パドックです。"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: അതിന്റെ ചലനത്തിലെ മാറ്റങ്ങളെ പ്രതിരോധിക്കുന്ന ഒരു വസ്തുവിന്റെ സ്വത്ത് എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ന്യൂട്ടന്റെ ആദ്യ ചലന നിയമം വിവരിച്ചതുപോലെ, ചലനത്തിലെ മാറ്റങ്ങളെ ചെറുക്കുന്ന ഒരു വസ്തുവിന്റെ സ്വത്തിനെ ജഡത്വം എന്ന് വിളിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Mikä on talvihoitoluokka I?","answer":"Hoitoluokka I(184 km: 0,2 % tiepituudesta, 1 % liikenteestä, 1 % raskaasta liikenteestä)Tie on suurimman osan ajasta paljas. Pyrkimyksenä on hyvä pito, mutta sään muutostilanteissa voi lievää liukkautta esiintyä. Matalia kapeita polannekaistoja ajokaistojen ja ajourien välissä voi ajoittain esiintyä. Pitkinä pakkaskausina, jolloin suolaus ei ole mahdollista, voi tien pinta olla osittain jäinen. Liukkauden ongelmatilanteet pyritään estämään ennakoivasti liukkauden torjunnalla.Hoitoluokka poistuu käytöstä lähivuosina hoitourakoiden kilpailutuksen yhteydessä. I-hoitoluokka siirtyy tyypillisesti Is tai Ib-luokkaan. "},{"question":"Inona avy ireo  inoan' ny Malagasy mandala ny fivavahan-drazana?","answer":"Ireto avy ny zavatra inoan' ny Malagasy mandala ny fivavahan-drazana ho manana ny hasiny: ny sampy, ny ody, ny hazomanga, ny vatolahy, ny karazan-kazo sasany, ny karazam-biby sasany (toy ny omby). Ireto ny zavatra tsy hita maso nefa inoany fisiana: ny Zanahary, ny fanahin' ny razana, ny kalanoro, ny tromba, ny avelo, ny matoatoa. Mba ho fanajana an' ireo fanahy ireo dia manatanteraka fanatitra sy sorona, ny Ntaolo malagasy. Ho fanajana ireo havany efa maty dia manao famadihan-drazana na manao asa lolo ny Malagasy."},{"question":"在加拿大，當你決定「U轉」與否之前，應該先查看？","answer":"交通規則"},{"question":"පැන්ඩෝරා පත‍්‍රිකා හෙළිදරව් කිරිම සිදුකර ඇති සංවිධානය කුමක්ද?","answer":"පැන්ඩෝරා පත‍්‍රිකා හෙළිදරව් කිරිම සිදුකර ඇති සංවිධානය වන්නේ ජාත්‍යන්තර ගවේෂණාත්මක මාධ්‍යවේදීන්ගේ සංවිධානයයි (ICIJ)"},{"question":"第一句: 该机构的总部设在法国巴黎, 海外办公室 - - 运营办公室 - - 设在弗吉尼亚州阿灵顿. 句子2: 该机构的总部设在弗吉尼亚州的阿灵顿, 其海外行动办公室设在法国的巴黎. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"नेपालमा सांस्कृतिक पर्यटनको कस्तो सम्भावना छ ?","answer":"नेपालमा पर्यटन सम्भावनाका महत्त्वपूर्ण क्षेत्रहरूमध्ये एक सांस्कृतिक विविधता हो । विश्वभरका पर्यटकहरू केवल नेपालको प्राकृतिक सौन्दर्य हेर्नका लागि आई रहेका छन् । नेपालको प्राकृतिक विविधताका जानकार विदेशी पर्यटकहरू नेपालको सांस्कृतिक विविधताका बारेमा भने अनभिज्ञ छन् । प्राकृतिक विविधतासँगै त्यस क्षेत्रमा विकसित पृथक् मानवीय चालचलन, संस्कार, भाषा, भेषभुषा, संस्कृतिलाई घुम्न आउने पाहुनाहरूले चासोको साथ लिनु र त्यसबाट मनोरञ्जन, आनन्द लिनु तथा खोजी गर्नुलाई सांस्कृतिक पर्यटन भनिन्छ । सांस्कृतिक पर्यटनले पर्यटकहरूलाई स्थानीय अनुष्ठान र दिनचर्यामा डुबाइदिन्छ, केवल प्राकृतिक सौन्दर्यता मात्र हैन, अनौठा अनुभवहरूको सम्झनाहरू पनि साझेदारी गर्दछ । विविधतामय नेपाली समाजमा सांस्कृतिक विविधता पाइने भएकाले सांस्कृतिक पर्यटनको प्रचुर सम्भावना छ । तसर्थ, हरेक भाषा संस्कृतिको संरक्षण, संवर्द्धन र प्रवर्द्धन गर्न आवश्यक छ । "},{"question":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020","answer":"Àjàkáyé-àrùn èrànkòrónà ọdún 2019-2020 tàbí Àjàkáyé-àrùn COVID-19 ni àjàkáyé-àrùn tí ó ṣẹlẹ̀ ní ààrin ọdún 2019 àti 2020 tí ò ń tàn káàkiri orílẹ̀ èdè gbogbo àgbáyé lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn kòrónà tí ó ń ṣàkóbá fún èémí ọ̀wọ́ kejì (SARS-CoV-2) ló ṣokùnfà àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà. Àgbègbè Wuhan, ní ìlú Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí tí kọ́kọ́ farahàn lóṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, tí ó sìn ti di nǹkan tí àjọ tí ó ń rí sì ètò ìlera ní àgbáyé, World Health Organization tí kéde rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí àrùn pàjáwìrì gbogboògbò lágbàáyé tí wọ́n gbọdọ̀ mójú tó. Titi di ọjọ́ kẹwàá oṣù ó ti ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 118,000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, tí 5,800 nínú wọn jẹ èyí tí wọ́n kà sí pé àrùn náà tí wọ̀ wọ́n lára jù. Ó ti ju orílẹ̀-èdè àádọ́fà (115) tó ti kàgbákó ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún yìí, pàápàá jùlọ àárín gbùngbùn orílẹ̀-èdè China, Italy, South Korea àti Iran. Ó ti ju ènìyàn ìgbàlélẹ́gbẹ̀rúnmẹ́rin, 4,200 tí àrùn yìí ti pa ní ìfọnnáfòṣu, ó tó ènìyàn ọgọ́rùn-ún-lé-lẹ́gbẹ̀ta, (3100) tí wọ́n kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè China nìkan, àti ẹgbẹ̀rún kan ènìyàn káàkiri àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè op kù káàkiri àgbáyé. Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, ó ti ju ènìyàn mẹ́rìnlélọ́gọ́ta ẹgbẹ̀rún (64,000) tí wọ́n ti mórí bọ́ nínú àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí. Ẹ̀rà yìí máa ń ràn láti ara enikan sí ẹlòmíràn nípa èémí ìpọ̀jáde bí a bá ń wúkọ̀ tàbí bí a bá ń sín.Àkókò tí ènìyàn bá kó àrùn yìí àti ìgbà tí ó máa farahàn ma ń sábà máa ń tó Ọjọ́ márùn-ún, ṣùgbọ́n nígbà mìíràn ẹ̀wẹ̀, ó lè tó nǹkan bí ọjọ́ méjì sí mẹ́rìnlá. Àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ sáà a máa ń wá bí, àìsàn ibà, ikọ́ wúwú, àti àìlèmí kánlẹ̀. Ìpeléke àrùn yìí máa ń fà àrùn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró, àti ìnira èémí. Lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ báyìí, àrùn yìí kò gbóògùn kankan. Ṣùgbọ́n ìwádìí ìjìnlẹ̀ ń lọ lórí rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́. Ìgbìyànjú láti mójú tó àwọn àmìn ìfarahàn rẹ̀ ni àwọn oníṣẹ́ ìwòsàn ń ṣe. Àwọn ọ̀nà tí wọ́n là kalẹ̀ láti dẹ́kun àrùn yìí fífọwọ́ déédé, jíjìnnà sí ara ẹni, pàápàá jùlọ ẹni tí ó bá ń ṣàìsàn tàbí fura sí pé wọ́n ní àrùn yìí àti ìyaraẹnisọ́tọ̀ ẹni tí ó fura pé òun ní àrùn yìí.Lára àwọn ọ̀nà ìdẹ́kun mìíràn tí wọ́n ń gbà láti dẹ́kun jíjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí káàkiri àgbáyé ni dídẹ́kun ìrìn-àjò, ìyà sọ́tọ̀ ẹni-afurasí, òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé, àti títi àwọn ilé-ìwé pa. Àwọn ìlú bíi Hubei lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti gbogbo orílẹ̀ èdè Italy ló wà ní ìyàsọ́tọ̀-àmójútó lọ́wọ́ báyìí, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà òfin kónílé-ó-gbélé ń lọ lọ́wọ́ lórílẹ̀ èdè China àti South Korea; bẹ́ẹ̀ náà, àyẹ̀wò fínnífínní ní pápákọ̀-òfuurufú àti ìdíkọ̀ ọkọ̀ ojúrìn;àti ìmọ̀ràn ìrìn-àjò ní ìlú tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí bá ti ń jàkálẹ̀. Ilé-ìwé títìpa pátápátá ní gbogbo orílẹ̀-èdè tàbí àgbègbè tí àrùn yìí ti ṣẹ́yọ ní àwọn orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn, èyí tí ṣe àkóbá fún ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ọ̀ọ́dúnrún mílíọ́nù (300 million) àwọn akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ jákèjádò àgbáyé. Àkóbá ńlá mìíràn tí Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 yìí ni ìfàsẹ́yìn ètò ọ̀rọ̀-aje àti ìbágbépọ̀, bẹ́ẹ̀ náà Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 ti fa ẹlẹ́yàmẹ̀yà àti ìjà-aòfẹ́-ọ-nílùú wá sí àwọn ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè China àti àwọn ọmọ ìran ìlà oòrùn Asia, bákan náà ìròyìn òfegè lórí ìkànnì ayélujára nípa Ìbẹ́sílẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀-àrùn ẹ̀ràn kòrónà lọ́dún 2019-20 àti àwọn aríjẹ-nídìí ìbàjé lórí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà kò gbẹ́yìn.Titi di ọjọ́ Kejìlá oṣù kẹta ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 126000 tí ó ti kó àrùn yìí káàkiri gbogbo àgbáyé, Ìwòye wà pé wọn kò jábọ̀ tó bí àrùn yìí ṣe ń ṣọsẹ́ pàápàá jùlọ àwọn tí àmìn ìfarahàn ṣì ṣẹ̀pẹ̀rẹ̀.Ní àtiparí oṣù Kejìlá lọ́dún 2019, àwọn onímọ̀ ìlera kéde pé àìsàn ẹ̀dọ̀fóró ṣẹ́yọ sí àwọn ènìyàn ní Wuhan, lágbègbè Hubei, lórílẹ̀-èdè China ṣùgbọ́n tí wọn kò mọ ohun tí ó ṣòkùnfà rẹ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí, wọ́n tọpinpin rẹ̀ ọjà kan tí wọ́n ti wọ́n ń pè ní Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market, wọ́n sìn ṣàkíyèsí pé láti ara zoonotic ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí tí ó ń fa àìsàn náà ti ṢẸ̀ wá. Kòkòrò Àìfojúrí yìí tí ó fa àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn ni wọ́n ń pè ní SARS-CoV-2, kòkòrò àìfojúrí tuntun tí ó fara pẹ́ kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà láti ara àdán, pangolin coronaviruses and SARS-CoV. Ìgbàgbọ́ wà pé, ó ṣeé ṣe kí kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí wá láti ara àwọn ẹ̀yà àdán tí wọ́n pè ní Rhinolophus.Àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn yìí kọ́kọ́ ṣẹ́yọ ní Ọjọ́ kìíní Oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2019, láti ara ẹnìkan tí kò dé ọjà oúnjẹ òkun, (Huanan Seafood Wholesale Market) tàbí ní ìbáṣepọ̀ kankan pẹ̀lú àwọn ogójì àwọn mìíràn tí àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́ fihàn pé wọ́n ní kòkòrò àìfojúrí náà. Nínú àyẹ̀wò ọ̀wọ́ àkọ́kọ́, ìpín méjì nínú mẹ́ta ni àyẹ̀wò fihàn pé wọ́n ìbáṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú wet (wet market), tí ó máa ń ẹran lóòyẹ̀.Àjọ ìlera àgbáyé World Health Organization (WHO) kéde àjàkálẹ̀ àìsàn náà gẹ́gẹ́ bí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn gbogboògbò tí ó nílò ìmójútó pàjáwìrì ní ọgbọ̀njọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020. Olùdarí àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, Who, Ọ̀gbẹ́ni Tedros Adhanom, gbóríyìn fún ìjọba orílẹ̀ èdè China fún akitiyan àti ìgbésẹ̀ wọ́n láti rí i pé àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn tí kòkòrò àìfojúrí kòrónà ń fà kò tàn kálẹ̀ ju bó ṣe yẹ lọ lórílẹ̀-èdè naa, bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé ó ń jà rànyìnrànyìn ní àwọn àgbègbè orílẹ̀-èdè mìíràn.Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ pẹ̀pẹ̀ àrùn yìí, iye àwọn ènìyàn tí ó ń lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí tó ìlọ́po méjì láàárín Ọjọ́ méje àti àbọ̀. Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, kòkòrò àìfojúrí yìí ti jàkálẹ̀ dé àwọn àgbègbè China, ọdún Chunyun, tí ó jẹ́ ayẹyẹ àìsùn ọdún tuntun ní China, tí wọ́n ṣe ní ìlú Wuhan lo ṣe àkóbá fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àìsàn yìí, nítorí pé ìlú Wuhan ni ìlú tí ìgbòkègbodò ọkọ́ tí gbòde jù ní China. Àsìkò yìí ni ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ fara kàṣà àrùn náà. Lógúnjọ́ oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020, orílẹ̀-èdè China kéde ogóje ènìyàn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì àrùn yìí lọ́jọ́ kan ṣoṣo, àti ènìyàn méjì mìíràn ní Beijing, pẹ̀lú enikan ní Shenzhen.Lọ́jọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020, àjọ ìlera àgbáyé, WHO kéde ìdí kù nínú àwọn tí ó ń kó àrùn yìí ní China, ṣùgbọ́n tí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn náà gbìnàyá ní orílẹ̀-èdè Italy, Iran àti South Korea. Iye àwọn ènìyàn tuntun tí ó ń kó àrùn náà ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn tí ju ti China lọ.Pínníṣín ni iye àwọn ọmọdé tí àyẹ̀wò ti fihàn pé wọ́n ní àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn yìí títí di ọjọ́ kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù kejì ọdún 2020. Ìkéde kan láti ọwọ́ àjọ ìlera àgbáyé WHO fihàn pé ìdá 2.4 ni àwọn ọmọdé tí ọjọ́ orí wọn kò ju mọ́kàndínlógún lọ ló ní àrùn COVID-19 yìí káàkiri àgbáyé.Iye àwọn tó ti kúLáàárín Ọjọ́ mẹ́fà sí mọ́kànlélógójì, tí àmìn àrùn náà ṣẹ́yọ àti àsìkò tí àrùn COVID-19 hànde ni àwọn tí wọ́n lùgbàdì rẹ̀ ń kú, àgbálògbábọ̀, ọjọ́ mẹ́rìnlá .Titi di ọjọ́ Mẹ́rìnlélogun oṣù kẹjọ ọdún 2020, ó ti ju ènìyàn 800,000 tí àrùn COVID-19 tí pá. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí NHC tí orílẹ̀ èdè China tí sọ, àgbàlagbà ni ó pọ̀jù nínú àwọn tí àrùn náà pa. Ó tó ìdá ọgọ́rin, 80% àwọn àgbàlagbà tí ọjọ́-orí ti kọjá ọgọ́ta tó kú, àti ìdá márùndínlọ́gọ́rin àwọn tí wọ́n ti ní àìsàn mìíràn lára tẹ́lẹ̀, pàápàá jùlọ àìsàn ọkàn, cardiovascular diseases àti itọ̀ ṣúgà, diabetes.Ẹni àkọ́kọ́ tí àìsàn yìí pa kú lọ́jọ́ kẹsàn-án oṣù kìíní ọdún 2020 ní ìlú Wuhan. Ẹlòmíràn tó kú ní orílẹ̀ èdè mìíràn yàtọ̀ sí China kú ní orílẹ̀-èdè Philippines, ẹlòmíràn tí ó tún kú, tí kì í ṣe láti ilẹ̀ Asia kú ní Faransé. Lẹ́yìn China, ó ti ju ènìyàn méjìlá. Mẹ́jìlá lọ tí wọ́n ti kú ní Iran, South Korea, àti Italy. Bákan náà, ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ènìyàn ìròyìn tí fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ pé wọ́n tí kú ikú àrùn kòrónà apá àríwá Amẹ́ríkà (North America), Australia, San Marino, Spain, Iraq, àti United Kingdom. Ìwé ìròyìn Daily NK jábọ̀ pé àwọn ọmọ-ogun tó ti ju igba (200) ni àrùn kòrónà ti pa lórílẹ̀-èdè North Korea."},{"question":"برای خرید ظروف و لوازم خانگی در تهران به کجا می‌توانم مراجعه کنم؟","answer":"بازار لوازم خانگی شوش یکی از بهترین مراکز خرید تهران برای خرید لوازم خانگی است و انواع ظروف آشپزخانه از برندهای داخلی و خارجی را عرضه می‌کند. از ویژگی‌های مهم و شناخته شده بازار شوش این است که هر کسی با هر میزان بودجه‌ای که دارد می‌تواند به آن مراجعه کند و بهترین و باکیفیت‌ترین محصولات را انتخاب کند. بازار لوازم خانگی شریعتی یکی دیگر از بهترین مراکز خرید تهران برای خرید لوازم خانگی است. "},{"question":"සමාජය හා ආර්ථිකය කෙරෙහි තොරතුරු හා සන්නිවේදන තාක්ෂණයේ බලපෑම ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"සමාජීය ප්‍රතිලාභවිනෝදාස්වාදය සඳහා විවිධ ක්‍රම බිහිවීම.(3D technology, කාටුන්, සමරූපන ක්‍රීඩා (Simulation games), හොලෝග්‍රැෆික් ප්‍රතිබිම්බ තාක්ෂණය (holographic image processing), මාර්ගගත ක්‍රීඩා (Online games))මිතුරන් සමඟ කතාබහ කිරීමට විවිධ ක්‍රම බිහිවීම. (whatsapp, Viber, skype)විශ්ව ගමිමාන සංකල්පය ඇති වීම.ආර්ථික ප්‍රතිලාභනිෂ්පාදන ඵලදායීතාව, ආර්ථික ඵලදායිතාව, ශ්‍රම ඵලදායීතාව වැඩිවීම නිසා ආර්ථික ඵලදායීතාව ඉහළ යාම. ( නව රැකියා බිහිවීම)ඕනෑම වේලාවක, ඕනෑම තැනක සිට තොරතුරු ප්‍රවේශනය කර ගැනීමේ හැකියාව."},{"question":"Berikan maklumat tentang buku yang bertajuk Atas Nama Kasih. ","answer":"Di bawah adalah maklumat mengenai buku bertajuk Atas Nama Kasih:Tajuk : Atas Nama KasihPenulis : Salina IbrahimPenerbit : Creative EnterpriseSinopsis Belakang Buku:Nur Kasih, ini adalah buah hatiku. Yang selama ini memberiku kekuatan untuk menghadapi hari-hari depan yang lebih gemilang. Memberikan nyawa - tragedi hitam sering-seringnya bertebaran dan bersipongan di setiap penjuru kenangan. Melumpuhkan impian dan cita-cita. Bersama duka dan air mata. Nur Kasih ini adalah waris tunggal yang perlu dipertahankan. Dan si kecil itu, Suria melampias resah yang meruntun segenap keinginan yang telah sekian lama Suria lupakan.Nur Kasih idamkan kehadiran seorang lelaki bergelar bapa. Lalu diceruk mana Suria harus mencari lelaki impian Nur Kasih itu? Lelaki mana yang sudi beristerikan gadis beranak satu sepertinya? Berkecil hati Nur Kasih, kecil lagi hati seorang Suria bila mana lelaki impian bakal tunangan orang. Lalu Suria membiarkan jodohnya ditentukan Nur Kasih. Kerana Suria percaya ... seorang bapa yang baik, adalah suami yang terbaik untuk dirinya..."},{"question":"кайсы кен батыш тарапта жайгашкан, Камларен же Жоголгон лимон кениби?","answer":"Камларен кени"},{"question":"How do traditional \\"Koraweema\\" farming methods contribute to sustainability?","answer":"Sri Lanka's traditional \\"Koraweema\\" or organic farming methods have a positive impact by emphasizing sustainability and environmental harmony. These practices prioritize organic and natural cultivation techniques, promoting soil health, preserving biodiversity, and ensuring the production of nutritious and environmentally friendly agricultural products."},{"question":"Magbigay ng halimbawa ng for loop sa Python upang ipakita ang even numbers mula 0 hanggang 10.","answer":"Pinapakita ng sumusunod na for loop sa Python ang even numbers mula 0 hanggang 10:for i in range(0, 11, 2):    print(i)"},{"question":"भारत आणि श्रीलंका यांच्यात खालीलपैकी कोणते बेट आहे?(A) गंगासागर(B) रामेश्वरम(C) नवीन मूर(D) लक्षद्वीप=> ","answer":"(B) रामेश्वरम"},{"question":"Inona no teoria ara-toekarena milaza fa ny mpiasa dia tokony hokaramaina araka ny anjara birikiny amin'ny famokarana?1-Teoria fanonerana ara-drariny2-Teoria karama farany ambany3-Ny teoria momba ny karama mahomby","answer":"Valiny: 3. Teoria momba ny karama mahomby"},{"question":"问：YouTube如何赚钱？","answer":"答：YouTube主要通过广告收入来盈利，包括视频前插广告、视频内嵌广告等。此外，YouTube还通过会员服务、超级聊天等功能获得收入。"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:వ. మఱియు రామచంద్రుండు త్రిజగదేక వీరుండును గోదండ దీక్షా గురుండునురాక్షసకులాంతకుండును నగుటంజేసి రాణి వాసలోహియగు రావణునిసంగరరంగంబునఁ బ్రఖ్యాతంబుగాఁ జంపి కొనిపోవుట ధర్మంబు; నీవురామచంద్రునకుఁబరమ భృత్యుండవును బుత్ర సముండవును నగుటంచేసి నీవెంట నరుగు దెంచుట తప్పు గాకబోయినను బగతీర్చక వచ్చు టుచితంబుగాదుకావు రాఘవేశ్వరుల కిన్నియుం దెలియ విన్నపంబు సేసి తడయక తోడ్కొనిరమ్మనిన నద్దేవికి నమస్కరించి హనుమంతుండిట్లనియె.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :మఱియున్ = అంతేకాక,రామచంద్రుండు = చంద్రుని వంటి శ్రీరాముడుత్రిజగత్ = ముల్లోకాలలోఏక = ముఖ్య మైనవీరుండును = శూరుడునూకోదండ = వింటి యొక్క (కోదండము అనే పేరుగల విల్లు యొక్క)దీక్షా = మంత్రోపదేశమునగురుండును = గొప్పవాడునూరాక్షసకుల = రాక్షస వంశానికిఅంతకుండును = యముడునూ (నాశకుడును)అగుటం జేసి (అగుటన్ + చేసి) = కావడం చేతరాణివాస = భార్య విషయమైద్రోహి + అగు = ద్రోహము చేసిన వాడైనరావణుని = రావణాసురునిసంగరరంగంబునన్ = యుద్ధరంగమందుప్రఖ్యాతంబుగాన్ = మిక్కిలి ప్రసిద్ధికలుగునట్లుగాచంపి = చంపికొనిపోవుట . : తీసుకొని వెళ్ళడంధర్మంబు = ధర్మమునీవు = నీవురామచంద్రునకున్ = శ్రీరామునికిపరమ = ముఖ్య మైనభృత్యుండవును = సేవకుడవునూపుత్ర = కుమారుడితోసముండవును = సమానమైన వాడవునూఅగుటంజేసి (అగుటన్ + చేసి) = కావడం చేతనీ వెంటన్ = నీ వెనుక (నీ వీపుపై కూర్చుండి)అరుగుదెంచుట = వచ్చుటతప్పు + కాకపోయినను = తప్పుకాదు కాని,పగతీర్పక = శత్రుత్వాన్ని ప్రతీకారముచే తీర్చకుండావచ్చుట = నీ వెంట రావడంఉచితంబు + కాదు = తగినది కాదుకావునన్ = కాబట్టినీవు = నీవురాఘవ = రఘువంశమువాడయినశ్వరులకున్ = ప్రభువులైన శ్రీరామచంద్రునికిఇన్నియున్ = ఈ సంగతులు అన్నితెలియన్ = తెలిసేటట్లువిన్నపంబు సి (విన్నపంబు + చేసి) = విన్నవించి చెప్పితడయక = ఆలస్యం చేయకుండాతోడ్కొని రమ్ము = ఆయనను నీవెంటబెట్టుకొని రమ్ముఅనినన్ = అని సీతమ్మ హనుమంతునికి చెప్పగాఅదేవికిన్ = ఆ సీతమ్మ తల్లికినమస్కరించి = వందనము చేసిహనుమంతుండు = ఆంజనేయుడుఇట్లనియె(ఇట్లు + అనియె) = ఇలా చెప్పాడుతాత్పర్యం :రాముడు, ముల్లోకాలలో మహావీరుడు, కోదండ దీక్షను పొందిన ఘనుడు. రాక్షసవంశ నాశకుడు. అందువల్ల తన భార్య విషయంలో ద్రోహం చేసిన రావణుని యుద్ధరంగంలో కీర్తి కలిగేట్లు చంపి, నన్ను తీసికొని వెళ్ళడం ధర్మము, నీవు శ్రీరామచంద్రునకు ముఖ్య సేవకుడవు. పుత్రునితో సమానుడవు. అందువల్ల నీతో రావడం తప్పు కాకపోయినా, పగ తీర్చకుండా రావడం మాత్రం ఉచితం కాదు. కాబట్టి నీవు శ్రీరామ ప్రభువునకు ఈ విషయాలు అన్నీ చెప్పి, ఆలస్యము చేయకుండా వెంటబెట్టుకొని రా” అని చెప్పగా, సీతకు నమస్కరించి, హనుమంతుడు ఇలా చెప్పాడు."},{"question":"Imagina que és um astronauta a descrever a vista da Terra do Espaço. ","answer":"Olhei pela janela da cápsula, e senti o ar preso no peito. Nunca na minha vida houvera visto tal beleza. A Terra, suspensa na vastidão negra do vazio, brilhava como mármore azul. Fios de nuvens brancas dançavam pelos continentes, fazendo-me contemplar o quanto tudo está interligado no nosso frágil ecossistema. "},{"question":"Iza no mpandinika nilaza hoe \\"Ny fahafahana dia ny zon’ny olona iray hanaja ny fahafahan’ny hafa.\\"","answer":"I Berchmans RAHELISON no nilaza an'io."},{"question":" गिधा आणि भांगडा कोणत्या राज्याचे लोकनृत्य आहेत?उत्तर : ","answer":"पंजाब"},{"question":"Siyabonana bab' uDlamini.Yebo siyabonana Ndlovukazi.Ninjani kodwa Mzizi?Siyaphila Ndlovukazi, yizwe nje elidunguzelayo.(ahambe aqonde emnyango) Hhayi-ke, salani madoda nizozibhungakahle! (aphume)Ufika nje siyaxoxa noMaNgema. Njengoba uthi izwe liyadunguzela nje,ngempela ushaye khona ngoba intando yeningi iyalidunguzelisa.Lisho uliphinde Ndabezitha. Selokhu kwavotwa nje sekukhona abantuasebekhulekela lo mfokazana wakwaDuma. Naye impela usehambaaqholoshe kuhle kwekhonde elihola umhlambi wezimfene.(ehleka) Wo! Wo! Dlamini, labo abamkhulekelayo yizimfene. Ushokahle uma uthi uqholosha kuhle kwekhonde.Ndabezitha, ungalingi uyivumele le nto. Phela inkosi yethu nguwe.Noma ngabe nguhulumeni ongumnikazi walo mthetho kodwa abantulaba ngabakho. Futhi-ke nje abantu abaningi bathi bazi wenaNdabezitha.(Aneke izandla) Angithi uma sekuvotiwe kuthiwa abantusebekhulumile.Nabantu bakho bazokhuluma. Futhi-ke bayakhuluma kumanje. Bathibayoke babone ngoba ngeke bona balandelane nesilima esingathishu. UDuma akayihole le mali yakhe kodwa angalingi acabangenjengoba ecabanga.(ubuso bugcwale ukumangala) Ucabangani uDuma we Dlamini?(naye abonakale ehwaqabala ebusweni) Abakhulumayo bathi uDumauthi nguye okhethwe ngabantu futhi kuyokhala esakhe isicathulo kulendawo.1. Ngokubona kwakho ukuziphatha/indlela enza ngayo izinto uMazongoloyamukelekile yini kuwena. Sekela impendulo yakho ngamaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo:Yamukelekile• UMazongolo ungumfundisi owenza imizamo yokwenza uxolo kulendawo. • Akahluleli muntu kulaba bantu ababehamba phambili kule ngxabano.• Nguyena owayengusihlalo womhlangano wokudala uxolo. "},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 富山県魚津市はベニズワイガニがたくさんとれます。魚津市は、みんなにカニを食べに来てもらうため、安く食べることができるイベントを開きました。18日は、イベントが始まる前から大勢の人が会場に並びました。カニは300匹用意しました。値段は1匹1000円です。来た人たちは、ゆでたばかりのカニをおいしそうに食べていました。30歳の男の人は「こんなに大きいカニを食べることができたので、並んでよかったです」と話しました。小学校2年生の男の子は「とれたばかりのような味でおいしいです」と笑って話しました。イベントは3月5日までの土曜日と日曜日などに開く予定です。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo karazana fahafahana mety hanan'ny olona?","answer":"Ireo karazana fahafahana mety hanan'ny olona dia:-Fahafahana maneho ny maha izy azy ny tena eo amin’ny kolontsaina: manana ny rafi-pisainana mandrafitra sy mamolavola azy ny olona amin’ny faritra tsirairay. Tsy azo tsaraina ny kolon-tsaina isam-paritra fa mandrindra ny fiaraha-monina izy ireny.-Fahafahana mitantana toe-draharaha rehetra ao amin’ny sokajim-piarahamonina ary mioty manontolo ny mety ho vokany: avy amin’ny vahoaka avokoa ny mpitantana rehetra ao anaty fokontany, ny firaisana, ny fivondronana, ny faritra, ary ny firenena.  Avy amin’ny safidin’ny vahoaka izany ny vokatry ny asan’ireo olona nomeny andraikitra ireo ka tsy azo anomezan-tsiny  an’iza na iza.-Fahafahana mifidy: mamela ny tsirairay haneho ny safidiny malalaka amin’ny fifidianana,  rehefa feno 18 taona, ankoatra ireo very zo.-Fahafahana hiteny na haneho hevitra: tokony halalaka ny fanehoana-kevitra saingy tokony hahay hihaino sy hahay handray ny hevitry ny hafa ny olona mba tena hisy io fahafahana io.-Fahafahana mivezivezy any amin’ny faritra tiana haleha: tokony hanaja ny soatoavin’ny faritra na Firenena tiany hidirany anefa ny tsirairay.-Fahafahana mitondra fikambanana avy amin’ny hosotra samihafa: fahasoavana avy amin’Andriamanitra, avy amin’ny mari-pahaizana na traikefa."},{"question":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh?Astaanta 4aad.","answer":"Imaamu maxamed bin sheybaani. Imaamka la yiraahdo Maxamed bin xasan alshaybaani waqtigiisa wuxuu u qaybiyay sadex qaybood oo kala ah xili uu seexanaayo , xili uu tukanaayo oo cibaadaysanaayo , xili uu waxbaranaayo, waxaa la yiraahdaa dadaalka uu waxbarashada iyo cilmiga ku dadaalaayo waxay ka gaartay inuu waayo waqti xattaa uu dharkiisa ku dhaaqdo isagoo ahaa nin aad u xarago badan, waxaa la yiraahdaa habeenkii wax yar ayuu ka seexan jiray markii la waydiiyay oo lagu yiri maxaa u seexan wayday ? wuxuu ku jawaabi  jirey  sidee u seexdaa iyadoo ummada dhan isugayso, dadkii waa seexdeen waxayna isku haleeyeen aniga oo waxay is dhaheen wixii aad diinta uga baahataan Maxamed Bin Xasan ayaan waydiinaynaa. Hore ayaa waxaa loo yiri '' nin lagu seexdow ha seexan '' nin dadka oo dhan sugayaan ma hurdaa u muuqata ? nin ummadiisu isku halaynayso miyaa hurdo qabataa ? nin  dadku fiirsanayaan oo tusaale u ah miyaa siduurabo iskaga seexda ?. Imaamu maxamed bin salaam albiikandii. Imaamka layiraahdo Maxamed bin salaam albiikandii wuxuun ahaa sheekhii imaamu bukhaari, ayaa maalin isagoo fadhiya gole cilmiga lagu yeersanaayo ayaa waxaa ka jabay qalinkiisii, markaas ayuu dhawaaqay oo yiri '' yaa hal diinaar qalin igaga iibsanaaya '' markaas ayaa dad badan qalimadoodii kusoo tuureen iyagoo ka rajaqaba inay hal qalin ku helaan hal Diinaar !!! hadde halka diinaar wuxuu u dhigmaa hal Garaam oo dahab ah . Imaamkan wuxuu yiri isagoo naftiisa ka sheekaynaaya :- 400 oo sheekh ayaan xadiiska ka bartay, cilmiga dalabkiisana waxaan ku bixiyay 40 kun oo diinaar, fidintiisa iyo gaarsiinta ummadana waxaan ku bixiyay 40 kun diinaar, waxaan xifdisanahay shankun oo xadiis. Allaahu akbar bal ila fiirsha imaankan hanka ku jira iyo sida uu cilmiga raadintiisa iyo baridiisaba ugu hagarbaxay !!!. "},{"question":"ඉන්දියාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රටක් ද?","answer":"ඔව්, ඉන්දියාව ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී රටක්. එය ලොව විශාලතම ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය වන අතර ෆෙඩරල් පාර්ලිමේන්තු ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදී ජනරජයක් ලෙස ක්‍රියාත්මක වේ. ඉන්දියාවේ දේශපාලන ක්‍රමය පදනම් වී ඇත්තේ 1950 දී සම්මත කරන ලද ඉන්දීය ආණ්ඩුක්‍රම ව්‍යවස්ථාව මතය. ඉන්දියාවේ ජනාධිපතිවරයා රාජ්‍ය නායකයා වන අතර අගමැති රජයේ ප්‍රධානියා වේ. මධ්‍යම, ප්‍රාන්ත සහ ප්‍රාදේශීය මට්ටම්වලට බෙදී ඇති අධිකාරිය සහිත බහු-ස්ථර පාලන ක්‍රමයක් රටෙහි ඇත. ඉන්දියාවේ ප්‍රජාතන්ත්‍රවාදය සංලක්ෂිත වන්නේ සර්වජන ඡන්ද බලයේ ක්‍රමයක් වන අතර, පුරවැසියන්ට ඡන්දය ප්‍රකාශ කිරීමට සහ පාර්ලිමේන්තුවට සහ විවිධ ප්‍රාන්ත ව්‍යවස්ථාදායකයන්ට තම නියෝජිතයන් තෝරා පත් කර ගැනීමට අයිතිය ඇත."},{"question":"Sino ang pambansang bayani ng Pilipinas?","answer":"Si Jose Rizal ang pambansang bayani ng Pilipinas. Ang buong pangalan niya ay Jose Protasio Rizal Mercado y Alonso Realonda. Kilala siya sa kanyang dalawang nobela na Noli Me Tángere na inilabas noong 1887 at El filibusterismo na inilabas noong 1891. Kanyang pinaglaban ang kalayaan ng Pilipinas sa pamamagitan ng kanyang pagsusulat kaysa sa pandirigma. Sa kayang mga nobela, mararamdaman ang pagmamahal niya sa bayan kung saan handa siyang mamatay para sa sariling bayan. Nakatulong ang kanyang mga nobela sa pagpupukaw ng damdaming makabayan at sa pagmumulat ng mga pang-aabuso ng mga Kastila sa kanyang mga kababayan."},{"question":"సిరగంపుట్టు ఆంధ్ర ప్రదేశ్ రాష్ట్రం, విశాఖపట్నం జిల్లా, ముంచంగిపుట్టు మండలంలోని గ్రామం. ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన ముంచంగిపుట్టు నుండి 23 కి.మీ. దూరం లోను, సమీప పట్టణమైన అనకాపల్లి నుండి 126 కి.మీ. దూరంలోనూ ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 30 ఇళ్లతో, 93 జనాభాతో 144 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 51, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 42. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 0 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 90. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 583493[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 531040.","answer":"సిరగంపుత్తు-3 (ముంచంగిపుట్టు)"},{"question":"Wọn ṣi n wa awọn ọmọ ṣọọṣi Ridiimu mẹjọ to ha sọwọ awọn agbebọn ni Kaduna","answer":"Awọn janduku agbebọn ti wọn n da awọn ara Oke-Ọya laamu tun ti sọko ibanujẹ wọn, lọtẹ yii, mẹjọ lara awọn ọmọ ijọ Ridiimu to wa ni Kaduna ni wọn ji gbe lalẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, wọn ti ko wọn wọgbo lọ.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, nnkan bii aago meje alẹ niṣẹlẹ naa waye, bọọsi kan lawọn eeyan naa wọ, wọn n rin irinajo lati lọọ ṣe ipalẹmọ eto isin ọdun Ajinde to n bọ lọna, lawọn agbebọn naa fi rẹbuu ọkọ wọn loju ọna marosẹ Kachia, ti wọn si ji wọn gbe.Wọn ni lati ṣọọṣi Redeemed Christian Church of God, to wa ni adugbo Region 30, lagbegbe Trinity Sanctuary, niluu Kaduna, ni wọn lawọn olujọsin naa ti gbera, wọn si ti rin irinajo to to kilomita mẹtalelọgọta ki wọn too bọ sọwọ awọn kọlọransi agbebọn yii.Ẹnikan to mọ nipa iṣẹlẹ ọhun, Eje Faraday, toun naa jẹ ọmọ ijọ ọhun, lo kede iṣẹlẹ yii lori atẹ fesibuuku rẹ pẹlu aworan bọọsi funfun tawọn janduku naa ṣakọlu si.O ni, ‘Ẹ gba wa o, mẹjọ lawọn ọmọ ṣọọṣi wa to wa ninu bọọsi ti wọn n gbe lọ siluu Kaicha, wọn fẹẹ lọọ mura silẹ fun eto ijere-ọkan ta a maa n ṣe lasiko ajọdun Ajinde ni o, awọn janduku ti da wọn lọna, wọn ja wọn bọọlẹ, wọn ko wọn sinu ọkọ tiwọn, wọn si ti wa wọn wọgbo lọ, ẹnikan o mọ’bi ti wọn wa bayii o.Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kaduna, Muhammad Jalige, ti fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ. O lawọn ṣi n ṣe iwadii lati mọ hulẹhulẹ nipa ọrọ naa, awọn o si ti i gbọ ipe kan lati ọdọ awọn ajinigbe naa tabi awọn ọmọ ṣọọṣi ti wọn ji gbe."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: \\"Ngày này năm xưa MU chiêu mộ ngôi sao từ Tottenham\\".","answer":"Ngày 31/7/2006, MU chính thức công bố bản hợp đồng mang tên Michael Carrick từ Tottenham. Để có được chữ ký của tiền vệ này, MU đã phải bỏ ra 18,6 triệu Bảng, chứ không phải 15 triệu Bảng như dự báo lúc ban đầu. Đó là khoản tiền khá lớn ở thời điểm ấy. Trước khi đến với MU, phong độ chói sáng của Carrick đã giúp Tottenham thi đấu rất thành công, cạnh tranh sòng phẳng suất dự Cúp C1 châu Âu với Arsenal cho đến những vòng đấu cuối cùng. Thương vụ chiêu mộ Carrick là một trong những bản hợp đồng thành công của MU. Sau khi đến với sân Old Trafford, Carrick đã thể hiện tầm quan trọng và giúp đội bóng thành Manchester lên ngôi vô địch Ngoại hạng Anh 2006/2007. MU cũng chính là bến đỗ cuối cùng trong sự nghiệp của Carrick khi danh thủ sinh năm 1981 có tổng cộng 12 năm gắn bó với Quỷ đỏ trên tư cách cầu thủ. Carrick đã có tất cả 464 lần ra sân cho MU và ghi được 24 bàn thắng. Cùng với MU, Carrick có tất cả 17 danh hiệu lớn nhỏ, trong đó có 5 Ngoại hạng Anh. Sau khi giải nghệ, Carrick tiếp tục gắn bó với Quỷ đỏ trong tư cách thành viên ban huấn luyện. Thậm chí sau khi Ole Gunnar Solskjær bị sa thải, Carrick đã có 3 trận làm HLV tạm quyền của MU với thành tích bất bại."},{"question":"Баатыр дордок деген эмне? ","answer":"Аңчылыкка тиешелүү сөз.  Тумшугу ичин көздөй имерилип турган бүркүттүн бир түрү."},{"question":" د حاضری د کتاب په برخه کی معلومات ورکړی ؟","answer":"ځواب : د حاضری کتاب هغه سند دی چی د کارمند موجودیت یا شتوالی د کار په معینو او ټاکلو وختونو کی تثبیتوی ."},{"question":"\\" සිංහල බෝධිවංශය \\" කෘතිය අයත්වන , සාහිත්‍ය යුගය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"කුරුණෑගල යුගය"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو أول شهيد في الإسلام؟","answer":"الإجابة: سمية بنت خباط زوجة ياسر بن عامر"},{"question":"కింది కర్తరి వాక్యాలను కర్మణి వాక్యాలుగా రాయండి.నేనెన్నో పుస్తకాలు రాశాను.","answer":"ఎన్నో పుస్తకాలు నాచేత రాయబడ్డాయి."},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa: Bidiyon Ku San Malamanku tare da Sheikh Dr Jabir Sani Maihula","answer":"Ku latsa hoton da ke sama don kallon bidiyon: An haifi Sheikh Jabir Sani Maihula ranar Juma'a 3 ga watan Yulin shekarar 1981 a garin Sifawa da ke jihar Sokoto. Ya fara karatun addini wajen mahaifi da mahaifiyarsa a gida na Fiƙihun Malikiyya da Iziyya da Ahalari, sannan ya halarci makarantar addini da ke cikin gidansu inda ya karanci Ƙur'ani da Hadisi. Ya kuma halarci makarantar soro wajen Malam Ibrahim Auro. Ya yi makarantar firamare a Sokoto sai sakandare ta Kwalejin Fasaha ta Rinjin Sokoto. Bayan nan sai ya samu gurbin yin digiri A Madina a shekarar 1999, amma sai da ya fara koyon Larabci na tsawon shekara ɗaya. A lokacin shi ne ɗalibi mafi ƙarancin shekaru Najeriya."},{"question":"وجدت هذا السؤال: ما هي عاصمة اليابان ؟ في موقع ثقافي ، ماهي الإجابة؟","answer":"الإجابة على السؤال هي طوكيو و تعتبر من بين اكبر العواصم في العالم, جد متقدمه من حيث البنيات التحتيه وتوجد وسط البلد على المحيط الهادي."},{"question":"Em que ano os Beatles foram primeiro aos EUA?","answer":"1964"},{"question":"Que língua é falada na Espanha?","answer":"A Espanha é um país multilíngue e tem o castelhano como idioma oficial em nível nacional. O castelhano é usualmente chamado \\"espanhol\\" internacionalmente. Contudo, a Espanha tem várias outras línguas cooficiais regionalmente: catalão, valenciano, galego, basco e aranês."},{"question":"Quais foram as principais contribuições de Karl Marx para a filosofia?","answer":"Marx foi um dos principais pensadores do socialismo e do comunismo, coautor do \\"Manifesto Comunista\\" e autor de \\"O Capital\\", onde desenvolveu a teoria da luta de classes."},{"question":"කනත්ත යනු සුසාන භූමියට සමාන පදයක් නොවන බවත්, බොරැල්ලේ කනත්ත හන්දියේ පොදු සුසාන භූමිය පිහිටා තිබීම හේතුවෙන් එම වචනය අද සුසාන භුමියේ අර්ථයෙන් භාවිත බව බවත් අසා ඇත. මෙහි සත්‍ය අසත්‍යතාව විමසන්න. කනත්ත අතීතයේ සුසාන භූමිය අදහසින් යොදා ඇත් ද?","answer":"කනත්ත යනු බොරැල්ලේ සුසානභූමියට කියන නාමයයි. එය හරියට රෙදි සෝදන සබන් වලට අපි සන්ලයිට් කැටයක් කියා ව හරටා  එක්වී ඇති අකාරයට එයද සුසානභූමියටද පර්‍යාය නාමයක් ලෙස වහරේ පවති. මහනුවර සුසානභූමිය මහයියාව ග්‍රාමයේ පිහිටියත් මහයියාව යනුවෙන් වැඩිදෙනෙක් යොදන්නේ සුසානභූමියටයි"},{"question":"Taipei mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Taipei mooy gëblag réewum Taïwan."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai puyu di air jernih\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud perihal orang yang senang kehidupannya."},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් පට මල්ල  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කට පළල් උසින් අඩු පං මල්ල"},{"question":"જે. કોલેનું જીવનચરિત્ર લખો .","answer":"જે. કોલેનું જીવનચરિત્રજે. કોલે એક અમેરિકન રેપર, ગાયક, ગીતકાર અને નિર્માતા છે, જે તેમના ભાવનાપૂર્ણ અને વિચારશીલ ગીતો માટે જાણીતા છે. તેઓએ ઘણી સફળ રેકોર્ડિંગ્ઝ બહાર પાડી છે અને વિશ્વભરમાં લાખો લોકોને પ્રેરિત કર્યા છે.પ્રારંભિક જીવનજે. કોલનો જન્મ 28 જાન્યુઆરી 1985ના રોજ ફ્રન્ટ રોયાલ, ન્યૂ જર્સીમાં થયો હતો. તેમના પિતા, રોબર્ટ ફોર્ટ, એક સ્થાનિક રેડિયો શો હોસ્ટ હતા અને તેમની માતા, કાર્મેન ડેવિસ, એક શિક્ષક હતા. જે. કોલેએ તેમના નાના ભાઈ, ઝેડને, સાથે ઉછર્યા.કારકિર્દીજે. કોલેએ તેમનું સંગીત કારકિર્દી 2007માં શરૂ કર્યું હતું, તેમના ગીત \\"The Come Up\\" ને યુટ્યુબ પર અપલોડ કરીને. તેમણે 2009માં તેમનું પહેલું મેક્ડ્રીમ રેકોર્ડ્સ EP, \\"The Come Up\\", બહાર પાડ્યું. તેમના બીજા EP, \\"Friday Night Lights\\", 2010માં બહાર પડ્યું અને તેને ખૂબ જ સારી રીતે ટીકાકારો દ્વારા સ્વીકારવામાં આવ્યું. તેમના ત્રીજા EP, \\"Born Sinner\\", 2013માં બહાર પડ્યું અને તે આલ્બમે તેમને વ્યાવસાયિક સફળતા અપાવી.જે. કોલેએ ઘણી સફળ એલબમ્સ બહાર પાડી છે, જેમ કે \\"2014 Forest Hills Drive\\", \\"4 Your Eyez Only\\", અને \\"KOD\\". તેમણે 5 ગ્રેમી એવોર્ડ્સ જીત્યા છે અને તેઓ 20 વખત ગ્રેમી માટે નોમિનેટ થયા છે.પ્રેરણા અને સફળતાજે. કોલેને તેમના પિતા અને નાના ભાઈ, ઝેડ, દ્વારા ખૂબ પ્રેરણા આપવામાં આવી છે. તેઓએ તેમના ગીતોમાં તેમની પ્રેરણા વ્યક્ત કરી છે. જે. કોલેની સફળતા તેમની સખત મહેનત, પ્રતિભા, અને લોકો સાથે જોડાવાની તેમની ક્ષમતાને આભારી છે.સ્વીકૃતિજે. કોલેને તેમના કાર્ય માટે ઘણી ખ્યાતિ અને સન્માન મળ્યા છે. તેમણે 5 ગ્રેમી એવોર્ડ્સ જીત્યા છે અને તેઓ 20 વખત ગ્રેમી માટે નોમિનેટ થયા છે. તેઓ વર્લ્ડ ડિઝની પાર્ક્સ અને રજાઓના પ્રેસિડેન્ટના રાઉન્ડ ટેબલના સભ્ય છે અને તેઓ ઘણી સં"},{"question":"📚 Манас эпосундагыАлтын-Көлдөгү алп арчанын түбүндөгү жан адамга көрүнбөгөн мүрөктүн суусун ким Чыйырдыга эмне үчүн берди?а) Байдалы Манаска ичиргенге б) Жакып Чыйырдыга ичиргенгев) Акбалта Манасты киринткенге г) Бакдөөлөт Манасты киринткенге","answer":"📚 Манас эпосундагыАлтын-Көлдөгү алп арчанын түбүндөгү жан адамга көрүнбөгөн мүрөктүн суусун ким Чыйырдыга Акбалта Манасты киринткенде берген.Туура жообу:в) Акбалта Манасты киринткенге "},{"question":"फिल्म खेल्नेलाई हामी के भन्छौं? ","answer":"फिल्ममा अभिनय गर्ने कलाकारलाई हामी नायक, नायिका भन्छौ ।"},{"question":"Sự kiện quan trọng nào được nói tới trong văn bản này? - Lên đường ngày 12 tháng 10 năm 1944 để tham gia cuộc đổ bộ lên Philippine, \\"West Virginia\\" được bố trí trong thành phần của Đội đặc nhiệm 77.2 dưới quyền chỉ huy của Chuẩn Đô đốc Jesse B. Oldendorf. Vào ngày 18 tháng 10, hàng thiết giáp hạm tiến vào vịnh Leyte, \\"West Virginia\\" di chuyển phía sau chiếc thiết giáp hạm \\"California\\". Lúc 16 giờ 45 phút, \\"California\\" cắt rời được một quả thủy lôi bằng máy cắt dây mìn ngầm (paravane); \\"West Virginia\\" né tránh được mối đe dọa, và ít phút sau nó bị phá hủy bởi hỏa lực pháo của một trong các tàu khu trục theo hộ tống.","answer":"Sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản này là cuộc đổ bộ lên Philippine vào năm 1944, trong đó tàu chiến \\"West Virginia\\" tham gia như một phần của Đội đặc nhiệm 77.2 dưới quyền chỉ huy của Chuẩn Đô đốc Jesse B. Oldendorf và những sự kiện diễn ra khi họ tiến vào vịnh Leyte."},{"question":"iPhone 7 Türkiye'ye ne zaman geldi?","answer":"Apple'ın Türkiye online mağazasında yaptığı güncellemeye göre iPhone 7, 14 Ekim'de Türkiye'de satışa sunulacak. Apple'ın anonsuna göre iPhone 7 ile birlikte yeni nesil Apple Watch'lar da 14 Ekim'den itibaren satışa sunulacak. Her iki cihazın da ön satışa sunulma tarihi büyük olasılıkla 7 Ekim olacak."},{"question":"السؤال: ما السورة التي بدأت باسم","answer":"الإجابة : التين"},{"question":"Kan?","answer":"Who?"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bermurah hati'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud suka memberi, tidak kedekut, pengasih"},{"question":"Inona no mampiavaka ny ala tropikaly Andasibe-Mantadia eto Madagasikara ?","answer":"Malaza ho fonenan'ny varika lehibe indrindra, ny Indri Indri, sy ny karazan-javamaniry hafa sy ny zava mananaina miavaka ny valan-javaboahary Andasibe-Mantadia."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Na dia niatrika tsikera aza izy ireo dia nanohy nanova, ary tamin'ny farany, dia nanova ny indostria izy ireo.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Na eo aza ny tsikera, ny fanavaozana maharitra nataony dia nitarika fiantraikany amin'ny indostria.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny dikan'ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"வினா :இதை தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்-bug report","answer":"விடை :bug report  தமிழ் மொழிபெயர்ப்பு  பிழை அறிக்கை"},{"question":"Mitkä ovat influenssan seuraukset ja jälkitaudit?","answer":"Influenssalla on useita jälkitauteja.Yleisimmin näihin sairastuvat vanhukset, pienet lapset, raskaana olevat sekä sairautensa vuoksi riskiryhmiin kuuluvat.  Influenssa voi myös pahentaa perussairautta ja huonontaa toimintakykyä.Jälkitauteja ovat lapsilla korvatulehdus ja keuhkoputkentulehdus sekä kaikissa ikäryhmissä keuhkokuume, joka voi viedä sairaalahoitoon ja aiheuttaa jopa kuoleman. Influenssainfektiota seuraava kuolema johtuu yleensä joko jälkitautina ilmaantuneesta bakteeriperäisestä infektiosta tai jo olemassa olevan perussairauden pahenemisesta.Raskaana olevilla korkeakuumeinen influenssa voi raskauden alkuvaiheessa aiheuttaa keskenmenon ja raskauden edetessä ennenaikaisen synnytyksen. Influenssan jälkeen myös sydäninfarktien ja aivoverenkierron häiriöiden ilmaantuvuus on lisääntynyt. Influenssainfektio voi joskus harvoin johtaa aiemmin terveen ihmisen kehon puolustusjärjestelmän epätarkoituksenmukaiseen korostuneeseen vasteeseen ja tätä kautta elinvaurioihin esimerkiksi keuhkoissa."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo            sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Waxa uu ahaa Sh. Mukhtaar Max’ed Xuseen.Sheeg Magaca Wasiirkii Arrimaha Dibadda Xukuumaddii 1964kii? "},{"question":"Que lingua é falada no país Argélia?","answer":"No país Argélia, a língua oficial e mais amplamente falada é o Árabe Argelino (Darija), que é uma variante do árabe. O francês também é amplamente utilizado, especialmente em contextos oficiais, comerciais, e educacionais, devido ao período colonial francês e à continuação das relações com a França. Além disso, várias línguas berberes também são faladas por grupos étnicos berberes no país."},{"question":"Yalna yalla defal la Jammu","answer":"AamiinTe defal lako, defal ko jullit ñi."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kelam disigi, lekung ditinjau'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud sesuatu yang kurang jelas hendaklah diselidiki dengan saksama"},{"question":"Балат жөнүндө кыскача эмне айта аласың ?","answer":"Балат 🎨Бул Стамбулдун чыныгы асыл ташы. Эски таш үйлөр менен капталган жаркыраган жана түркүн түстүү көчөлөр уникалдуу атмосфераны түзүп, өткөнгө алып барат.Туркия 🇹🇷"},{"question":"નીચેના રૂઢિપ્રયોગ નો અર્થ આપો:કાન નહીં દેવા","answer":"ધ્યાન ન આપવું"},{"question":"කමත් බසෙන් උහන් ගෙඩිය  යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කමතට ගෙන ආ වංගෙඩිය"},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - இந்தியாவில் கம்பெனி ஆட்சியின் போது, காஷ்மீர் பள்ளத்தாக்கு, சீக்கியப் பேரரசின் கீழ் 1799 முதல் 1849 முடிய இருந்தது. இரண்டாம் ஆங்கிலேய-சீக்கியப் போருக்குப்","answer":"பின்னர் சீக்கியப் பேரரசு வீழ்ச்சி அடைந்தது. பிரித்தானிய இந்தியாவின் ஆட்சியின் போது, காஷ்மீர் பள்ளத்தாக்கு, 1846ல் ஜம்மு காஷ்மீர் இராச்சியத்தின் கீழ் வந்தது."},{"question":"Descreva o símbolo da Internazionale (Inter de Milão).","answer":"O símbolo da Internazionale, também conhecida como Inter de Milão, é um escudo azul e preto com a inscrição \\"FC Internazionale Milano\\" em letras brancas, além das iniciais \\"FCIM.\\""},{"question":"Access Bank","answer":"Access Bank plc, tí a mọ̀ sí Access Bank, jẹ́ ilé-ìfowópamọ́ gbogboogbò ti orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà; ó sì jẹ́ ohun-ìní Access Bank Group . Ó ní ìwé-àṣẹ nípasẹ̀ Central Bank of Nigeria, olùṣàkóso ilé-ìfowópamọ́ orílẹ̀-èdè.Ní àkọ́kọ́, wọ́n jẹ́ báńkì ilé-iṣẹ́ kan; ní ọdún 2012, wọ́n gbòòrò sí báńkì ti ara-ẹni àti ilé-ìfowópamọ́ ìṣòwò. Access Bank àti Diamond Bank dàpọ̀ ní Ọjọ́ kìn-ín-ní, Oṣù Kẹrin, Ọdún 2019. Ní ìparí ìdàpọ̀ rẹ̀ pẹ̀lú ilé-iṣẹ́ ìfowópamọ́ ti Diamond, Access Bank ṣe àfihàn ààmì ìdánimọ̀ tuntun rẹ̀, èyí tí ń ṣe àfihàn ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ ti ilé-ìfowópamọ́ tuntun ńlá kan. Ilé-ìfowópamọ́ yìí gba àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ tó lé ní 28, 000 ní ọdún 2021.Lẹ́yìn ìṣọpọ̀ yìí, Access Bank plc di báǹkì tí ó tóbi jùlọ ní Áfíríkà lágbọn ti oníbàárà, pẹ̀lú àwọn oníbàárà tó ju mílíọ̀nù méjìlélógójì lọ, àti báńkì tí ó tó tóbi jùlọ ní Nàìjíríà lágbọn ti dúkíà.Ní ìbẹ̀rẹ̀ ọdún 2021, Access Bank kéde pé ó ti ṣe ìdánimọ̀ àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè Áfíríkà tuntun mẹ́jọ fún ìfẹ̀lójú tó lọ́ọ̀rìn, pẹ̀lú èróńgbà láti je àǹfàní láti inú àdéhùn ìṣòwò ọ̀fẹ́ jákèjádò kọ́ńtìnẹ́ẹtì kan. Awọn ìlú tó jẹ́ ọjà àfojúsùn wọn ni Morocco, Algeria, Egypt, Côte d'Ivoire, Senegal, Angola, Namibia àti Etiopia, èyítí yóò ṣe ìfẹ̀lójú mímọ̀-lágbàáyé báńkì náà sí àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè méjìdínlógún. Access Bank ni a nírètí láti ṣètò àwọn ọ́fíìsì sí àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè, ṣe alábàáṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú àwọn ilé-ìfowópamọ́ tó wà, àti kí ó lo àwọn ẹ̀rọ agbagbe rẹ̀ láti ṣe àwọn iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ sí àwọn oníbàárà."},{"question":"ভূগোল বিষয়ের শিক্ষক জনাব মতিউর রহমান দশম শ্রেণির বাংলাদেশ ও বিশ্বপরিচয় ক্লাসে সৌরজগৎ নিয়ে আলোচনা করছিলেন। প্রথমে তিনি একটি গ্রহ নিয়ে আলোচনা করলেন, সূর্য থেকে যার গড় দূরত্ব ২২.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার এবং পৃথিবী থেকে ৭.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার। পরে তিনি অপর একটি গ্রহের কথা বললেন, সূর্য থেকে যার গড় দূরত্ব ১৫ কোটি কিলোমিটার এবং উপরিভাগের তাপমাত্রা ১৩.৯০° সেলসিয়াস।উদ্দীপকে বর্ণিত ঘটনায় জনাব মতিউর রহমান প্রথমে কোন গ্রহ নিয়ে আলোচনা করেছেন? ব্যাখ্যা করো।","answer":"উদ্দীপকে বর্ণিত ঘটনায় জনাব মতিউর রহমান প্রথমে মঙ্গল গ্রহ নিয়ে আলোচনা করেছেন।মহাকর্ষ বলের প্রভাবে মহাকাশে কতগুলো জ্যোতিষ্ক সূর্যের চারিদিকে নির্দিষ্ট কক্ষপথে পরিক্রমণ করছে; এদের গ্রহ বলা হয়। সৌরজগতে আটটি গ্রহ আছে। এর মধ্যে একটি হলো মঙ্গল। সূর্য থেকে দূরত্বের দিক দিয়ে পৃথিবীর পরে মঙ্গল গ্রহের অবস্থান। সূর্য থেকে এর গড় দূরত্ব ২২.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার এবং পৃথিবী থেকে ৭.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার। উদ্দীপকে এ গ্রহটির প্রতিই ইঙ্গিত করা হয়েছে।উদ্দীপকে বলা হয়েছে, ভূগোল বিষয়ের শিক্ষক জনাব মতিউর রহমান দশম শ্রেণির বাংলাদেশ ও বিশ্বপরিচয় ক্লাসে সৌরজগৎ নিয়ে আলোচনা করেন। তিনি প্রথমে যে গ্রহ নিয়ে আলোচনা করেন সূর্য থেকে সেটির গড় দূরত্ব ২২.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার এবং পৃথিবী থেকে ৭.৮ কোটি কিলোমিটার। সুতরাং বলা যায় যে, তিনি প্রথমে মঙ্গল গ্রহ নিয়ে আলোচনা করেছেন। এ গ্রহটিতে কোনো ধরনের প্রাণের উপযোগী পরিবেশ আছে বা ছিল কিনা তা নিয়ে বিজ্ঞানীদের মধ্যে ব্যাপক কৌতুহল রয়েছে।"},{"question":"සම්මත රග්බි  කණ්ඩායමක කී‍්‍රඩකයන් කී දෙනෙක් සිටීද?","answer":" 15"},{"question":"Bakit itinawag na \\"Ghost Month\\" ang Agosto?","answer":"Galing sa kulturang Tsino ang paniniwala na Ghost Month ang ikapitong buwan sa kanilang kalendaryo. Kadalasan itong tumatapat sa Agosto.Tuwing Ghost Month, kumakalawa umano ang mga kaluluwa ng mga patay na kriminal at makasalanan mula sa kanilang pagkakakulong sa impiyerno. Pinaniniwalaan ng mga Tsino na magdudulot ng malas ang mga kaluluwa. Dahil dito, mas nagiging maingat ang mga Tsino sa mga desisyong pampinansyal at pangnegosyo katulad ng pagbili ng bagong ari-arian o paglakbay. "},{"question":"Astaamaha qofka hanka sare leh  Sheekadii Takeo Awsahira.","answer":"Sheekadii Takeo Awsahira ee u dhashay wadanka japaan ahaana midkii japaan u horseeday horumarka ay maanta haysato :- Wuxuu yiri takeo dawladayda ayaa waxay ii dirtay in aan wax ka soo barto wadanka jarrmalka, gaar ahaan jaamacada layiraahdo (University of Hamburg), waxaana laydiray in aan soo barto makaaniknimada iyo sida matoorada loo sameeyo, jarmalka ayaan aaday anigoo xanbaarsan himmiladaydii ii gaarka ahayd,  ee ku milantay jirkayga dhuuxana iga gashay ee aan har iyo habeen ku hamminaayay saan ku gaarilahaa, himmiladaas oo ahayd in aan sameeyo matoor !! . Waxaan aqaanay inay farsama kasta ay leedahay shay sir ah oo farsamadaas u ah udub dhexaad (Model Motors), haddii aad barato sida moodeelkaas loosameeyo gacanta waxaad ku dhigtay sirta farsamadaas ay ku dhisan tahay. Macallimiintii wax i baraysay meeshay iga barilahaayeen sida loo sameeyo matoorada, ayay waxay isiiyeen kutub badan oo igu dhaheen xifdi ilaa aan xifdiyay wixii ku qornaa walina aanan lahayn aqoon aan ku samayn karo matoor, waayo farsamo hadal laxifdiyo uma baahnee waxay u baahan tahay in gacanta wax lagaa baro oo lagu tababaro laguna tuso sida wax lays kugu rakibaayo oo lays kugu xiraayo. Markii aan arko matoor shaqaynayaa wuxuu ilayahay sidii hal xiraale aan la furi karin, layma barin sida loo fur furo, sida loo cabbiro bir kasta oo ku jirta matoorka, hadal uun ayaa lay baraa farsamo gacan layma baro. Waxaan u hilawsanahay sidii aan ku gaarilahaa in aan matoorkaas gacantayda ku furfuro  kuna xirxiro  bir kastana aan u aqoon lahaa qaabka loo sameeyo looguna rakibo meesha ay ku jirto, saan ku baran lahaa bir kasta, bool kasta, silig kasta iyo shaqada ay  qabanayaan, waxaan u hilawsanahay in aan  matoorka habsiiyo sidii waalid ilmihiisii muda ka maqnaa oo kale, in aan is arko anigoo qaba dhar ay ka buuxdo olyo iyo  naafto, gacmahaygana aan ku daliigo olyada matoorka, in aan gacmahayga iyo dharkaygaba ay kasoo carafto urka olyada. Maalin maalmaha ka mid ah ayaan waxaan arkay shirkad xayaysiinaysa oo rabta inay soo bandhigto matooro lagu sameeyay wadanka talyaaniga, markaas waxay ahayd bisha awalkeeda waxaana soo qaatay biilkii laysoo diray, shirkadii ayaan u tagay waxaana ku arkay matoor awoodiisu le'egtahay laba faras oo kale qiimihiisuna uu dhan yahay lacagta bisha laysoo diray ee aan haysto, waxaan is iri haddaad lacagta kugadato matoorka bishan waxaad cunto ma helaysid, hadadaan gadanina matoorka waligaa magaaraysid in aad ka salgaarto himmadada ah in aad matoor samayso, muda hadaan fikriray waxaa ila xoog badatay in aan gaajoodo oo matoorka iibsado, matoorkii ayaan iibsaday guriga ayaan u soo qaatay, markaan guriga u soo socday lugihii ayaa i cuslaaday farxad darteed waxaan aaminay in aan maanta garabka kuwato wixii adduunka ugu qaalisanaa, saan u soo socday markaan soogaaray guriga ayaan matoorkii dhigay miis halkan yaala, markaas  ayaan fariistay anigoo aaminsan in aan guriga soogashaday shaygii adduunka ugu qaalisanaa, marna matoorkaan fiiriyaa marna farxadaa  igabadata oo aad ayaan u farxaa, naftayda ayaan ugu sheekaynayaa oo ku dhahayaa '' matoorkan waa sirta ay ku hormareen reer yurub'', '' haddii aan sameeyo matoor waxaa hubaal ah in aan taariikhda iyo nolosha japaan wax weyn ka badali doono. Waxaan naftayda ku iri matoorkan wuxu ka kooban yahay boolal, biro yaryar ah iyo kuwa waaweyn, sida loo rakibay waxay ku dhisan tahay aqoon iyo isku dheelitir, haddii marka aan ku guulaysto in aan fufuro isla markaasna aan markale rakibo oo uu shaqeeyo waa talaabo weyn oo aan horey u qaaday saan uga salgaaro sirta ay yurub ku hormartay. Waxaan soo diyaarsaday waraaqo iyo qalimaan waxan bilaabay in aan guud ahaan sawiro matoorka, waxaan ku xejiyay in aan bir kasta iyo bool kastaba aan sawiro meesha uu ku jiro, sida ugu jiro iyo in aan tiro siiyo bir kasta iyo meesha ay ku jirto, dadaal dheer oo ay waheliso daal, rafaad, hurdo la'aan, waxaan ku guulaystay in aan furfuro matoorkii, waxaan guda galay in aan xirxiro oo rakibo matoorka, markaan dhameeyay rakibaadii iyo xirxiridii ayaan istaaray oo daaray, markaan maqlay codkii matoorka oo shidmay jirkayga dhan waxaa buuxiyay farxad, farxadii aan maalintaas farxay waxaan ku qiyaaso magaranaayo, furfurida iyo  xirxirada matoorka waxay igu qaadatay sadex maalmood oo aan hal mar wax cunaayay hurda aad u yar aan seexanaayay. Gudoomiyihii ardayda japaanka ee wax ka barta wadanka jarmalka ayaan u tagay oo u sheegay in aan ku guulaystay in aan furfuro oo xirxiro matoor, markaas ayuu yiri, waa talaabo fiican, waxaan hayaa matoor kharaabsan waxaan rabaa inaad hagaajiso oo soosaarto cilada keentay inuu kharaabo oo aad ka dhigto matoorkan mid shaqaynaaya. Toban maalmood oo aan nasniin lahayn ayay iga qaadatay in aan ogaado cilada matoorkan haysata, waxaan ogaaday inay jirto sadex birood oo gubtay isla markaasna dhamaaday, waxaan isku dayay in aan sadexdaas birood aan gacantayda ku sameeyo oo aanan kasoo gadan tukaanka, dadaal dheer kadib waxaa ii suurtagashay in aan sameeyo sadexdaas birood oo aan ku rakibo matoorka, markii aan  ku xiray birihii matoorka oo aan daaray codkii matoorkana aan maqlay  waxaan dareemay raaxo iyo farxad aad u weyn iyadoo waliba isagoo uu ihayo daal farabadan, gaajo, hurdo la'aan, waxaas oo dhan in aan u dulqaato waxaa ii sahlay shaqadaan hayo ayaa wax kasta igala weyn. Markii uu ogaaday gudoomiyihii in aan ku guulaystay inaan hagaajiyay matoorkii kharaabsanaa, wuxuu igu yiri maanta waxaa lagaarabaa inaad adigu matoor gacantaada ku samayso. Haddaba si ay iigu suurtagasho in aan sameeyo matoor, waxaan qaatay go'aan ah in aan ka shaqeeyo meelaha geyrashyada eelagu hagajiyo matoorada, waxaan xirtay dhargii olyada badnaa ee ay xirtaan dadka ka sheqeeya gayrashyada, waxaan ku talagalay in aan noqdo shaqaale dhega nugul, karti badan, aan noogin, daal aqoon, shaqadiisa u heelan, iyado ay jirto in aan ka dhashay reer ahaan qoyska  kataliya wadanka japaan, reer boqor ayaad tahay iima diidin in aan ka shaqeeyo garaash, reer boqor ayaad tahay iima diidin in aan meel kasta u maro sidii aan japaan u hormarin lahaa. Shaqadaan waxay igu qaadatay sideed sano oo aan shaqaynaayo shan iyo toban saac, markii shaqadu dhamaatana waxaan ku dhihi jirey  ninka meesha haysta waardiyaha igu qor mushaharna kaama rabo, waxaas oo dhan waxaan uga goleeyahay in aan habeenkii ku soo jeedo in aan u dhabagalo bir kasta sida ay u shaqayso iyo sida loosameeyo. Boqorkii japaan katalinaayay ayaa maqlay sheekadayda, markaas ayuu lacag ii soo diray aan ku iibsado dhamaan qalabka lagasameeyo matoorada, qalabkii ayaan soo dhoofsaday  waxaana  la imi wadanka japaan, boqorkii ayaa codsaday in aan u imaado si uu ii arko qadasharafna iisiiyo,  markaas ayaan ku iri  ilaa aan toban matoor oo ay ku qorantahay japaan ayaa lagu sameeyay aan sameeyo, ma istaahilo in aan boqorka qaabilo ama qado sharaf laysameeyo.  Sagaal sano kadib waxaan ku guulaystay in aan sameeyo warshad lagu sameeyo matoorada, maalintii aan sameeyay toban matoor oo aan dusha kaga qoray '' waxaa lagu sameeyay japaan'' ( made in japan),  waxaan u qaaday oo geeyay matooradii guriga madaxtooyada , markii ladaaray matooradii ayaa waxaa soo galay boqorkii isagoo dhoolacadaynaaya markaas ayuu yiri '' codkii ugu macaanaa ayaan maanta maqlayaa, matooro japaan lagu sameeyay ayaan codkooda maqlayaa'' . Markii aan indhahayga ku arkay in aan sirtii ay ku horumareen reer yurub aan japaan usoo raray, ayaan seexday 10 saac oo xiriir ah, mana seexan 10 saac oo xiriir ah 15 sano gudahood. Walaalaha qiimah badanoow aynu is waydiino, maxaa sababay inuu ninkaan dadaalka intaas le'eg ku bixiyo horumarka wadankiisa? Maxaa keenay inuu noqdo mid rafaad kasta u mara sidii uu wadankiisa u hormarin lahaa ?  Walaalaha qiimaha badanoow, ninkan wuxuu ahaa wiil loo diray inuu jarmalka  wax ku soo barto, waxaa is weydiin leh intee soomaali loo diray inay jarmalka wax ku soo bartaan, malaga helay wiil ninkan oo kale ah ? intee wiil soomaaliyeed wax barasho loogu diray wadamada reer yurub malaga helay wiil lamid ah ninkan oo kale ? intee wiil soomaaliyeed wax barasho loogu diray wadanka maraykanka ma'aragnay wiil noqday sida wiilkan oo kale?Intee wiilal deeq waxbarasho loogu diray adduunka daafihiisa ma'aragnay hal wiil oo hankii takeo kujiro?. Intee wiil soomaaliyeed naftiisa ku haligay isagoo u tahriibaaya wadamada reer galbeedka? Mays waydiinay wiilashaasi maxay naftooda u haligaayeen ? maxay badda u dhaxaysa liibiya iyo talyaaniga iskugu biimaynaayeen ? maxay barafka u dhaxeeya ruushka iyo yurub iskugu biimaynaayeen ? maxaa ka maqnaa oo ay raadinaayeen ? ma lacag raadis ayay ahaayeen ? ma sharaf raadis ayay ahaayeen ? ma aqoon raadis ayay ahaayeen ? maxay tahay sababta ugu weyn ee ay naftooda ugu biimaynayaan dhibaatooyinkaas oo dhan ? hankoodu magarsiisanaa inay soo min guuriyaan horumarka iyo ilbaxnimada ka jirta wadamadaas ay u qaxeen oo ay keenaan wadankooda ?  haddii aad weydiiso dhallin yaro tahriibaysa oo aad ku dhahdo maxaa yurub ugu socotaan ? jawaabta ugu badan ay ku siinayaan waxaa weeye, shaqo raadis ayaan nahay, basaboor raadis ayaan nahay, caruurta ayaan u soo xamaalanaynaa iwm, waxaa is weydiin leh dhallin yaradii soomaaliyeed hankoodii ma'intaas ayuu noqday shaqo, basaboor , xamaali !!! . Waxaa layaableh, inaad aragto wiilashii, odoyaashii, gabdhihii, hooyooyinkii, u qaxay wadamada reer galbeedka  iyagoo lacag lagarab taagan  nin dagaal ooga ah oo sabab u ahaa inay wadankooda kasoo qaxaan,  warmaynu garan weynay xattaa inaynaan taageerin dagaal oogihii shalay wadanka inaka soo qixiyay ? warmaynu garan waynay inay ceebtahay in aan fadhi ku diriryada ku taageerno dagaal oogayaashii wadankeena hoos u dhigay ee maanta inaan qaxooti noqono sababta u ahaa ? Nacaybka aan wadankeena hooyo u qabnaa waynaa !! inaynu ka qaxno isla markaasna kii sababta u ahaa in qarankeenii dumo, adduunka daafihiisa ku firxano, qaxooti noqono aynu lagarab istaagno hiil iyo hoo, hadal iyo lacag, soo cajiib maahan ? dhamaan dadka soomaliya buburka kawada waxaa taageera qurba joogta soomaaliyeed, taasna waa shay laga naxo, meeshaad ka shaqayn lahayd horumarka wadankaaga inaad ka shaqayso burburka wadankaaga, meeshaa horumarka galbeedka yaala soo rari lahayd inaad ku mashquusho qabyaalad iyo dhammaan wixii wadankeena hoosu dhac ku keenaya soo shay laga naxo maahan ? "},{"question":"Berikan saya lirik lagu negeri Melaka.","answer":"Lirik lagu negeri Melaka adalah seperti berikut:Lirik dan komposer: Saiful BahriMelaka Bandar BersejarahTempat tumpah darah kitaDijunjung dengan sepenuh jiwaUntuk maju dan jayaRakyat Melaka sudah bersatu paduBerikrar taat setiaJujur berkhidmat setiap masaMelaka maju jaya"},{"question":" Sheeg maxaa loo-yaqaanaa codka uu Geela Sameeyo?","answer":"Waxaa Loo-Yaqaanaa Olol."},{"question":"Tsara kokoa ve ny mihinana voankazo alohan’ny sakafo ?","answer":"Araky ny fanazavana nataon’ilay nutritionniste vahiny Laura Tajan dia tsara ny mihinana voankazo minitra vitsivitsy alohan’ny sakafo. Tsy mety kosa hoy ity farany ny mihinana voankazo adiny iray na roa alohan’ny sakafo. Rehefa hoanina alohan’ny sakafo ny voankazo dia mitondra fibres amin’ireto farany ka manamora ny fandevonan-kanina. Raha toa kosa ka mihinana voankazo adiny iray na roa alohan’ny sakafo dia ilay voankazo no tonga voalohany ao amin’ny vavony ka manjary levona haingana ny siramamy anatin’ny voankazo ka mety hiteraka hypoglicémie amin’ny vatana izany. "},{"question":"No contexto da física, explique o significado de Velocidade.","answer":"Velocidade é uma medida escalar da rapidez com que um objeto se desloca em uma direção específica. Ela leva em consideração tanto a magnitude quanto a direção do movimento."},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :তিনি ব্রিটিশ রাজ কর্তৃক গ্রেফতার হন। পঞ্চাশের মন্বন্তরে","answer":"১৯৪৩ সালে তিনি একটি এতিমখানা প্রতিষ্ঠা করেন। ভারত বিভাগের পর তিনি ঢাকায় স্থায়ী হন। ১৯৫৪ সালে নারীদের অংশগ্রহণে বিজয়ী হয়ে তিনি পূর্ববাংলা আইন পরিষদের সদস্য নির্বাচিত হন। ১৯৫৬ সালে তিনি চীনে পাকিস্তান প্রতিনিধিদলে ছিলেন।"},{"question":"Ijọba fẹẹ ka iye awọn eeyan to talaka ju lọ l’Ekoo","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii ni eto kika iye eeyan ti oṣi ati iṣẹ n ba finra loju paali jake-jado origun mẹrẹẹrin ipinlẹ Eko maa bẹrẹ. Igbesẹ yii maa waye lati leṣẹẹ-lugbẹ lakọtun nipinlẹ naa.Kọmiṣanna feto ọrọ aje ati iṣunna owo (Economic Planning and Budget) nipinlẹ Eko, Sam Egube, lo sọ eyi di mimọ lọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, to kọja yii, ninu atẹjade kan ti Akọwe agba lọfiisi rẹ fi sode lorukọ ijọba ipinlẹ Eko.O ni igbesẹ yii pọn dandan lati le mọ ipo ti eeyan kọọkan wa ni ti ọrọ aje, iṣuna owo, airina ati airilo, kijọba si le pinnu eto to maa ba ipo olululuku mu lati le gbọn oṣi ati iṣẹ danu lawujọ wa.O lawọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ oluṣiro ipinlẹ Eko (Lagos Bereau of Statistics) yoo bẹrẹ si i lọ kaakiri ojule kọọkan lawọn ijọba ibilẹ ati kansu mẹtadinlaaadọta to wa l’Ekoo, lati wọọdu kan si ekeji, lati beere awọn ibeere ti wọn ti ṣeto sinu iwe ọwọ wọn.O ni ọjọ mẹẹẹdọgbọn gbako ni wọn yoo fi ṣewadii ọhun, ojoojumọ si ni, bẹrẹ lati ọjọ kẹrinlelologun, oṣu yii.O ṣalaye pe lẹyin ti iwadii ati onka yii ba ti pari ni wọn yoo ṣeṣiro lati mọ awọn ohun tijọba yoo ṣe sawọn agbegbe, wọọdu atijọba ibilẹ kọọkan ti yoo tubọ mu ọrọ aje rugọgọ si i fawọn eeyan, ti yoo si din iṣẹ oun oṣi ku.Wọn waa rọ awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Eko lati fọwọ sowọ pọ nigba tawọn oṣiṣẹ ajọ naa ba de ọdọ wọn, ki wọn si fi suuru ati ootọ inu dahun awọn ibeere wọn, ki wọn le jẹ anfaani ijọba awa-ara-awa lọjọ iwaju"},{"question":"‘கலை முழுமை’ பற்றித் தொல்காப்பியம் குறிப்பிடுவனவற்றை எழுதுக.","answer":"தொல்காப்பியம்  என்பது இன்று கிடைக்கப்பெறும் மிக மூத்த தமிழ் இலக்கண நூலாகும். இஃது இலக்கிய வடிவிலிருக்கும் ஓர் இலக்கண நூலாகும். இந்நூலை இயற்றியவர் தொல்காப்பியர் என்று தொல்காப்பியப் பாயிரத்தில் குறிப்பிடப் பட்டுள்ளது. தொல்காப்பியத்தில் இடைச்செருகல்கள் உள்ளதாக அறிஞர்கள் கருதுகின்றனர்.பழங்காலத்து நூலாக இருப்பினும், இன்றுவரை தமிழ் இலக்கண விதிகளுக்கு அடிப்படையான நூல் இதுவேயாகும்.‘கலை முழுமை’, என்பது இலக்கியத்திற்கான நோக்கம் அல்லது அறிவியல் சார்ந்த கருத்துநிலைகள், கலை உருவாக்கத்தின் போதே சரிவர இணைந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்று தொல்காப்பியம் குறிப்பிடுகின்றது."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Dees na wéyal fippig Sàrt bu Kawe bi!","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Dees na wéyal fippig Sàrt bu Kawe bi!\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Dees: AUXna: AUXwéyal: VERBfippig: NOUNSàrt: NOUNbu: PRONKawe: ADJbi: DET!: PUNCT"},{"question":"Lẹyin ti Ojo atawọn ọrẹ ẹ fipa ba ọmọ lo pọ tan ni wọn tun fẹẹ ki iya mọlẹ n’Ikarẹ-Akoko","answer":"Awọn afurasi mẹrin ti wọn fẹsun ifipabanilopọ kan ni wọn ti n jẹjọ lọwọ nile-ẹjọ Majisreeti to wa l’Oke-Ẹda, niluu Akurẹ.Awọn olujẹjọ ọhun, Ojo Damilọla, Babalọla Bọdunde, Jimoh Fatai ati Saliu Abdul ni wọn fẹsun kan pe wọn fipa ba ọmọbinrin ẹni ọdun mẹẹẹdogun kan lo pọ niluu Ikarẹ-Akoko, lọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn ati ikejidinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun ta a wa yii.Bakan naa ni wọn lawọn mẹrẹẹrin tun gbiyanju ati fipa ba iya ọmọdebinrin yii lo pọ ki Ọlọrun too ko o yọ lọwọ wọn.Iwa ti wọn hu yii ni wọn lo ta ko abala ofin okoolugba o din meji (218) ninu iwe ofin ipinlẹ Ondo ti ọdun 2006. Gbogbo awọn olujẹjọ naa ni wọn lawọn ko jẹbi awọn ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn.Agbefọba, Taiwo Oniyẹrẹ, ni iyalẹnu nla lo jẹ laaarọ ọjọ igbẹjọ naa pẹlu bi iya ọmọ ti wọn fipa ba lo pọ ṣe yi ohun pada, to si n bẹbẹ fun awọn afurasi ọdaran ọhun.Agbẹjọro fun awọn olujẹjọ, Ọgbẹni J. O. Adewale bẹ adajọ lati yọnda awọn onibaara oun niwọn igba ti iya ọmọ to lọọ fẹjọ sun awọn ọlọpaa ti loun ko ṣẹjọ mọ.Adajọ J. O. A. Adepọju ni kawọn afurasi ọhun ṣi lọọ maa ṣere lọgba ẹwọn Olokuta titi di ọjọ karun-un, oṣu to n bọ yii. O tun pasẹ fawọn ọlọpaa lati fi ojulowo ati ẹda iwe ẹsun naa ṣọwọ si ọfiisi ajọ to n gba adajọ nimọran."},{"question":"Ruang gua yang paling besar di dunia adalah? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut.  A. Gua Nasib Bagus, Sarawak B. Gua Kelawar, Kedah  C. Gua Kelam, Pahang D. Gua Batu Tok Bidan, Terengganu","answer":"Jawapan yang betul adalah A. Gua Nasib Bagus, Sarawak.Gua Nasib Bagus yang terletak di Taman Negara Gunung Mulu di Sarawak, boleh memuatkan sebuah kapal terbang Boeing 747-200."},{"question":"ஜெயகாந்தனின்  வாழ்கை வரலாற்றை எழுதுக. ","answer":"பிறப்புஜெயகாந்தன் அவர்கள், தென்னிந்தியாவில் உள்ள தமிழ்நாட்டில் இருக்கும் கடலூரில் ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 24 ஆம் தேதி, 1934 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஒரு வேளாண் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார்.ஆரம்ப வாழ்க்கையும், கல்வியும்ஜெயகாந்தன் அவர்களுக்கு, சிறு வயதிலிருந்தே பள்ளிப்படிப்பில் நாட்டமில்லாமல் இருந்தது. எனவே, அவர் ஐந்தாம் வகுப்பு வரையே பள்ளிக்குச் சென்றார். இதன் காரணமாக, அவருக்கும், அவரது தந்தைக்கும் கருத்து வேறுபாடு ஏற்பட்டதால், அவர் தனது தாயார் மற்றும் தாத்தாவிடம் மிகவும் நெருக்கமாக இருந்தார். வீட்டில் அவருக்கும், அவரது தந்தைக்கும் சுமூகமானப் பேச்சுவார்த்தை இல்லாமல், இருவரும் எதிரும், புதிருமாக இருந்தனர். அவர் பள்ளிச் செல்லவில்லை என்ற ஒரே காரணத்தால், அவரது தந்தை அவருக்குக் கடுமையான தண்டனைகள் வழங்கினார். சிறுவனாக இருந்து இதனை சற்றும் தாங்கிக் கொள்ள இயலாததால், அவர் தனது 12 வது வயதில் வீட்டை விட்டு ஓடி, விழுப்புரத்தில் உள்ள அவரது மாமாவின் வீட்டிற்கு வந்து சேர்ந்தார். அங்கு, அவரது மாமா அவருக்கு கம்யூனிச கொள்கைகளையும், சுப்ரமணிய பாரதி படைப்புகளையும் அறிமுகப்படுத்தி வைத்தார்.இலக்கியம் மீது ஆர்வம் சிறிது காலம் கழித்து, ஜெயகாந்தன் அவர்களுடைய தாயார் அவரை சென்னையில் உள்ள இந்திய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சியின் உறுப்பினரான அவரது உறவினர் வீட்டிற்கு அழைத்துச் சென்றார். இந்திய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி அலுவலகத்தில் தனது பிள்ளைப் பருவத்தைக் கழித்த அவர், தமிழ்நாட்டின் கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சித் தலைவர்களுக்குப் பரிச்சயமானார். அக்கட்சி அலுவலகத்தைத் தனது வீடாகவும், அக்கட்சி உறுப்பினர்களைத் தனது குடும்ப அங்கத்தினர்களாகவும் கருதிய அவர், அவர்களின் கலந்துரையாடல்களைக் கேட்க கேட்க, இலக்கியத்தின் மீது அவருக்கு நாட்டம் ஏற்பட்டது. இதனால், கட்சியின் அங்கத்தினரான ஜீவானந்தம் என்பவர், அவருக்குத் தமிழாசிரியர் ஒருவரை அவருக்குக் கல்வி கற்றுத் தருமாறு பணியில் அமர்த்தினார். தமிழ் இலக்கிய, இலக்கணங்களை முறையாகக் கற்றுத் தேர்ந்த அவர், பல இடங்களில் முழுநேரம் மற்றும் பகுதிநேர வேலைகளில் வேலைப் பார்த்தார். 1949ல், இந்திய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சிக்குத் தடைவிதிக்கப்பட்டதால், அக்கட்சிக்குத் தடை உத்தரவு விதிக்கப்பட்டது. இதன் பொருட்டாக, அவர் தஞ்சாவூரிலுள்ள ஒரு காலணிகள் விற்கும் கடையில் தற்காலிகமாகப் பணியில் சேர்ந்தார். அவருக்குக் கிடைத்த ஓய்வு நேரங்களில், எழுதும் பழக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்திக் கொண்டார். மேலும், புதிய கட்சிகளின் வருகையால், இந்திய கம்யூனிஸ்ட் கட்சி முழுவதுமாக அழிந்ததால், காமராஜரின் கொள்கைகள் மீது அவருக்குப் பற்று ஏற்பட்டதால், அவரது தொண்டனாக மாறி, அவர் இருந்த தமிழகக் காங்கிரஸ் கட்சியில் சேர்ந்தார்.எழுத்துலக வாழ்க்கைஜெயகாந்தன் அவர்கள், அவரது இலக்கிய வாழ்க்கையை 1950களில் தொடங்கினார். பல்வேறு தினசரி மற்றும் மாத நாளிதழ்களான சரஸ்வதி, தாமரை, கிராம ஊழியன், ஆனந்த விகடன் போன்றவற்றில் அவரது படைப்புகள் வெளியாயின. அவரது படைப்புகளனைத்தும் ரசிகர்களிடம் நல்ல வரவேற்பைப் பெற்றதால், அவருக்குப் புகழும், அவரது படைப்புகளுக்கு அங்கீகாரமும் கிடைத்தது. இதனால், அவர் தலைச்சிறந்த தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்களில் ஒருவராகப் போற்றப்பட்டார். எழுத்துலகில் கொடிக்கட்டிப் பறந்த அவர், தமிழ்த் திரையுலகிலும் வலம் வந்தார். அவரது மிகவும் வெற்றிப்பெற்ற படைப்புகளான “உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்” மற்றும் “சில நேரங்களில் சில மனிதர்கள்” போன்ற நாவல்கள் படமாக்கப்பட்டன. “உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்” என்ற படம், சிறந்த மாநில மொழித் திரைப்படத்திற்கான ‘குடியரசுத் தலைவர் விருதில் மூன்றாம் விருதான பத்ம பூஷன் விருதை’ பெற்றது.அவரது படைப்புகள்ஜெயகாந்தன் அவர்கள், பல்வேறு வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு, நாவல்கள், குறுநாவல்கள், சிறுகதைகள் தொகுப்பு, கட்டுரைகள், போன்றவற்றைப் படைத்துள்ளார். அதில் சில குறிப்பிடத்தக்கப் படைப்புகள்:‘வாழ்விக்க வந்த காந்தி 1973’, ‘ஒரு கதாசிரியனின் கதை’, ‘பிரம்ம உபதேசம்’, ‘சில நேரங்களில் சில மனிதர்கள்’, ‘ஒரு மனிதன் ஒரு வீடு ஒரு உலகம்’, ‘சினிமாவுக்குப் போன சித்தாளு’, ‘கண்ணன்’, ‘உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்’, ‘ரிஷிமூலம்’, ‘கருணையினால் அல்ல’, ‘கங்கை எங்கே போகிறாள்’, ‘ஒவ்வொரு கூரைக்கும் கீழே…’, ‘சுந்தர காண்டம்’ மற்றும் பல.தமிழ்த் திரையுலகில் இவருடைய கதைகள் பல திரைப்படங்களாகத் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டன. அவை: ‘சில நேரங்களில் சில மனிதர்கள்’, ‘ஒரு நடிகை நாடகம் பார்க்கிறாள்’, ‘ஊருக்கு நூறு பேர்’, ‘உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்’, ‘யாருக்காக அழுதான்’, மற்றும் ‘புதுச் செருப்பு’.அவர் இயக்கிய திரைப்படங்கள்: ‘உன்னைப் போல் ஒருவன்’, ‘யாருக்காக அழுதான்’, மற்றும் ‘புதுச்செருப்பு கடிக்கும்’விருதுகள்1972 – சாஹித்ய அகாடமி விருது2002 – இலக்கியத்திற்காக இந்திய அரசு வழங்கும் மிக உயர்ந்த விருதான ‘ஞான பீட விருதைப்’ பெற்ற இரண்டாவது தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்.2009 – இந்திய அரசின் மிக உயரிய விருதான ‘பத்ம பூஷன் விருதை’, இலக்கியத்துறைக்காக முதல்முறை வென்றார்.2011 – ரஷ்ய விருதுகாலவரிசை1934: தமிழ்நாட்டில் இருக்கும் கடலூரில் ஏப்ரல் மாதம் 24 ஆம் தேதி, 1934 ஆம் ஆண்டில் ஒரு வேளாண் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார்.1950: அவரது இலக்கிய வாழ்க்கையை 1950களில் தொடங்கினார்.2002: இலக்கியத்திற்காக இந்திய அரசு வழங்கும் மிக உயர்ந்த விருதான ‘ஞான பீட விருதைப்’ பெற்ற இரண்டாவது தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்.2009: இந்திய அரசின் மிக உயரிய விருதான ‘பத்ம பூஷன் விருதை’, இலக்கியத்துறைக்காக முதல்முறை வென்றார்."},{"question":"मिथिला चित्रकलाको बारेमा संक्षेपमा लेख्नुहोस्।","answer":"मिथिला चिकला नेपालको सांस्कृति सम्पदा हो । नेपालको तराईको मिथिला क्षेत्रमा निकै राम्रोसँग फस्टाएको यस चित्रकला नेपालको चित्रकलाको एक अभिन्न अङ्गको रुपमा स्थापित भएको छ । मिथिला चित्रकालाको आफ्नै मौलिक विशेषताहरु छन् । विशेष गरी भुइँमा र भित्तामा यस्ता किसिमका चित्रकला बनाइने हुनाले यसलाई भूमीचित्र र भित्तेचित्र पनि भन्ने गरिन्छ । स्थानिय स्रोतसाधनको प्रयोगले नै आकर्षक चित्र बनाइनुको साथै रङ्ग संयोजन पनि गरिने हुनाले यो विशेष महत्वको छ । विभिन्न खाले रङ्गको तयारी गर्नको लागि भिन्न भिन्न स्थानिय स्रोत साधनको प्रयोग गरिन्छ । नीलको बोटबाट निलो, चामलको पिठोबाट सेतो, गोबरमा ध्वाँसो र गुद मिसाएर कालो, बाख्रीको दुधमा सिन्दूर मिसाएर सिन्दूर, बेसारबाट पहेलो सिमीको पातबाट हरीयो र सागपात र फलबाट रातो रङ्ग तयार पारिन्छ। खास गरी विवाह, ब्रतबन्ध, चाडपर्व, पूजाआजा आदि अवसरहरुमा मिथिला चित्रकला बनाइन्छ ।"},{"question":"Nassau mooy gëblag man réew?","answer":"Nassau mooy gëblag réewum Bahamas."},{"question":"సూర్యునితో 60° కోణమును ఏర్పరచు, 6 మీ. పొడవు గల స్థూపము యొక్క నీడ పొడవు ఎంత ?","answer":"tan60° = CB/AB=6/AB= √3 = 6/ABనీడ పొడవు AB = 6/√3 మీ."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي مكونات الحاسوب؟","answer":"الإجابة: كاينة مكونات مادية وهي وحدات الادخال ووحدات الاخراج ووحدات التخزين ومكونات غير مادية اللي هي البرامج"},{"question":"Ajụjụ: Onye meriri Australia's Ụdịdị kacha elu na-esote 8? Azịza ya:","answer":"Ọ bụ Melissa Juratowitch"},{"question":"问题：三星手机在可持续发展方面有何努力？","answer":"答案：三星手机致力于推动可持续发展，制造使用环保材料、并采取了能源节约和电子废物回收等措施。"},{"question":"Kedụ n'ime kọntinet a ga-ahụ Latvia?","answer":"Kọntinet a ga-ahụ Latvia bụ na Northern EuropeLatvia dị na Northern Europe, n'akụkụ ọwụwa anyanwụ nke Oké Osimiri Baltic na n'ebe ugwu ọdịda anyanwụ nke East European Craton (EEC), n'etiti latitudes 55 ° na 58 ° N (obere ebe dị n'ebe ugwu nke 58 °), na lonjitudes 21 ° na 29° E (obere mpaghara dị n'ebe ọdịda anyanwụ nke 21°)."},{"question":"Mejupụta ilu a:Nwata Nna ya dunyere ohi.... ","answer":"Azịza:N'eji ụkwụ agbaka ụzọ.Nke a pụtara n'onye nwere nkwado onye isi n'eji obisike na atụghị ụjọ eme ihe. "},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Russie.","answer":"Gëblag réewum Russie mu ngi tuddu Moscou."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்தியாவிலிருந்து முதல் பிரபஞ்ச அழகி யார்?","answer":"விடை: சுஷ்மிதா சென் சுஷ்மிதா சென் அன்று இந்தியாவின், ஐதராபாத் நகரில் பிறந்தார். நடிகையான இவர், பாலிவுட் திரைப்படங்களில் அதிக அளவில் நடித்துள்ளார். பிரபஞ்ச அழகி பட்டம் வென்ற முதல் இந்தியப் பெண் என்ற பெருமையை பெற்றவர். முன்னாள் பிரபஞ்ச அழகியான இவர், பிரபஞ்ச அழகி 1994 பட்டம் வென்றவர். 1994ம் ஆண்டு, தனது பதினெட்டாவது வயதில், பெமினா மிஸ் இந்தியா பட்டத்தை சுஷ்மிதா வென்றார். பிரபஞ்ச அழகி போட்டியின் போது, தகுதிச் சுற்றுகள் அனைத்திலும் சுஷ்மிதா மூன்றாவது இடத்தைப் பிடித்தார், தகுதிச் சுற்றுகளில் முதலிடத்தை கொலம்பியாவின் கரோலினா கோமெஸ் பிடித்தார், இரண்டாம் இடத்தை மிஸ் கிரீஸ் அழகி ரீ டோடோன்ஸீ பிடித்ததுடன், நீச்சலுடை மற்றும் மாலை நேர உடைப் போட்டிகளில் வென்றார். நீச்சலுடை, நேர்காணல் மற்றும் மாலை நேர உடை அரையிறுதிப் போட்டிக்களில் முறையே இரண்டாவது, ஐந்தாவது மற்றும் மூன்றாவது இடங்களை சுஷ்மிதா பிடித்தார், இப்போட்டிகளில் மிஸ் கொலம்பியா மற்றும் மிஸ் வெனிசுலா அழகி மினோகா மெர்காடோவுக்கு அடுத்த இடத்தில் சுஷ்மிதா இருந்தார். இந்த மூன்று போட்டியாளர்களும் இறுதி மூன்று போட்டியாளர்களாக தேர்வாகினர். முடிவில், நடுவர்கள் தங்கள் வாக்குகளை சுஷ்மிதாவுக்கு அளித்து, இந்தியாவிலிருந்து பிரபஞ்ச அழகி பட்டத்தை வெல்லும் முதல் பெண் என்ற பெருமையை அளித்தனர்."},{"question":"வினா:திருக்குறள் ……………… ஆன நூல்.அ) குறள் வெண்பாக்களால்ஆ) சிந்தியல் வெண்பாக்களால்இ) ஆசிரியப்பாவால்ஈ) கலிப்பாவால்","answer":"விடை:குறள் வெண்பாக்களால்"},{"question":"Zdanie 1: Nora Navarro urodziła się jako drugie z sześciorga dzieci lekarza Winifredo Santos i Marii Rosario Santos y Navarro. Zdanie 2: Nora Navarro urodziła się jako drugie z sześciorga dzieci Winifredo Santos, lekarza, i Marii Rosario Santos y Navarro. Pytanie: Czy zdanie 1 i zdanie 2 wyrażają to samo znaczenie? Tak czy nie?","answer":"Tak."},{"question":"ከዚህ በታች የተገለጸው ትዊት አዎንታዊ፣ አሉታዊ ወይም ገለልተኛ የሆነ ስሜትን ይገልፃል?“ጌታቸው አሰፋ የዜጎችን ኢ-ሰብአዊ አያያዝ ሲቃወም፤ የሚያደናቅፉት እነ ደመቀ ነበሩ። - አቶ አስመላሽ ወስላሴ  (የአይጥ ምስክር )","answer":"አሉታዊ"},{"question":"नेपाली संस्कृतिमा \\"लोक डोहोरी\\" संगीतको भूमिका र ग्रामीण समुदायमा यसको लोकप्रियता व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"लोक दोहोरी ग्रामीण जीवन र सामाजिक विषयवस्तुहरू प्रतिबिम्बित गर्ने परम्परागत लोक संगीत हो, र यो नेपाली ग्रामीण समुदायहरूमा लोकप्रिय छ।"},{"question":"Maxay tahay faaidooyinka waa weyn ee miraha Sabiibka iyo cudurada ay la dagaallamaan?","answer":"Sabiibku waa miraha geedka canabka oo la qallajiyay iyadoo qorax loo dhigay ama lagu qalljiyay mashiinnada wax lagu qallajiyo. Sabiibka waxaa badanaa lagu macaaneeyaa cunnada mana lahan sonkor dheeraad ah oo lagu daray.Sabiibku waa miro nafaqo badan oo xambaarsan faaidooyin aan la soo koobi karin, waxaa lagaa helaa barootiin, faybar, fitamiin C, fitamiin E, fitamiin K, fitamiin B2, fitamiin B3, fitamiin B6, folate, calcium, iron, magnesium, phosphorus iyo potassium.Aan eegno faa’idooyinka caafimaad ee miraha sabiibka:1. Sare u qaadista caafimaadka wadnaha:Sabiibku waa il aad u wanaagsan oo laga helo antioxidants iyo “phytonutrients” kuwaas oo ka hortaga cudurrada raaga sida wadne xanuunka iyo dhan-qalalka (stroke). Daraasad lagu sameeyay wadanka Mareykanka ayaa lagu sheegay in sabiibka oo la cuno maalin kasta ay hoos u dhigto cadaadiska dhiigga. Faybarka ku jira sabiibka wuxuu yareeyaa kolestaroolka xun (LDL).2. Ka Hortagga Kansarka:Walxaha sunsaarista ee ku badan sabiibka waxay la dagaallamaan waxa loo yaqaanno “free radicals” ee sababa koriimada unugyada kansarka.3. Ka Hortagga cudurka macaanka:Sabiibku wuxuu aad ugu roon yahay dadka qaba cudurka sonkorowga nooca 2-aad. Daraasad la sameeyay ayaa lagu arkay in cunista sabiibku ay 23% yareyso heerka gulukoosta cunnada kadib.4. Caafimaadka caloosha:Sabiibka waxaa laga helaa faybar, kaas oo caloosha jilciya islamarkaana daaweeya calool istaagga. Sabiibka oo maalin kasta la cunaa waxay jilcisaa saxarada waxayna caawisaa cunno shiidista.Sabiibka waxaa ku jira barootiinka “tartaric acid” oo ah lidka hurka kaas oo wanaajiya shaqada mindhicirrada islamarkaana nidaamiya dheelitirka bakteeriyada caloosha. Daraasad la sameeyay ayaa lagu ogaaday in sabiibku uu hoos u dhigo halista kansarka ku dhaca mindhicirrada waa wayn (colorectal cancer).5. Ka hortagga dhiig yarida:Sabiibka waxaa ku jira maadada xadiidka (iron) oo ka hortagta dhiig yarida iyo fitamiin B oo muhiim u ah samaysanka unugyada cascas ee dhiigga.6. Suuska ilkaha:Daraasad lagu daabacay Joornaalka Nafaqada ayaa lagu ogaaday in walxaha “phytochemicals” eek u jira sabiibku ay caawiyaan caafimaad qabka ilkaha iyo cirridka iyagoo la dagaallama bakteeriyada afka islamarkaana ka hortagga suuska ilkaha gala.7. Lafo-beelka:Sabiibka waxaa laga helaa xaddi fiican oo kalsiyaam ah taas oo aasaasi u ah caafimaadka lafaha iyo ilkaha. Dumarka gaaray howlgabnimada dhalmada kadib (Postmenopuase) waxaa lagula dardaarmaa inay joogteeyaan cunista miraha sabiibka si looga hortago Lafa beelka (osteoporosis).8.Caafimaadka indhaha:Sabiibka waxaa ku jira “polyphenols” oo nooc maadooyinka sunsaarista ka mid ah taas oo ka hortagga dhaawaca xididada xorta ahi (free radicals) ay gaarsiiyaan indhaha. Tani waxay yareysaa khatarta cilladaha aragga lumiya sida caadka indhaha fuulo iyo xanuunka loo yaqaanno “Macular Degeneration” oo ah cillad timaadaa qofka markuu duqoobo.9. Gaaska:Haddii aashitada caloosha soo deyso ay ku badato jirka waxay keentaa xanuuno ay ka mid yihiin gaastirik iyo laab-jeexa. Sabiibka waxaa laga helaa xaddi fiican oo ah xadiid, copper, potassium, iyo magnesium kuwaas oo caawiya isku dheellitiridda heerka aashitada caloosha. Cunista sabiibku waxay hoos u dhiigtaa laab jeexa iyo gaaska."},{"question":"Ama","answer":"Olundi - ebe"},{"question":"Which vegetable was the first to be grown in space?","answer":"Potato"},{"question":"VESPRT సిద్ధాంతం ప్రకారం NH3లో బంధకోణం 107°48′ ఉండడానికి గల కారణంA) బంధ ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంట, ఒంటరి ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంటల ఆకర్షణB) బంధ ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంట, ఒంటరి ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంటల వికర్షణC) బంధ ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంట, ఒంటరి ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంటల ఆకర్షణ సమానంగా ఉండడంD) బంధ ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంటల వికర్షణ అధికంగా ఉండడం వలన","answer":"B) బంధ ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంట, ఒంటరి ఎలక్ట్రాన్ జంటల వికర్షణ"},{"question":"Da’du waa tilmaame.","answer":"Da’da waxaa loo isticmaalaa in lagu soo saaro tilmaamayaasha nafaqada iyadoo ay weheliso cabbiraad jireedyo sida dhererka iyo culayska.Qiimaynta nafaqada xilliga masiibooyinka carruurta ka yar 5 sano ayaa la cabbiraa madaama ay u nugul yihiin waxyaabaha saameeya nafaqada sida jirrooyinka iyo cuntoyarida."},{"question":"「あっしには関わりのねえことでござんす」というセリフが流行語となった、1972年に中村敦夫主演で放映された時代劇は何でしょう？","answer":"木枯らし紋次郎"},{"question":"બાળ કવિતા \\"ઘડીયાળ મારું નાનું\\" લખો.","answer":"ઘડીયાળ  મારું  નાનું,  તે ચાલે  છાનું માનુંએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએને  નથી  પાંખ,   પણ  ચાલે  ફટ  ફટએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેખાવાનું  નહિ  માગે પણ ચાવી આપે ચાલેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેઅંધારે  અજવાળે,  સૌના વખતને સંભાળેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેદિવસ  રાતે  ચાલે  પણ થાક નહિ લાગેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેટક ટક કરતું બોલે,  જરા ય નહિ   થોભેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેઘડીયાળ  મારું  નાનું,  તે ચાલે  છાનું માનુંએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છેએ તો કેવી નવાઈ જેવી વાત છે"},{"question":"පාපන්දු ක්‍රීඩාවේ වරදක් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"රීතියක් ලෙස, පාපන්දු වරදක් යනු ක්‍රියාකාරී ක්‍රීඩාවට බාධා කරන ක්‍රීඩකයෙකු විසින් කරන ලද අසාධාරණ ක්‍රියාවකි. තරඟ තීරකයෙකු ක්‍රීඩාවේ නීති විනිශ්චය කරන අතරතුර වැරදි තීරණය කරයි. පාපන්දු වැරදිවලට දඬුවම් කරන විවිධ ප්‍රතිඵල ඇත. විනිසුරුට සෘජු හෝ වක්‍ර නිදහස් පහරක් ප්‍රදානය කළ හැකිය (වරදට අනුව). සමහර අවස්ථාවලදී, පාපන්දු ක්‍රීඩාවේ වරදක් ප්‍රතිවාදී කණ්ඩායමට දඬුවම් පහරක් ලබා දෙයි."},{"question":"Muhammad Inuwa Yahaya","answer":"Muhammad Inuwa Yahaya (a bi ní ọjọ kẹsán, oṣù kẹwa ọdún 1961) jẹ alabojuto ati olóṣèlú Naijiria. Òún ni Gomina ti a yan ni ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe nínú idibo gómìnà ọdún 2019 lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ All Progressive Congress (APC).Wọ́n bí Muhammad Inuwa Yahaya ní ọjọ́ kẹsànán oṣù kẹwàá ọdún 1961 ní agbègbè Jekadefari, ní ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe. Bàbá rẹ̀ tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Alhaji Yahaya Umaru, jẹ́ oníṣòwò.Yahaya lọ sílé-ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ ti Central nígbà tí ó lọ sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ girama ti Science Secondary School tí ó wà ní ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe. Ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè ìkíní nínú Ìmọ̀ ìṣirò owó ní ọdún 1983 nínú ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ fáfitì ti Ahmadu Bello University, Zaria.Yahaya ti ṣiṣẹ́ ní àwọn ilé-iṣẹ́ ìjọba ati aládàáni ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó kọ́kọ́ bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ pẹ̀lú ilé-iṣẹ́ ìjọba Ìpínlẹ̀ Bauchi tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Bauchi State Investment and Property Develpment Company tí ó sì jẹ́ ọ̀gá àgbà aṣèṣirò owó nílé ìṣẹ́ náà ní ọdún 1984 sí 1985. Bákan náà ni ó tún jẹ́ adarí àgbà fún ilé-iṣẹ́ A.Y.U Civil Engineering Company Ltd láàrín ọdún 1993 sí 1999.Ní ọdún 2003 ni Gómìnà Muhammed Danjuma Gòkè yàn án sípò kọmíṣánà fún ètò owó ìná àti ìdàgbà-sókè ọrọ̀-ajé.Yahaya jẹ́ ìkan gbòógì nínú àwọn ẹgbẹ́ akọ́ṣẹ́mọṣẹ́ wọ̀nyí:Association of Nation Accountants of Nigeria (ANAN),Nigeria Institute of Management (NIM)Chartered Institution of Taxation of Nigeria (ACITN).Yahaya dara pọ̀ mọ́ ìṣèlú ní ọdún 2003, tí ó sì díje sí ipò Gómìnà ní abẹ́ àsí ẹgbẹ́ ìṣèlú All Progressives Congress (APC) ní ọdún 2015 ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe. Nígbà tí ó di ọjọ́ kíní oṣù Kẹwàá ọdún 2018, ó jáwé olúborí nínú ìdìbò abẹ́lé inú ẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀ pẹ́lú ìbò tí ó tó mọ́kàndínláàdọ́rún tí ó fi gbẹyẹ lọ́wọ́ akẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀ tí ó ń jẹ́ Muhammed Jibrin Barde láti díje sípò Gómìnà ní ọdún 2018.Wọ́n kéde Yahaya gẹ́gẹ́ bí ẹni tó jáwé olúborí nínú ìdìbò sípò gómìnà ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe náà ní ọjọ́ kẹsàán oṣù kẹta ọdún 2019 lẹ́ni tó mókè pẹ̀lú iye ìbò tí ó tó 364,179 láti fi fẹ̀yìn alatako rẹ̀ Sẹnetọ Usman Bayero Nafada láti inú ẹgbẹ́ Peoples Democratic Party (PDP), tí ó ní ìbò 222,868.Bákan náà ni Yahaya tún wọlé sípò gómìnà lẹ́ẹ̀kejì ní ọdún 2022 nígbà tí ó foju alátakò rẹ̀ gbolẹ̀ pẹ̀lù ìbò tí ó tó 342,821 láti inú ẹgbẹ́ ìṣèlú Peoples Democratic Party (PDP) , ìyẹn Muhammad Jibiri Barde tí ó ní iye ìbò 233,131. Ìkéde ìjáwé olúborí rẹ̀ yí ni ó wáyé láti ẹnu òṣìṣẹ́ Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC), Maimuna Waziri, tí ó sọ wípé ẹgbẹ́ APC borí pẹ̀lú ìbò tí ó tó 74,493 nínú ìdìbò náà.Gómìnà Yahaya fẹ́ ìyàwó méjì, ó sì bí ọmọ méje tí gbogbo wọn ń gbé ní ìpínlẹ̀ Gombe. Àkọ́bí rẹ̀ lọ́kùnrin náà ṣègbéyàwó ní ọdún 2022."},{"question":"‘बुलेट महाराज’ उपनामले कसलाई चिनिन्छ ?","answer":"‘बुलेट महाराज’ उपनामले युवराज त्रैलोक्यलाई चिनिन्छ।"},{"question":"Inona no mahatonga ny olona tsy hampiasa zezika natoraly fa aleony mampiasa zezika simika?","answer":"ny mahatonga ny olona tsy hampiasa zezika natoraly dia satria lafo ny zezika natoraly mihoatra amin'ny zezika simika. Ny zezika simika ihany koa dia mamokatra kokoa mihoatra amin'ny zezika natoraly"},{"question":"প্রশ্নঃ কে বলেছে অস্ত্রের নল থেকে শক্তি আসেউত্তরঃ","answer":"মাও জেডং"},{"question":"Apakah maksud Gerak badan?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah Senaman"},{"question":"வினா:   இந்தியாவின் மிக உயர்ந்த விருது என்ன? ","answer":"  விடை:  பாரத ரத்னா1.   இந்திய மாமணி அல்லது பாரத ரத்னா இந்தியாவில் குடிமக்களுக்கு வழங்கப்படும் மிக உயர்ந்த     விருதாகும்.2.   மிகச்சிறந்த தேசிய சேவை ஆற்றியவர்களைப் பாராட்டிப் பாரத ரத்னா விருது வழங்கப்படுகிறது. 3.  இச்சேவை கலை, அறிவியல், இலக்கியம் கலாச்சாரம், விளையாட்டு மற்றும் பொதுச்சேவை ஆகிய      துறைகளை உள்ளடக்கி இருக்கிறது."},{"question":"\\"Курманбек\\" эпосу жөнүндө  факты...","answer":"Курманбектин \\"калмак доорунда\\" жашаган тарыхый инсан экендиги башка тарыхый булактарда да кездешет. Түрк, иран авторлорунун кабарларында Курманбек казак каны Эшим менен бир доордо жашап, калмак төбөлдөрүнө каршы күрөшүп турат. Конкреттештире келгенде калмак төбөлдөрүнүн кыргыздарга карата баскынчылык жортуулдары, чабылып, чачылуу, кан төгүүлөр менен коштолгон калк тагдыры, элдин аларга каршы жүргүзгөн коргонуучулук, баатырдык күрөшү эпостун түзүлүшүнө негиз болот. Чыгармадагы элдик баатыр Курманбектин Ата Журт, Ата Мекен эгемендүүлүгү, азаттыгы үчүн аң-сезимдүүлүк менен өлүмгө жалтанбай барган эрдиги азыркы кыргыз коомунда да өзүнүн маани-маңызын жоготпой келет."},{"question":"Thu nhập bình quân đầu người của Thái Nguyên cao nhất trung du và miền núi phía Bắc, đúng hay sai?","answer":"Đúng.  Giải thích: Thu nhập bình quân đầu người của tỉnh Thái Nguyên năm 2022 là gần 4,6 triệu đồng một tháng, cao nhất trong 14 tỉnh trung du và miền núi phía Bắc. Bắc Giang cao thứ hai với 4,3 triệu đồng, Phú Thọ 3,9, Hòa Bình và Tuyên Quang 3,1, còn lại dưới 3 triệu đồng. Thu nhập của người dân Thái Nguyên chủ yếu đến từ tiền lương, tiền công và thu phi nông, lâm, ngư nghiệp. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਪਰਦੇਸੁ ਝਾਗਿ ਸਉਦੇ ਕਉ ਆਇਆ ॥ਵਸਤੁ ਅਨੂਪ ਸੁਣੀ ਲਾਭਾਇਆ ॥ਗੁਣ ਰਾਸਿ ਬੰਨਿੑ ਪਲੈ ਆਨੀ ॥ਦੇਖਿ ਰਤਨੁ ਇਹੁ ਮਨੁ ਲਪਟਾਨੀ ॥੧॥ਸਾਹ ਵਾਪਾਰੀ ਦੁਆਰੈ ਆਏ ॥ਵਖਰੁ ਕਾਢਹੁ ਸਉਦਾ ਕਰਾਏ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਸਾਹਿ ਪਠਾਇਆ ਸਾਹੈ ਪਾਸਿ ॥ਅਮੋਲ ਰਤਨ ਅਮੋਲਾ ਰਾਸਿ ॥ਵਿਸਟੁ ਸੁਭਾਈ ਪਾਇਆ ਮੀਤ ॥ਸਉਦਾ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਨਿਹਚਲ ਚੀਤ ॥੨॥ਭਉ ਨਹੀ ਤਸਕਰ ਪਉਣ ਨ ਪਾਨੀ ॥ਸਹਜਿ ਵਿਹਾਝੀ ਸਹਜਿ ਲੈ ਜਾਨੀ ॥ਸਤ ਕੈ ਖਟਿਐ ਦੁਖੁ ਨਹੀ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਸਹੀ ਸਲਾਮਤਿ ਘਰਿ ਲੈ ਆਇਆ ॥੩॥ਮਿਲਿਆ ਲਾਹਾ ਭਏ ਅਨੰਦ ॥ਧੰਨੁ ਸਾਹ ਪੂਰੇ ਬਖਸਿੰਦ ॥ਇਹੁ ਸਉਦਾ ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕਿਨੈ ਵਿਰਲੈ ਪਾਇਆ ॥ਸਹਲੀ ਖੇਪ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਲੈ ਆਇਆ ॥੪॥੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 372 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਸ਼ਾਹ! (ਚੌਰਾਸੀ ਲੱਖ ਜੂਨਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ) ਓਪਰਾ ਦੇਸ ਬੜੀਆਂ ਔਖਿਆਈਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਲੰਘ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ (ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ) ਸੌਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਆਇਆ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਂ ਸੁਣਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਨਾਮ ਵਸਤ ਬੜੀ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਲਾਭ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੈ ।ਹੇ ਗੁਰੂ! ਮੈਂ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਰਮਾਇਆ ਪੱਲੇ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਲਿਆਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ-ਰਤਨ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਇਹ ਮਨ (ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਖਰੀਦਣ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਰੀਝ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ।੧।ਹੇ ਸ਼ਾਹ! ਹੇ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ! ਤੇਰੇ ਦਰ ਤੇ (ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਵਣਜ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ) ਜੀਵ-ਵਪਾਰੀ ਆਏ ਹਨ (ਤੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਖ਼ਜ਼ਾਨੇ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ) ਸੌਦਾ ਕੱਢ ਕੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਜਾਚ ਸਿਖਾ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ-ਸ਼ਾਹ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਪਾਸ ਭੇਜਿਆ(ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਦਰ ਤੋਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਉਹ) ਰਤਨ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਰਮਾਇਆ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ, ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਿਚ ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਦੀ ਕੀਮਤ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।(ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਨੂੰ) ਪਿਆਰ-ਭਰੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਾਲਾ ਵਿਚੋਲਾ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ,ਉਸ ਪਾਸੋਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੌਦਾ ਲੱਭਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਵਲ ਡੋਲਣੋਂ ਹਟ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਇਸ ਰਤਨ ਨੂੰ ਇਸ ਸਰਮਾਏ ਨੂੰ) ਚੋਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਖ਼ਤਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ, ਹਵਾ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ ਨਹੀਂ, ਪਾਣੀ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ ਨਹੀਂ (ਨਾਹ ਚੋਰ ਚੁਰਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਨਾਹ ਝੱਖੜ ਉਡਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ ਨਾਹ ਪਾਣੀ ਡੋਬ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ।ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਮੈਂ (ਗੁਰੂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਖਰੀਦਿਆ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਲ ਲੈ ਜਾਵਾਂਗਾ ।ਈਮਾਨਦਾਰੀ ਨਾਲ ਖੱਟਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਰਤਨ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰਨ ਵਿਚ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਦੁੱਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਹਾਰਨਾ ਪਿਆ,ਤੇ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਸੌਦਾ ਮੈਂ ਸਹੀ ਸਲਾਮਤਿ ਸਾਂਭ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ-ਘਰ ਵਿਚ ਲੈ ਆਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਤੇਰੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਤੇਰੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ) ਲਾਭ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਨੰਦ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਪੂਰੀਆਂ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਸ਼ਾਂ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਸ਼ਾਹ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ! ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਸਲਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਹੇ ਭਾਈ! ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਨੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ) ਸੌਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ (ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਹੀ) ਨਾਨਕ ਭੀ ਇਹ ਲਾਹੇਵੰਦਾ ਸੌਦਾ ਖੱਟ ਸਕਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੬।\\""},{"question":"问题：油的营养价值如何？","answer":"回答：油是脂肪的重要来源，提供能量和必需脂肪酸，但摄入应适量控制，避免摄入过多的脂肪。"},{"question":"उदार विनिमय दर व्यवस्थापन प्रणाली (LERMS) कधी सुरू केली गेली?(A) 1992(B) 1980(C) 1989(D) 1991=>","answer":" (A) 1992"},{"question":"\\"Ny fanabeazana dia dingana iray fianarana sy fahazoana fahalalana, fahaiza-manao ary soatoavina. Matetika izany dia atao any amin'ny andrim-panjakana toy ny sekoly, ny oniversite  izay anarahan'ny mpianatra ny fandaharam-pianarana voarafitra. .\\"Inona no atao hoe fanabeazana ary aiza no misy azy matetika?","answer":" Ny fanabeazana dia dingan'ny fianarana sy fahazoana fahalalana, fahaizana ary soatoavina. Matetika any amin'ny andrim-panjakana toy ny sekoly, kolejy ary oniversite izany."},{"question":"Адам жүрүшүнөн — кул болот, ат жүрүшүнөн — пул болот.","answer":"Эгер адам баскан турганы жакшы болбосо, туура жүрүп, туура баспаса, анын даражасы түшүп, кор болот. Аттын басканы бузулуп, ээсине баш ийбей олку-солку боло берсе сатылып пул болот."},{"question":"Маргарита пиццасы кимдин ысымына койулган?","answer":"Маргарита пцюиццасы - ханыша (королева) Маргаританын ысымына коюлган."},{"question":"Zer da antropologian mitologia, eta nola ulertzen du gizarteek mundua ulertzeko sortutako istorioak?","answer":"Mitologia da gizarteek mundua ulertzeko sortutako istorioen bilketa. Mitologiak ulertzen ditu kulturaren baloreak, sinboloak eta tradizioak istorio mitologikoen bidez."},{"question":"Qui était l'artiste Vik Muniz ?","answer":"Vik Muniz, artiste visuel brésilien, est connu pour son utilisation innovante de matériaux non conventionnels, tels que le chocolat, le sucre et les déchets, pour créer des œuvres complexes et à grande échelle. Sa série « Pictures of Junk » réinterprète des peintures emblématiques à partir de matériaux mis au rebut, mettant en lumière les problèmes de déchets et de culture de consommation."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaan waxa ku waajibay qofkii ugu yeera qof kaali aan ciyaarne Qamaar?","answer":"Qofkii qof ugu jeera iney qamaaraan ama Qamaar ciyaaraan wuxuu bixinayaa saddaqo sida ka sugnaatay Nabiga (scw).    "},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 働きながら子どもを育てる人のために、子どもの食事を短い時間で作ることができる商品ができています。","answer":"ハウス食品グループは、1歳半から6歳ごろまでの子どものための冷凍食品を、1月から売っています。ハンバーグや魚の料理など12種類です。どの料理も野菜を5種類以上使っていて、子どもが食べやすい大きさや味にしてあります。商品は家などに届けてもらうため、買い物に行く必要がありません。 商品を作った会社の人は「子どもと一緒に遊ぶ時間がもっと長くなるといいと思って、作りました」と話しています。 江崎グリコは、赤ちゃんがすぐ飲むことができる液体ミルクを売っています。去年、今までより長い9か月使うことができるようにしました。会社は、買う人が増えたと言っています。"},{"question":"Manana ity teny nakorontanan ity ianao:ydivVinavinao ilay teny rehefa alamina","answer":"Ilay teny rehefa alamina dia \\"vidy\\""},{"question":"フランス語で「通り過ぎる」という意味の「passe(パッセ)」と、港を表す「port(ポール)」の合成語で、国外に出るときに必ず必要なものといえば何？","answer":"パスポートです。"},{"question":"ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ ਕੌਣ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ (ਜਨਮ: 11 ਜਨਵਰੀ 1973, ਉਮਰ 39 ਸਾਲ) ਭਾਰਤ ਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਸੇਵਾ ਮੁਕਤ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਖਿਡਾਰੀ ਹੈ। ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ ਨੇ ਹੁਣ ਤੱਕ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ 162 ਟੈਸਟ ਖੇਡੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਜਿਹਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ 52.82 ਦੀ ਔਸਤ ਨਾਲ 13,206 ਰਨ ਬਣਾਏ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ 36 ਸੈਂਕੜੇ ਅਤੇ 63 ਅਰਧ ਸੈਂਕੜੇ ਲਗਾਏ ਹਨ। ਟੈਸਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਨਿਜੀ ਸਕੋਰ 270 ਰਨ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨਾ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਕਟ ਤੋਂ ਸੰਨਿਆਸ ਲੈਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ ਨੇ 344 ਇੱਕ-ਦਿਨਾ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ 39.16 ਦੀ ਔਸਤ ਨਾਲ 10,889 ਰਨ ਬਣਾਏ ਹਨ। ਇੱਕ-ਦਿਨਾ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ 12 ਸੈਂਕੜੇ ਅਤੇ 83 ਅਰਧ ਸੈਂਕੜੇ ਦਰਜ ਹਨ।ਰਾਹੁਲ ਦ੍ਰਾਵਿੜ ‘ਦ ਵਾਲ’ ਯਾਨੀ ਕੰਧ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਨਾਲ ਮਸ਼ਹੂਰ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਧਰਤੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਦੂਸਰੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਟੈਸਟ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ 53.03 ਦੇ ਔਸਤ ਨਾਲ 7690 ਰਨ ਬਣਾਏ ਹਨ, ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਉਹ ਵੈਸਟ ਇੰਡੀਜ਼ ਦੇ ਬ੍ਰਾਇਨ ਲਾਰਾ ਅਤੇ ਆਸਟ੍ਰੇਲੀਆ ਦੇ ਰਿਕੀ ਪੋਂਟਿੰਗ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਪਰ ਹਨ।"},{"question":"کله کارمند د ترفیع لپاره وړ ګڼل کیږي؟","answer":"ځواب مامور په لاندې حالتو کي د ترفیع مستحق ګڼل کېږي .۱ – د ۳ ګاله بالفعل خدمت بشپړول ، ۲ – د ارزیابي د فورمې شتون ، ۳ – د لمړۍ درجه تقديرنامې اخيستل"},{"question":"යුරෝපයේ සාමාන්‍ය ජනගහනයට සාපේක්ෂව අධිකම පර්‍යේෂක ඝණත්වයක් හිමි ප්‍රදේශය කුමක්ද? ","answer":"යුරෝපයේ සාමාන්‍ය ජනගහනයට සාපේක්ෂව අධිකම පර්‍යේෂක ඝණත්වයක් හිමි ප්‍රදේශය වන්නේ ඉතාලියේ ට්‍රියෙස්තේ(Trieste) නුවරයි."},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਦੁੱਧ ਬਾਹਰ ਉਗਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਦੁੱਧ ਖੱਟਾ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੇਰਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਸੁੱਕ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਦੁੱਧ ਖੱਟਾ ਲੱਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một đoạn văn tối đa 500 chữ: Từ ngày mai (1-8): Xe không có ETC đi nhầm vào làn thu phí tự động có bị tước bằng lái?","answer":"Khoản 4 Điều 3 Quyết định 19/2020/QĐ-TTg nêu rõ, thu phí dịch vụ sử dụng đường bộ theo hình thức điện tử không dừng (ETC) là hình thức thu phí dịch vụ sử dụng đường bộ tự động, phương tiện giao thông đường bộ không cần phải dừng lại để trả phí dịch vụ sử dụng đường bộ khi tới trạm thu phí dịch vụ sử dụng đường bộ. Về mức phạt đối với các lỗi khi đi qua trạm thu phí ETC, tại điểm c khoản 4 Điều 5 Nghị định 100/2019/NĐ-CP, được sửa đổi bởi điểm b khoản 3, điểm d khoản 34 Điều 2 Nghị định 123/2021/NĐ-CP quy định, xe không đủ điều kiện để thu phí ETC đi vào làn đường dành riêng thu phí theo hình thức điện tử tự động không dừng tại các trạm thu phí gồm: Xe không gắn thẻ đầu cuối; Xe gắn thẻ đầu cuối mà số tiền trong tài khoản thu phí không đủ để chi trả khi qua làn thu phí điện tử tự động không dừng. Nếu có một trong các hành vi trên, người điều khiển phương tiện giao thông sẽ bị phạt tiền từ 2-3 triệu đồng. Ngoài ra, người điều khiển phương tiện khi đi sai vào làn thu phí điện tử không dừng tại các trạm thu phí còn bị áp dụng hình thức xử phạt bổ sung, là tước quyền sử dụng Giấy phép lái xe từ 1 - 3 tháng. Bên cạnh đó, các xe có gắn thẻ ETC, nhưng số tiền trong tài khoản thu phí không đủ để chi trả khi qua làn ETC thì người điều khiển ô tô sẽ bị phạt 2 - 3 triệu đồng và bị tước quyền sử dụng giấy phép lái xe từ 1 - 3 tháng. Về thủ tục mở tài khoản thu phí không dừng, Điều 10 Quyết định 19/2020/QĐ-TTg \\"Về việc thu phí dịch vụ sử dụng đường bộ theo hình thức điện tử không dừng\\" quy định, nhà cung cấp dịch vụ thu phí mở tài khoản thu phí cho chủ phương tiện trên hệ thống thu phí điện tử không dừng ngay lần đầu gắn thẻ đầu cuối. Mỗi tài khoản thu phí có thể sử dụng để chi trả cho nhiều phương tiện giao thông đường bộ; mỗi phương tiện giao thông đường bộ chỉ được nhận chi trả từ một tài khoản thu phí. Tài khoản thu phí được lưu trữ trên cơ sở dữ liệu của hệ thống thu phí điện tử không dừng, bao gồm các thông tin: Thông tin liên hệ của chủ phương tiện: Số chứng minh nhân dân, hoặc số thẻ căn cước công dân, hoặc số hộ chiếu; mã số doanh nghiệp, địa chỉ nơi cư trú hoặc địa chỉ trụ sở chính; số điện thoại liên lạc và địa chỉ hộp thư điện tử tiếp nhận chứng từ thu phí điện tử không dừng; Mã số định danh của phương tiện giao thông đường bộ được nhận chi trả từ tài khoản thu phí; Tải trọng phương tiện, số chỗ ngồi, loại xe, biển kiểm soát xe; Số tiền trong tài khoản, lịch sử giao dịch của tài khoản. Trong thời hạn tối đa 10 ngày, kể từ ngày nhận được thông tin thay đổi theo quy định tại Điểm a, Điểm c, Khoản 3 Điều này, chủ phương tiện phải thông báo cho nhà cung cấp dịch vụ thu phí để cập nhật trên hệ thống thu phí điện tử không dừng. Trong thời gian tối đa 5 ngày kể từ khi nhận được thông tin thay đổi quy định tại Điểm c, Khoản 3 Điều này, đơn vị đăng kiểm xe cơ giới phải cập nhật trên hệ thống đăng kiểm và nhà cung cấp dịch vụ thu phí phải cập nhật trên hệ thống thu phí điện tử không dừng. Theo H.L (An Ninh Thủ Đô) https://www.anninhthudo.vn/tu-ngay-mai-1-8-xe-khong-co-etc-di-nham-vao-lan-thu-phi-tu-dong-co-bi-tuoc-bang-lai-post512368.antd Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS"},{"question":"¿Qué es la existencia en filosofía y cómo se relaciona con la humanidad?","answer":"La existencia se refiere al hecho de estar presente o ser. Los filósofos a lo largo de la historia han explorado preguntas sobre la existencia humana, incluyendo cuestiones sobre el significado de la vida, el propósito y la autenticidad personal."},{"question":"Кийиктин пири кандай айтылат?","answer":"Кийиктин пири – Кайберен."},{"question":"අවුරුදු සියයක යුද්ධය කවදාද සහ එහි සටන් කළේ කවුද?","answer":"ඉංග්‍රීසි සහ ප්‍රංශ ජාතිකයන් 14 වැනි සියවසේ මැද භාගයේ සිට 15 වැනි සියවස දක්වා සටන් කළහ. ඉංග්‍රීසි රජු බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය දූපත් පමණක් නොව ප්‍රංශයේ නෝමන්ඩි ප්‍රදේශයේ රජකම් කළේය. (එය සිදු වූ ආකාරය පිළිබඳ කතාව සඳහා විලියම් ද ජයග්‍රාහකයා ගැන කියවන්න.) මෙම මහාද්වීපික පාදමේ ප්‍රතිඵලය වූයේ ඉංග්‍රීසි ජාතිකයන් බොහෝ දුරට ප්‍රංශයේ, බ්‍රිටනි සිට ප්‍රංශයේ දකුණට සහ නැගෙනහිරින් ෆ්ලැන්ඩර්ස් දෙසට සටන් කළ බවයි. මෙම කාලය තුළ සටන් කිරීම විශේෂයෙන් කුරිරු විය. \\"Men at Arms\\" යනු සම්පූර්ණ සන්නාහයෙන් සැරසී සිටි නයිට්වරුය. මෙම මිනිසුන් අතැති අයට සහය වූයේ හරස් දුනු (ප්‍රංශ පැත්තේ) සහ දුනුවායන්, ඉංග්‍රීසි වෝර් දුන්න භාවිතා කරමින්, ඉංග්‍රීසි පැත්තේ ය. යුධ දුන්න ඉතා බලවත් ආයුධයක් විය."},{"question":"இந்த உரை என்ன முக்கியமான நிகழ்வைப் பற்றியது: இதே நேரத்தில் இரண்டாம் உலகப் போர் மற்றும் கொரியப் போர் ஆகியவற்றின் மூலம் அமெரிக்க போர் வீரர்களிடம் இருந்து விருத்த சேதன முறை தென் கொரிய மக்களிடமும் பிரபலமானது.","answer":"கொரியப் போர்"},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি? ১৮৮৩ সালে রাষ্ট্রগুরু সুরেন্দ্রনাথ বন্দ্যোপাধ্যায় জাতীয় সম্মেলনের আয়োজন করেন। এটিই ছিল ঊনবিংশ শতাব্দীর ভারতের প্রথম রাজনৈতিক সম্মেলন। এরপর ধীরে ধীরে কলকাতা ভারতের স্বাধীনতা আন্দোলনের এক গুরুত্বপূর্ণ কেন্দ্রে পরিণত হয়। বিশেষত বিপ্লবী সংগঠনগুলির অন্যতম প্রধান কেন্দ্রে পরিণত হয় কলকাতা শহর। ১৯০৫ সালে সাম্প্রদায়িক ভিত্তিতে বঙ্গভঙ্গের প্রতিবাদে কলকাতায় ব্যাপক গণবিক্ষোভ ও ব্রিটিশ দ্রব্য বয়কট (স্বদেশী আন্দোলন) শুরু হয়। এই সব গণআন্দোলনের তীব্রতা এবং দেশের পূর্বভাগে অবস্থিত কলকাতা থেকে দেশ শাসনের প্রশাসনিক অসুবিধার কারণে ১৯১১ সালে ব্রিটিশ ভারতের রাজধানী দিল্লিতে স্থানান্তরিত করা হয়। ১৯২৩ সালে ক্যালকাটা মিউনিসিপ্যাল অ্যাক্টের অধীনে কলকাতার স্থানীয় স্বায়ত্তশাসন কর্তৃপক্ষ কলকাতা পৌরসংস্থা প্রতিষ্ঠিত হয়। ১৯২৪ সালে এই পৌরসংস্থার প্রথম মেয়র নির্বাচিত হন দেশবন্ধু চিত্তরঞ্জন দাশ। পরবর্তীকালে সুভাষচন্দ্র বসু, বিধানচন্দ্র রায়, আবুল কাশেম ফজলুল হক প্রমুখ বিশিষ্ট স্বাধীনতা সংগ্রামীরা এই পদ অলংকৃত করেছিলেন। দ্বিতীয় বিশ্বযুদ্ধ চলাকালীন জাপানি সেনাবাহিনী একাধিকবার কলকাতা শহর ও বন্দরে বোমা নিক্ষেপ করেছিল। কলকাতায় জাপানি বোমাবর্ষণের প্রথম ও শেষ ঘটনাটি ঘটে যথাক্রমে ১৯৪২ সালের ২০ ডিসেম্বর এবং ১৯৪৪ সালের ২৪ ডিসেম্বর। যুদ্ধের সময় কলকাতায় পঞ্চাশের মন্বন্তরে লক্ষাধিক মানুষ অনাহারে মারা যান। এই মন্বন্তরের কারণ ছিল সামরিক তাণ্ডব, প্রশাসনিক ব্যর্থতা ও প্রাকৃতিক দুর্যোগ। ১৯৪৬ সালে পৃথক মুসলিম রাষ্ট্র পাকিস্তানের দাবিতে এক ভয়ংকর সাম্প্রদায়িক দাঙ্গায় কলকাতায় চার হাজারেরও বেশি মানুষ প্রাণ হারান। ভারত বিভাগের সময়ও বহু মানুষ সাম্প্রদায়িকতার শিকার হন। দেশভাগের পর বহুসংখ্যক মুসলমান পূর্ব পাকিস্তানে পাড়ি জমান এবং সেই দেশের লক্ষ লক্ষ হিন্দু কলকাতায় চলে আসেন। এর ফলে শহরের জনপরিসংখ্যানে একটি বিরাট পরিবর্তন সূচিত হয়।","answer":"পঞ্চাশের মন্বন্তরে |"},{"question":"Responde la siguiente adivinanza: Cien amigos tengo, todos en una tabla. Si yo no los toco ellos no me hablan.","answer":"La respuesta es: el piano."},{"question":"Podgorica moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Podgorica moy péeyu réwum Monténégro"},{"question":"Inona no teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe \\"mando \\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe mando dia lena."},{"question":"E Shopping nedir?","answer":"E-ticaret, ürün ve hizmetleri internet üzerinden alıp satma işidir. E-ticaret müşterileri, bilgisayarlarından ve akıllı telefonlar, akıllı saatler ve Amazon Echo cihazları gibi dijital yardımcılar gibi diğer temas noktalarından alışveriş yapabilirler."},{"question":"පළමු FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය පැවැත්වූයේ කවදාද?","answer":"පළමු FIFA ලෝක කුසලානය 1930 දී සංවිධානය කරන ලදී."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Malásia?","answer":"A capital da Malásia é Kuala Lumpur."},{"question":"السؤال: للهاجد معنيان متضادان ما هما؟","answer":"الإجابة: الأول هو المصلي في الليل ، والثاني هو النائم."},{"question":"Y-a t-il des écoles d'architecture au Bénin?","answer":"Oui. Il y a beaucoup des Universités au Benin. Par exemple, l’Université nationale des sciences, technologies, ingénierie et mathématiques (UNSTIM) propose un bon programme d’architecture."},{"question":"Cuir an abairt seo a leanas i gcrích: Bhí Johnson le feiceáil i dhá chluiche ag Corn Domhanda FIFA 2006 agus ghlac sé páirt freisin i gCópa Meiriceá 2007 chomh maith leis an Cupa Óir 2007. ","answer":"I gcluiche oscailte Copa América na Stát Aontaithe i gcoinne na hAirgintíne bhuaigh sé agus ansin d'athraigh sé pionós chun na Stáit Aontaithe a chur ar aghaidh 1-0 i gcluiche a chaill siad 4-1."},{"question":"A = {2, 3, 4, 5, 6} అయిన Aకి గల ఉపసమితుల సంఖ్య ఎంత?","answer":"2^5= 32"},{"question":"Điền từ vào chỗ trống trong bài thơ \\"Mời trầu\\" sau của Hồ Xuân Hương để làm câu thơ có ý nghĩa và vần điệu.Quả cau (...) miếng trầu hôi,Này của Xuân Hương mới quệt rồi.Có phải duyên nhau thì thắm lại,Đừng xanh như lá, bạc như vôi.","answer":"đó là từ 'nho nhỏ'.Theo sách Giảng văn Văn học Việt Nam (Nhà xuất bản Giáo dục, 1998), Mời trầu gây ấn tượng với nhiều người bởi nó như một câu chuyện tâm tình. Đây bài thơ tứ tuyệt (bốn câu ba vần) rất hay và rất mẫu mực về cấu trúc, niêm luật và vần điệu."},{"question":"Quem Madonna beijou no VMA 2003?","answer":"Britney Spears e Christina Aguilera"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा सोप्या शब्दात अर्थ सांगा करावे तसे भरावे","answer":"जसे कृत्य असेल त्याप्रमाणे चांगलेवाईट फळ भोगावे लागते."},{"question":"පළල් පත්‍ර වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටියක් වන දිය ගෝවා ගැන කරුණු කියන්න.","answer":"පළල් පත්‍ර වර්ගයේ වල් පැළෑටියක් වන දිය ගෝවා ගැන කරුණු පහත දැක්වේ.විද්‍යාත්මක නම : Limnocharis foava busheanauකුලය : Limnocharieacaeලක්‍ෂණ  : වාර්ෂික / බහුවාර්ෂික ජලජ පළල් පත්‍ර ශාකයකි. ෙරෙසෝමය සහිතය. ධාවක කෙඳන් මුල් ඇති වී අළුත් පැළ ඇත වේ. මෙම වල් පැළෑටිය මීටර 0.5-1 පමණ උසට වැඩේ. මෙහි පත්‍ර පළල්, අණ්ඩාකාර, තරංගී නාරටි වින්‍යාසයක් සහ දිග ත්‍රිකෝණාකාර වෘන්තයක් සහිතය. එමෙන්ම පාදස්ථයේ පත්‍ර කොපු ඇත. මෙහි ප්‍රචාරණය සිදු වන්නේ ධාවක කෙඳන් සහ බීජ මඟිනි. තවද තෙත පරිසරයක් ඇති කුඹුරුවල, නොගැඹුරු ඇල දොල, වගුරු බිම් ආශ්‍රිතව දැකිය හැක."},{"question":"நவீன தாவரவியலின் தந்தை என அழைக்கபடுபவர்?","answer":"லின்னேயஸ்"},{"question":"Kodi mphare ya chimanga ndi yotani?","answer":"Choyamba, chimanga chouma chimaviikidwa m'madzi ndi laimu, nthawi zambiri amathira phulusa. Kenako amaphika, kumiza, kukhetsa, ndi kuchapa kangapo. Mbewuzo amazipeta n’kupanga ufa wonyowa umene umapangikako kapena kuumira kukhala ufa."},{"question":"问题：孔子的教育理念是什么？","answer":"答案：孔子的教育理念强调因材施教，他主张“有教无类”，认为教育应该面向所有人。"},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Mặc dù có diện tích rộng lớn, Greenland không có hệ thống đường bộ hay đường sắt liên kết giữa các khu định cư. Ở đây vẫn có những con đường trong thị trấn, tuy nhiên chúng kết thúc ở ngoại ô. Để di chuyển giữa các vùng, ","answer":"người dân chủ yếu sử dụng thuyền, xe trượt tuyết, xe chó kéo, trực thăng.Đại dương và các vịnh hẹp cung cấp hệ thống \\"đường cao tốc\\" rộng lớn nhất ở Greenland. Đó là lý do tại sao ở nhiều khu định cư nhỏ, bạn sẽ không thấy ôtô nhưng có rất nhiều thuyền neo đậu ở bờ biển."},{"question":"வினா :கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களை வைத்து மசால் வடை செய்வது குறித்த  செய்முறை விளக்கம் தருக.  தேவையான பொருட்கள்: 1.கடலை பருப்பு 1 கப் 2.பெரிய வெங்காயம் 3 3.பச்சை மிளகாய் 3  4.காய்ந்த மிளகாய் 2 5.பூண்டு பல் 4 6.இஞ்சி துண்டு 17.பட்டை துண்டு 18.சோம்பு 1 மேசை கரண்டி 9.தேவையான அளவு உப்பு10.தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்11.சிறிதளவு கருவேப்பிலை12.சிறிதளவு கொத்தமல்லி13.சிறிதளவு புதினா","answer":"விடை :செய்முறை விளக்கம்:1. முதலில் கடலை பருப்பை நன்கு கழுவி சுத்தம் செய்து அதை சுமார் 3 மணி நேரம் வரை ஊற வைக்கவும். பின்பு வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், இஞ்சி, கொத்தமல்லி, புதினா, மற்றும் கருவேப்பிலையை நறுக்கி, மற்றும் பூண்டை தட்டி எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு மின் அரவை எடுத்து அதில் சோம்பு, பட்டை, காய்ந்த மிளகாய், மற்றும் இஞ்சியை போட்டு அதை ஒரு சுற்று சுற்றி கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்பு அதில் நாம் ஊற வைத்திருக்கும் கடலை பருப்பை அரைத்து கொள்ளவும். இந்த பருப்பை கொரகொரப்பான பதத்திற்கு அரைத்தால் போதுமானது.  4. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் இந்த அரைத்த கலவையை போட்டு அதனுடன் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் வெங்காயம், பச்சை மிளகாய், தட்டி வைத்திருக்கும் பூண்டு,  கொத்தமல்லி, கருவேப்பிலை, புதினா, மற்றும் தேவையான அளவு உப்பை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கிளறி விடவும்.5. இந்த கலவையை நன்கு கிளறி விட்ட பின் அதிலிருந்து சிறிதளவு மாவை எடுத்து அதை உருண்டையாக உருட்டி பின்பு அதை கையில் வைத்து பக்குவமாக தட்டி  தட்டையான வடிவிற்க்கு மாற்றி ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.6.இவ்வாறு மீதமுள்ள மாவுகளையும் உருட்டி பின்பு தட்டி தயார் செய்து  வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.7. பின்னர் ஒரு கடாயில் எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும். மிதமான சூட்டில்  இந்த வடைகளை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுக்கவும்.இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Các cấp Công đoàn triển khai thực hiện Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW của Bộ Chính trị: Tinh thần đổi mới có ngay trong cách triển khai thực hiện","answer":"Công đoànDệt May Việt Nam tổ chức hội nghị triển khai hội nghị học tập, quán triệt Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW, ngày 12.6.2021 của Bộ Chính trị về \\"Đổi mới tổ chức và hoạt động của Công đoàn Việt Nam trong tình hình mới\\" theo hình thức trực tuyến tại 4 điểm cầu Hà Nội, TPHCM, Huế, Đà Nẵng. Có 156 Ủy viên Ban thường vụ, Ủy viên Ban Thường vụ, Ủy viên Ban Chấp hành, Uỷ viên Ủy Ban kiểm tra CĐ Dệt May Việt Nam, cán bộ, chuyên viên cơ quan CĐ Dệt May Việt Nam, Chủ tịch, phó Chủ tịch, cán bộ chuyên trách các CĐCS trực thuộc CĐ Dệt May Việt Nam tham gia. Để nội dung triển khai đến được đoàn viên, NLĐ, CĐ Dệt May Việt Nam tổ chức quay và dựng phim tường thuật Hội nghị trực tuyến học tập, nghiên cứu, quán triệt Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW của Bộ Chính trị và gửi đến 100% CĐCS để phát và tuyên truyền cho cán bộ đoàn viên, NLĐ. Bên cạnh đó CĐ ngành còn thực hiện riêng 01 số truyền thanh CĐ về chủ đề  \\"Đổi mới tổ chức và hoạt động của Công đoàn Việt Nam trong tình hình mới\\" bao gồm nội dung chính: Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW của Bộ Chính trị về \\"Đổi mới tổ chức và hoạt động của Công đoàn Việt Nam trong tình hình mới: 05 quan điểm chỉ đạo, 05 mục tiêu cụ thể và 06 nhiệm vụ giải pháp\\". Chương trình này được phát tại 100% CĐCS. Để mỗi đoàn viên, NLĐ hiểu và nắm được nội dung Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW, CĐ ngành đã thực hiện 01 infographic về các nội dung chính của Nghị quyết, sau đó đăng tải trên Cổng thông tin điện tử và trang Fanpage của CĐ ngành… Cán bộ CĐ phải hiểu sâu sắc về nội dung Nghị quyết số 02-NQ/TW Tại Hà Nam việc thực hiện Nghị quyết số 02/NQ-TW của Bộ chính trị bước đầu đã góp phần đổi mới nhiều hoạt động CĐ, thu hút đông hơn người lao động quan tâm tới tổ chức CĐ nói chung và CĐCS nói riêng tạo thuận lợi hơn trong công tác phát triển đoàn viên và thành lập CĐCS. "},{"question":"Чыңгыз Айтматов деп айтканда эле көз алдыңызга кайсы чыгармалар келет?","answer":"\\"Кылым карытар бир күн\\"\\"Гүлсарат\\"\\"Жамиля\\"\\"Биринчи мугалим\\"\\"Атадан калган туяк\\"\\"Делбирим\\"\\"Саманчынын жолу\\"\\"Эрте келген турналар\\"\\"Обон\\"\\"Бугу эне\\"\\"Чыпалак бала\\"\\"Кассандра тамгасы\\"\\"Жетинин бири\\"\\"Кыямат\\"\\"Ак кеме\\" ж.б.у.с"},{"question":"Sallar juma'a raka'a nawa ce","answer":"(a) biyu(b)uku(C) biyar"},{"question":"2వేల సంవత్సరాల క్రితం నుంచి బైగా తెగ మహిళలు పచ్చబొట్టు వేసుకుంటున్నారునేను పచ్చబొట్టు గురించి ఆలోచిస్తూనే పెరిగాను. చెవి, ముక్కు కుట్టడం కూడా మహిళల అణిచివేతకు చిహ్నాలుగానే భావిస్తాను.మా అమ్మ ఒంటిపై కొన్ని పచ్చబొట్లున్నాయి. మా అమ్మమ్మకు ఇంకా ఎక్కువున్నాయి. ఆనాడు టాటూలు వేయించుకోవడం మినహా తమకు మరో మార్గం లేకుండా పోయిందని వాళ్లు నాకు చెప్పారు.ఉత్తరప్రదేశ్‌లోని గ్రామీణ ప్రాంతాల్లో పెళ్లైన మహిళలు పచ్చబొట్టు వేసుకోవడం తప్పనిసరి. స్థానికంగా దాన్ని 'గొడ్న' అంటారు. మేము ఆ పల్లెల నుంచే వచ్చాం.పచ్చబొట్టు వేసుకోకుంటే అత్తింటివాళ్లు మేమిచ్చే నీళ్లు తాగరట. ఆహారం తీసుకోరట. పచ్చబొట్టు లేనివారిని అంటరానివారిగా చూస్తారట. ఇవన్నీ మా అమ్మే నాకు చెప్పింది. మా నాన్నకు పచ్చబొట్ల అవసరమే లేదు. ఎందుకని అమ్మను అడిగితే, అతను అమ్మాయి కాదుగా అని చెప్పింది.అమ్మకు చిన్నప్పుడే పెళ్లైంది. 1940లో పట్టుమని పదకొండేళ్లు కూడా లేని అమ్మకు పెళ్లి చేశారు. కొన్ని వారాల తర్వాత ఓ పెద్దావిడను పిలిపించి అమ్మకు పచ్చబొట్టు పొడిపించారు.పచ్చబొట్టు-చీకటి వారసత్వంపచ్చబొట్టు వేసుకోకుంటే ఏదోలా చూస్తారని మా అమ్మ చెప్పిందిసుమారు 7 దశాబ్దాల తర్వాత మా అమ్మ పచ్చబొట్టు కొంచెం చెరిగిపోయింది. కానీ చిన్నతనంలో టాటూ వేస్తున్నప్పుడు భరించిన బాధ ఆమె మనసులో ఇప్పటికీ అలాగే ఉంది.చేతులపై ఉన్న పచ్చబొట్టు డిజైన్‌ ఏంటో కూడా ఆమెకు తెలియదు. నాకు కూడా అదేంటో అర్థం కాలేదు. అది బహుశా 'పూల్-పత్తి' అయి ఉండొచ్చట. అంటే పూలు-ఆకులు అన్నమాట.ఫ్లోరా, ఫానా ఎక్కువ మంది ఇష్టపడే డిజైన్లని లక్నో యూనివర్శిటీలో సామాజిక శాస్త్రవేత్తగా పనిచేస్తున్న కియా పాండే చెప్పారు. గ్రామీణ భారతదేశంలో పచ్చబొట్లపై ఆమె విస్తృత పరిశోధన చేశారు.భర్తల పేర్లు, తండ్రుల పేర్లు కూడా ఎక్కువగా వాడతారు. ఊరి పేరు, తెగ ఆచార, సంప్రదాయాలు, దేవుళ్ల చిత్రాలు వంటి వాటిని కూడా పచ్చబొట్టుగా పొడిపించుకుంటారు. ప్రతి పల్లెలో టాటూలు వేయించుకున్న మహిళలు వందల సంఖ్యలో కనిపిస్తారని కియా పాండే చెప్పారు.ఈ పచ్చబొట్టు అర్థం ఏమిటో ఈమెకు తెలియదుకొన్ని గిరిజన తెగల్లో ఆడవాళ్లతో పాటు మగవాళ్లు కూడా పచ్చబొట్టు పొడిపించుకుంటారు. జీవించి ఉన్నప్పుడు, మరణం తర్వాత కూడా ఇదొక రకమైన గుర్తింపు చిహ్నమట. చనిపోయిన తర్వాత ఆత్మ స్వర్గానికో, నరకానికో వెళ్తుందని, ఎక్కడి నుంచి వచ్చారని అక్కడ అడుగుతారని ఒక కథ ప్రచారంలో ఉంది. అలాంటి సమయంలో పచ్చబొట్టు.గుర్తింపుnGive me a good title for the article above.","answer":"పచ్చబొట్టు వద్దంటున్న గిరిజన మహిళలు"},{"question":"முகக்குறிப்பால் அகக் குறயை அறிபவரை………………ஆக்கிக்கொள்ள வேண்டும்.அ) பகைஆ) நகைஇ) துணைஈ) இணை","answer":"இ) துணை"},{"question":"Latari bi ijamba ọkọ ṣe tun pa eeyan mẹjọ, awọn eeyan Akoko fẹhonu han","answer":"Ọgọọrọ awọn ọdọ ilu Akoko ni wọn jade lọsan-an ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, lati fẹhonu han ta ko bi ẹmi awọn eeyan ṣe n sọnu ninu ijamba ọkọ to n waye lemọ lemọ lagbegbe naa.Ọpọlọpọ wakati lawọn olufẹhonu naa fi di gbogbo ọna to wọ ilu Akungba ati Iwarọ Ọka Akoko pa, lai fun ẹnikẹni ninu awọn arinrin-ajo to fẹẹ gba oju ọna marosẹ ọhun laaye lati kọja.Ibinu lawọn ọdọ naa fi le awọn aṣoju gomina ipinlẹ Ondo ti Amofin Tunji Abayọmi ko sodi lati ṣabẹwo si ibi ti ijamba naa ti waye lalẹ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ọsẹ to kọja pada.Kọmisanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo, Ọgbẹni Bọlaji Salami, nikan ni wọn faaye gba ko gbe ọkọ rẹ kọja, gbogbo ọkọ awọn akọwọọrin rẹ to tẹle e ni wọn da pada.Gbogbo arọwa tí Kọmiṣanna feto ọgbin nipinlẹ naa, Gboyega Adefarati, pa fawọn ọdọ tinu n bi ọhun ko jọ bii ẹni wọ wọn leti rara, ohun ti wọn n ṣaa n tẹnumọ ni pe awọn ko fẹẹ ri awọn aṣoju Gomina Akeredolu ṣoju, wọn ni oun funra rẹ lawọn fẹ ko waa ba awọn sọrọ.Iṣẹlẹ yii lo mu kawọn alasẹ Fasiti naa tete kede titi ileewe ọhun pa lẹyẹ-o-ṣọka.Wọn ni awọn fun gbogbo awọn akẹkọọ naa di aago mẹfa irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ki olukuluku wọn fi pada sile rẹ."},{"question":"போரைத் தொடங்கும் நிகழ்வாகக் கருதப்படுவது …………………….அ) கோட்டை வளைத்தல்ஆ) போரிடல்இ) ஆநிரை கவர்தல்ஈ) கோட்டை காத்தல்","answer":"போரைத் தொடங்கும் நிகழ்வாகக் கருதப்படுவது …………………….இ) ஆநிரை கவர்தல்"},{"question":"Cadangkan langkah-langkah bagi menggelakkan rusuhan daripada berlaku.","answer":"Pengisytiharan perintah darurat akan dilakukan sekiranya berlakunya rusuhan untuk mengadakan perintah berkurung. Untuk mengelakkannya, dasar ekonomi dan sosial yang lebih baik harus digubal untuk mementingkan kebajikan dan kesejahteraan rakyat. Kita harus mementingkan perpaduan rakyat dan mencari penyelesaian melalui meja rundingan untuk menggelakkan tindakan kekerasan atau bersenjata."},{"question":"Tukarkan ayat aktif berikut kepada ayat pasif tanpa mengubah maksud asalnya.Ayat aktif: Persatuan Ibu bapa dan Guru (PIBG) sekolah itu akan mengadakan mesyuarat tergempar.","answer":"Ayat pasif yang betul ialah 'Mesyuarat tergempar akan diadakan di sekolah itu oleh Persatuan Ibu bapa dan Guru (PIBG).'"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?ලෝහ ","answer":"අලෝහ"},{"question":"Ayat 1: Dengan kata lain, \\"ingat kematian'' atau \\"ingat bahawa anda akan mati''. Ayat 2: Dengan kata lain, \\"ingat kematian'' atau \\"ingat bahawa anda akan mati''. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Ya, betul."},{"question":"මනා පෙනුමකින් යුත්  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"කඩවසම් "},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 先週、雨がたくさん降って、道に水がたまって川のようになった所がありました。愛知県では、30台以上の車が水の中で動くことができなくなりました。水がたまっている道に車が入ったときに、安全に逃げる方法を専門家に聞きました。水の高さが10cmぐらいになったら、高くて安全な所に運転して避難してください。水がひざの下ぐらいの高さになったら、車の外に出て安全な所に逃げます。水の高さが1mぐらいになると、車が浮いて流される危険があります。車に水が入ってドアや窓が開かなくなったら、窓のガラスを割って車の外に出ます。日本自動車連盟の人は「窓のガラスを割るために、ハンマーを用意しておいてください。ほかの物では窓のガラスを割ることができません。ハンマーは、運転している人の近くに置いておきましょう」と話しています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- たまっ: 1）集まって増える。2）お金や財産がふえる。3）後まで残る。- 方法: 1）ものごとを行うやり方。しかた。- 避難: 1）危ない目にあわないように、にげること。- ひざ: 1）ももと、すねのつなぎ目にある、関節の前側の部分。2）すわったときの、ももの上の部分。- 浮い: 1）水の上にある。沈んでいたものが、水の上に出る。うかぶ。2）地面から離れて、空中にある。3）表面に現れる。4）心がはずむ。5）お金や時間の余りが出る。6）しっかりとくっついていない。7）相手にされなくなる。- 流さ: 1）液体などが低いほうへ動くようにする。2）水などにうかべて動かす。3）よごれを洗い落とす。4）うわさなどを広める。5）予定していたことを、取りやめる。6）そのことを気に留めない。- 割っ: 1）一つのものをいくつかに分ける。2）こわす。くだく。3）混ぜてうすめる。4）ありのままをかくさずに言う。5）外に出る。6）ものごとがある数量より下になる。7）割り算をする。記号は「÷」。- 割る: 1）大型の金づち。2）ハンマー投げに使う道具。鉄の玉に鉄の線のついたもの。"},{"question":"नेपालको पुरानो नाम के हो ?","answer":"गोरखा राज्यको विजयद्वारा स्थापना भएको हुनाले एकीकरणपछिको प्रारम्भिक दिनहरूमा नेपाल \\"गोरखा राज्य\\" वा \\"गोरखा साम्राज्य\\" को रूपमा चिनिन्थ्यो।"},{"question":"හමස් පෙට්ටිය යනු කුමක්ද? ","answer":"බොහෝ දෙනෙකු එය මාස හයකින් විවෘත කරනා  පෙට්ටියක් යන අරුත දී ඇත.හමස්කාලය යනු පොල්පලදාව අඩු කාලයටද යෙදෙන්නකි. අතීතයේදී සේවකයින්ට වැටුප් ගෙවූයේ හමසකට වරක් හෙවත් මාස හයකට වරක් බව කියවේ. එය හැඳින්වූයේ ඡම්මාසික වේතන නමිනි. එම වේතනය දෙනු සඳහා මුදල් රැස්කර තිබූ පෙට්ටිය හමස් පෙට්ටියයි. අද වන විට අරුත වෙනස් වී ඇත. "},{"question":"Inona no dikan’ny teny hoe “foana”?","answer":"Ny dikany teny hoe “foana” dia ilazana zavatra tsy misy na zavatra poakaty tany ampiandohana."},{"question":"O que significa o ditado popular: \\"Quanto mais alto, maior a queda\\"?","answer":"Provérbio usado para designar pessoas soberbas, que se acham superiores às demais.Exemplo: “Aquele diretor não olha na cara de ninguém.” “Eu prefiro nem ligar. Quanto mais alto, maior a queda.”"},{"question":"Мээнеткеч адам жөнүндө жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Мээнеткеч адам өзүн-өзү шыктандырып турат. Ал эми жалкоону сырттан шыктандырып, жөндөп туруу керек.Адатта мээнеткеч адам өзүнүн күчүн сынап, көргөзөйүн деп кызматына чын ыкласы менен берилет. Ыкшоо адамды улам кызыктырып, чөйрөсү мактап турушу керек."},{"question":"Raadsel: Een vrouw zit midden in de nacht in de woonkamer. Er brand geen enkel licht. Het is helemaal donker. Toch leest ze een boek. Hoe kan dat? ","answer":"De reden is dat de vrouw blind is en een brailleboek leest."},{"question":"ਆਮ ਲੋਕ ਤਕਰੀਬਨ ਏਨਾ ਕੁ ਜਾਣਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਵਧੀਆ ਅਦਾਕਾਰ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ 135 ਦੇ ਲਗਪਗ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਨਿਵੇਕਲੀ ਛਾਪ ਛੱਡਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਿਭਾਏ। ਉਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤੀਆਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ਮਕਬੂਲ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਪਰ ਇਹ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਏਨਾ ਟੇਢਾ ਮੇਢਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘਰਸ਼ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਕਿਆਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ। ਪੰਜਾਬੀਅਤ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਤਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਜਨਮ ਇੱਕ ਮਈ 1913 ਨੂੰ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਵਿਖੇ ਹੋਇਆ। ਪੁਰਖਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਪਿੰਡ ਭੇਰਾ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ, ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਦੇ ਬੜੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਹਰਬੰਸ ਲਾਲ ਸਾਹਨੀ ਅਤੇ ਸ੍ਰੀਮਤੀ ਲਕਸ਼ਮੀ ਦੇਵੀ ਦਾ ਪੰਜਾਂ ਧੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਜੰਮਿਆ ਪੁੱਤਰ ਸੀ। ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ ਯੁਧਿਸ਼ਟਰ ਸੀ ਪਰ ਨਾਂ ਲੈਣਾ ਔਖਾ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਘਰ ਦਾ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਵੀ ਸਖ਼ਤ ਮਨ੍ਹਾ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਨੂੰ 'ਗੁਰੂਕਲ ਪੋਠੋਹਾਰ' ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਨੇ ਪਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਫਿਰ ਚੌਥੀ ਜਮਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਸਕੂਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਾਖਲ ਕਰਵਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਲ1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਡੀ.ਏ.ਵੀ. ਕਾਲਜ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਤੋਂ ਇੰਟਰਮੀਡੀਏਟ ਪਾਸ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਸ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੋਫੈਸਰ ਜਸਵੰਤ ਰਾਏ ਨਾਲ ਸੰਪਰਕ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਭੈਣ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦਾ 1936 ਵਿੱਚ ਵਿਆਹ ਹੋਇਆ।ਸਾਲ 1930 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਲਹੌਰ ਦਾਖਲ ਹੋਇਆ ਜਿੱਥੋਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਕਾਲਜ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਹਾਣੀਆਂ ਲਿਖੀਆਂ।  ਗੌਰਮਿੰਟ ਕਾਲਜ ਵਿੱਚ ਪੜ੍ਹਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਯਥਾਰਥਵਾਦੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਲੱਗਾ, ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪਾਤਰ ਸੁਭਾਵਕ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਲਹਿਜ਼ੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਦੇ ਸਨ। ਪਾਰਸੀ ਰੰਗਮੰਚ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਚੱਲਤ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ ਕਰਦੇ। ਸੰਨ 1934 ਵਿੱਚ ਲਾਹੌਰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਦੀ ਐਮ.ਏ. ਕਰਨ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਾਪਸ ਰਾਵਲਪਿੰਡੀ ਆ ਗਿਆ ਤੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨਾਲ ਵਪਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੱਗ ਪਿਆ। ਇਨ੍ਹੀਂ ਦਿਨੀਂ ਹੀ ਦਵਿੰਦਰ ਸਤਿਆਰਥੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਹੀਨਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਘਰ ਰਿਹਾ। ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਵਪਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਉਕਤਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਈ ਨਵੀਂ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਅੰਗੜਾਈਆਂ ਲੈ ਰਹੀ ਸੀ।  ਫਿਰ ਓਧਰੋਂ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਕੁੱਖੋਂ ਵੱਡਾ ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮੀਆਂ ਬੀਵੀ ਨਾਟਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ  ਦਿਲਚਸਪੀਆਂ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਰਹੇ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਆਪਣਾ ਬੋਰੀਆ ਬਿਸਤਰਾ ਵਲ੍ਹੇਟ ਕੇ ਕਲਕੱਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਤੁਰ ਪਏ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਰਵਿੰਦਰ ਨਾਥ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕਰ ਲਈ। ਉੱਥੇ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹਾ ਵਾਤਾਵਰਣ ਸੀ, ਸੋਹਣਾ ਤੇ ਨਾਲ ਸਨ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਵਰਗੀ ਰੂਹ ਦੇ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ। ਉੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਹੋਰਾਂ ਬਰਨਾਰਡ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ ਨਾਟਕ 'ਆਰਮਜ਼ ਐਂਡ ਦੀ ਮੈਨ' ਖੇਡਿਆ। ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਨਿਕੇਤਨ ਦੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਖਾਸ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਰਹੀ ਕਿ ਟੈਗੋਰ ਨੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਮਾਂ ਬੋਲੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਿਖਣ ਲਈ ਪ੍ਰੇਰਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1940 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਅਤੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਇੰਗਲੈਂਡ ਲਈ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਗਏ, ਜਿੱਥੇ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੇ ਚਾਰ ਸਾਲ ਬੀ.ਬੀ.ਸੀ. ਲੰਡਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨੌਕਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ। ਇਹ ਉਹ ਸਮਾਂ ਸੀ ਜਦ ਰੋਜ਼ਾਨਾ ਜਰਮਨ ਜੰਗੀ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਲੰਡਨ ਉਤੇ ਬੰਬਾਰੀ ਕਰਦੇ ਸਨ। ਬੇਟਾ ਪ੍ਰੀਕਸ਼ਤ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਦਾਦਾ-ਦਾਦੀ ਕੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ। ਜਦ ਬਲਰਾਜ 1944 ਵਿੱਚ ਲੰਡਨ ਤੋਂ ਮੁੜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਜੰਗ ਦੀ ਭਿਆਨਕਤਾ ਵੇਖ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਕਲਾ ਨੂੰ ਸਮਾਜਿਕ ਤਬਦੀਲੀ ਨਾਲ ਜੋੜ ਕੇ ਵੇਖਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਬੰਬੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ ਚੇਤਨ ਆਨੰਦ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੋਲ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਉੱਥੇ ਉਹ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਪੀਪਲਜ਼ ਥੀਏਟਰ ਐਸੋਸੀਏਸ਼ਨ (ਇਪਟਾ) ਦਾ ਸਰਗਰਮ ਆਗੂ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਬਣ ਗਿਆ, ਜੋ ਨਾਟਕ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਲਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਦਾ ਹਥਿਆਰ ਸਮਝਦੀ ਸੀ।ੇ ਦਮਯੰਤੀ ਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਉਪਰੰਤ ਆਪਣੇ ਆਪ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਫਿਟਕਾਰਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਸਕਿਆ। ਸਾਲ 1949 ਵਿੱਚ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਭੂਆ ਦੀ ਕੁੜੀ ਸੰਤੋਸ਼ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਇਆ। ਵਿਆਹ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਗ੍ਰਿਫਤਾਰ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ। ਇਨਕਲਾਬੀ ਨਾਟਕੀ ਸਰਗਰਮੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਛੇ ਮਹੀਨੇ ਜੇਲ੍ਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਜ਼ਾਰੇ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ  ਕੀ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਬਲਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਨਾਂ ਯੁਧਿਸ਼ਟਰ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"Iza no emperora frantsay voalohany?","answer":"Napoléon Bonaparte no emperora Frantsay voalohany."},{"question":"Awọn ajinigbe wọle lọọ ji ọba alaye gbe laafin rẹ l’Ekiti","answer":"Awọn ajinigbe to n ṣọṣẹ nipinlẹ Ekiti lọwọlọwọ ti gba ọna mi-in yọ bayii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe kọ lu aafin Ọbadu tilu Ilẹmẹṣọ-Ekiti, Ọba David Oyewumi, ti wọn si ji kabiyesi naa gbe.Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ aabọ Ọjọru, Tọsidee, niṣẹlẹ naa waye niluu naa to wa nijọba ibilẹ Ọyẹ.Gẹgẹ bi a ṣe gbọ, niṣe lawọn agbebọn naa fo fẹnsi aafin wọle lẹyin tawọn oloye ti wọn waa ṣepade ti lọ sile, bẹẹ ni wọn da ibọn bolẹ lati ko awọn ti wọn ba nibẹ ni papamọra. Lẹyin eyi ni wọn bẹrẹ si i beere ọba alaye naa, ti wọn si n fiya jẹ awọn ti wọn ri, eyi to tumọ si pe oun gan-an ni wọn n wa.Bi wọn ṣe ri kabiyesi la gbọ pe wọn gbe e, wọn si wọ ọ kuro laafin lọ sibi ti ẹnikẹni ko mọ di akoko yii.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ, ASP Sunday Abutu to jẹ Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti sọ pe nnkan to ba ni lọkan jẹ gbaa ni, ati pe ibọn tawọn eeyan ọhun fi waa ṣọṣẹ lagbara pupọ.O waa ni iwadii ti bẹrẹ, ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa yoo si wa gbogbo ọna lati gba Ọba Oyewumi silẹ lọwọ awọn ajinigbe, ati lati mu awọn ọdaran naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ko ti i pe ọsẹ kan tawọn agbebọn kọ lu Elewu tilu Ewu-Ekiti, Ọba Adetutu Ajayi, lasiko to n lọ si Ayetoro-Ekiti lati ilu ẹ, ṣe ni wọn si yinbọn fun un lọwọ, ẹsẹ ati ikun lasiko to n gbiyanju lati sa fun wọn, eyi to sọ ọ dero ileewosan."},{"question":"Trả lời các câu hỏi sau:a) Hãy nêu các số nguyên tố nhỏ hơn 30.b) Tìm một ước nguyên tố của 91.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Theo phần \\"Có thể em chưa biết\\" (Trang 43/SGK), các số nguyên tố nhỏ hơn 30 là: 2; 3; 5; 7; 11; 13; 17; 19; 23; 29.b) Trước tiên ta tìm các ước của số 91 bằng cách lấy 91 lần lượt chia cho các số tự nhiên từ 1 đến 91, ta được các ước của 91 là: 1; 7; 13; 91, trong đó có 7 và 13 là các số nguyên tố. Vậy các ước nguyên tố của 91 là: 7 và 13. Do đó ta trả lời: \\"Một ước nguyên tố của 91 là 7\\" hoặc \\"Một ước nguyên tố của 91 là 13\\". "},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Georgia O'Keefe. ","answer":"Ealaíontóir Meiriceánach ab ea Georgia Totto O'Keeffe (15 Samhain 1887 - 6 Márta 1986). Bhí aithne uirthi as a cuid pictiúr den ábhar neamhbheo, Nua-Eabhrac, agus tírdhreacha i Nua-Mheicsiceo. Tá O’Keeffe aitheanta mar “Máthair an nua-aoiseachais Meiriceánach”. Rugadh Georgia O'Keeffe ar 15 Samhain, 1887, i dteach feirme i Sun Prairie, Wisconsin. Feirmeoirí déiríochta ab ea a tuismitheoirí, Francis Calyxtus O'Keeffe agus Ida (Totto) O'Keeffe. Ba de shliocht na hÉireann a hathair. Ungárach ab ea a seanathair ar thaobh a máthar, George Victor Totto, a tháinig go dtí na Stáit Aontaithe i 1848. As a seanathair sin a baisteadh í. Ba é O’Keeffe an dara duine as seachtar leanbh. D’fhreastail sé ar Scoil Halla an Bhaile i Sun Prairie. Agus in aois 10 di, bhí cinneadh déanta aici a bheith ina healaíontóir, agus lena deirfiúracha, Ida agus Anita, d’fhoghlaim sí ealaín ó uiscedhathanna áitiúla. D’fhreastail O’Keeffe ar an meánscoil Sacred Heart Academy i Madison, Wisconsin, mar scoláire cónaithe idir 1901 agus 1902. Níos déanaí sa bhliain 1902, bhog muintir O'Keeffe ó Wisconsin go dtí Peacock Hill i Williamsburg, Virginia. D’fhan O’Keeffe i Wisconsin lena haintín ag freastal ar Madison Central High School."},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto : Este es el primer terremoto en alcanzar un nível 7 en la escala de terremotos de Japón desde el terremoto de 2011... ","answer":"Que dejó 18.000 muertos y un desastre nuclear en la central de Fukushima."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:સફેદ ફૂલ ને કેસરી દાંડી વાતાવરણને મહેકાવતા જાય રાત જતી ને સુવાસ લઈને નવી સવાર આવતી જાય","answer":"પારિજાત"},{"question":"Noufissa Benchehida","answer":"Noufissa Benchehida (tí wọ́n bí ní 23 Oṣù Kẹẹ̀wá Ọdún 1975) jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Mòrókò.Wọ́n bí Benchehida ní Mòrókò ní ọdún 1975. Ó fẹ́ràn eré sinimá láti ìgbà èwe rẹ̀. Ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ ní ilé-ìwé Cours Florent tí ó wà ní ìlú Paris. Benchehida gba oyè-ẹ̀kọ́ nínu ìmọ́ eré-ìtàgé láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga Conservatory of Casablanca, bẹ́ẹ̀ ló sì tún lọ sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Ecole supérieure d'hôtellerie et de tourisme à Montpellier.Benchehida kó àkọ́kọ́ ipa fíìmù rẹ̀ ní ọdún 2004 nínu eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Syriana tí olùdarí rẹ̀ síì n ṣe Stephane Cagan. Ó di gbajúmọ̀ lẹ́hìn tí ó kó ipa Zineb Hejjami gẹ́gẹ́ bi ọlọ́pàá nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ El kadia ní ọdún 2006. Ó sọ di mímọ̀ wípé òun gbádùn kíkó ipa náà ṣùgbọ́n òun kò fẹ́ láti máa ṣe irúfẹ̀ ipa bẹ́ẹ̀ ní gbogbo ìgbà, àti pé òun fẹ́ láti kópa nínu àwọn eré oníjà. Bákan náà ní ọdún 2006, ó kópa nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Moulouk Attawaif. Ní ọdún 2011, Benchehida kó ipa olú-ẹ̀dá-ìtàn nínu eré Agadir Bombay, gẹ́gẹ́ bi obìnrin kan tí ó n ṣe àgbàwí fún àwọn obìnrin ẹgbẹ́ rẹ̀. Myriam Bakir ló darí eré náà. Ní ọdún 2015, ó kópa nínu fíìmù Aida.Ní ọdún 2016, Benchehida kópa nínu eré tí àkólẹ́ rẹ̀ jẹ́ A la recherche du pouvoir perdu (\\"Ṣíṣe àwárí agbára tí ó sọnù\\"), èyí tí Mohammed Ahed Bensouda darí. Iṣé takuntakun rẹ̀ nínu eré náà ló fun ńi àmì-ẹ̀yẹ ti Golden Sotigui níbi ayẹyẹ Sotigui Awards ti ọdún 2017. Benchehida tún gba àmì-ẹ̀yẹ òṣèrébìnrin tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ Panafrican Film and Television Festival of Ouagadougou.Benchehida maá n sọ èdè Faransé, èdè Lárúbáwá àti èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì."},{"question":"Sunday ọlọkada gbe ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun pẹlu ibọn n’Ijẹbu-Ode, ni wọn ba ko sọwọ ọlọpaa","answer":"Sunday olokada ati ero to gbeBo tilẹ jẹ pe Sunday Francis, ọlọkada ẹni ọdun mejidinlogoji (38) n’Ijẹbu-Ode, sọ pe oun ko mọ ero toun gbe lọsẹ to kọja lọhun-un ri, iyẹn Qudus Giwa, ṣugbọn ko jiyan nipa ibọn ti ero naa gbe sinu apo, o lo sọ foun pe bajinatu loun n ru kiri laṣaalẹ, laago mẹsan-an alẹ ọjọ naa.Ibọn ṣakabula to gun gbọọrọ kan ni Qudus Giwa, ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlọgbọn (27) ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun Ẹiyẹ, gbe sinu apo lalẹ ọjọ kẹtala, oṣu kẹfa, n’Ijẹbu-Ode.Alaye to ṣe fun ALAROYE ni pe wọn n ja laduugbo oun lalẹ ọjọ naa, oun gẹgẹ bii ọmọ Ẹiyẹ si fẹẹ sa kuro laduugbo, nitori oun mọ pe wahala naa yoo kan oun.Qudus sọ pe nibi toun ti n fi adugbo silẹ loun ti ri Sunday ọlọkada, loun ba ni ko gbe oun lọ si Idọwa, pe oun fẹẹ ri ẹnikan nibẹ.O ni nigba tawọn n lọ loun ṣalaye fun Sunday pe jagamu, (ibọn) lo wa ninu apo toun gbe dani, oun si fẹẹ sa lọ ni. Akọroyin wa beere pe ṣe o ti mọ ọlọkada naa ri tẹlẹ ni, Qudus si dahun pe bẹẹ ni.‘Mo sọ fun wọn pe ile wọn (ile Sunday) ni ma a sun tilẹ ba ṣu ju, Idọwa lawọn naa n gbe, mo ṣalaye fun wọn pe awọn ti wọn n ja yẹn ko ni i mọ pe ile wọn ni mo sun, wọn o dẹ ni i le waa mu mi.‘Nibi ta a ti n lọ lawọn ọlọpaa ti da wa duro, a gbiyanju lati sa lọ, ṣugbọn wọn ri wa mu, bi wọn ṣe ko wa lọ si teṣan niyẹn.’ Bẹẹ ni Qudus Giwa ṣalaye tiẹ.Ṣugbọn Sunday loun ko mọ Qudus ri, ‘ilẹ to ti ṣu lo jẹ ki n gbe e lọjọ yẹn. Mo ti ṣiwọ iṣẹ lọjọ naa, mo n lọ sile ni, n’Idọwa, iyẹn ni mo ṣe gbe e. Nigba to dẹ sọ nnkan to gbe dani fun mi, ko si nnkan ti mo le ṣe si i, ba a ṣe n lọ naa niyẹn tawọn ọlọpaa fi mu wa.’Atimọle awọn SARS lawọn mejeeji wa lasiko ti a pari akojọpọ iroyin yii, CP Kenneth Ebrimson si ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn gbe wọn lọ si kootu lẹyin awọn iwadii ti yoo fidi otitọ mulẹ."},{"question":"Kí ni bùdá tí ó ń fi iye sílébù hàn nínú ọ̀rọ̀?","answer":"Ègé ni."},{"question":"এক ভদ্রলোককে একটি ছেলে তার বয়স জিজ্ঞেস করেছিল। তিনি উত্তর দিলেন এ রকম করে,\\"তোর যে দিনে জন্ম তখন আমার বয়সখানি,এখনকার তোর বয়সের সমান ছিল জানি।আরও বলি হোক না ক্রমে চৌদ্দ বছর গত,তোর বয়সটি হবে আমার এই বয়সের মতো।\\"ভদ্রলোকটির বয়স কত?","answer":"ভদ্রলোকটির বয়স ২৮ বছর।ভদ্রলোকটি কবিতার ছন্দে বলেছেন যে ছেলেটির এখন যে বয়স, ছেলেটির যখন জন্ম হয় তখন ভদ্রলোকের বয়স ছিল সেটা। তিনি আরও বলেছেন, ভদ্রলোকের এখন যা বয়স, ১৪ বছর পরে ছেলেটির বয়স হবে সেটা।তাই, বলা যায় ছেলেটির বয়স ১৪ বছর এবং ভদ্রলোকের বয়স ২৮ বছর। ছেলেটির যখন জন্ম হয় তখন ভদ্রলোকের বয়স ছিল ১৪ বছর এবং ১৪ বছর পরে ছেলেটির বয়স হবে ২৮ বছর তথা ভদ্রলোকের বর্তমান বয়সের সমান।"},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--नागिन पोसली आणि पोसणाराला डसली\\t","answer":"वाईट गोष्ट जवळ बाळगल्या वर ती कधी ना कधी उलटतेच"},{"question":"විශද යන්නෙහි තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"විශද යන්නෙහි අර්ථය වන්නේ දීප්තියෙන් ආලෝකමත් කරන යන්නයි.උදාහරණයක්: බුදු දහමින් විශදවන ජීවන දර්ශනය"},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ny tany efitra mafana indrindra eran-tany, any Afrika Avaratra indrindra?","answer":"Ny Sahara no tany efitra mafana indrindra eran-tany, mamakivaky firenena maromaro any Afrika Avaratra."},{"question":"اين مقاله را در يک جمله خلاصه کنید: \\"با بخار، پاک کردن لکه های مختلفی از بدن خارج میشود. اگر بعد از تمیز کردن با بخار هنوز لکه های باقی مانده ای دارید، چند راه وجود دارد که می توانید با آنها مقابله کنید. اول با ساده ترین گزینه شروع کنید، که صابون و آب است. يه اسفنج بگيرید و توي آب بگذارید. يک مقدار مواد شوینده ظرف روی اسفنج بگذارید و ان را مسااژ دهید. آب اضافه اسفنج را بگیرید و لکه را با اسفنج پاک کنید طوریکه لکه با مخلوط صابونی پوشیده شود. بعد، صابون را از اسفنج پاک کنید و آب تازه را در اسفنج بگذارید. اسفنج را بردارید و منطقه صابونی را پاک کنید تا صابون و لکه را از سطح خارج کنید. مطمئن شوید که لکه را با اسفنج زياد پاک نميکنيد.نباید با زياد زورزدن پارچه را پاره کنيد. به جاي آب و صابون، مي توانيد از سرکه براي پاک کردن لکه ها استفاده کنيد. سرکه سفید یا سیب را بردارید و یک پارچه را خیس کنید. لکه رو با پارچه پاک کنید و پارچه را با سرکه اشباع کنید. مطمئن شوید که خیلی به پارچه ضربه نمیزنید تا لکه بیشتر نشود و به پارچه آسیب زده نشود. می توانید لکه را با پارچه به صورت دایره ای به آرامی مالش دهید تا ذرات لکه را با پارچه از بین ببرید. اگه سرکه ندارید میتوانید از وودکا هم استفاده کنید. وقتي پارچه خشک بشود، بوي هرکدامشان از بين ميرود. اگر هیچ یک از روش های دیگر برای تمیز کردن لکه کار نکند، ممکن است لازم باشد که یک پاک کننده سنگین تجاری مانند Tuff Stuff، Resolve یا Folex را امتحان کنید. یه پارچه یا اسفنج بردارید و آنرا خیس کنید. مواد پاک کننده را مستقیماً روی پارچه پاشید و از پارچه برای پاک کردن لکه استفاده کنید. همچنین می توانید با حرکات دایره ای به آرامی محل را مالش دهید تا باعث کاهش لکه شود. مطمئن شوید که پاک کننده را روی بخشی از پوشش که به طور معمول قابل مشاهده نیست تست می کنید. اگر ميخواهید مطمئن بشيوید که پاک کننده به پارچه آسيب نميزند، اگر لکه ي قهوه يا شرابي داريد، شراب را امتحان کنید. اين براي درمان لکه هاي سياه مايع ساخته شده است. اگر لکه هنوز سرسخت است، ممکن است مجبور باشید تا به طور کامل پاک کنید، یک دور دیگر از تمیز کردن را انجام دهید.\\"  خلاصه:","answer":"میتوانید لکه را با بخار، آب و صابون، سرکه پاک کنید. اگر نشد، از پاک کننده های سنگین استفاده کنید."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是語言學中的「語音學」？","answer":"答案：語音學是研究語音聲音和語音產生過程的學科。它涉及語音聲音的物理特性、聲音的產生和傳播、語音聲學分析和語音調查等，用於研究不同語言的語音系統和語音變異。"},{"question":"भारत में साइमन कमीशन का स्वागत कैसे किया गया? ","answer":"भारत में सरकार के कामकाज को देखने और संवैधानिक सुधारों का सुझाव देने के लिए साइमन कमीशन का गठन किया गया था।  लेकिन भारत के नेताओं ने इसका पुरजोर विरोध किया। साइमन कमीशन का विरोधसमस्या यह थी कि आयोग में एक भी भारतीय सदस्य नहीं था।  वे 7 सदस्य थे लेकिन सभी गोरे यानी अंग्रेज थे।  भारतीयों ने इसे अपने आत्मनिर्णय के अधिकार का उल्लंघन और अपने स्वाभिमान के अपमान के रूप में देखा। 1928 में जब साइमन कमीशन भारत आया तो लोगों ने ‘साइमन वापस जाओ’ के नारे के साथ अभिवादन करके अपना विरोध दिखाया।  प्रदर्शनों में कांग्रेस और मुस्लिम लीग सहित सभी दलों ने भाग लिया।"},{"question":"வினா:எந்த விலங்கின் பால் இளஞ்சிவப்பு நிறத்தில் இருக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: நீர்யானை"},{"question":"问题：朝鲜的文化特色有哪些？","answer":"答案：朝鲜的文化特色包括传统舞蹈、音乐、绘画和曲艺等。"},{"question":"Inona izany fanahy?","answer":"Fitambaran’ny fihetsika vokatry ny retsika tsapan’ny olombelona ny fanahy"},{"question":"如何开始学习Spring Boot？","answer":"学习Spring Boot有很多途径。你可以通过在线教程、书籍或者视频教程开始学习。在开始学习Spring Boot之前，最好已经有一些Java和Spring框架的基础知识。同时，实践也是非常重要的，你可以在学习过程中尝试创建自己的Spring Boot应用。"},{"question":"भानुभक्त आचार्यको जन्म कहिले र कहाँ भएको थियो ?","answer":"भानुभक्त आचार्यको जन्म वि.सं. १८७१ असार २९ (सन् १८१४ जुलाई १३) मा चुण्डी रामघामा भएको थियो ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'ilmu pelita hati'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud ilmu pengetahuan menjadi panduan untuk membuat keputusan yang bijak."},{"question":"\\"Кыйын кезең\\" чыгармасынын темасы эмне?","answer":"\\"Кыйын кезең\\" чыгармасынын темасы он алтынчы жылкы Улуу үркүн окуясы, андан кийинки жылдардагы кыргыз элинин турмушу, ата-энесинен жетим калган жаш жеткинчектердин татаал турмушу, тагдыры. \\"Кыйын кезең\\", \\"Ажар\\" ошондой эле \\"Зарыгам\\", \\"Ала-Тоо\\" чыгармалары бири бирине үндөшүп, жалпы Үркүн темасын берип турат. К. Тыныстанов, К. Баялинов, М. Элебаевдин бул чыгармалары турмуштун чоң бурулушуна кептелген эл турмушу, анын ичинде кыргыз жаштарынын ар түрдүү кыйын, оор шарттагы абалы Үркүн темасы аркылуу берилет. "},{"question":"Quem foi Plutarco?","answer":"Plutarco, ou Lúcio Méstrio Plutarco, foi um historiador, biógrafo, ensaísta e filósofo médio platônico grego, conhecido principalmente por suas obras Vidas Paralelas e Morália. Além de suas funções como sacerdote do Templo de Delfos, Plutarco também foi um magistrado em Queroneia e representou sua pátria em várias missões em países estrangeiros."},{"question":"Lanjutkanlah penggalan teks di bawah ini agar menjadi sebuah paragraf cerita pendek anak yang runtun.Judul: Kegagalan Rubah.Suatu hari, seekor rubah merasa sangat lapar. Oleh karena itu, ia pergi mencari ...","answer":"makanan. Setelah sekian lama mencari, ia tidak berhasil menemukan sesuatu yang bisa dimakan. Akhirnya, ketika perutnya keroncongan, ia tersandung tembok rumah petani. Di bagian atas dindingnya, si rubah melihat anggur terbesar dan terlezat yang pernah ia temukan dalam hidupnya. Anggur ini punya warna ungu yang bersinar. Hal tersebut membuat nafsu makan sang rubah makin meningkat. Untuk mencapai buah anggur milik petani, rubah harus melompat dengan tinggi di udara. Saat melompat, ia membuka mulutnya agar bisa langsung memakan buah tersebut. Sayangnya, rubah malah meleset. Rubah mencoba beberapa kali tetapi terus mengalami kegagalan. Akhirnya, ia memutuskan untuk menyerah dan pulang ke rumah. Di perjalanan, ia bergumam, \\"Aku yakin anggur itu rasanya asam,\\" kata rubah."},{"question":"Nse Ikpe-Etim","answer":"Nse Ikpe-Etim (tí a bí ní ọdún 1974) jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà. Òkìkí rẹ̀ kàn ní ọdún 2008 fún ipa rẹ̀ nínú Reloaded. Wọ́n yàn án fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ Dirama Òṣèrébìrin tó dára jù fún ẹ̀dá-ìtàn \\"Nse\\" nínú \\"Journey to Self ní Africa Viewers Awards lọ́dún 2014.Wọ́n bí Etim ní ọjọ́ kọkànlélógún, Oṣù Ọ̀wàrà, Ọdún 1974 ní ìlú Èkó. Etim lọ sí Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ̀bẹ́ẹ̀rẹ̀ Awa àti Ilé ẹ̀kọ́ àwọn ológun (Command Primary School) ní ìlú Kaduna, ó tẹ̀síwájú ní St Louis College, Jos àti Kọ́lẹ́jì Ìjọba Àpapọ̀ ní ìlú Jos àti Ìlọrin. Ó sọ pé iṣẹ́ bàbá rẹ̀ bí òṣìṣẹ́ Báànkì àpapọ̀ ló fa gbígbé tí àwọn ń gbé kiri gbogbo àgbègbè. Ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè nínú ẹ̀kọ́ tíátà ní Yunifásítì Calabar.Etim ní àkọ́bí nínú  àwọn mẹ́fà. Ó sọ pé ohun ni àwọn alágbàtọ́ tí wọ́n jẹ́ òyìnbó nínú Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò rẹ̀ Toolz.  Ọjọ́ kẹrìnlá ọdún 2013 ló fẹ́ ọ̀rẹ́ rẹ̀ àtijọ́ Clifford Sule ní ìlànà ìgbéyàwó-òfin ní Èkó. Lẹ́yìn ìgbà náà ni wọ́n ṣe ìgbéyàwó Ìbílẹ̀ ní ìlú rẹ̀ Akwa Ibom àti Èkó. Ìlú Ọba (London) ló ń gbé pẹ̀lú ọkọ rẹ̀ báyìí , tí ó jẹ olùkọ́ni àgbà ní Iléẹ̀kọ́ Yunifásítì Middlesex tí ó sì má ń wà ṣiṣé fíìmù ní NàìjíríàEtim bẹ̀rẹ̀ eré orí ìtàgé ní ilé ẹ̀kọ́ yunifásítì ní ọmọ ọdún méjìdínlógún. Eré àkọ́kọ́ tí ó ti kọ́kọ́ hàn ni eré àtìgbàdégbà \\"Inheritance\\". Nígbà tí ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè ní Yunifásítì, ó kúrò ní agbo fíìmù ráńpẹ́ láti dáwọ́lé àwọn ohun mìíràn kí ó tó wà kópa nínú fíìmù Reloaded tí Emem Isong ṣe, àwọn òṣèré tí wọ́n jọ kópa ni Ramsey Nouah, Rita Dominic, Ini Edo àti Desmond Eliot. Ní oṣù Ọ̀pẹ, ọdún 2019, wọ́n ṣe àfihàn rẹ̀ nínú àkójọ àwòrán Collaborative Polaris, lábẹ́ Ìfọmọnìyànṣe Supernova, wọ́n ṣe Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò fún pẹ̀lú àwọn èèyàn bíi William Coupon, Bisila Bokoko àti Adé Adékọ́lá.Ní ọdún 2020 ó kópa nínú eré Quam's money tí ó sòpọ̀ mọ́ eré Tope Oshin, New money.Ní ọdún 2021, ó kópa pẹ̀lú Richard Mofe-Damijo àti Zainab Balógun nínú eré Ṣèyí Bàbátọ́pẹ́ tí ò pè ní Wine."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： 保育士3人を逮捕　国は日本中の保育園を調べることを考える","answer":"警察は4日、静岡県裾野市にあるさくら保育園で子どもの世話をしていた保育士3人を逮捕しました。警察によると、保育士は1歳の子どもの顔を押したり、子どもの足を持って逆さに持ち上げたりした疑いがあります。裾野市によると、保育士はほかにも、子どもにナイフを見せて脅したり、ごはんを食べない子どもの頭をたたいたりしていて、全部で16のひどいことをしていました。厚生労働省は「子どもの安全を大事にしなければならない場所でこのようなことがあって、とても残念です。日本中の保育園で子どもの世話を正しくしているかどうか調べることを考えています」と話しています。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bunga bukan sekuntum'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud lelaki atau perempuan yand terdapat di dunia ini bukan seorang sahaja."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kari tulang rusuk? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah secara terperinci. ","answer":"Kari tulang rusuk ialah sejenis hidangan kari yang dibuat menggunakan tulang rusuk, biasanya tulang rusuk lembu, sebagai bahan utamanya. Hidangan ini popular di beberapa negara, termasuk Malaysia, dan dikenali dengan kekayaan rasanya serta tekstur daging yang lembut.Bahan untuk kari tulang rusuk: 1 kg tulang lembu (rusuk), 2 sudu besar atau 1 paket kecil rempah kari daging, 1 cawan santan pekat segar, 4 cawan air (tambah atau kurangkan ikut suka), ½ inci lengkuas, 2 biji ubi kentang - opsyenal, Gula pasir / gula melaka dan garam secukup rasa, Air asam jawaBahan tumis: 1 tangkai daun kari - dilurut, 5 biji bawang merah, 2 ulas bawang putih, ½ inci halia, 2 sudu besar cili kisar/boh, 2 sudu besar minyak masakCara penyediaan:1. Cuci tulang, buang lemak yang berlebihan. Kemudian tuskan.2. Kupas dan potong dadu ubi kentang.3. Ketuk lengkuas.4. Bancuh serbuk rempah kari dengan sedikit air supaya menjadi pes.5. Kisar bawang merah, bawang putih dan halia.Cara memasak:1. Masukkan tulang ke dalam periuk, tambah air dan lengkuas. Tutup periuk, kemudian rebus sehingga daging pada tulang empuk. Kalau menggunakan periuk tekanan (Noxxa, Philips), rebus dengan tekanan tinggi selama 15 minit *. Kemudian ketepikan.2. Panaskan minyak masak di dalam periuk lain dengan api sederhana. Tumis bahan kisar dan daun karisehingga garing dan naik bau.3. Masukkan cili kisar dan tumis hingga pecah minyak. Tambah pes rempah kari, dan tumis hingga pecah minyak juga.4. Masukkan tulang, gaul sebati dan biarkan seketika (5-10 minit) supaya tulang mesra dengan rempah.5. Masukkan air rebusan yang telah ditapis (untuk membuang buih kotoran dan serpihan tulang), kentang, santan dan air asam jawa.6. Masak sambil mengacau sehingga kentang empuk dan kuah pecah minyak.7. Perasakan dengan gula dan garam, kemudian padamkan api, angkat dan dihidang.* 15 minit adalah masa memasak high pressure untuk tulang rusuk. Kalau guna tulang gearbox, set pada 25minit"},{"question":"Quem foi a primeira mulher negra a ganhar o Oscar de Melhor Atriz?","answer":"A atriz Halle Berry foi a primeira mulher negra a ganhar o Oscar de Melhor Atriz por sua atuação no filme A Última Ceia, de 2001."},{"question":"எறும்பு ____________ கல்லும் தேயும். (ஊரக் / ஊறக்)","answer":"விடை : ஊரக்"},{"question":"Denetimli makine öğrenmesi nedir?","answer":"Veri bilimciler algoritmalara, bağıntıları değerlendirmeleri için etiketlenmiş ve tanımlı veriler sağlar. Örnek verilerde algoritmanın hem girdi hem de çıktısı belirtilir. Örneğin, el yazısı içeren şekillerin görüntülerine açıklamalar eklenerek bu şekillerin hangi rakama karşılık geldiği belirtilir. Bir denetimli öğrenme sistemi, yeterli örnek verilmesi halinde her bir rakamla ilişkili piksel ve şekil kümelerini tanıyabilir. Bunun sonucunda 9 ile 4 veya 6 ile 8 gibi rakamları birbirinden güvenilir bir şekilde ayırt ederek elle yazılmış rakamları tanıyabilir. Denetimli öğrenmenin avantajları basitlik ve tasarım kolaylığıdır. Olası bir sınırlı sonuç kümesini tahmin ederken, verileri kategorilere ayırırken veya başka iki makine öğrenmesi algoritmasından gelen sonuçları birleştirirken yararlı olur. Ancak, milyonlarca veri kümesinin etiketlenmesi zor olabilir. "},{"question":"Kí ni fíìmù?","answer":"Fíìmù jẹ́ ọ̀rọ̀ kàn tí a fi kó àwòràn papọ̀. A máa ń gbé fíìmù jáde nígbà tí a bá gbá àwòrán àwọn ènìyàn àti àwọn nǹkan sílẹ̀ pẹ̀lú kámẹ́rà, tàbí tí a bá ṣẹ̀dá àwòràn nǹkan nípa lílo àwọn irinṣẹ́ kòmpútà. A máa ń lo fíìmù láti ṣẹ̀fẹ̀, láti dá àwọn ènìyàn lára yá, gẹ́gẹ́ bí irinṣẹ́ ńlá tí a fi ń kọ àwọn ará ìlú ní nǹkan tuntun. Àwòrán wúlò láti bá ènìyàn sọ ọ̀rọ̀ pàtàkì. Àkọ́lé àwọn eré tí wọ́n máa ń gbé jáde nínú fíìmù máa ń ní ìtumọ̀, ó sì máa ń pe èrò sọ́kàn òǹwòran.“Longman dictionary of contemporary English” (1995) túmọ̀ fíìmù gẹ́gẹ́ bíi:A story that is told using sound and moving pictures, shown at a cinema or on television for entertainment…. To use a camera to record a story or real events so that it can be shown in the cinema or on television.(Ìtàn tí a sọ pẹ̀lú ohùn àti àwòràn tí ó dúró sójú kan, tí a gbé síta fún wíwò ni sinimá tàbí lóríi tẹlifísàn fún ìdálárayá… tí a fi ẹ̀rọ agbàwòrán sílẹ̀ kámẹ́rà gba ìtàn tàbí ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ ojú ayé sílẹ̀ kí a bà á le gbé síta fún wíwò ní sinimá tàbí lórí tẹlifísàn.)Ohun tí ó ṣe kókó ni wí pé ìtàn ni fíìmù máa ń sọ pẹ̀lú àwòràn àwọn ò̀ṣèré lóríṣìíríṣìí. Ẹ̀rọ kámérà ni wọ́n máa ń lò láti gba àwọn àwòrán yìí sílẹ̀.Oríṣìírìṣìí fíìmù ni ó wá. Àwọn tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìtàn ìwáṣẹ̀ tàbí àwon ìtàn akọni. Wọ́n máa ń pè wọ́n ní “epics/historical films”. Àpẹẹrẹ àwọn fíìmù àgbéléwò tí ó wà lábẹ́ ọ̀wọ́ yìí, tí wọ́n sì ti gbé jáde ni; Jógun-ó-mí, Odùduwà, Efúnsetán Aníwúrà àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ.A tún ni àwọn kan tí wọ́n níí ṣe pẹ̀lu híwu ìwà òdaràn. Àpẹẹrẹ àwọn fíìmù tí ó ti wà lórí igbá tí ó sì wa lábẹ́ ọ̀wọ́ yìí ni; Tombolo, Isakaba àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Ọ̀wọ́ kẹta ni wọ́n ń pè ní “comedy films” (àwàdà). Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ fíìmù tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ẹ̀fẹ̀ ni wọ́n tí gbé jáde. Àpẹẹrẹ ni fíìmù baba latin, òǹṣèrè kan tí ó gbajúmọ̀ nínú fíìmù Yorùbá tí ó pè ní, “Mr President” tàbí èyí tí òṣèré inú fíìmù òyìnbó ní ilẹ̀ Nàíjáríà kan tí a ń pè ní Nkem Owoh ṣe. Ó pè é ní “Osuofia in London”.Ọ̀wọ́ kẹrin ni èyí tí wọ́n ń pè ní “drama films” (fíìmù orí ìtàgé). Orí ìtàgé ni wọ́n ti kọ́kọ́ máa ń ṣe irú eré báyìí kí wọ́n tó gbé jáde sínú kásẹ̀tì. Àpẹẹrẹ ní Àkànní Òpómúléró àti Ṣàǹgó. Yàtọ̀ sí èyí, a tún rí àwọn tí wọ́n máa ń ṣe láti ba àwọn ènìyàn lẹ́rù. Nínú irú fíìmù yìí, a ó ò máa rí oríṣi nǹkan tí yóò ba ènìyàn lẹ́rù bíi iwin olórí mẹ́fà, kí ilẹ̀ dédé lanu gbé ènìyàn kan ṣoṣo mi láàárín ọjà àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Àpẹẹrẹ irúfẹ́ fíìmù wọ̀nyí ni Aníkúlápó tí Ìyá Rainbow ò̀ṣèré Yorùbá kan gbé jáde. Irúfẹ́ fíìmù yìí ni wọ́n ń pé ni “Horror films” lédè òyìnbó.Bákan náà ni a ní a tún rí àwọn tí wọ́n ń pè ní “dance and musical film” (oníjó). Àwọn wọ̀nyí níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ijó. Àpẹẹrẹ kan ni fíìmù Láídé Bákàrè; Ijóyá. A tún ní àwọn mìíràn bíi Science fiction (Mérìírí ti sáyéńsì), Action film (oníjàgídíjàgan) àti Adventure films (ìtàn lórí ìwádìí) tí kò tíì bẹ̀rẹ̀ lọ́dọ̀ wa níbí.Ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ nínú àwọn fíìmù tí ó ń jáde ní orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà ló ní àkóónú tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìṣòró tí ó ń kójú àwọn mùtúmùwà ilẹ̀ Áfíríkà. Àwọn fíìmù kan máa ń gbe ẹ̀sìn kìrìsítẹ́nì àti mùsùlùmí lẹ́sẹ̀ nígbà tí àwọn kan ń polongo ìhìnrere. Àpẹẹrẹ irú àwọn fíìmù wọ̀nyí nii “Agbára ńlá” tí Mike Bamiloye ṣe, “látòrunwá” àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lo.̣ Yàtọ̀ sí àwọn fíìmù tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ẹ̀sìn lóríṣìíríṣìrí, a tún ní àwọn tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìdàrúdàpọ̀ tí ó máa ń ṣẹlẹ̀ nígbà tí àwọn tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú ìdàrúdàpọ̀ tí ó máa ń ṣẹlẹ̀ nígbà tí àwọn ẹ̀sìn méjì ọ̀tọ̀ọ̀tọ̀ bá kọlu ara wọn, yálà nígbà tí àwọn ọmọ wọn bá fé láti fẹ́ ara wọn tàbí nígbà tí ọ̀rọ̀ ilẹ̀ bá dạ̀ wọ́n pọ̀. Àpẹẹrẹ ní fíìmù kan tí wọ́n pè ní “Not without my daughter” (Láìsí ọmọbìnrin mi) tí ó ń sọ ìtàn nípa okùnrin mùsùlùmí kan àti obìnrin kìrìsìtẹ́nì kan tí wọ́n fẹ́ ṣe ìgbéyàwó tí wọ́n sì tún rí oríṣI ìṣòro nígbà tí wọ́n ń gbáradì fún ìgbéyàwó wọn.Bákan náà, àwọn fíìmù kan tún wà tí iṣẹ́ pàtàkì tí wọ́n ń jẹ́ níí ṣe pẹ̀lú àrùn tí ó bá ń kojú àwùjọ lásìkò kan kì í sẹ ní Afrika nìkan ní irú fíìmù yìí ti ń jáde. Ní ilẹ̀ Amerika, a rí fíìmù kan tí wọ́n pè ní “philadephia”. Pàtàkì ohun tí ó jẹ́ àkóónú fíìmù yìí ní bí àwọn ènìyàn ṣe máa ń hùwà sí àwọn tí ó ní àrùn éèdì. Ní ìlẹ̀ Nàìjíríà náà, a rí irú fíìmù bíi “Elébòlò” (charlot) àti “wheel of change” (Kẹ̀kẹ́ ìyípadà) tí ó níí ṣe pẹ̀lú àrùn kògbóògùn éèdì.Síwájú sí ì, àwọn àkóónú mìíràn tí fíìmù tún máa ń ní ni ìwà ìbàjẹ́, ìkìlọ̀ lórí bí wọ́n ṣe máa ń kọ iyán àwọn obìnrin ilẹ̀ Afrika kéré, ìkìlọ̀ nípa àṣà òkèèrè tí ó gbòde kan àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ.Àwọn fíìmù tí ó kọ́kọ́ jádé máa ń fi àṣà Yorùbá hàn sí gbogbo àgbáyé nítorí wí pé àwọn tí wọ́n ń ṣe fíìmù nígbà náà gbà wí pé ọ̀nà kan tí àwọn lè gbà láti jẹ́ kí àwọn ará ìlú òkèèrè ó gba fíìmù Yorùbá gẹ́gẹ́ bí iṣẹ́ tí ó kúnjú òṣùwọ̀n ni láti fi ạ̀ṣà àti ìṣe wa hàn nínú eré náà. Ní ọdún 1975 Ọlá Balógun gbé fíìmù kan tí ó pè ní “Àjàní Ògún”. Lẹ́yìn èyí, àwọn díè nínú àwọn tí ń ṣe eré ìbílẹ̀ káàkiri bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní kópa nínú òwò fíìmù. Lásìkò yìí ni Herbert Ogunde ṣe fíìmù tí ó pè ní “Aiye”. Fíìmù yìí jáde ni ọdún 1980. Ohun kan ṣoṣo tí kò wá jẹ́ kí fíìmù yìí dí ìtẹwọ́gbà káàkiri ni pé, ó fi àwọn Yorùbá hàn gẹ́gẹ́ bí ènìyàn burúkú tí wọ́n máa ń ṣe oríṣìíríṣìí ẹgbẹ́ tí ó ń bànìyàn lẹ́rù. Yàtọ̀ sí èyí, owó tí olóyè Ogunde fi ṣe fíìmù yìí fẹ́ẹ̀ lè má pé nígbà tí wọ́n tà á tán. Níṣe ni ó dàbí ẹni tó ṣòwò tí kò jèrè.Ṣùgbọ́n ti olóyè Ògúǹdé ṣe ti àwọn bíi Ọlá Balógun, Adéyemí Afọláyan tí gbogbo ènìyàn mọ̀ sí “Ade love” àti Moses Oláìyá tí wọ́n ń pè ní “Bàbá Sàlá”. Gégé bí Nosa Owens-Ibie (2004) ṣe sọ, gbogbo fíìmù tí wọ́n ṣe pẹ̀lú owó tí wọ́n yá ni ilé-ìfowópamọ́, wọ́n jẹ gbèsè tí púpọ̀ wọn ò tilẹ̀ dábàá àti ṣe fíìmù àgbéléwò mọ́ léyìn náà. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ohun tí “Ade love” sọ kí ó tó kú ni ọdún 1995 nínú ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò kan tí wọ́n ṣe fun; ó ṣàlàyé bí òun ṣe yá owó ní báńkì láti ṣe fíìmù rẹ̀ “Destiny” (àyànmọ́). Ó ní ní ìgbà náa, dọ́là kan jẹ déédé náìrà mẹ́wàá, ṣùgbọ́n ní ọjọ yìí, ó di náírà kan-dínlógún fún dọ́là kan. Ó ní òun ní láti ya owó si ni láti san owó tí oùn yá ṣe fíìmù náà. Ohun kan tí a ṣàkíyèsí ni pé, owó fa ọwọ́ aago fíìmù Yorùbá sẹ́yìn.Ní ọdún 1992, Ládi Ládébò, ọ̀kan nínú àwọn tó ṣẹ̀ṣẹ̀ bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní ṣe fíìmù sí fídíò gbá oyè méjì lórí fíìmù rẹ̀ méjì: “Èèwò” àti “Vender”. Lẹ́yìn èyí, àwọn bíi Ọlá Balógun àti Herbert Ogunde bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí níí ṣe fíìmù pẹ̀lú irínṣẹ́ tuntun. Èyí jẹ́ kí àwọn fíìmù wọ̀nyí di gbajúmọ̀ ní ilẹ̀ Nàíjíríà àti ní òkèèrè. Ògúǹ̀dé ṣe “Jaiyesinmi”, “Àròpin N’tènìà” àti Àyànmọ́. Láàárín ọdún 1993 sí ọdún 1996, àwọn tí wọ́n ń ṣe fíìmù Yorùbá ti pọ̀ sí. Fíìmù Yorùbá tí ó jáde ní àkókò yìí lé ní igba (200). Àwọn tí wọ́n ṣẹ̀ṣẹ̀ ń ṣe fíìmù Yorùbá ni ìgbà náà ni: Jimoh Aliu tí ó ṣe “Ètékéte”, Tunde Àlàbí hundeyin ṣe “Iyawo alhaji”, Professor Pellar náà ṣe fíìmù mẹ́ta. Àwọn ni “Idán ńlọ”, “Owó Idán” àti “Agbára”. Oyin Adéjọbí náà ṣe fíìmù kan tí ó pè ní “Orogún Adédigba” ní ọdún 1995. Yàtọ̀ sí èyí, Yẹmí Fáróunbí ṣe fíìmù kan tí ó pè ní “Ẹ̀bùn Olúwa” ní ọdún yìí kan náà. Àwọn òṣèrè bíi Jídé Kòsọ́kọ́ àti Ṣọlá Fósùdó ṣe fíìmù kan tí wọ́n pè ní “Ọkọ Ìyàwó”.Lẹ́yìn tí àwọn òṣèrè yìí ṣe fíìmù yìí tán, àwọn òṣèrè mìíràn bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí í gbé fíìmù tiwọn náà jáde. Bí wọ́n bá ni kí wọ́n ka oríṣi fíìmù Yorùbá tí ó ti jáde, yóò tó ìdá mẹ́fà fíìmù tí ó ti jáde ní ilé-iṣẹ́ àwọn onífíìmù tí ó gbajúmọ̀ nísìnyí. Orúkọ tí wọ́n ń pé ilé-iṣẹ́ náà, tí ó kó àwọn òṣèré mọ́ àwọn tí ń ṣe fíìmù jọ ni wọ́n ń pè ní Nollywood. Ilé-iṣẹ́ fíìmù Yorùbá ti tóbi si; àkóónú fíìmù wọn sì ti ń yípadà sí ti àtijọ́ tí ó jẹ́ wí pé ọ̀rọ̀ ẹ̀sìn ìbílẹ̀, ẹ̀fẹ̀ àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ, ni ó ń jẹ ẹ́ lógún.Ohun pàtàkì kan tí ó ya fíìmù Yorùbá sọ́tọ̀ ní èdè àmúlò. Gégẹ́ bí a ṣe mọ̀ pé àwọn Yorùbá kìí ń sọ̀rọ̀ lásán, wọn máa ń sọ̀rọ̀ pẹ̀lú làákàyè àti ọgbọ́n. Àwa náà sí mọ̀ pé èdè Yorùbá yìí kún, ó dùn, ó ṣe pàtàkì, ó sì jọjú gidigidi. Tí wọ́n bá ko eré, ìṣẹ̣̀lẹ̀ láwùjọ àti ọgbọ́n inú rẹ̀ ní wọn ó kó jọ. Àkóónú eré wọn á máa lọ láti orí ìbálòpọ̀ tí ò lẹ́tọ̀ọ́, ìwà ìbàjẹ́ láwùjọ láàárín ọ̀tọ̀kùlú àti ìjọba, ìjà ìyálé àti ìyàwó, ìrirí ayé, àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ.Èdè Yorùbá tí wọ́n fi ń gbé ìtàn wọn kalẹ̀ yìí jẹ́ kí ó yé gbogbo mùtúmùwà ohun gbogbo tí wọ́n ń sọ. Ó sì jẹ́ kí tàgbà tọmọdé, akẹ́kọ̀ọ́ àti olùkọ́, kòfẹ́sọ̀ àti àgbẹ̀ rí ẹ̀kọ́ kan tàbí òmíràn dìmú nínú fíìmù wọn. Wọn kì í dédé sọ̀rọ̀ bí kò bá ṣe wí pé ó lóhun tí ònkọ̀tàn rí. Àwọn òṣèré náà sì máa ń gbìyànjú láti túmọ̀ gbogbo ohun tí ó bá yẹ kí wọ́n sọ kí ó le yé gbogbo ènìyàn.Ohun mìíràn tí a tún gbọ́dọ̀ ṣàkíyèsí ni pé àwọn olóṣèlú a máa fi àwọn eré ìgbálódé orí ìtàgé àti ti inú fíìmù polongo ara wọn nígbà ìdìbò. A rí ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ àpẹẹrẹ, nínú àwọn fíìmù àgbéléwò tí ó ti wà lórí àtẹ. Ọ̀kan nínú àwọn tí wọn lò láti kìlọ̀ nípa ìdìbò, ṣe ìlérí àwọn ará ìlú àti tí wọ́n fi pe àfiyèsí àwọn ará ìlú nígbà ìdìbò ni fíìmù tí wọ́n pè ní “Olúọmọ-rẹ̀mílẹ́kún”. Ẹni tí ó ba ṣe àfiyèsí tí ó kún nínú fíìmù yìí yóò mọ̀ wí pé ọ̀kan nínú àwọn olùdíje fún ipò gómìnà ní ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ní ó fi polongo. A lè sọ wí pé fíìmù máa ń jẹ́ kí òye àwọn ènìyàn kún síi. A tún gbọ̣́dọ̀ ṣàkíyèsí pé kìí ṣe gbogbo fíìmù ni ó ń kó ipa gidi ní àwùjọ, àwọn kan tilẹ̀ máa ń polongo ìwà ìbàjẹ́ ni."},{"question":"Viết lại các tập hợp sau bằng cách liệt kê các phần tử của tập hợp đó:a) A = {x | x là số tự nhiên chẵn, 20 < x < 35}b) B = {x | x là số tự nhiên lẻ, 150 < x < 160}.","answer":"a) Các số tự nhiên chẵn thỏa mãn 20 < x < 35 là: 22; 24; 26; 28; 30; 32; 34.Vậy bằng cách liệt kê A là A = {22; 24; 26; 28; 30; 32; 34}.b) Các số tự nhiên lẻ thỏa mãn 150 < x < 160 là: 151; 153; 155; 157; 159.Vậy bằng cách liệt kê A là A = {151; 153; 155; 157; 159}."},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي تسمى بني إسرائيل ؟","answer":"الإسراء."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو الحيوان المكسيكي الأصلع؟","answer":"الإجابة: الكلب"},{"question":"英國倫敦“大本鐘”的名字是來自？","answer":"伊莉莎白塔原名大本鐘，命名來源眾說紛紜，有一種說法稱大本鐘的名字來自於班傑明·豪爾爵士。"},{"question":"Bill Gates","answer":"William Henry \\"Bill\\" Gates III tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Ọ̀wàwà, ọdún 1955 (28/10/1955) jẹ́ oníṣòwò ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Amerika, alaanu, oludako ati alaga ilé-iṣẹ́ Microsoft, ilé-iṣẹ́ atolànà kọ̀m̀pútà tó dá sílẹ̀ pẹ̀lú Paul Allen. Gates jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn tó lọ́wọ́ jùlọ lágbàáyé òun sì ni olówó jùlọ ní àgbáyé lọ́dún 1995, 2009, àyàfi ọdún 2008, nígbà tó bọ́ sí ipò kẹta. Nígbà tó fi ṣíṣe ní Microsoft, Gates wà ní ipò CEO àti amójútó àgbà atolànà kọ̀m̀pútà, bẹ́ẹ̀ sì ni òun ni onípìn-ín ìdákowò tó tóbi jù lọ, ipin ajoni. Ó tún ti kọ ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ìwé."},{"question":"اگر ہر چیز کی کوئی وجہ ہے تو پہلی وجہ کیا ہے؟ ایک غیر سبب یا خود موجود ہستی کے تصور پر بحث کریں۔","answer":"یہ سوال پہلی وجہ یا بے وجہ وجود کے وجود کے لیے کائناتی دلائل کا استعمال کرتا ہے۔ فلسفی اور ماہر الہیات ایک ضروری وجود کے تصور کو تلاش کرتے ہیں جو کسی پیشگی وجہ پر انحصار نہیں کرتا ہے۔ یہ خیال ایک خود ساختہ ہستی کے تصور کو متعارف کراتا ہے، جسے اکثر مذہبی مباحث میں خدا کے ساتھ شناخت کیا جاتا ہے۔"},{"question":"ప్రత్యేక తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్రావిర్భావానికి దారితీసిన పరిస్థితులను గూర్చి ఇద్దరు మిత్రుల మధ్య సంభాషణను రాయండి.","answer":"ఇద్దరు మిత్రుల మధ్య సంభాషణ :శ్రీరామ్ : గోపాల్ ! నీకు మన నూతన రాష్ట్ర శుభాకాంక్షలు. నిజంగా ఈ రోజు మన కలలు పండిన బంగారు రోజు.గోపాల్ : శ్రీరామ్ ! నీకు కూడా, నా నూతన రాష్ట్ర శుభాకాంక్షలు. ఈ మన కోరిక తీరడం వెనుక, ఎందరో మన పెద్దల కృషి, ఎందరో అమాయకుల ప్రాణత్యాగాలు ఉన్నాయి కదూ !శ్రీరామ్ : అవును గోపాల్ ! మట్టి చెన్నారెడ్డిగారి నాయకత్వంలో 1969లో జరిగిన తెలంగాణ రాష్ట్ర ఉద్యమం, ఈ మన రాష్ట్ర సాధనకు తొలిమెట్టు అని, పెద్దలంటున్నారు.గోపాల్ : రాష్ట్ర సాధనకు మన తెలంగాణ ప్రభుత్వ ఉద్యోగులూ, ఉపాధ్యాయులూ, చేసిన సమ్మెలూ, పోరాటాలు కూడా, ప్రధాన పాత్ర వహించాయి.శ్రీరామ్ : ముఖ్యంగా మన ముఖ్యమంత్రి కె.సి.ఆర్ నాయకత్వంలో ప్రొఫెసర్ జయశంకర్ గారి పర్యవేక్షణలో, టి.ఆర్.యస్. పార్టీ సాగించిన పోరాటాలు, సమ్మెలు, రైల్రోకోలు, వంటా వార్పులు, మన కోరికలు తీరడానికి ప్రధానంగా దోహదం చేశాయి.గోపాల్ : తెలంగాణ ప్రజలు అందరూ రోడ్లపైకి వచ్చి, “సకల జనుల సమ్మె, వంటా వార్పూ వంటివి చేపట్టారు. ముఖ్యంగా మన ఉస్మానియా విశ్వవిద్యాలయ విద్యార్థులు, ఈ ఉద్యమంలో అంతులేని మహత్తరమైన పోరాటాన్ని చేశారు.శ్రీరామ్ : ఎన్నోసార్లు మన టి.ఆర్.యస్. పార్టీ ఎమ్.ఎల్.ఏలు, యమ్.పిలు, తమ పదవులకు రిజైన్ చేశారు. నిజానికి అన్ని పార్టీలూ, ఈ మన చిరకాల వాంఛ నెరవేరడానికి ఉద్యమంలో ముందుకు దూకాయి.గోపాల్ : \` అటు కేంద్రంలో ఉన్న కాంగ్రెస్, బి.జె.పి పార్టీలు కూడా, ఈ విషయంలో ఏకమై, మన కోరికను తీర్చాయి.శ్రీరామ్ : గోపాల్ ! నీవు చెప్పింది నిజం. మన తెలంగాణ బిడ్డలు సైతం, ఎందరో ఈ ఉద్యమంలో పాల్గొని తమ ప్రాణాలు అర్పించారు. వారి త్యాగాల్ని మనం ఎప్పుడూ మరువకూడదు.గోపాల్ : నిజం చెప్పావు. ఉంటా."},{"question":"\\"Văn tế nghĩa sĩ Cần Giuộc\\" là tác phẩm nổi tiếng của nhà thơ Nguyễn Đình Chiểu, sáng tác năm 1861. Địa danh Cần Giuộc trong bài thơ, hiện thuộc tỉnh nào?","answer":"Sau khi thành Gia Định và đại đồn Chí Hòa thất thủ (tháng 2/1861), Pháp thừa thắng đánh chiếm một số vùng xung quanh. Ở Long An, mặt trận chống giặc hình thành rộng khắp từ Bến Lức qua Cần Đước, Cần Giuộc đến Tân An... Các nghĩa này hoạt động dưới ngọn cờ của Bình Tây Đại nguyên soái dân phong Trương Định. Chỉ huy nghĩa quân ở vùng Cần Đước, Cần Giuộc lúc bấy giờ là Bùi Quang Diệu.Ngày 16/12/1861, Bùi Quang Diệu chỉ huy 3 cánh quân tập kích đồn Tây Dương ở chợ Trường Bình, Cần Giuộc. Nghĩa quân chiếm được đồn địch, đốt nhà dạy đạo và đâm bị thương Đồn trưởng Dumont, hạ được một số lính Mã tà, Ma ní. Pháp liền dùng đại bác từ tàu chiến đậu trên sông Cần Giuộc để chiếm lại đồn. Phía nghĩa quân hy sinh 15 người (có tài liệu ghi là 27 người).Nhà thơ Nguyễn Đình Chiểu (1822-1888), lúc bấy giờ về Cần Giuộc, ở chùa Tôn Thạnh bốc thuốc, dạy học và sáng tác thơ văn. Ông đã viết bài Văn tế nghĩa sĩ Cần Giuộc như lời truy điệu các nghĩa sĩ hy sinh trong trận đánh này.Nhớ linh xưaCôi cút làm ăn,Riêng lo nghèo khổ,Chưa quen cung ngựa đưa tới trường nhungChỉ biết ruộng trâu ở theo làng hộ;Việc cuốc, việc cày, việc bừa, việc cấy, tay vốn làm quen;Tập khiên, tập mác, tập giáo, tập cờ, mắt chưa từng ngó.Tiếng phong hạc phập phồng hơn mười tháng, trông tin quan như nắng hạn trông mưa.Mùi tinh chiên vấy vá đã ba năm, ghét thói mọi như nhà nông ghét cỏ."},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Am dangeen bëgg a laaj seen Yonent na ñu laajee woon Muusaa ca bu njëkk? Képp ku weccee ngëm ak weddi, réer na te wàcc na yoon wu njub wa.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Am da ngéen bëgg a laaj séen Yonent na ñu laajewoon Muusaa ca bu njëkk? Képp ku weccee ngëm ak weddi, réer na te wàcc na yoon wu njub wa."},{"question":"ਦਸਤਾਵੇਜ਼ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਿੰਟ ਬਹੁਤ ਅਸਪਸ਼ਟ ਨਿਕਲਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਪ੍ਰਿੰਟਰ ਦੀ ਸਿਆਹੀ ਘੱਟ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਪ੍ਰਿੰਟ ਦੇ ਕਾਗਜ਼ ਮੁੱਕ ਗਏ ਸੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਪ੍ਰਿੰਟਰ ਦੀ ਸਿਆਹੀ ਘੱਟ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"મોતની યે બાદ તારી – બરકત વિરાણી ‘બેફામ’ રચિત  કવિતા લખો","answer":"મોતની યે બાદ તારી ઝંખના કરતો રહ્યોકે તું જન્નતમાં મળે એવી દુઆ કરતો રહ્યોજો તું જાણે તો ભરી મહેફીલ ત્યજીને સાથ દઇએવી એકલતા ભરી મારી દશા કરતો રહ્યોએ હતો એક મોહ કે રહેશું જીવનભર સાથમાંવ્હેમ તો એજ છે જે આપણને જુદાં કરતો રહ્યોકોણ જાણે શું હતું એનાં નીકળતાં શ્વાસમાંમાનવી આ સૃષ્ટિની ઝેરી હવા કરતો રહ્યો"},{"question":"Заполните следующую фразу: Премьер-министр Великобритании Тони Блэр извинился перед британцами, пострадавшими от","answer":"Урагана Катрина. Многие британские граждане, оказавшиеся в ловушке в Новом Орлеане, пожаловались в британское министерство иностранных дел на отсутствие реакции со стороны их правительства после того, как ураган разрушил инфраструктуру в радиусе почти 200 миль от побережья Мексиканского залива США."},{"question":"۵ بازیگر معروف مرد ایرانی را نام ببر.","answer":"بازیگران مرد معروف بسیاری در دوره‌های مختلف در سینمای ایران فعال بوده‌اند. از بین آنها می‌توان به عزت‌الله انتظامی، علی نصیریان، پارسا پیروزفر، شهاب حسینی و نوید محمدزاده اشاره کرد."},{"question":" Waa maxay tilmaanta iimaanku","answer":" Tilmaanta iimaanku waa waxyaalahahaddii qofka laga helo lagu sheegi karo \\"qofmuumin ah\\"."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Sáng 31/7, theo thông tin PV Etime thu thập, UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi vừa có chỉ đạo cho Sở TNMT, BQL KKT Dung Quất và chính quyền các địa phương tăng cường công tác quản lý nhà nước về đất đai trên địa bàn. Tỉnh Quảng Ngãi nhìn nhận trong thời gian qua, trên địa bàn đã diễn ra tình trạng một số tổ chức, cá nhân tự ý triển khai san lấp mặt bằng; xây dựng công trình trên phần diện tích đất thực hiện dự án, khi chưa có quyết định giao (cho thuê) đất của cấp có thẩm quyền. Để nâng cao hiệu quả công tác quản lý nhà nước về đất đai trên địa bàn, UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi yêu cầu người đứng đầu BQL KKT Dung Quất và các KCN Quảng Ngãi; chính quyền các huyện, thị xã, thành phố và cơ quan, đơn vị liên quan triển khai thực hiện nghiêm túc nội dung văn bản chỉ đạo trước đó (Chỉ thị số 04/CT-UBND ngày 17/5/2022), của Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh. Chủ tịch UBND các huyện, thị xã, thành phố thực hiện đầy đủ trách nhiệm về quản lý đất đai; tuyệt đối không để xảy ra việc tổ chức, cá nhân tự","answer":"ý triển khai san lấp mặt bằng, xây dựng công trình trên phần diện tích đất thực hiện dự án khi chưa có quyết định giao (cho thuê) đất của cấp có thẩm quyền. Trong quá theo dõi và kiểm tra, khi phát hiện những trường hợp (cá nhân, tổ chức) có hành vi vi phạm, phải tiến hành xử lý nghiêm khắc theo quy định của pháp luật về đất đai. UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi giao trách nhiệm cho Sở TNMT kiểm tra, rà soát; không tham mưu cho tỉnh giao (cho thuê) đất, đối với các tổ chức có hành vi vi phạm về đất đai. Được biết thời gian qua, dư luận người dân Quảng Ngãi tỏ ra bức xúc trước việc phát hiện hàng loạt sai phạm liên quan đất đai của Công ty Hà – Mỹ Á trong quá trình triển khai thực hiện 2 dự án khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận; dự án khu dân cư Nghĩa Thuận, ở huyện Tư Nghĩa. Cụ thể, đối với khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận, tại thời điểm khởi công vào tháng 4/2017, dự án vẫn chưa có ĐTM; chưa có (đến ngày 7/7/2022 mới có) quyết định chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng và cho thuê đất. Và đến thời điểm này, dù được hoàn thành và đưa vào hoạt động gần 3 năm, hiện khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận vẫn chưa có giấy phép xây dựng. Tương tự là dự án khu dân cư Nghĩa Thuận (cũng do Công ty Hà – Mỹ Á làm chủ đầu tư), dù mới được cấp quyết định đầu tư (vào ngày 22/5/2018) và đến thời điểm này, vẫn chưa được có quyết định chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng, giao đất nhưng chủ đầu tư, đã san lấp và thi công hoàn thành cơ sở hạ tầng đường giao thông nội bộ, điện…"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'besar perut'? Berikan satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Maksudnya ialah hamil. Contoh ayat: Kami bakal mendapat anak saudara kerana kakak sudah besar perut."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : libros. ","answer":"¿Cuál es el libro más grande del mundo? "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bau busuk tidak berbangkai\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud fitnah atau celaan yang tidak beralasan."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 新型コロナウイルスの心配が少なくなって、日本から外国に行ったり来たりすることがまたできるようになりました。政府によると、3月に日本に来た外国人は2019年の同じ月の65%まで戻りました。しかし、外国に行った日本人は36%で、増えていません。国は外国に行く人を増やすために、新しくパスポートを取る人や更新する人のうち3210人に、インターネットの買い物で使うことができる8000円の券を贈ることを決めました。旅行会社は、学生などの若い人が利用しやすい値段のツアーなどを増やします。10日、フランスやオーストラリア、グアムなど23の国と地域の政府の人も出席した会見がありました。フランスの人は「新型コロナの前と同じように旅行に来る人が増えましたが、日本人はまだです。すぐに来てほしいです」と言いました。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。- 政府: 1）国の政治を行うところ。2）内閣。- 増やす: 1）多くする。- パスポート: 1）国が発行する、外国旅行に必要な身分証明書。旅券。- 更新: 1）新しいものにかえること。または、かわること。- 券: 1）「乗車券」「入場券」などの略。切符。チケット。- 贈る: 1）品物を人にあげる。プレゼントする。2）手柄のあった人に、位や勲章などを与える。- ツアー: 1）観光やスポーツなどのために、団体で行く旅行。- 増やし: 1）ある範囲に区切られた土地。- 地域: 1）前もって場所や時間を決めておき、公式に人と会うこと。"},{"question":"شنو السميه ديال المدينه اللي أسسها القائد جوهر الصقلي؟","answer":"  هي مدينه القاهره وجوهر الصقلي تولد فصقيليه سنه 928 ميلاديه وتوفى سنه 992 ميلاديه ومعروف باسم جوهر الرومي وهو من اهم واشهر القواد ف.التاريخ الفاطمي بحيث انه اسس مدينه القاهره الفاطميه وبنى جامع الازهر. تيتعتبر فاتح بلاد المغرب ومصر وفلسطين والشام والحجاز وهو من الشيعه."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക ഏത് വിഷയത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്: \\"കേരള ഹൈക്കോടതിയുടെ പഴയ മന്ദിരം പ്രവർത്തിച്ചിരുന്നത് എറണാകുളത്തെ റാംമോഹൻ പാലസിലാണ്. പുതിയ മന്ദിരത്തിന്റെ ശിലാസ്ഥാപനം 1994 മാർച്ച് 14-ന് സുപ്രീം കോടതിയുടെ അപ്പോഴത്തെ മുഖ്യന്യായാധിപനായ എം.എൻ. വെങ്കിട ചെല്ലയ്യ നിർവഹിച്ചു. 2005-ൽ മന്ദിരത്തിന്റെ നിർമ്മാണം പൂർത്തിയായി. 2006 ഫെബ്രുവരി 11-ന് സുപ്രീം കോടതിയുടെ അപ്പോഴത്തെ മുഖ്യന്യായാധിപനായ വൈ.കെ. സബർവാൾ പുതിയ മന്ദിരത്തിന്റെ ഉദ്ഘാടനം നിർവഹിച്ചു.\\"","answer":"മുകളിലെ ഖണ്ഡിക \\"കേരള ഹൈക്കോടതി\\" യെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്."},{"question":"ma kamapani a ma network mu dizo la Malawi","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili ndi ma kampani a ma network a ma foni a m'manja anayi1. TNM Malawi2. Airtel Malawi3. Access Communications Malawi4. MTL"},{"question":"Зарыл ишиң болбосо Зардалыда эмне бар. Макалды түшүндүрүп бер?","answer":"Зардалы деген айыл Баткенге карайт суулардан өтүп (суусу терең ашып ташыган аккан дарыя) тоолорду ашып жогору ылдый жүрүп канча кыйынчылыктар менен жетишкен. Ошондуктан зарыл ишиң болбосо Зардалыга барып кыйналып жүрбө деген мааниде айтылган. "},{"question":"“శివాజీ కళ్యాణి దుర్గాన్ని సాధించాడు. వీరులకు సాధ్యము కానిది లోకమున లేదు కదా” ఈ వాక్యాలలో గల అలంకారాన్ని గుర్తించి, లక్షణం రాయండి.","answer":"అర్ధాంతర న్యాసాలంకారము : సామాన్యమును విశేషముచే కాని, విశేషమును సామాన్యముచే కాని సమరించుట."},{"question":"In \\"The Tempest,\\" Prospero, the exiled Duke, wields magic and language to manipulate characters and orchestrate events. What does this tell us about the power of language and its relationship to illusion and reality?","answer":"\\"The Tempest\\" is a fascinating exploration of language's transformative potential. Consider these key points:Language as Magic: Prospero's spells and incantations are essentially linguistic constructions. He controls the characters and the very fabric of the play through his masterful use of language.Illusion and Manipulation: The play blurs the lines between reality and illusion. Prospero's theatrical tricks and persuasive language manipulate the audience's perception, forcing them to question what they see and hear.Language as Power: Ultimately, the play suggests that language is a powerful tool that can shape reality, deceive, and even redeem. Prospero's journey is about learning to use language responsibly and finding forgiveness through its creative power."},{"question":"Tirela tẹ tọkọ-tiyawo pa loju ọna Ṣagamu-Ogijo","answer":"Ni nnkan bii aago mẹjọ ku ogun iṣẹju, aarọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kejila, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2020 yii, ni iku ojiji pa tọkọ-taya kan loju ọna Ṣagamu-Ogijo, nipinlẹ Ogun. Ọlọkada to gbe wọn lo fi tiẹ ko ba wọn nigba to fẹẹ ya ọkọ Camry kan silẹ, bo ṣe takiti, ti tirela to n bọ lẹyin tẹ wọn pa niyẹn.Nigba to n ṣalaye bi ijamba naa ṣe ṣẹlẹ gan-an, Alukoro TRACE, Ọgbẹni Babatunde Akinbiyi, sọ pe Ogijo ni ọlọkada to da wahala silẹ naa ti n bọ, Ṣagamu lo si n lọ.O ni mọto bii mẹta ni ọkada ti ko ni nọmba naa ti ya silẹ, nibi to ti n sare buruku loju popo.Igba to fẹẹ ya mọto ayọkẹlẹ Camry ti nọmba ẹ jẹ FKY 733GF silẹ lo lọọ kọ lu mọto naa lẹyin, bii igba ti ẹyin fori sọ apata lo ri, nitori niṣe lọkada ṣubu yakata si titi, ti awọn tọkọ-tiyawo to gbe naa ṣubu pẹlu, ki wọn too dide ni tirela to n bọ lẹyin, ti nọmba ẹ jẹ AGL 505 WX ti ba wọn nibẹ, to si tẹ wọn pa.Ọlọkada yii ko ku ni tiẹ, o kan ṣeṣe ni. Akinbiyi sọ pe ile igbokuu-si to wa nileewosan Ọlabisi Ọnabanjọ, ni Ṣagamu, lawọn gbe oku awọn tọkọ-taya naa lọ. O ni ileewosan Idẹra lawọn gbe ọlọkada to ṣeṣe lọ."},{"question":"Iru ki waa leleyii, wọn lawọn Fulani to sa kuro n’Igangan ti tun paayan mẹta n’Imẹkọ","answer":"O kere tan, eeyan mẹta ni wọn ku iku ojiji nibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Amule Ọlọgẹdẹ, n’Imẹkọ, ipinlẹ Ogun, lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ti i ṣe ọjọ kẹfa, oṣu kẹfa, ọdun 2021.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe awọn Fulani to paayan rẹpẹtẹ n’Igangan, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ni wọn tun pa awọn t’Imẹkọ yii naa lẹyin ti wọn sa kuro l’Ọyọọ, ti wọn si wọle sipinlẹ Ogun.Awọn eeyan mẹta to ku iku ojiji naa ni Fẹmi Bara, John Taiwo ati Tunde Taiwo.ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn ọkunrin mẹta yii wa lori ọkada Bajaj tuntun ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ ra ni lasiko ti wọn kagbako naa. Oko wọn ni wọn ti n bọ, wọn si n pada s’Imẹkọ ti wọn n gbe ni ki wọn too ko sọwọ awọn Fulani ọhun. Bi wọn ṣe dumbu wọn tan ni wọn tun gbe ọkada wọn lọ.Balogun Imẹkọ-Isalẹ, Oloye Ganiu Akinlẹyẹ, to fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ fawọn akọroyin niluu Abẹokuta, ṣalaye pe nnkan bii aago mọkanla alẹ ọjọ Sannde naa niṣẹlẹ yii waye.O tẹsiwaju pe awọn Fulani apaayan yii ti tẹdo sibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Sagada, n’Imẹkọ. Balogun sọ pe aarọ Mọnde lawọn ọlọpaa waa ko oku awọn mẹta to doloogbe naa lọ si mọṣuari ileewosan Imẹkọ.‘Awọn darandaran to sa kuro n’Igangan lẹyin ti wọn paayan ti wa labule Sagada, nipinlẹ Ogun. Oke Agbẹdẹ gan-an nibi ti wọn wa, ni wọọdu keji.‘Odo kan wa ta a n pe ni Ọyan, laarin Sagada ati Igangan lo wa, wọn wa nibẹ bi mo ṣe n ba yin sọrọ yii. A ti sọ fawọn agbofinro to yẹ ka sọ fun, ṣugbọn a ko ti i ri i ki wọn gbe igbesẹ rere kan lori ẹ.’ Bẹẹ ni Balogun Imẹkọ-Isalẹ wi.Awọn araalu paapaa sọrọ, wọn fẹdun ọkan ṣalaye pe ẹmi awọn ko de, nitori igbakigba lawọn Fulani n daamu awọn ti wọn n pa awọn bii ẹran.Awọn araalu sọ pe ọga ọlọpaa tẹlẹ to ni kawọn maa ko ibọn awọn waa funjọba lo ko awọn si wahala yii, nitori nigba ti wọn ti gba awọn ibọn atawọn nnkan ija awọn yooku pe kalaafia le wa lawọn ko ti ni nnkan igbara ẹni silẹ mọ.Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, naa fidi iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ. Ṣugbọn o ni eeyan ko le sọ pe Fulani lawọn to pa awọn to ku n’Imẹkọ yii, nitori ọkada awọn oloogbe naa ti wọn tun gbe sa lọ lẹyin ti wọn pa wọn si ni.Oyeyẹmi sọ pe adigunjale lawọn to pa wọn naa yoo fẹrẹ jẹ. O ni ikọ alaabo tijọba Ogun ṣẹṣẹ gbe kalẹ yoo yanju ọrọ yii, wọn yoo wa awọn to ṣiṣẹ ibi naa ri,wọn yoo si ri i pe wọn gba ọkada naa pada ki wọn ma baa tun lọọ maa fi ṣiṣẹ ibi kiri."},{"question":"Explain the cultural significance of \\"Purano Nepal\\" and its role in preserving traditional folk songs.","answer":"Purano Nepal is a genre of traditional Nepali folk songs that preserve cultural stories, history, and heritage."},{"question":"Pergunta: Qual cidade é chamada de cidade das flores no Paquistão? Resposta:","answer":"Pexauar"},{"question":"Looy Jél?","answer":"Lépp laay Jél."},{"question":"Ibo abẹle Ondo: Kekemeke loun ko ni igbẹkẹle ninu ẹ, Abraham naa binu kuro","answer":"Ọkan ninu awọn to n dije sipo gomina ninu eto idibo to n bọ lọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun ta a wa yii, ti pariwo pe oun ko ni igbẹkẹle kankan ninu eto idibo abẹle ẹgbẹ APC to n lọ lọwọ nipinlẹ Ondo.Alaga ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC nipinlẹ Ondo tẹlẹ ri ọhun ni lati igba tawọn asaaju ẹgbẹ ti ta ku lori ilana ti wọn fẹẹ ṣamulo ninu eto idibo abẹle naa loun ti mọ pe ejo wọn ti n lọwọ ninu.Bakan naa ni Kekemeke tun fẹsun kan gomina ipinlẹ Kogi, Alaaji Yahaya Bello, to jẹ alaga igbimọ to n ṣeto idibo ọhun pe ko ka awọn oludije yooku si rara, yatọ si Akeredolu nikan. O ni nnkan bii aago mọkanla aabọ alẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, nigba ti eto idibo naa ku bii wakati perete ko bẹrẹ loun sẹsẹ n ri iwe akọsilẹ orukọ awọn aṣoju to fẹẹ dibo, eyi to lodi si ilana ti wọn fi n ṣeto ibo abẹle.Ọkan ninu awọn olukopa mi-in, Oluṣẹgun Abraham, loun ko ni i kopa ninu eto abẹle naa mọ. Ọkunrin naa ni oun ko nigbagbọ ninu awọn ti wọn n ṣe kokaari eto naa.Akọwe iroyin rẹ, Ọgbẹni Kunle Adumashi, lo fidi eleyii mulẹ."},{"question":"Awọn Fulani ya wọ ipinlẹ Ọyọ tibọntibọn, agbegbe Ìbàràpá lawọn agbofinro ti da wọn duro","answer":"Lẹyin ọjọ mẹta ti awọn agbofinro ilẹ Yoruba, Amọtẹkun ẹka ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti lọọ gbéjà ka awọn afurasi ajinigbe mọ ibuba wọn ninu aginjù igbo, ti wọn sì yinbọn pa mẹta ninu awọn agbesunmọmi náà lẹyìn ija alagbara to waye laarin wọn, awọn Fulani ti  dihamọra ija wọ ipinlẹ Ọyọ, wọn ni wọn fẹẹ gbẹsan pipa tàwọn agbofinro pa ninu wọn lọjọsi ni.Orugànjọ́ lawọn eeṣin-ò-kọ-kú ẹda naa fi boju wa. Loru ọjọ Abamẹta, Sátidé, mọju ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, ni wọn ya wọ ipinlẹ Ọyọ tibọn-tibọn.Ọkan ninu awọn olugbe ilu Idere, lagbegbe Ìbàràpá, to fìdí iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ woye pé ẹsan pipa ti awọn Amọtẹkun pa ninu wọn lasiko ija to waye nigba ti awọn agbofinro wa wọn lọ sinu aginjù igbo ti wọn n lo fún iṣẹ laabi won, lawọn afurasi agbesunmọmi náà fẹẹ gba ti won fi ṣigun wọ ipinlẹ yìí.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Ọkọ bọọsi nla meji to kún fun awọn Fulani bíi ogoji (40) lawọn Amọtẹkun, Operation Burst atawọn ọdẹ ri lagbegbe Ibarapa loru mọju ọjọ Sannde.“Fulani ni gbogbo wọn, gbogbo wọn ni wọn dihamọra pẹlu nnkan ìjà bii ibọn, àdá, idà ati oríṣìíríṣìí nnkan ìjà oloro.“Agọ ọlọpaa to wa niluu Eruwa lawọn agbofinro gbe wọn lọ. Lẹyin naa lawọn alaga kansu agbegbe Ibarapa wọn panu pọ fọwọ si i pe kí won gbe awọn eeyan wonyi lọ sileeṣẹ ọlọpaa n’Ibadan.”Agbẹnusọ fun ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi, fidi iroyin yii múlẹ, o ni iwadii ṣi n lọ lọwọ lori iṣẹlẹ naa.Sugbon nigba ti akọroyin wa pe agbẹnusọ fún ẹṣọ Amọtẹkun ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ lati fìdí iṣẹlẹ yii mulẹ siwjau, obinrin naa, Abilekọ Ayọọla Adedọja, sọ pe oun yóò pe pada nitori oun n wa mọto lọwọ, ṣugbọn lẹyin wakati meji sigba naa ti akọroyin wa tun pe é, ko gbe awọn ipe naa titi ta a fi kọ iroyin yii tan."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la pregunta a: \\"Con una predicción de Urbain Le Verrier, observaciones telescópicas que confirman la existencia de un planeta mayor fueron hechas en la noche del 23 al 24 de septiembre de 1846, en el Observatorio de Berlín, por el astrónomo Johann Gottfried Galle (asistido por Heinrich Louis d'Arrest), trabajando a partir de los cálculos de Le Verrier\\"? El tema es el descubrimiento de Neptuno.","answer":"Pregunta : \\"¿quién descubrió el planeta Neptuno?\\". "},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy tego paragrafu: W wieku 4 lat Szolkowy wraz z matką przeprowadził się do Erfurtu, gdzie zaczął trenować łyżwiarstwo figurowe. Jego pierwszą partnerką była Johanna Otto. Kolejną jego partnerką była Claudia Rauschenbach, z którą w 2001 zdobył mistrzostwo Niemiec. Gdy Rauschenbach zakończyła karierę, Szolkowy nie mógł znaleźć partnerki. W końcu w 2003 zaczął jeździć wraz z Aloną Sawczenko. Przeprowadził się do Chemnitz i był reprezentantem klubu Chemnitzer EC. Ich trenerem stał się Ingo Steuer. W 2004 Szolkowy i Sawczenko zdobyli mistrzostwo Niemiec. Po otrzymaniu niemieckiego obywatelstwa przez Alionę para mogła reprezentować Niemcy w Igrzyskach Olimpijskich w 2006. Na Mistrzostwach Europy w 2006 para zdobyła srebrny medal, a 3 kolejnych Mistrzostwach Europy w 2007, 2008 i 2009 -złote. Na Mistrzostwach Europy w 2010 para zdobyła swój drugi srebrny medal. W 2007 na Mistrzostwach Świata w Tokio zdobyli brąz, by w Göteborgu","answer":"i Los Angeles nie mieć sobie równych. W 2011 roku wywalczył ponownie złoty medal mistrzostw świata, tym razem było to w Moskwie, a rok później w Nicei wywalczył kolejne złoto. w Igrzyskach Olimpijskich w 2010 roku zdobył w parze sportowej brązowy medal olimpijski."},{"question":"వ్యవస్థీకృత రంగంలో ఉద్యోగాలను అందరూ కోరుకుంటారు. కానీ ఈ రంగంలోని ఉపాధి అవకాశాలు చాలా నిదానంగా పెరుగుతున్నాయి. ఫలితంగా, అధిక శాతం కార్మికులకు చాలా తక్కువ వేతనానికి అవ్యవస్థీకృత ఉద్యోగాలు తప్పించి మరో దారి లేదు.ప్రశ్న : అవ్యవస్థీకృత రంగం కన్నా వ్యవస్థీకృత రంగం మెరుగైనది అనుకుంటున్నారా? మీ అభిప్రాయం తెలుపండి.","answer":"వ్యవస్థీకృతరంగం మెరుగైనది – అభిప్రాయం :అవును. అవ్యవస్థీకృత రంగం కంటే వ్యవస్థీకృత రంగం మెరుగైనదని భావిస్తాను.వ్యవస్థీకృతరంగంలో క్రమబద్ధమైన ఉపాధి షరతులు ఉండి నమ్మకంగా పని ఉంటుంది.ప్రభుత్వ నియమ నిబంధనలు పాటించబడతాయి.ఈ రంగంలో కార్మికులకు ఉద్యోగ భద్రత ఉంటుంది.వారు నిర్ధారిత పనిగంటలు మాత్రమే పనిచేస్తారు.వారికి జీతంతో కూడిన సెలవు, సెలవులలో వేతనం, భవిష్యనిధి వంటి ప్రయోజనాలు"},{"question":"ਭਾਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹੜਾ ਅਕਸ਼ਾਂਸ਼ ਵਿਤ ਜਾਂ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਅਕਸ਼ਾਂਸ਼ ਰੇਖਾ ਲਗਪਗ ਦੋ ਸਮਾਨ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਦੀ ਹੈ ? ਇਸਦਾ ਅਕਸ਼ਾਂਸ਼ ਕਿੰਨਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਭਾਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਕਰਕ ਵਿਤ ਜਾਂ ਕਰਕ ਰੇਖਾ ਲਗਪਗ ਦੋ ਬਰਾਬਰ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡਦੀ ਹੈ । ਇਸਦਾ ਅਕਸ਼ਾਂਸ਼ 23°30′ ਉੱਤਰ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"ഈ വാചകം ഏത് പ്രധാന സംഭവത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്: ഈ കൂട്ടപ്പലായനത്തിന്റെ കാരണങ്ങൾ ചരിത്രകാരന്മാർക്കിടയിൽ അഭിപ്രായവ്യത്യാസങ്ങൾ മൂലം പല രൂപങ്ങളിൽ കാണപ്പെടുന്നുണ്ട്. യഹൂദ സൈനിക മുന്നേറ്റം, അറബ് ഭൂരിപക്ഷ ഗ്രാമങ്ങളുടെ ഉന്മൂലനം, മനഃശാസ്ത്രപരമായ യുദ്ധം, ദേർ യാസീൻ കൂട്ടക്കൊലയ്ക്ക് ശേഷം സയണിസ്റ്റ് നാട്ടുപട നടത്തിയേക്കാവുന്ന മറ്റൊരു കൂട്ടക്കൊലയെക്കുറിച്ചുള്ള ഉൾഭയം പലരെയും സംഭ്രാന്തിയിലാഴ്ത്തിയത്, ഇസ്രായേൽ അധികൃതരുടെ നേരിട്ടുള്ള പുറത്താക്കൽ ഉത്തരവുകൾ, സമ്പന്ന വിഭാഗങ്ങളുടെ സ്വമേധയായുള്ള ഒഴിഞ്ഞുപോക്ക്, പലസ്തീൻ നേതൃത്വത്തിന്റേയും അറബ് പലായന ഉത്തരവുകളുടേയും ശക്തിക്ഷയം, യഹൂദ നിയന്ത്രണത്തിൽ ജീവിക്കാനുള്ള വിസമ്മതം എന്നിവയും ഈ കൂട്ടപ്പാലായനത്തെ പ്രബലമായി സ്വാധീനിച്ച ഘടകങ്ങളിൽ ഉൾപ്പെടുന്നു.","answer":"ദേർ യാസീൻ കൂട്ടക്കൊലയ്ക്ക്"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的地下交通系統是哪個？","answer":"答案：英國的倫敦地鐵"},{"question":"Iza no ranomasina any atsinanan'i Madagasikara?","answer":"Any atsinanan'i India no misy ny ranomasina Indianina."},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 太平洋戦争が続いていた1945年2月10日、群馬県太田市にアメリカの軍が空から攻撃をしました。この空襲を撮った映像が見つかりました。","answer":"太田市には、日本の軍の飛行機が訓練をする場所があって、空襲が何度もありました。この日の空襲では160人以上が亡くなりました。映像は飛行機の工場で働いていた男性が撮って、県の歴史の博物館にコピーがありました。 映像には、走って逃げる大勢の人や10ぐらいのアメリカの軍の飛行機が写っています。 空襲の専門家は「逃げている人たちは慌てているように見えます。みんなの命を守るための考え方が十分ではなくて、空襲の前にみんなを避難させていなかったからだと思います」と話しています。"},{"question":"Faaiidooyinka midhaha afakaadhaha maxaa ka mid ah.?","answer":"Midhaha afakaadhaha (avocado) waxa ay leeyihiin waxtar badan, maa ha oo kaliya mid waxtar leh in la isku qurxiyo, laakiin sidoo kale waa cunto gaar ah. Cabsida qabaan dadka badhkood ee ah in ay baruur badani ku jirto kasakow, waxa uu leeyahay faa’iidooyin dhowr ah. Waa maxay sirta midhahani?Midhaha avocado waxa ay gaar ku yahan dhadhan aad u macaan,waa midho si aada loogu isticmaalo diyaarinta nuucyada kala duwan ee cuntada, avokado waxa uu sumcad wanaagsan ku leeyahay qaybaha quruxda, iyada oo inta badan lagu isticmaalaa sameynta waxyaabaha qurxinta wajiga iyo daryeelka jidhka.Shaki kuma jiro in muhiimadda ku ladhan midhahan ay sababteeda leeyihiin, midhaha avocado waxaa ku jira tiro ka mid ah fitamiin iyo macdamo lagama maarmaan u ah koritaanka iyo ilaalinta caafimaadka ,waxa sidoo kale ku jira dufanka dabiiciga ah ee nasiiya tamarta. Sidan soo socota ayaan kusoo bandhigaynaa xaqiiqooyinka ku saabsan muhiimadda ay leedahay cunidda avocado:1- Waxa uu hodan ku yahay nafaqada: Avocado waa mid kamid midhaha aad ka hodanka ugu ah nafaqada ee lagama maarmaanka u ah jidhka, waxa ku jira (acid Pantothenic, fiber ka iyo vitamin “K” iyo “C” iyo qaar ka mid ah birta sida copper, folic acid, potassium acid, waxana fitamiinadan iyo macdantan tiradan le’eeg laga yaabaa inay yareeyaan halista cudurrada.2- Joogtaynta heerka caafimaad ee Cholesterol ka: Avocado waxa ku jira pantothenic acid, sidaa daradeed ayaa acid kani uu door muhiim ah ugu leeyahay isku dheeli-tirka heerka (Cholesterol ) ka baruurta dhiigga ku jirta, taasoo lagu xaqiijiyay daraasad lagu sameeyay dad ka cabanaya cholesterol-ka dheeraadka, sida lagu faafiyay website ka ”Gazundhaat-stiif”.Sida laga soo xigtay daraasadani, dadkii nidaamkooga cunto uu kutiirsanaa avocado ah muddo todobaad ah, waxa hoos u dhacay heerka (Cholestarol)ka “LDL” baruurta xun ee dhiiggooga ku jirtay, halka heerka cholesterol-ka “HDL” baruuta fiican ay korodhay.3- Waxa uu nafaqo u leeyahay haweenka uurka leh: Dufanka caafimaadka qaba iyo protein kujira avocado ah, waxa ay ka dhigaan midhahan cunto muhiim u ah haweenka uurka leh oo u baahan tiro badan oo nafaqo ah xiliga ay uurka leeyihiin.4- Waxa uu waxtar u leeyahay indhaha: Sida laga soo xigtay daraasad lagu sameeyay 29 qof waxa cadaatay maadada “lutein” ay indhaha u wanaagsantahay,waxana ay ka hortaga cudurka ku dhaca ee keena dhalaadka cad ee sababa aragtida oo xumaata ama indha la’aanta. Waxa xusid mudan in 81 microgram oo maadada “lutein” ka ah ay ku jirto midhaha avocado.5- Xoojinta habka difaaca jidhka: Midhaha avokado waxa ku jira tiro aad u badan oo fitamiin “C” ah, xabada kaliya ee avocado waxa au daboolayaa 20% oo ka mid ah baahi maalmeedka vitamin tan, kasoo kaa caawinaya xoojinta nidaamka difaaca jidhka. Sida badh kamid ah ay qabaan vitamin “C” gu waxa uu yareeyaa halista duriga, xasaasiyada, dhaawacyada murqayada iyo dhiiga karka aadka u sareeya.6- Avocado-du waxay faaido u leedahay timaha: waxay ka hor tagtaa in timuhu daataan isla markaana waxay kobcisaa koritaankooda. Avocado-du waxay hodan ku tahay fiitamiinada B iyo E kuwaasoo ilaaliya quruxda iyo caafimaadka timaha.7- Waxay hodan ku tahay Potassium: Midhaha avocado-da waxaa ku jira macdanta Potassium in ka badan tan ku jirta muuska. Daraasado dhowr ah ayaa muujiyay in macdanta Potassium hoos u dhigto dhiig karka, khatarta wadne xanuunka iyo howlgabka kelyaha.8- Waxay ilaalisaa caafimaadka indhaha: avocado-da waxaa ku jira  nafaqooyin lagu kala magacaabo Lutein iyo Zeaxanthin oo muhiim u ah caafimaadka indhaha.9-Waxa uu kaa caawinayaa yareynta miisaanka: Inkastoo midhaha avocado ay ku jirta tiro badan oo acidka dufanka dabiiciga ah, dadka badhkood waxa ay sheegayaan in uu kaa caawinayo yaraynta miisaanka,waxana ay sabab uga dhigeen in cunista 1 avocado ah uu kor u qaadayo dareenka dharaga."},{"question":"Ity misy lahatsoratra:Izy dia poety, mpanoratra, mpampianatra, akademisianina. Andriamalala Emilson Daniel Tsiferana no anarany, zana-dRazafitsiferana Randimby sy Razafinirina Marguerite. Niray fikambanana tamin-dry Paul Dussac io rainy io. Teraka ny 22 Oktobra 1918 tao Toamasina i Emilson Daniel Andriamalala. Nanambady an-dRamialinoro Lalasoa Berthe izy. Niteraka 13 mianadahy izy ireo, dimy lahy sy valo vavy, ka ny roa amin'ny lahy sy ny telo amin'ny vavy no efa maty. Iray amin'ireo rahalahiny iray tampo aminy Randimby Tsiferana Nardy. Ny 25 mey 1979 no nodimandry tao Itaosy i Emilson Daniel Andriamalala.Inona no resahin'io lahatsoratra io?","answer":"Ny mombamomba ny mpanoratra Malagasy Emilson Daniel Andriamalala no resahin'io lahatsoratra io."},{"question":"Ali Koç'un Fenerbahçenin  başkanlığa geldiği kongreye ne zaman yapıldı?","answer":"Ali Koç'un başkanlığa geldiği kongre 2-3 Haziran 2018'de yapıldı."},{"question":" கேள்வி: ‘சென்றிடுவீர் எட்டுத்திக்கும் – கலைச்செல்வங்கள் யாவும் கொணர்ந்திங்கு சேர்ப்பீர்– பாரதியாரின் இக்கூற்று உணர்த்தும் கருத்து?அ) பலதுறை நூல்கள் தமிழில் உருவாக்கப்பட வேண்டும்.ஆ) பலகலைகள் தமிழில் புதிதாகத் தோன்ற வேண்டும்.இ) உலகெங்கும் காணப்படும் செல்வங்கள் தமிழகத்தில் வந்து சேர்தல் வேண்டும்.ஈ) கலைச் செல்வங்களை உலகம் முழுவதும் பயணம் செய்து கண்டுகளிக்க வேண்டும்.","answer":" பதில்: இ) உலகெங்கும் காணப்படும் செல்வங்கள் தமிழகத்தில் வந்து சேர்தல் வேண்டும்."},{"question":"ඉන්දියාවේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"නව දිල්ලිය (හින්දි = නායි දිල්ලි) ඉන්දියාවේ අගනගරයයි. නෙළුම් දෙවොල (Lotus Temple), හුමායුන්ගේ සොහොන, කොනෝට් පෙදෙස, අක්ෂර්දම් දෙවොල සහ ඉන්දියා ද්වාරය 1911 දෙසැම්බර් 15 වැනිදා මුල් ගල් තබන ලද නව දිල්ලිය 20 වන සියවසේ ප්‍රසිද්ධ බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය නගර ශිල්පීන් දෙදෙනෙකු වූ එඩ්වින් ලුටියන්ස් සහ හර්බට් බේකර් විසින්ද සැලසුම් කර ඇත. පසුව 1931 පෙබරවාරි 13 වැනි දින අර්වින් ආදීපාද වයිස්රෝයි විසින් නගරය නිල වශයෙන් විවෘත කරන ලදී. සුවිසල් රුක් සෙවණැති මාර්ගවලින් හෙබි නව දිල්ලි නගරයේ රටේ ප්‍රධාන ආයතන සහ ගොඩනැගිලි රාශියක් පිහිටා ඇත. භුමි ප්‍රමාණය වර්ග කි.මී. 42.7 කි.අලංකාර තැන් ඇත.එය ලෝකයේ වේගයෙන්ම වර්ධනය වන නගර වලින් එකකි. ඉන්දියාවේ දෙවෙනියට විශාලම නගරය වෙයි."},{"question":"Ilang oras ang nasa pagitan ng New York at Manila?","answer":"Dalawa ang posibleng sagot depende kung kasalukuyang nasa Daylight Savings Time o DST ang Estados Unidos. Labintatlong (13) oras ang diperensya ng Manila at New York kung hindi nasa DST ang Estados Unidos. Kapag nasa DST naman, labindalawang (12) oras na lang ang diperensya. Isa ang Estados Unidos sa mga bansang nag-oobserba ng Daylight Savings, kung saan ay inaagahan nila ng isang oras ang mga orasan upang makatipid sa kuryente."},{"question":"Jumla ta 1: Jerin farko ya sami karbuwa sosai daga masu sukar fiye da na biyu. Jumla ta biyu: Jerin na biyu ya sami karbuwa sosai daga masu sukar fiye da na farko. Tambaya: Shin jumla ta 1 da jumla ta 2 suna bayyana ma'ana iri ɗaya ko a'a?","answer":"A'a basu bayyana ma'ana iri daya ba"},{"question":"నేను వికీపీడియాలో చైతన్య భారతి ఇన్‌స్టిట్యూట్ ఆఫ్ టెక్నాలజీ గురించిన క్రింది టెక్స్ట్ స్నిప్పెట్‌ని కనుగొన్నాను.ఇచ్చిన టెక్స్ట్ స్నిప్పెట్ ఆధారంగా చైతన్య భారతి ఇన్స్టిట్యూట్ ఆఫ్ టెక్నాలజీని ఎప్పుడు స్థాపించారు? ప్రశ్నకి సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిస్నిప్పెట్: మొత్తం నిర్మించారు ప్రాంతంలో 4,45,467 చదరపు అడుగుల 30 ఎకరాల విస్తరించి Rs.25.oo కోట్లు విలువ. ఎఐసిటిఇ నుండి పొందింది నిధుల Rs.1.3 కోట్లు విలువ. కళాశాల 1979 లో స్థాపించబడింది. సంస్థ 200 విద్యార్ధ ఒక తీసుకుంటున్న మూడు అండర్గ్రాడ్యుయేట్ ప్రోగ్రామ్లను మొదలైంది. 2007 ద్వారా ఈ 900 విద్యార్థులు మొత్తం తీసుకుంటున్న తొమ్మిది అండర్ గ్రాడ్యుయేట్ మరియు ఏడు స్నాతకోత్తర కోర్సులను పెరిగింది. 196 ఎంసెట్ ర్యాంక్తో తెలివైన మరియు ప్రతిభావంతులైన అభ్యర్థులు నుంచి ముఖ్యంగా ECE లో CBIT లో ప్రవేశ కోరుతూ, EEE, CSE, ఐటి, మెకానికల్ ఇంజనీరింగ్ మొదలైనవి శాతం కూడా సగటున 95% స్థిరంగా ఉంది.దాని విద్యార్థులు భారత అంతరిక్ష పరిశోధనా సంస్థతో డిజైన్ మరియు ఉపగ్రహము, STUDSAT, విజయవంతంగా ప్రయోగలో పాల్గొన్న జట్టు భాగంగా ఉన్నప్పుడు కళాశాల కోసం మైలురాళ్ళు ఒకటి. STUDSAT విజయవంతంగా కక్ష్యలోకి ఉంచుతారు మరియు 11:07 గంటలకు 2010 జూలై 12 న మొదటి సిగ్నల్ అందుకుంది","answer":"చైతన్య భారతి ఇన్స్టిట్యూట్ ఆఫ్ టెక్నాలజీని 1979 లో స్థాపించబడింది."},{"question":"Write a short story about a character who discovers a hidden talent.","answer":"एक पात्र के बारे में एक लघु कहानी जिसने एक छुपी हुई प्रतिभा का खोज किया।"},{"question":"menene cikaken maanar kalma?","answer":"Kalma ita ce tushen harshe mai ɗauke da manufa ko ma'ana mai amfani, ana iya amfani da ita da kanta, kuma ta ba da maana mai kyau."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي أكرمه الله تعالى بمعجزة إحياء الموتى؟    ","answer":"    الجواب: عيسى عليه والسلام."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: I Finlands vinter- och fortsättningskrig","answer":"deltog 330 judiska soldater och 20 lottor av vilka 23 stupade. Nästan samtliga som deltog kom från Helsingfors, Åbo, Viborg och Vasa. Vid minnestillställningen för de stupade i Helsingfors synagoga 6 december 1944 deltog sittande president marskalk Mannerheim."},{"question":"在加拿大，当驾驶执照被吊销，他会？","answer":"在任何情形下都不准驾驶"},{"question":"لاندې پوښتنې ځواب کړئ. چا چې دا سندره وویله باید غوا وي","answer":"ټوبي کیت"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أكبر رقم لقميص اللاعب في 2005؟","answer":"91الإجابة:"},{"question":"ما السورة التي بُدأت باسم من أسماء الله الحسنى؟","answer":"الإجابة : الرحمن."},{"question":"ماهو مقياس مقاومة السائل للتدفق والانسياب:(أ) الميوعة (ب) التماسك والتلاصق(ج) التوتر السطحي (د) اللزوجة","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة (د)  اللزوجة."},{"question":"අනපේක්ෂිත යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අනපේක්ෂිත යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය අපේක්ෂිත වේ. "},{"question":"متن زیر به چه مساله ای اشاره می کند:من در طول این سال‌ها ده‌ها برنامه رادیویی اجرا کرده و صدها جلسه و نشست عمومی را با حضور مخاطب زنده مدیریت کرده‌ام. بخش پرسش و پاسخ بخش مهمی از این جلسات است و من می‌خواهم همه احساس راحتی کنند و اگر سؤالی در ذهنشان می‌جوشد آن را مطرح کنند. اما باوجودآنکه سعی می‌کنم مردم احساس راحتی و آرامش کنند، وقتی دست‌ها بالا می‌روند، همیشه تعداد مردانی که آماده‌اند سؤالی بپرسند بیشتر از زنان است. اغلب اولین دست‌هایی که بالا می‌رود دست مردان است.","answer":"در جلسات عمومی، زنان کمتر از مردان ممکن است سؤال خود را بپرسند."},{"question":"Vraag: Wie wordt als de grondlegger van het parlementarisme in Nederland beschouwd?","answer":"Antwoord: Johan Rudolph Thorbecke"},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Kepentingan Mempelajari dan Menguasai Bahasa Asing.","answer":"Bahasa jiwa bangsa merupakan pepatah yang membawa maksud bahasa adalah identiti sesuatu bangsa. Namun dalam era kemodenan globalisasi ini, tiada keterbatasan dalam teknologi telah mengubah seluruh dimensi dalam komunikasi antara manusia. Kemampuan dan kemahiran bertutur dalam pelbagai bahasa diperlukan agar persefahaman itu dapat dicapai apabila berkomunikasi dengan individu yang berlainan bangsa. Kemahiran ini penting bukan sahaja untuk individu tetapi ia memainkan peranan penting untuk syarikat dan juga negara. Oleh itu, kita seharusnya mencari kepentingan tersurat dan tersirat dalam menguasai bahasa asing.Kepentingan utama adalah kemahiran menguasai bahasa asing dapat memudahkan perhubungan atau komunikasi dengan orang yang berlainan bangsa. Bayangkan jika tiada penterjemah bahasa di konfederasi yang melibatkan pelbagai negara di dunia ini. Maka, kemahiran menguasai bahasa asing ini penting bagi menjadi jambatan kepada persefahaman yang ingin dilaksanakan. Bahkan, dengan menguasai bahasa asing, kita dapat berinteraksi dengan pelancong yang mengunjungi negara kita. Hal ini akan memberikan kesan kepada mereka kerana mereka akan merasakan mudah untuk bertanya dan memahami penjelasan kita tentang budaya atau sejarah tempat yang mereka lawati sepanjang percutian mereka. Jelaslah bahawa dengan menguasai pelbagai bahasa, kita mudah berkomunikasi untuk bertukar fikiran serta maklumat antara satu sama lain.Selain itu, menguasai bahasa asing akan membantu seseorang individu itu untuk memperoleh ilmu pengetahuan. Ilmu pengetahuan yang terdapat di dunia ini ditulis dalam pelbagai bahasa, khususnya bahasa Inggeris yang menjadi bahasa utama dunia. Sebagai contoh, untuk meningkatkan pengetahuan dalam bidang agama Islam seseorang wajib menguasai bahasa Arab yang merupakan bahasa kitab suci Al-Quran. Dengan penguasaan bahasa tersebut, mereka bukan sahaja memahami konteks yang disampaikan malah boleh berkongsi ilmu pengetahuan yang diperoleh kepada masyarakat setempat masing-masing agar bersama-sama menikmati manfaat daripadanya. Janganlah kita bersikap seperti katak di bawah tempurung yang bermaksud orang yang tidak mahu menerima pembaharuan, perubahan ataupun ilmu yang baru.Di samping itu, penguasaan bahasa asing akan membuka peluang seseorang untuk melanjutkan pelajaran ke peringkat yang lebih tinggi. Pihak kerajaan telah pun melakukan inisiatif menghantar pelajar kita ke luar negara untuk melanjutkan pelajaran ke peringkat yang lebih tinggi namun para pelajar ini perlu menguasai bahasa asing agar tidak kekok untuk menetap di sana sepanjang tempoh pengajian. Bahan-bahan ilmiah atau rujukan juga dikeluarkan dalam pelbagai bahasa jadi pelajar-pelajar di dalam mahupun luar negara seharusnya menguasai bahasa asing untuk memahami intipati ilmu yang dikongsikan. Pembelajaran secara global ini membantu kita dalam menambah baik dari segi ekonomi malahan penting bagi industri perubatan di mana mereka boleh mengkaji kes-kes yang berlaku di luar negara dan melakukan persediaan sekiranya terdapat kes yang sama berlaku dalam negara.Pada waktu yang sama, dengan mempunyai kemahiran bahasa asing, ia akan membantu seseorang itu mendapat peluang pekerjaan yang lebih banyak. Kemajmukan masyarakat dalam negara kita mempengaruhi syarikat-syarikat tempatan untuk mencari pekerja yang mempunyai kemahiran berbahasa asing. Hal ini kerana ia memudahkan urusan syarikat sekiranya harus berunding dengan pelanggan yang berlainan bangsa. Tambahan pula, individu yang menguasai bahasa asing ini mampu menjadi aset penting negara dalam menarik pelabur asing supaya melabur dalam negara kita. Kelebihan ini sewajarnya dimanfaatkan sepenuhnya oleh semua pihak agar kemajuan diri dan juga negara dapat dikecapi dan berterusan dari masa ke masa.Tuntasnya, kemahiran menguasai bahasa asing adalah cukup penting untuk semua pihak. Barang siapa yang memahami kepentingan bahasa asing pasti akan bertindak segera kerana mahu merebut kebaikan yang ditawarkan oleh bahasa tersebut. Justeru, sokongan ibu bapa dan pelbagai pihak adalah mustahak dalam memastikan anak-anak mengambil subjek bahasa asing dalam institusi pelajaran yang disertai oleh mereka agar generasi akan datang majoritinya menguasai bahasa asing. Golongan pelajar perlulah merebut peluang yang disediakan oleh pihak kerajaan kerana kemahiran bertutur dalam pelbagai bahasa akan memberikan nilai tambah kepada diri mereka. Sekaligus masyarakat kita mampu duduk sama rendah, berdiri sama tinggi dengan masyarakat seantero dunia untuk bersaing dalam semua aspek di peringkat global."},{"question":"Faith Ikidi","answer":"Faith Ikidi jẹ obinrin agbabọọlu ilẹ Naigiria ti a bini 28, óṣu febuary ni ọdun 1987 si ilu Port Hacourt. Arabinrin naa jẹ Defender fun Super Falcons ilẹ Naigiria ati Piteà IF ni Sweden.Ni ọdun 2006, Ikidi jẹ ọkan lara awọn Elere Naigiria ti o jẹ Awọn Afirica akọkọ lati kopa ninu ere idije swedish nibi ti wọn ti jẹ aṣoju fun QBIK.Faith ko ipa pataki ninu aṣeyọri Super Falcons ni Cup awọn Obinrin ilẹ Afirica Agbaye ni ilu Cameroun. Arabinrin naa jẹ ikan ninu awọn agba obinrin agbabọọlu ti VAVEL UK fun loruko ni ọdun 2017."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي المونة ديال السيما ؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي ماده كاتستخدم باش تجمع الطوب والحجر وكاتعمر الفراغات اللي بيناتهم."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Pada tahun apakah yang 1965 World Series MVP dipilih ke Hall of Fame Baseball?","answer":"Tahun 1972"},{"question":"Күн нурунун таасири витамин D синтезине кандай салым кошот?","answer":"Күн нурунун таасири териде D витамининин пайда болушун шарттайт. Сыртта, өзгөчө күндүн нурунда убакыт өткөрүү сөөктөрдүн ден соолугуна жана иммунитетине пайдалуу D витамининин деңгээлин кармап турууга жардам берет."},{"question":"जपाकुसुमसंकाशं काश्यपेयं महद्युतिम् ।तमोऽरिं सर्वपापघ्नं प्रणतोऽस्मि दिवाकरम् ॥","answer":"अर्थ : जास्वंदाच्या फुलाप्रमाणे कांती असलेल्या, कश्यपपुत्र, अत्यंत तेजस्वी, अंधकाराचा शत्रू, सर्व पापांचा नाश करणार्‍या सूर्याला मी नमस्कार करतो."},{"question":"دلیل اینکه بعضی ازشناگران هنگام شنا احساس می‌کنند نمی‌توانند هوای کافی بگیرند و به عبارتی نفس کم می‌آورند چیست؟","answer":"یکی از دلایل اساسی و مهم در ایجاد این مشکل این است که شناگر هنگام نفس‌گیری به طور کامل هوا را زیر آب خالی نمی‌کند به عبارتی ریه ها هنوز هوا دارند، اگر هوا کاملا زیر آب خالی شود وقتی شناگر هواگیری می‌کند ناخودآگاه ریه‌های خالی از هوا پر شده و این مشکل مرتفع می‌گردد."},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Moo ndàx kenn ci yéen bëgg na a lekk yàpp u mbokkam mu dee? Bëgguléen ko kày!","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Moo ndàx kenn ci yéen bëgg na a lekk yàpp u mbokkam mu dee? Bëgguléen ko kày!\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Moo: INTJndàx: ADVkenn: PRONci: ADPyéen: PRONbëgg: VERBna: AUXa: PARTlekk: VERByàpp: NOUNu: ADPmbokkam: NOUNmu: PRONdee: VERB?: PUNCTBëgguléen: VERBko: PRONkày: ADV!: PUNCT"},{"question":"ਜੈਵਿਕ ਵਧਾਓ (Biological magnification) ਕੀ ਹੈ ? ਕੀ ਪਰਿਸਥਿਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਦੇ ਭਿੰਨ ਪੱਧਰਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ ਜੈਵਿਕ ਵਧਾਓ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਵੀ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ?","answer":"ਜੈਵਿਕ ਵਧਾਓ (Biological magnification) – ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਸਾਧਨਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਹਾਨੀਕਾਰਕ ਰਸਾਇਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਡੀ ਭੋਜਨ ਲੜੀ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਕਰਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਗਾੜ੍ਹਾ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਕਿਰਿਆ ਨੂੰ ਜੈਵਿਕ-ਵਧਾਓ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਰਸਾਇਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਵੱਖ-ਵੱਖ ਢੰਗਾਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਅਸੀਂ-ਫਸਲਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਰੋਗਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਕੀਟ ਨਾਸ਼ਕ, ਪੀੜਕ ਨਾਸ਼ਕ ਆਦਿ ਰਸਾਇਣਾਂ ਦਾ ਛਿੜਕਾਓ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਾਂ । ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੁੱਝ ਭਾਗ ਮਿੱਟੀ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਭੂਮੀ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਸ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਪੌਦੇ ਜੜ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਖਣਿਜਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹੀ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਨਾਲ ਇਹ ਰਸਾਇਣ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਕਰ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਸੇਵਨ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਦਰਤਾ ਵਧਦੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਸਦੇ ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਜੈਵਿਕ ਵਧਾਓ ਦਾ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਰਬ-ਆਹਾਰੀ ਹੈਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਰਬ-ਆਹਾਰੀ ਹੈ । ਉਹ ਪੌਦਿਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਜੰਤੂਆਂ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਈ ਭੋਜਨ-ਲੜੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਸਥਾਨ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਣ ਕਰ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਸਾਇਣਿਕ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਵੇਸ਼ ਅਤੇ ਗਾੜ੍ਹਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਜਲਦੀ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਜੈਵਿਕ ਵਧਾਓ ਦਾ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਦਾਹਰਨ–ਉੱਤਰੀ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਿਸ਼ੀਗਨ ਝੀਲ ਦੇ ਆਸਪਾਸ ਮੱਛਰਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਰਨ ਲਈ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਡੀ.ਡੀ.ਟੀ. ਦਾ ਛਿੜਕਾਵ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਪੇਲੀਕਨ ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਪੰਛੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਘੱਟ ਹੋ ਗਈ । ਵਾਤਾਵਰਨ ਦੇ ਜਾਣਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਪਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਕਿ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਦਸ ਲੱਖ ਕਣਾਂ ਵਿਚ 0.2 ਕਣ ਡੀ. ਡੀ. ਟੀ. (1ppm = 1/1000000) ਹੈ । ਡੀ.ਡੀ.ਟੀ. ਦੇ ਉੱਚ ਪੱਧਰ ਕਾਰਨ ਪੇਲੀਕਨ ਪੰਛੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਡਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਛਿਲਕਾ ਪਤਲਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਨਿਕਲਣ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਹੀ ਅੰਡੇ ਟੁੱਟ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਸਨ ।"},{"question":"Mepụta isi okwu maka ederede a:Dịka ọtụtụ ka na-ekwu na ọrịa coronavirus adịghị na Naịjirịa, nwa afọ Igbo, Joseph Chidiebere, butere ya bụ ọrịa. Ọ maghị ebe maọbụ etu o si bute ya n'ihi na o meghi njem ọbụla. O kwukwara na o cheghị na ya zutere onye ọbụla nwere ọrịa ahụ. Mana site na mbọ ọ gbara, na sitekwa n'ike Chukwu, ọrịa ahụ ataghị isi ya. Gere akụkọ ya n'uju n'ihe nkiri dị n'elu. Ndị mere akụkọ a bụ Chukwunaeme Obiejesi na Chiemela Peter. Akụko ndị ga-amasị gị:","answer":"N'ezie, nke a bụ isi okwu maka ederede enyere - mgbake Coronavirus: 'Etu m si bute ọria Covid-19 ma merie ya'"},{"question":"Завершите параграф: Раскольников не привык к толпе и, как уже сказано, избегал всякого общества, особенно в последнее время. Но теперь его вдруг что-то потянуло к людям. Что-то новое открылось в нем, и вместе с тем ощутилась какая-то жажда людской компании.","answer":"Он так устал от целого месяца этой сосредоточенной тоски своей и мрачного возбуждения, что хотя бы одну минуту хотелось ему вздохнуть в другом мире, хоть бы в каком бы то ни было, и, несмотря на всю грязь обстановки, он с удовольствием оставался теперь в распивочной."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න ස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්","answer":"ස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්මා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිරළු පොළොව මතින් දිලෙනාවිඩාබර දිගු ගමනේමුදු සිනිදු දෙපා රිදෙනාවේදනා සුසුම් අතරේආදරේ ශේෂ වේවිද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිස්වේත මීදුම් ඉරා දෙනෙත් මඟ ඇහිරුජිවිතේ සීත සෘතුවේ ගිරි දුර්ග අතරින්මා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවිමා එක්ක එනවාද චන්න කින්නරාවි…සඳ නිවීගිය රාත්රියේ තාරකා ගොළුව ඝන අදුරේළය මතින් වැතිරි සොඳුරු හීනයකට ඉඩ දීහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවිහිනැහෙන්න පුළුවන්ද චන්න කින්නරාවි"},{"question":"බයියා  කියන එකේ තේරුම කියන්න","answer":"1) 1818 ඌව වෙල්ලස්ස කැරැල්ලේ කැප්පෙටිපොල දිසාවේ අත් අඩන්ගුවට පත් වීමෙන් පසු ඉතුරු උන කැරෙල්ලේ සෙසු සාමාජිකයන් අම්පාර හම්බන්තොට පළාතට පලාගිය අතර එම පළාත් වල සිටි පුද්ගලයන් ඔවුන් ව හැඳින් වූයේ බයට සැඟවුණු පුද්ගලයන් ලෙසයි ඔවුන් බය ඈයෝ  බයියෝ  ලෙස හැඳින්වුවා. රටේ සිටි වීර ජන කොටසක් විදිහට මේ බයියෝ හෙවත් ඌව වෙල්ලස්සේ ජාතික වීරයෝ එලෙස විසිර ගිය අතර මුල්ලේරියාව ට මානසික රෝහලක් ඉදී කරලා  ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨ යුද ජයග්‍රහණයක් වසන් කළා වගේ ශ්‍රේෂ්ඨ වීර ජන කොටසක් වසන් කිරීමට මේ බයියා  කියන වචනේ යොදා ගන ඇති බව පෙනේ2) රන්බණ්ඩා  සෙනෙවිරත්න මහතාගේ අදහස අනුව තුන්වේල බත් කෑ පිරිස් .එතුමා  තමා  බයියෙකු ලෙස නොබියව හදුන්වා  දුන්නේය.3) එක්තරා අයවැය සභාගත කිරීමකින් පසු එවකට ජනාධිපති හා මුදල් ඇමති මහින්ද රාජපක්ෂ විසින් \\"කොහොමද ගමේ බයියගෙ අයවැය \\" ලෙස උදාරම්ව විමසූ අතර ඉන් ඔහු මතු කිරීමට උත්සාහ කළේ තමා ගැමි මූලයක් සහිත නායකයෙක් බවය.කෙසේ වෙතත් එය පාරාවළල්ලක්ව පොහොට්ටුවාදීන් බයියන් වූ අතර ඔවුන් නාවන ලද බේරේ වැව බයියන්නෑ වැව විය."},{"question":"බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය වර්ජින් දූපත් (BVI) කොහේද සහ BVI හි කොටසක් වන දූපත් මොනවාද?","answer":"බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය වර්ජින් දූපත් (BVI), නිල වශයෙන් වර්ජින් දූපත් යනු, කැරිබියන් දූපත් වල, පුවර්ටෝ රිකෝට නැගෙනහිරින් සහ එක්සත් ජනපද වර්ජින් දූපත් සහ ඇන්ගුයිලාට වයඹ දෙසින් පිහිටි බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය විදේශීය ප්‍රදේශයකි. මෙම දූපත් භූගෝලීය වශයෙන් Virgin Islands දූපත් සමූහයේ කොටසක් වන අතර Lesser Antilles හි Leeward දූපත් වල සහ බටහිර ඉන්දීය කොදෙව්වේ කොටසක පිහිටා ඇත. බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය වර්ජින් දූපත් සමන්විත වන්නේ Tortola, Virgin Gorda, Anegada සහ Jost Van Dyke යන ප්‍රධාන දූපත් සහ තවත් කුඩා දූපත් සහ කේස් 50කට වැඩි ප්‍රමාණයකින් ය. දූපත් 16 ක් පමණ ජනාවාස වී ඇත. අගනුවර, රෝඩ් ටවුන්, විශාලතම දූපත වන ටොර්ටෝලා හි පිහිටා ඇති අතර එය කිලෝමීටර 20 (සැතපුම් 12) පමණ දිග සහ කිලෝමීටර 5 (සැතපුම් 3) පළල වේ. 2010 සංගණනයේදී දූපත් වල ජනගහනය 28,054ක් වූ අතර ඉන් 23,491ක් ටොර්ටෝලා හි වාසය කළහ. වත්මන් ඇස්තමේන්තු අනුව ජනගහනය 35,802 (ජූලි 2018) වේ."},{"question":"Miten celsiusasteet muutetaan fahrenheitasteiksi ja päinvastoin?","answer":"Muuttaaksesi celsiusasteet fahrenheitasteiksi kerro lämpötila yhdeksällä, jaa vastaus viidellä ja lisää siihen luku 32.Muuttaaksesi fahrenheitasteet celsiusasteiksi vähennä fahrenheitasteista 32, jaa vastaus yhdeksällä, kerro vastaus viidellä."},{"question":"ඝාන්ටාර හැඩ ඇති යන්නට කියන තනි පදය කුමක් ද ?","answer":"ඝාන්ටාකාර"},{"question":"О каком напитке говорится в следующем тексте: высушенный солод стал основой Октябрьского Эля, который традиционно варился осенью, а потом год настаивался в деревянных бочках с добавлением хмеля. Именно этот крепкий, 8-12% хмельной","answer":"Октябрьский Эль можно назвать отцом IPA (Indian Pale Ale, индийский светлый эль, АйПиЭй или просто ИПА)."},{"question":"A ko ni ilẹ kankan ta a maa fawọn janduku apaniyan ti wọn n pera wọn ni darandaran-Akeredolu","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, Rotimi Akeredolu, ko fọrọ awọn darandaran ṣawada lasiko yii rara, o ti kilọ fun Mallam Garba Shehu, Oluranlọwọ pataki fun Aarẹ lori eto iroyin, pe ko ṣọra ẹ, ko si ṣọ ohun to maa maa tẹnu ẹ jade, o lawọn gomina kọja ẹni arifin latọdọ oṣiṣẹ Aarẹ eyikeyii, bẹẹ si lawọn o ni i yọnda abala ilẹ pinniṣin fawọn Fulani darandaran ni gbogbo ilẹ Yoruba ati ni Guusu orileede yii.Oluranlọwọ gomina lori akanṣe iṣẹ, Ọgbẹni Doyin Ọdẹbọwale, lo fi atẹjade kan lede lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, eyi ti Gomina Akeredolu fi fesi sọrọ ti Garba Shehu kọ lorukọ Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lori ipinnu awọn gomina iha Guusu ilẹ wa ti wọn lawọn fofin de fifi maaluu jẹko ni gbangba lagbegbe awọn.Akeredolu ni Garba Shehu kere si ẹni to maa maa ṣepinnu fun Aarẹ lori awọn ọrọ to ta koko bii eyi ti wọn n sọ yii, bẹẹ si ni ko laṣẹ lati maa gbe awọn alakalẹ ijọba lelẹ lorukọ ijọba apapọ fawọn gomina.Apa kan atẹjade Akeredolu naa ka pe: “Ọgbẹni Garba Shehu fi atẹjade kan lede fawọn oniroyin eyi to fẹ ka gbagbọ pe ero Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari lori wahala awọn agbẹ atawọn darandaran lo wa ninu ẹ, ati pe awọn aba ti wọn kọ sibẹ lo maa yanju iṣoro yii.O tun sọrọ nipa ipinnu adaṣe kan to ni Buhari ṣe lati ṣi ọna silẹ fun kikọ awọn ibudo ifẹranjẹko ati titun awọn igbo ọba ṣe gẹgẹ bii ojuutu gidi si iṣoro awọn darandaran to di lemọlemọ yii.‘‘Gbogbo ẹni to ba ṣakiyesi bi ọkunrin Garba yii ṣe n sọrọ, ati bawọn eeyan bii tiẹ naa ṣe n sọrọ, maa ri i pe ọrọ itanra-ẹni-jẹ ati irọ gbuu to le tanna ran yanpọnyanrin lọrọ wọn, ko si ṣoro lati mọ pe iromi wọn to n jo lori omi yii, onilu rẹ n bẹ nisalẹ odo, awọn ọta ilẹ wa ni wọn n gbẹnusọ fun.‘‘Ọgbẹni Garba ni lati bọ si gbangba ko sọ awọn to ran an niṣẹkiṣẹ to n jẹ, tori o daju pe ki i ṣe Aarẹ. Ko le maa lugọ sẹyin ika kan ko ro pe ko sẹni to ri oun, awọn ọrọ to n jade lẹnu wọn yii fihan pe wọn n ṣiṣẹ fawọn kan ni.”Akeredolu ni o ya oun lẹnu gidi lati gbọ ninu atẹjade ọhun pe Aarẹ ti fọwọ si awọn aba ti Minisita feto ọgbin, Alaaji Sabo Nanono gbe siwaju rẹ nigba ti awọn aba tawọn gomina taraalu dibo yan sipo ṣi wa niwaju Aarẹ ti wọn ko ti i fọwọ si i.Gomina Akeredolu ṣalaye siwaju si i pe: “Ọgbẹni Garba sọ pe ikede tawa gomina mẹtadinlogun iha Guusu ilẹ wa ṣe ko tẹwọn loju ofin, ko bofin mu to, ṣugbọn ipinnu awọn eeyan kan lati gba ilẹ awọn baba nla ẹni-ẹlẹni, ki wọn fa a le awọn eeyan tiwọn lọwọ, awọn eeyan wọn apaayan to n gbebọn-rin atawọn mọlẹbi wọn, ki wọn pese ileewosan nnkan ọsin, omi fawọn ẹran ọsin, ki wọn si kọle ati ileewe fawọn darandaran wọnyi lawọn igbo ọba, Garba ko si ri eyi bii iwa ajagungbalẹ, iwa oju dudu ti ko yatọ si tawọn oyinbo amunisin aye ọjọun.”Nipari ọrọ rẹ, Akeredolu ni: “Ọrọ ati iwa Garba fihan pe agbodegba ẹda kan ni. Awọn eeyan bii tiẹ to ku ti wọn n ronu, ti wọn n la ala bawọn ṣe maa mu ẹya mi-in lẹru gbọdọ taji loju oorun wọn. Ko si abala ilẹ kan, bo ti ko kere to, ibaa jẹ eyi to wa lakọọlẹ tabi tijọba, ni gbogbo agbegbe ilẹ Yoruba, ati ni agbegbe Guusu pata, ta a maa fi silẹ fawọn janduku apaayan ti wọn dibọn pe ara wọn ni darandaran.”"},{"question":"Ireto misy fehezanteny roa : Fehezanteny 1 : Mahafinaritra ny andro androany, akanjo maivamaivana dia ampy.Fehezaznteny 2 : Mibaliaka ny masoandro ary manga ny lanitra.Mitovy dika ve ireo fehezanteny ireo ?","answer":"Eny, misy ifandraisany ireo fehezanteny ireo. Rehefa mibaliaka ny masoandro dia mafana ny andro ka tsy mila manao mafana be firy amin’ny akanjo hanaovana."},{"question":"Mama Kasi ma pięć córek. Jeśli imiona jej córek to odpowiednio Klara, Karolina, Klaudia, Kinga, to jakie będzie imię piątej córki?","answer":"Kasia."},{"question":"هن مضمون کي هڪ جملي ۾ خلاصو ڪريو. گوشت جي سطح تي اڏامندڙ گوشت جي هر شي کي ڇڪيو ۽ اڇلائي ڇڏيو. ان دوران ، اسٽاڪ کي هڪ سٺي ڇڪ ذريعي ڇڪيو ۽ هڏا ۽ vegetablesڀاڄيون اڇلايو. اسٽاڪ کي پاسي تي رک. ٿڌي ٿيڻ کان پوءِ ، ان کي ٽڪڙن جي سائيز جي ٽڪرن ۾ ڪٽي ڇڏيو. تيل کي گرم ڪريو. ٻرڻ کان پوءِ ، گرمي کي وچولي کان گهٽ ڪريو ، coverڪيو ۽ 20 منٽن تائين ٻوڙيو. خلاصو:","answer":"هڪ وڏي ڳري تري واري برتن ۾ ، سڀني اسٽاڪ جي اجزاء کي گڏ ڪريو ۽ وچولي تيز گرمي تي ٻرڻ لاءِ آڻيو. هڪ دفعو اسٽاڪ ٻرندي آهي ، گرمي کي وچولي کان گهٽ تائين گهٽايو ۽ 3 کان 4 ڪلاڪن تائين ٻوڙيو. گوشت جي سيني کي برتن مان ڪ andو ۽ ان کي ٿڌي ڪرڻ لاءِ هڪ پيالي ۾ رک. برتن کي صاف ڪريو اسٽاڪ ۾ سستيءَ سان وجهي ۽ ڪٽيل سينو شامل ڪريو. آلو ، ٽماٽا ، لوڻ ۽ مرچ شامل ڪريو ۽ وڌيڪ 20 منٽن لاءِ ٻوڙيو. هڪ سٺين رائي جي ماني جي سلائس سان گڏ ٿانو ۾ گرم خدمت ڪريو ۽ ان کي کير واري ڪريم سان گارنش ڪريو."},{"question":"Ami-ẹyẹ ko ti i tọ si mi bayii, mi o ti i gbija Yoruba debi aṣeyọri – Sunday Igboho","answer":"Nitori ipa takunakun to n ko lati gba gbogbo ilẹ Yorùbá silẹ lọwọ awọn apanijaye Fúlàní, apapọ ẹgbẹ awọn ọdọ Yorùbá, ìyẹn Yoruba Youth Socio-Cultural Association, YYSA, lọọ gbe àmì-ẹyẹ nla kan ka Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo aye mọ̀ si Sunday Igboho mọle nirọlẹ ọjọ Àbámẹ́ta, Sátidé, to kọja.Ṣugbọn sí iyalẹnu awọn adari ẹgbẹ naa, akínkanjú ọmọ Yorùbà yii kọ àmì-ẹyẹ naa, o ni oun ko ti i ṣàṣeyọrí nipa ominira gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá tí oun n wá.ALAROYE gbọ pe eyi kọ nigba akọkọ ti Sunday Ìgbòho yoo kọ àmì-ẹyẹ sí àwọn tó fẹẹ fi imọriri wọn hàn nípa ijijagbara rẹ lọrun.Ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹyìn Igboho fìdí ẹ mulẹ fakọroyin wa pe “Eyi ki i ṣe igba akọkọ ọga, bẹẹ náà ni wọn kọ amì-ẹyẹ ‘Ogo Ọmọ Yorùbá’ tí àwọn ẹgbẹ kan naa fún wọn lọjọ kẹwàá, oṣù kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021 yii.”Nigba to n dupẹ fún ìmọ riri ẹgbẹ awọn ọdọ naa lori akitiyan rẹ̀, Sunday Igboho sọ pé “Mi o ti i nilo ami-ẹyẹ bayii. Asiko ti gbogbo wa ni iṣẹ lati ṣe ka tóo lè máa sun oorun àsùn-han-an-run la wa yii, kì í ṣe asiko lati máa kan saara sí mi pé mo ṣiṣẹ takuntakun.“Nigba ta a ba ṣàṣeyọrí lori iṣẹ ta a dawọ le yii, nigba naa, a le waa máa fúnra wa lami-ẹyẹ ba a bá ṣe fẹ.“Lọwọlọwọ yii, adua ni mo fẹ ki ẹyin ọdọ ati gbogbo ọmọ Yorùbá máa fi ran mi lọwọ ká lè ṣaṣeyọri lori ominira Yoruba ta a fẹ.Ààrẹ ẹgbẹ YYSA, Ọgbẹni Habib Ọlálékan Hammed, atawọn eeyan rẹ waa ṣèlérí atilẹyin gbogbo ọdọ Yorùbá fún Sunday Igboho, nigba yoowu to ba nilo wọn."},{"question":"பகத் சிங் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இந்திய விடுதலைப் போராட்டத்தின் வீரஞ்செறிந்த பக்கங்களில் பகத் சிங்கின் பெயர் பொன்னெழுத்துகளால் பொறிக்கப்பட்டது. ஆங்கிலேய ஆட்சிக்கு எதிராக போராடியாவர், இந்தியாவில் மார்க்சியத்தைப் பேசிய முதல்வருகளில் ஒருவர். இளம் வயதிலேயே ஆங்கிலேயர்களால் தூக்கிலிடப்பட்டார்.மேற்கோள்:நாளை காலை மெழுகுவர்த்தி ஒளி மங்குவது போல் நானும் மறைந்து விடுவேன். ஆனால், நம்முடைய நம்பிக்கைகள், குறிக்கோள்கள் இந்த உலகத்தைப் பிரகாசிக்கச் செய்யும்.தனி நபர்களைக் கொல்வது எளிது, ஆனால் உங்களால் கருத்துகளைக் கொல்ல முடியாது.கேளாத செவிகளைக் கேட்கச் செய்வதற்கு உரத்த குரல் தேவைப்படுகிறது.அனைவருக்கும் விடுதலையைக் கொண்டுவரக் கூடியதும், மனிதனை மனிதன் சுரண்டும் கொடுமையை சாத்தியமற்றதாக்கக் கூடியதுமான புரட்சியின் பலிபீடத்தில் தனிநபர்களின் உயிர்ப்பலிகள் தவிர்க்க இயலாதவை.சரியான கல்வியும் புரிந்து கொள்ளும் திறனும் உள்ளவரால் கூட புரிந்து கொள்ள முடியாத சம்ஸ்கிருத ஸ்லோகங்களும் முதல் தரமான அராபிய இலக்கியங்களின் வரிகளும், எளிய மொழியில் சொல்லப்படும் எளிய வாசகங்கள் தரும் உற்சாகத்தைத் தருவதில்லை.புரட்சியாளர்கள் இறக்க வேண்டும்.புரட்சியாளர்கள் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தும் கொள்கைகள் தியாகத்தின் மூலமாகத்தான் வலுவடையும், நீதிமன்றத்தின் மேல் முறையீடுகள் மூலம் அல்ல.எனது வாழ்நாளில் நான் கடவுளை வணங்கியதில்லை. சொல்லப்போனால், ஏழைகளின் துயரங்களுக்குக் காரணமாக இருக்கிறார் என்று கடவுளைப் பல முறை ஏசியிருக்கிறேன். இப்போது அவரிடம் மன்னிப்புக் கேட்டால், தனது முடிவு நெருங்கிவிட்டதால் மன்னிப்புக் கேட்கிறான் இந்தக் கோழை என்று உங்கள் கடவுள் சொல்வார்அம்மா, எனது நாடு ஒரு நாள் சுதந்திரமடைந்துவிடும் என்பதில் எனக்கு எந்தச் சந்தேகமும் இல்லை. ஆனால், வெள்ளைக்காரத் துரைமார்கள் விட்டுச்சென்ற நாற்காலிகளில் மாநிறத் தோல் துரைமார்கள் வந்து உட்கார்ந்துவிடுவார்கள் என்று பயமாக இருக்கிறது.“சாத்வீகப் போராட்டத்தின் மூலம் இந்த பிரிட்டிஷ் ஆட்சியை அகற்றிவிடலாம் என்ற உடோப்பிய முறை இத்துடன் முடிவுக்கு வருகிறது. இந்த முறையால் எந்தவிதப் பலனும் இல்லை என்று வளர்ந்துவரும் இளைய சமுதாயம் சந்தேகமே இல்லாமல் நன்கு உணர்ந்திருக்கிறது” “காந்தியைப் பின்பற்றுவதைக் கைவிட்டுவிட்டு, லெனின் காட்டும் வன்முறை சார்ந்த புரட்சிகரப் பாதையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுங்கள்“ (நாடாளுமன்றத்தின்மீது வெடிகுண்டு தாக்குதல் நடத்தியதற்காக கைதுக்குப் பிறகு விடுத்த அறிக்கையில்.)"},{"question":"Làm gì để tránh đột quỵ khi chơi thể thao?","answer":"Khi cảm thấy đau đầu, chóng mặt, nôn ói, nhịp tim quá nhanh nên dừng lại; cần chuẩn bị thể lực trước những cuộc thi lớn để tránh đột quỵ gây tử vong.Khi nhiệt độ cơ thể tăng quá mức, chuyển hóa tại các tế bào bị rối loạn. Ở mức độ nặng, tế bào não bộ có thể ngưng hoạt động gây phù nề và tổn thương não. Hệ tim mạch cũng bị ảnh hưởng nghiêm trọng do nhịp tim bị tăng lên kịch trần, đường kính mạch máu giãn tối đa và tụt huyết áp. Tình trạng cô đặc máu làm cho máu dễ bị vón cục và gây thuyên tắc. Việc giảm lưu lượng tưới máu có thể gây suy chức năng những cơ quan đích như não, tim, thận... Ngoài ra, mất nước nhiều qua mồ hôi sẽ dẫn đến hậu quả giảm natri máu và rối loạn nước - điện giải."},{"question":"Fulani bii ọgọrin ya wọ Ibadan, lawọn ọdọ kan ba fẹẹ koju wọn","answer":"Ija igboro iba ṣẹlẹ laarin awọn Fúlàní darandaran atawọn ọdọ Yoruba n’Ibadan, lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, Ọlọrun lo si mọ iye èèyàn ati dukia tí ìbá lọ sí í bi ko ṣe iṣẹ takuntakun tawọn agbofinro ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ṣe lati kòòré wahala naa.Yánpọyánrin ọhun ni iba ṣẹlẹ ni nnkan bíi aago marun-un irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọjọ keje, oṣu kejì, ọdun yii, nígbà tí àwọn arinrinajo Fúlàní bíi ọgọ́rin (80) wọ igboro Ibadan lẹẹkan ṣoṣo.Ninu ọkọ tirela ti wọn wa, eyi ti nọmba rẹ̀ jẹ KTG 220 ZZ (BAUCHI) la ti ri maaluu mẹ́ẹ̀ẹ́dọ́gbọ̀n (25) ati alupupu mẹtala.Ipo àìbalẹ̀ ọkàn ti ilẹ Yorùbá wa lori iwa ipaniyan ati ijinigbe awọn Fúlàní ló mú kí àwọn ọmọ iṣọta to wa lagbegbe Iwo Road, n’Ibadan, maa mura lati kọ lu awọn àjèjì onimaaluu naa.Ṣugbọn èèrà kò ti i rin awọn Fúlàní ti irinajo wọn kò àwọn ará Ìbàdàn láyà sókè yii ti awọn agbofinro ilẹ Yorùbá, Amọtẹkun, ẹka ipinlẹ Ọyọ, atawọn oṣiṣẹ Operation Burst ti i ṣe ikọ agbofinro ijọba ipinlẹ naa fi lọọ da awọn arinrinajo naa duro, ti wọn sì gbé wọn lọ sì agọ ọlọpaa to wa laduugbo Agodi, n’Ibadan.Eyi lo si fopin sí ìkọlù ti iba waye láàrin ọdọ ti wọn ti n gbero lati kọ lu awọn Fúlàní naa.Ninu ifọrọwanilẹnuwo ti awọn ọlọpaa ṣe fawọn eeyan naa ni wọn ti sọ pé àwọn kò bá tìjà wa s’Ibadan, ipinlẹ Eko ati Ògùn gan-an lawọn n lọ gẹgẹ bí Agbẹnusọ fún ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ọyọ, CSP Olugbenga Fadeyi ṣe fìdí ẹ̀ múlẹ.SCP Fadeyi fi kun ùn pe awọn to ni maaluu inu mọto naa sọ pe awọn nnkan ọsin ọhun naa lawọn n ko lọ sí odo ẹran to wa l’Agege, nipinlẹ Eko, láti tà, nigba ti awọn to ní àwọn alùpùpù naa sọ pe Too Geetì Ògèrè, nipinlẹ Ogun, lawọn ko awọn alùpùpù naa lọ fún iṣẹ ọkada."},{"question":"次の段落を完成させなさい： 社会を風刺する絵で有名なバンクシーが11日、ウクライナのボロジャンカでかいた新しい絵をインターネットに出しました。ボロジャンカは首都キーウから50kmぐらいの町で、ロシア軍の攻撃でたくさんの人が亡くなりました。","answer":"絵は、壊れたアパートの壁にかいてあります。女の子が壊れた建物の上で逆立ちしているように見えます。 キーウからこの絵を見に来た女性は「バンクシーがここに来て、ロシアがしたことを世界に見せることは、ウクライナの歴史に残ります」と話しました。 この場所の近くでは、子どもが柔道で大人を投げているような絵も見つかりました。外国の新聞などは、これもバンクシーの絵のようだと伝えています。柔道が好きなロシアのプーチン大統領が、ウクライナに抵抗されていることを風刺していると言われています。"},{"question":"Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"bagai aur di atas bukit\\".","answer":"Setelah gagal mencari anaknya yang hilang, wanita itu kini berserah sahaja kepada nasib bagai aur di atas bukit."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Theo Bảo hiểm Xã hội tỉnh Đồng Nai, từ đầu năm 2022 đến nay, đơn vị đã phối hợp cùng ngành chức năng tiến hành thanh tra, kiểm tra việc chấp hành pháp luật bảo hiểm tại hơn 300 đơn vị, doanh nghiệp trên địa bàn tỉnh. Các đơn vị, doanh nghiệp đã khắc phục gần 55 tỷ đồng nợ bảo hiểm xã hội, bảo hiểm thất nghiệp và bảo hiểm y tế. Trong quá trình thanh tra, kiểm tra, ngành chức năng yêu cầu doanh nghiệp truy đóng các khoản bảo hiểm cho gần 400 lao động với số tiền gần 2,6 tỷ đồng; kiến nghị thu hồi khoảng 6 tỷ đồng bảo hiểm y tế, bảo hiểm xã hội ngắn hạn chi sai quy định. Vi phạm phổ biến về pháp luật bảo hiểm của doanh nghiệp là chậm nộp, nợ kéo dài các khoản bảo hiểm; trốn đóng về đối tượng (đối tượng phải đóng bảo hiểm nhưng doanh nghiệp không đóng) và đóng bảo hiểm với mức thấp hơn so với quy định. Ông Phạm Minh Thành, Giám đốc Bảo hiểm Xã hội Đồng Nai, cho biết trên địa bàn Đồng Nai có rất nhiều doanh nghiệp nợ bảo hiểm với số tiền hàng trăm tỷ đồng. Trong đó, không","answer":"ít doanh nghiệp nợ với số tiền lớn (trên dưới 10 tỷ đồng), thời gian dài (trên 6 tháng). Dù cơ quan bảo hiểm đã nhiều lần làm việc, đốc thúc, doanh nghiệp cố tình chây ì, không thanh toán. Thanh tra, kiểm tra là công cụ hữu hiệu giúp ngành chức năng phát hiện sai phạm của doanh nghiệp, đưa ra chế tài, từ đó nhanh chóng thu hồi nợ, bảo vệ quyền lợi của người lao động. Theo ông Phạm Minh Thành, có nhiều doanh nghiệp nợ bảo hiểm là do sản xuất kinh doanh khó khăn, thua lỗ. Tuy nhiên, không ít doanh nghiệp dù kinh doanh có lãi, mở rộng sản xuất, vẫn cố tình trốn đóng, chậm nộp các khoản bảo hiểm. Hiện pháp luật quy định hành vi trốn đóng bảo hiểm có thể bị xử lý hình sự, song khi áp dụng vào thực tế vẫn còn nhiều vướng mắc, khó thực hiện. Tới đây, Bảo hiểm Xã hội Đồng Nai tiếp tục tiến hành thanh tra, kiểm tra đột xuất, định kỳ tại các đơn vị có số nợ tiền bảo hiểm lớn, thời gian nợ kéo dài, có khả năng tài chính, nhưng cố tình nợ đọng, trốn đóng các khoản bảo hiểm. Ngoài ra, cơ quan chức năng còn thanh tra các đơn vị đã được đôn đốc sau thanh tra, kiểm tra nhưng vẫn cố tình vi phạm."},{"question":"Por que estamos numa década crítica para garantir um futuro habitável, sustentável e justo? Tenha como referência o ano de 2023 como base.","answer":"Os impactos e riscos das mudanças climáticas estão se tornando cada vez mais complexos e mais difíceis de gerenciar, pois diferentes perigos ocorrem simultaneamente e interagem com múltiplos riscos criados por modelos de desenvolvimento insustentáveis e injustiça social."},{"question":"¿En qué país se encuentra la torre de Pisa?","answer":"La torre de Pisa es una torre inclinada que se encuentra en Italia."},{"question":"බුදුන් පුදන ඖෂධ වර්ග 108 මොනවද?","answer":"බුදුන් පුදන ඖෂධ වර්ග 108 පහත සඳහන් වේ,1. ඒකාවේරිය. 2. ඉරිවේරිය. 3. කප්පරවල්ලිය. 4. නීරමුල්ලිය.5. නාමල් රේණු. 6. නෙළුම් රේණු. 7. දෙළුන් ලෙලි. 8. ගොංකැකිරි අල.9. කොල්ලන් කොළ. 10. රත්කිහිරිය. 11. වල්වේලාමුල්. 12. වියළි කහ.13. වද කහ. 14. රණවරා මල්.15. බෙලිමල්. 16. කුඩුමිරිස්සමුල්.17. සාදික්කා. 18. මාසක්කා ඇට. 19. දේවදුරු. 20. මහදුරු.21. ලොක්සුඹුළු. 22. වැල් දෙහි මුල්. 23. මූරුවා මුල්. 24. දියමිත්ත.25. දෙහි මුල්. 26. දොඩංමුල්. 27. කටුකරෝහණ. 28. උදු ඇට.29. කොල්ලු ඇට. 30. වදුරු මෑ ඇට. 31. අරළු. 32. බුළු.33. නෙල්ලි. 34. අස්වැන්න. 35. පොල්පලා. 36. කටුවැල්බටු.37. එලබටු මුල්. 38. නෙරෙන්චි. 39. නස්නාරන් මුල්. 40. බේත් එඬරු මුල්.41. බෙලි මුල්. 42. මිදි මුල්. 43. තොටිල මුල්. 44. පලොල් මුල්.45. ඇත්දෙමට මුල්. 46. දෑබරන අල. 47. ඉරමුසු මුල්. 48. රත් හඳුන්.49. සුදු හඳුන්. 50. අගිල් අරටු. 51. දේවදාර. 52. විෂ්ණුක්‍රාන්තිය.53. බැබිල මුල්. 54. කොහොඹ පොතු. 55. හාතාවාරිය අල. 56. මානෙල් අල.57. කලාදුරු අල. 58. මාදංපොතු. 59. කුඹුක් පොතු. 60. පාවට්ටා මුල්.61. නික මුල්. 62. වැල්මදට. 63. තිප්පිලි. 64. සූදුරු.65. කලුදුරු. 66. අතිවිඩයන්. 67.රත්මල් කැකුළු. 68. දුම්මැල්ල.69. රසකිඳ. 70. සාරන අල. 71. අමුක්කරා අල. 72. අලබේත්.73. වැල් තිබ්බටු. 74. කොරාසාති. 75. කලිස්පතුරු. 76. වැල් කහඹිලියා.77. අලහැල මුල්. 78. සිවිය මුල්. 79. මුරුංගා මුල්. 80. වල්කොත්තමල්ලි.81. කොතල හිඹුටු. 82. උළුහාල්. 83. සුදුළූණු. 84. ලුණුවරණ පොතු.85. ඉගිණි ඇට. 86. වලඟ සහල්. 87. ගම්මිරිස්. 88. වියළි ඉඟුරු.89. කොත්තමල්ලි. 90. පත්පාඩගම්. 91. අරත්ත අල. 92. කරපිංචා නැටි.93. වැල්මී. 94. වෙනිවැල්ගැට. 95. කටුකරඬු මුල්. 96. ගල්මද.97. එනසාල්. 98. පඩවැල්. 99. කිරාන. 100. මස්බැද්ද.101. කෝවක්කා අල. 102. අත්තික්කා පොතු. 103. බේදුරු අල. 104. අලු කෙසෙල් අල.105. ඉඟුරු පියලි. 106. කුරුඳු පොතු. 107. දොඩම් පනාමුල්.108. සැවැන්දරා මුල්."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚 Тыныбек манасчы кайсы манасчы менен айтышкандан кийин элге таанылган? а) Надыр менен б) Эшмамбет менен в) Эсенаман ырчы г) Чоңду манасчы менен","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚а) Надыр менен."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Togo?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Togo mu ngi tudu Lomé."},{"question":"የዳግማዊ ሚኒሊክ ልጅ መቼ ሥልጣን ያዙ?","answer":"በ1908"},{"question":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện quan trọng nào? - Ngày 8 tháng 8 năm 2016, trong bài phát biểu phát sóng truyền hình quốc gia, Nhật hoàng Akihito đã tỏ ý định rõ ràng về việc thoái vị vì tuổi cao sức yếu. Tuy nhiên, ông chưa thể dễ dàng trao lại vương quyền cho hoàng thái tử vì luật pháp Nhật Bản hiện không có quy định về việc thoái vị. Đây là một đoạn video hiếm hoi của Nhật hoàng Akihito phát biểu trên truyền hình với thần dân. Trong thời gian trị vì 28 năm, Nhật hoàng mới chỉ một lần phát biểu với hình thức này vào tháng 3 năm 2011, sau thảm họa Động đất và sóng thần Tōhoku 2011.","answer":"Văn bản này nói về sự kiện quan trọng khi Nhật hoàng Akihito phát biểu trên truyền hình vào ngày 8 tháng 8 năm 2016, tỏ ý định thoái vị do tuổi cao sức yếu. Tuy nhiên, vấn đề phức tạp ở chỗ luật pháp Nhật Bản lúc bấy giờ không có quy định về việc một Nhật hoàng có thể thoái vị. "},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny tselatra atosiky ny varatra, ny orana atosiky ny rahona, _\\"","answer":"\\"Ny tselatra atosiky ny varatra, ny orana atosiky ny rahona, fa ny olona atosikiny fitiavana.\\""},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa:Wani jami'in wata makaranta a Indiya ya bayar da hakuri, bayan da wasu hotuna na wasu dalibai da suka rufe kawunansu da kwallaye yayin jarabawa ya rinka yawo a shafukan sada zumunta. An dauki hoton ne a lokacin wata jarabawa a wata makarantar sharar fagen shiga jami'a ta Haveri da ke jihar Karnataka a Indiya. Hotunan sun nuna daliban makarantar zaune a cikin aji da kwalaye bisa kawunansu, an huda kwalayen ta yadda za su samu iska. An bayyana cewa an yi hakane domin hana daliban satar amsa. Daya daga cikin malaman makaranatar ya fito ya roki gafara bayan afkuwar lamarin. Ya ce makarantar ta yi amfani da wannan sabon tsarin ne sakamakon ta ji labarin tsarin ya yi amfani matuka a wata makarantar. Ya kuma bayyana cewa an yi hakan ne da yardar daliban, kuma wasu daliban ma daga gidajensu suka zo da kwalayensu. Ya ce ''ba a tilasta wa kowane dalibi da cewa dole sa ya saka kwali a kai ba, idan za ku iya gani akwai wadanda babu kwalin a kansu .'' Ya ce ''wasu sun cire kwalayen bayan mintuna 15 wasu kuma bayan mintuna 20, bayan sa'a daya mu da kanmu muka ce kowa ya cire kwalin.'' Rahotanni sun bayyana cewa jami'ai a yankin sun garzaya makarantar bayan sun samu labarin wannan sabon tsarin da makarantar ta bullo da shi. SC Peerjade wanda jami'i ne a kasar ya bayyana wannan sabon tsarin da makarantar ta yi gwaji a matsayin ''rashin imani.''","answer":"Tabbas, ga kanun labarai don rubutun da aka bayar - Sabon salon hana satar amsa a Indiya ya kawo rudani"},{"question":"Escreva a continuação para esse parágrafo - Foi substituto de Justo Villar na Copa América Centenário","answer":", na qual o Paraguai foi eliminado no início da fase de grupos."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en esta categoría: Deportes","answer":"¿Qué equipo ganó la serie mundial de 2012? San Francisco Giants"},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:ومحمد هو الطفل الثالث في عائلة مكوّنة من 5 أبناء، إذ تسبقه الأختان صفية وسعاد، فيما أنجبت والدته أخويه صلاح وعلي في عامي 1931 و1933، ثم توفيت بعد","answer":"ذلك في عام 1937. وقد نشأ محمد في بيئة عائلية تقليدية حيث كانت القيم والتقاليد تلعب دورًا هامًا. على الرغم من موت والدته وهو صغير، إلا أنه استمر في تلقي تعليمه ونموه بفضل الدعم العائلي. فيما بعد، أثرت تلك الظروف الصعبة على شخصيته وألهمته للتفوق في حياته وتحقيق إنجازات كبيرة."},{"question":"கதையைப் படித்து, கடந்த காலத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி மீண்டும் எழுதவும்:ஜூனோ யானை தனிமையில் உள்ளது மற்றும் காட்டில் உள்ள மற்ற விலங்குகளுடன் நட்பு கொள்ள முயற்சிக்கிறது. ஆனால், மற்ற விலங்குகள் ஜூனோவின் அளவு காரணமாக அவனுடன் விளையாட மறுக்கின்றன. ஒரு நாள், எல்லா விலங்குகளும் டேரா புலியை விட்டு ஓடுகின்றன, அவர் கண்டதை எல்லாம் சாப்பிடுகிறார். ஜூனோ சென்று தேராவிற்கு ஒரு ஸ்விஃப்ட் கிக் கொடுக்கிறார். உடனே தேரா ஓடுகிறது. ஜூனோ இப்போது அனைவரின் நண்பன்.","answer":"ஜூனோ யானை தனிமையில் இருந்தது. காட்டில் உள்ள மற்ற விலங்குகளுடன் நட்பு கொள்ள முயன்றான். இருப்பினும், ஜூனோவின் அளவு காரணமாக மற்ற விலங்குகள் அதனுடன் விளையாட மறுத்தன. ஒரு நாள், எல்லா விலங்குகளும் டேரா என்ற புலியை விட்டு ஓடிக்கொண்டிருந்தன, அது கிடைத்த அனைத்தையும் தின்று கொண்டிருந்தது. ஜூனோ சென்று தேராவுக்கு ஒரு ஸ்விஃப்ட் கிக் கொடுத்தார். உடனே தேரா ஓடியது. ஜூனோ இப்போது அனைவரின் நண்பராக இருந்தார்."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Efter en tids krigstjänst måste Berendes på grund av ett dråp 1635 gå i landsflykt, men fick 1641 nåd. 1645 värvade han ett dragonregemente, och som överste för detta utmärkte han sig flera gånger under","answer":"Karl X Gustavs polska krig. 1656 blev han överste för Åbo och Björneborgs kavalleriregemente och 1657 generalmajor och deltog med utmärkelse i Karl Gustavs danska krig, särskilt i Stormningen av Frederiksodde och tåget över Bält. 1664 avskedades Berendes från sin överstebefattning."},{"question":"土佐藩の坂本龍馬が組織したのは何隊でしょう？","answer":"海援隊です。"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Lịch thi đấu EURO 2020 Nhận định Bóng đá và Nhận định EURO 2020 Game dự đoán Euro 2020 Đây là lần đầu tiên kể từ World Cup 1966, bóng đá Anh mới vô địch một giải đấu lớn ở cấp độ tuyển quốc gia. Đội tuyển nữ của họ dưới sự dẫn dắt của HLV người Hà Lan Sarina Wiegman đã xuất sắc vượt qua những đối thủ sừng sỏ nhất để lên đỉnh EURO 2022. Gặp Đức ở chung kết trên sân nhà Wembley, tuyển nữ Anh có trận thứ 6 liên tiếp giữ nguyên đội hình xuất phát, trong khi đối thủ thiếu vắng chân sút chủ lực Alexandra Popp vì chấn thương lúc khởi động. Tuyển nữ Anh vượt lên dẫn bàn trước nhờ công của tiền vệ Ella Toone ở phút 62, song đến phút 79, Lina Magull đã gỡ hòa cho tuyển nữ Đức. Kết quả hòa 1-1 sau thời gian thi đấu chính thức buộc 2 đội phải bước vào hiệp phụ. Phút 110, tiền đạo vào sân thay người Chloe Kelly tỏa sáng ghi bàn quyết định giúp tuyển nữ Anh giành chiến thắng chung cuộc 2-1. Như vậy, tuyển nữ Anh vô địch giải EURO nữ 2022 một cách thuyết phục với thành tích toàn thắng 6 trận. Sau khi vượt qua vòng bảng, họ lần lượt hạ Tây Ban Nha và Thụy Điển ở tứ kết và bán kết để giành quyền vào chung kết. Tại EURO 2020, tuyển nam của Anh cũng đã thi đấu rất xuất sắc nhưng đáng tiếc gục ngã trước Italia ở chung kết trên chấm luân lưu.","answer":"Bóng đá Anh giành chức vô địch EURO đầu tiên trong lịch sử"},{"question":"క్రింది సమీకరణంలో లోపించినది రాయండి.CO2 + 2H2O → CH2O + …….. + O2A) CO2B) H2OC) C6H12O6D) 6SO2","answer":"B) H2O"},{"question":"次のパラグラフを続ける： 来月14日はバレンタインデーです。東京の池袋にあるデパートでは1月20日から、特別な売り場でチョコレートを売っています。","answer":"このデパートでは「フェアトレード」のチョコレートがよく売れています。フェアトレードでは、正しい働き方でカカオを作ったか、正しい値段で買ったかをチェックしています。 京都にある会社は、フェアトレードのチョコレートを売っています。この会社は、インドネシアでカカオを作っている人たちに、いいカカオをたくさん作る技術を教えています。このためカカオを作っている人の収入は1.5倍ぐらいに増えました。 この会社の品物を買った人は「買うときには、おいしさだけではなくて、誰かのためになっているかも考えます」と話しました。"},{"question":"Inona no sakafo hohanin'ny vorona?","answer":"Ny voa, ny bibikely ary ny biby madinika no sakafo fihinan'ny vorona."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ 北海道函館市は、高級な昆布の1つ「真昆布」が有名です。しかし、夏にとった真昆布にヒドロゾアというクラゲなどの仲間が付いていて、漁業をしている人たちが困っています。市によると、この昆布を食べても体に問題はありません。しかし、売るときにきれいに見えないため、付いたところを切って捨てます。このため、売ることができる昆布が少なくなったり、市場などに出すのが遅くなったりしています。真昆布を海で50年以上育てている人は「こんなにひどい被害は初めてです。毎年続いたら、仕事ができなくなります」と話しています。函館市は、今年の夏はとても暑くて、海の水の温度が高かったことが原因だろうと考えています。そして、漁業をしている人の団体にもっと話を聞くことにしています。","answer":"北海道の昆布に被害　「海の温度が高かったことが原因だろう」"},{"question":"小倉百人一首で、最初の一文字だけで歌が特定できる、いわゆる「一字きまり」の歌は何首あるでしょう？","answer":"７首 （「むすめふさほせ」として覚えます）です。"},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto : El 19 de noviembre se desató la Operación Urano. Los soviéticos habían estado colocando tropas en ambos lados de Stalingrado, formando una pinza alrededor de la ciudad. El 23 de noviembre esa pinza se cerró sobre Stalingrado, atrapando a trescientos mil soldados del Reich. Al mismo tiempo, la Operación Marte intentó atrapar a más soldados alemanes en Smolensk, pero fracasó.","answer":"El evento más importante del texto sería la Operación Urano. "},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 去年10月に岡山県と北海道で鳥インフルエンザが見つかってから、日本のいろいろな県にウイルスが広がっています。10日、宮崎県川南町の農家でもこの病気が見つかりました。この病気が見つかると、ウイルスがうつらないように、にわとりを全部殺します。殺すにわとりの数が、去年10月から日本全部で1008万になりました。1000万以上のにわとりを殺すのは、初めてです。専門家は、今までより早い9月下旬に、ウイルスがうつった鳥が外国から飛んできたことが原因だと話しています。鳥インフルエンザが広がっているため、大分県で有名な「鶏めし」を作っている会社では生産が少なくなっています。鶏肉を買うことが難しくなって、生産がいつもの30％ぐらいになっています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。"},{"question":"Escribe el evento más importante del texto :El titular de Globovisión había participado de una reunión de la Sociedad Interamericana de Prensa (SIP), organización que nuclea a empresarios de medios de la región, en la isla de Aruba. Allí, aseguró que Chávez es responsable de la muerte de venezolanos durante el fallido golpe de Estado contra él en 2002.","answer":"Lo más importante fue este hecho histórico qué quedo marcado en la historia de la humanidad (golpe de Estado contra él en 2002). "},{"question":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको इतिहासको संक्षिप्त विवरण दिनुहोस्।","answer":"काठमाडौं उपत्यकाको हजारौं वर्ष पुरानो इतिहास छ र यो प्राचीन मन्दिर, दरबार र सांस्कृतिक सम्पदाका लागि परिचित छ।"},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal o categoría de esta pregunta: ¿Quién estuvo en funciones durante un periodo más largo, William Taft o Theodore Roosevelt?","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es historia. "},{"question":"Ijọba fẹẹ fofin de ọti inu ọra (pẹlẹbẹ), ati igo keekeeke","answer":"Ijọba ti ni awọn yoo fofin de awọn ọti ti wọn n ṣe keekeeke, eyi ti wọn n ṣe sinu ọra ti wọn n pe ni pẹlẹbẹ, eyi ti wọn n ṣe sinu igo atawọn lailọọnu mi-in. Ọga agba ajọ to n ri si ọrọ ounjẹ ati oogun lilo nilẹ wa, (NAFDAC), Ọjọgbọn Mojisọla Adeyẹye, lo sọrọ naa ni Satide opin ọsẹ to kọja.Obinrin naa ni, ‘‘Ileeṣẹ NAFDAC, labẹ idari ileeṣẹ eto ilera ilẹ wa fi n to gbogbo ilu leti pe opin yoo de ba pipese awọn ọti lile sinu ọra, ike ati igo keekeeke.’’Obinrin naa ni mimu awọn nnkan wọnyi lai bikita n ṣe akoba fun awọn to n mu un lai kiyesara, bẹẹ lo tun n ṣakoba fun ilera ati aabo awọn araalu.Adeyẹye ni bi awọn eeyan ṣe n ni anfaani si awọn ọti pẹlẹbẹ ateyi ti wọn n ṣe sinu igo to jẹ olowo pọọku yii n jẹ ki awọn eeyan ṣi i lo nipa mimu un ni amuju, eyi to ni o n fa aṣilo ọti, to si n ṣakoba ti ko kere fun awujọ wa.O fi kun un pe iwadii Ajọ Eleto Ilera Agbaye (WHO) jẹ ko di mimọ pe mimu awọn ọti yii lai bikita ti ṣokunfa iku eeyan to to bii miliọnu mẹta kaakiri agbaye, ọpọ ni ilera wọn ko da pe mọ, to si ti sọ ọkẹ aimọye eeyan di alaabọ ara.Adeyẹye ni ojuṣe NAFDAC ni lati ṣiṣẹ pọ pẹlu awọn alẹnulọrọ lawujọ, lati din ọsẹ ti awọn ilokulo ọti yii n ṣe ku."},{"question":"ඕසෝන් වියන රැක ගැනීම සදහා ස්ථාපිත කර ඇති සම්මුතිය කුමක්ද?","answer":"වියානා සම්මුතිය."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Yàlla ku'y Nanguwaakoon u tuub la, Jaglewaakoon la.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Yàlla ku'y Nanguwaakoon u tuub la, Jaglewaakoon la.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Yàlla: PROPNku: PRON'y: AUXNanguwaakoon: NOUNu: ADPtuub: NOUNla: AUX,: PUNCTJaglewaakoon: NOUNla: AUX.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Berikan pertanyaan untuk : \\"Antibodi (Ab), juga dikenal sebagai imunoglobulin (Ig), adalah protein berbentuk Y besar yang diproduksi oleh sel-sel B yang digunakan oleh sistem kekebalan tubuh untuk mengidentifikasi dan menetralkan benda asing seperti bakteri dan virus.\\"? Topiknya adalah antibodi.","answer":"Teks diatas menyebutkan mengenai manfaat antibodi (Ab) atau imunoglobulin (Ig) untuk sistem kekebalan tubuh. Sehingga, pertanyaan yang tepat apabila teks diatas digunakan sebagai jawabannya adalah : \\"bagaimana antibodi digunakan dalam tubuh manusia?\\""},{"question":"Namakan cara-cara penghargaan untuk sumbangan tokoh yang menjaga keamanan dan keharmonian negara Malaysia. ","answer":"Penghargaan seperti pengiktirafan negara diberikan dan dibuktikan melalui pemberian darjahkebesaran dan diabadikan nama di tempat awam seperti nama jalan dan nama bangunan. Maka, nama-nama tokoh yang berjasa akan kekal diingatan dan menjadi sebutan seperti contoh Jalan Tunku Abdul Rahman dan Universiti Tun Abdul Razak. Kesimpulannya, penghargaan yang diberi akan melahirkan rasa bersyukur kerana negara kita mempunya ramai tokoh yang berjasa. Tokoh-tokoh negara juga akan dikenali ramai.Cara kedua termasuklah menjaga kebajikan tokoh dan pegawai keselamatan serta ahli keluarga. Program ziarah dan pemberian bantuan kesihatan dan pendidikan boleh dilaksanakan bagi menggembirakan hati keluarga tokoh. Biodata tokoh perlu disimpan dengan mengadakan temubual dan disiarkan di media untuk rujukan dan tontonan generasi depan. Contoh penghargaan ini adalah melalui Majalah Tiga dan Program Negaraku ASTRO. Kisah benar dan fakta tepat berkaitan tokohdapat dikongsikan untuk diambil teladan oleh generasi muda dan meniupkan patriotism supaya rela berkorban demi bangsa dan negara.Satu lagi cara adalah menganjurkan majlis pengisahan tokoh bagi memperingati dan mengadakan bacaan doa dan yassin seluruh negara untuk memperingati mereka yang telah meninggal dunia. Ini akan mendidik generasi muda untuk mengetahui sejarah negara dan mengenali tokoh-tokoh yang berjuang untuk kemanan , kedaulatan dan kemerdekaan negara kita. Sebagai contoh, pertandingan melukis atau sajak boleh diadakan supaya generasi muda mengenali tokoh-tokoh. Kesimpulannya, majlis pengisahan tokoh penting ibarat pepatah tak kenal maka tak cinta."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Marco Aurelio Soto. ","answer":"Bhí Marco Aurelio Soto (1846-1908) ina Uachtarán ar Hondúras ón 27 Lúnasa 1876 go dtí an 19 Deireadh Fómhair, 1883. Bhí cáil an liobrálachais air. Is iomaí leasú a rinne sé sa tír lena linn, lena n-áirítear Leabhar Náisiúnta (Bibliotéca Nacional de Honduras) a bhunú sa bhliain 1880.Rugadh é i Tegucigalpa ar an 13 Samhain 1846, bhain sé cáilíocht abhcóide amach agus chláraigh sé ina bhall den Ghluaiseacht Leasúcháin (Movimiento Reformista) a bhunaigh Justo Rufino Barrios sa bhliain 1871.Bhí sé ina uachtarán ar an tír ar feadh sé bliana. Ba é a rinne príomhchathair na tíre de Tegucigalpa."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Vitsika momba kitay ka ...................................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Vitsika momba kitay ka harivariva an-tanin'olona \\" "},{"question":"Ai là tiến sĩ Toán học đầu tiên của Việt Nam?Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi trên trong những câu sau:A. Hoàng Xuân SínhB. Lê Văn ThiêmC. Phạm Tỉnh Quát","answer":"B. Lê Văn ThiêmGS Lê Văn Thiêm, sinh năm 1918 ở Đức Thọ, Hà Tĩnh. Năm 1930, bố mẹ qua đời, ông vào Quy Nhơn, nương tựa người anh cả để học trường College de Quy Nhơn. Theo tư liệu của Đại học Quốc gia Hà Nội, chỉ trong 4 năm, Lê Văn Thiêm đã hoàn thành chương trình 9 năm và đứng đầu danh sách khen thưởng của nhà trường khi tốt nghiệp Cao đẳng tiểu học (tương đương với phổ thông cơ sở ngày nay). Ba tháng sau, Lê Văn Thiêm lập thi đỗ tú tài phần 1 (tương đương lớp 11), việc mà người bình thường phải chuẩn bị khẩn trương trong hai năm. Ngay năm sau, ông lại thi đỗ tú tài toàn phần.Năm 1938, Lê Văn Thiêm ghi tên theo học lớp Lý - Hoá - Sinh (PCB) để chuẩn bị học ngành Y do trong nước chưa đào tạo cử nhân Toán. Năm sau, với thành tích đỗ thứ nhì kỳ thi PCB, ông được nhận học bổng sang Pháp du học.Năm 1939, Lê Văn Thiêm trở thành sinh viên khoa Toán tại Đại học Sư phạm Paris. Bị gián đoạn đèn sách do chiến tranh thế giới thứ hai, đến năm 1943, ông mới tiếp tục việc học và năm sau nhận bằng thạc sĩ Toán.Được học bổng, Lê Văn Thiêm sang Đức làm luận án tiến sĩ Toán tại Đại học Göttingen do nhà Toán học Hans Wittich hướng dẫn. Luận án \\"Về việc xác định kiểu của một diện Riemann mở đơn liên\\" được Lê Văn Thiêm bảo vệ thành công ngày 4/4/1945. Ông trở thành người Việt Nam đầu tiên cầm trong tay bằng tiến sĩ Toán."},{"question":"ما هي الآثار المحتملة لاستهلاك الأغذية الملوثة على الصحة؟","answer":"إن استهلاك الأغذية الملوثة بالنويدات المشعة الناجمة عن طارئة نووية أو إشعاعية سيزيد من مقدار النشاط الإشعاعي في الجسم ويمكن أن يزيد من المخاطر الصحية المرتبطة بالتعرض للإشعاع. وسيتوقف مستوى الخطر على نوع النويدات المشعة التي تم بلعها ومقدار الإشعاعات التي تنفذ إلى الجسم."},{"question":" Qeex Xiriiriye? ","answer":" Xiriiriye Waa wax lagu xiriiriyo ama lagu kabayo dhismaha weeraha."},{"question":"Hacettepe Erasmus kimler başvurabilir?","answer":"Kitaba ulaşmak için tıklayınız.Seviye tespit sınavına üniversitemiz örgün eğitim kademelerinin herhangi birinde (ön-lisans, lisans, yüksek lisans, doktora) kayıtlı, tam zamanlı öğrenciler katılabilir. ...Başvuru için istenen bilgiler aday tarafından eksiksiz ve doğru bir şekilde verilmek zorundadır."},{"question":"කුළු බඩු යනු මොනවාද?","answer":"ආහාර රසවත් කිරීමට හා ආහාර මත වර්ධනය වන අහිතකර බැක්ටීරියා වර්ග විනාශ කිරීමෙන් ආහාර සංරක්ෂණය කිරීමට උපකාරී වන වියළි බීජ වර්ග, පළතුරක් හෝ මුල් වර්ගයක් වශයෙන් කුළු බඩු, සරලව හඳුනාගත හැකිය. මෙම කුළු බඩු වර්ගවලින් බොහොමයක් ආහාර පිසීමට භාවිතා කිරීමට අමතරව ඖෂධ වර්ග, සුවඳ විලවුන්, ආලේපන වර්ග හෝ ආගමික කටයුතු සඳහා භාවිතා කිරීම දැකගත හැකිය."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي صور رفع الحرج في الشريعة الإسلامية؟","answer":"الإجابة: اعتبار المرض والخطأ والنسيان والسفر، والإكراه والنوم، أعذارًا لتخفيف الأحكام وتشريع الرخص."},{"question":"Nibo lẹyin n gbe, nibo lẹyin wa: Nigba t’Abiọla atawọn eeyan rẹ kọju ija si Awolọwọ ni 1979 (12)","answer":"Inu Ọgagun Muritala Muhammed ko dun rara si ohun ti Ọgagun agba Yakubu Gowon, olori ijọba Naijiria nigba naa,  ṣe fun Theophilus Akindele yii. Muritala fẹ ki wọn le ọkunrin naa kuro lẹnu iṣẹ ijọba pata ni, ko fẹ idaduro fungba diẹ ti Gowon ṣe fun un. Loju Muritala, bii igba ti Gowon n fi aaye agbaju gba ọkunrin olori ileeṣẹ eto ibanisọrọ yii ni, ati pe oun lo n fun un layọ yọ, to fi jẹ ki ọkunrin naa maa foju di oun odidi minisita. Bi o ba jẹ oun Muritala ni olori ijọba, iru awọn eeyan bii Akindele to n fa wahala, to si jọ ara rẹ loju yii, oun yoo yọ ọ danu bii ẹni to yọ jiga ni, ti kinni kan ko si ni i ti idi rẹ yọ. Ṣugbọn Gowon ko ṣe bẹẹ, nitori o mọ lọkan ara rẹ pe ni tododo, Akindele yii ko ṣe kinni kan. Gbogbo ohun ti ọkunrin naa ṣe, Gowon mọ pe fun anfaani gbogbo Naijiria ni, ohun ti ko si ni i jẹ ki Naijiria fowo ṣofo nipa gbigbe iṣẹ fun ITT ni.Ṣugbọn ko le sọ bẹẹ loju awọn ọmọọṣẹ rẹ ninu iṣẹ ologun ti wọn jọ n ṣejọba. O mọ pe MKO Abiọla ni olori ileeṣẹ ITT ni Naijiria, oun ni aṣoju wọn, ati pe Abiọla yii, ọrẹ timọtimọ lo jẹ fun Muritala, boya ni ko si jẹ wọn jọ mọ ohun to n lọ nileeṣẹ naa ni. Bẹẹ Muritala ni ero lẹyin ninu awọn ọga ṣọja ti wọn jọ n ṣejọba ologun, boun ba si huwa kan ti ko tẹ wọn lọrun, wọn le ditẹ mọ oun, iyẹn bi wọn ko ba tilẹ gba ijọba naa lọwọ oun. Ati pe ki i kuku tilẹ i ṣe oni, ki i ṣe ana, ti Muritala ti maa n gbo Gowon lẹnu nibi ipade nla yii, bi inu ba si bi i tan pata, ko si ohun ti ko le ṣe. Ohun to jẹ ki Gowon ni ki wọn da Akindele duro fungba diẹ lẹnu iṣẹ ree, nitori ko fẹẹ ri ija Muritala ati awọn eeyan rẹ, bẹẹ si ni ko le le Akindele kuro lẹnu iṣẹ patapata, nigba to mọ pe ọkunrin naa ko ṣe nnkan kan ti ko dara, iṣẹ tirẹ lo n ṣe gẹgẹ bii ojulowo oṣiṣẹ ijọba.Nitori pe wọn mọ pe gbogbo ohun ti awọn ṣe naa ko dara, ko gbọdọ lu jade, itiju ati abuku ni yoo jẹ fun gbogbo awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba naa, iyẹn ni Gowon ṣe kilọ fun Akindele pe ohun to ṣẹlẹ yii ko gbọdọ jade ninu beba tabi nileeṣẹ iroyin kankan. Akindele ni oun ti gbọ, ko si ṣe meni ko ṣe meji, o ko faili ati awọn iwe rẹ, o jade nipade, o gba ọọfiisi rẹ lọ. Nigba to de ọọfiisi rẹ paapaa,  ko le ba ẹni kan sọrọ, o kan sọ fun akọwe rẹ pe ko pa gbogbo ipade to ni rẹ pata, ko sọ fun awọn ti awọn jọ fẹẹ ṣepade pe oun le ma ri aaye ri wọn fun igba pipẹ. Nigba ti akọwe rẹ beere pe nigba wo ni koun waa da fun wọn pe ki wọn wa, Akindele sọ fun un pe ko ma da igba kankan fun wọn o, nitori oun ko mọ igba toun le pada si ẹnu iṣẹ yii, pe ijọba apapọ ti da oun duro fungba diẹ na, oun ko si mọ ọjọ ti wọn yoo pe oun pada pe koun waa bẹrẹ iṣẹ oun.Bo ti sọ bẹẹ lo palẹ ẹru rẹ mọ, n lo ba lọ. Ṣugbọn ni fẹẹrẹ ti ilẹ mọ lọjọ keji, olori ileeṣẹ Daily Times igba naa, Alaaji Babatunde Jọsẹ, ẹni to n gbe ni bii ile kẹta si ile Akindele gba ilẹkun ile wọn lati wọle, wọn si sare ji Akindele loju oorun fun un. Nigba to jade si i ni palọ ti iyẹn jokoo si, ohun ti Jọsẹ kọkọ beere ni pe ki lo ṣẹlẹ nibi iṣẹ wọn, bẹẹ lo fa iwe naa yọ gadagba, ti wọn si ti kọ ọ sibẹ pe ija agba laarin Muritala ati Akindele ti jẹ ki wọn da Akindele duro lẹnu iṣẹ fungba diẹ na o. O ya Akindele lẹnu, o si ya Jọse naa lẹnu nigba ti Akindele ṣalaye fun un pe bi ọrọ se jẹ naa ree, ṣugbọn oun ko mọ bi kinni naa ti de inu beba. Nibi ti wọn ti n sọrọ lọwọ ni Gowon ti tẹlifoonu si i, iyẹn si Akindele, pe oun ti ri iṣẹ ọwọ rẹ, ko maa reti awọn ṣọja ti yoo waa gbe e ni ile rẹ laipẹ rara. Bi Jọse ti gbọ bẹẹ loun sare jade, ko fẹ kawọn ṣọja ba oun nile ẹ.Akindele jokoo sile ẹ, o n reti awọn ṣọja, awọn ọrẹ rẹ ti wọn si ti gbọ ọrọ yii bẹrẹ si i pe pe ki lo de, ṣe ko si nnkan kan, wọn si n ba a daro ohun to ṣẹlẹ si i. Awọn kan ti wọn gbọ pe Gowon n ran ṣọja bọ waa gbe e ni ko tete sa jade nile ẹ, ko ma duro rara.Akindle taku, o loun ko le sa jade ninu ile oun nigba toun ko ṣe ohun kan. Oun ko fun oniroyin ni iroyin ohun to ṣẹlẹ, koda oun o ti i fi ẹnu ara oun sọ ọrọ naa fun ẹnikan kan titi ti Jọsẹ fi de ọdọ oun, to fi mu iwe wa, ki waa ni koun maa sa lọ fun, bi awọn ṣọja ba fẹẹ wa ki wọn wa jare. Ṣugbọn bii wakati meji kọja, ko ri ṣọja kankan ko wa, titi di bii wakati mẹrin. Lẹyin naa ni Gowon tun tẹlifoonu si i pada funra ẹ, o ni ko maa bọ ko waa ri oun ni ọọfiisi oun. Akindele ko fẹẹ lọ, o si sọ bẹẹ fun Gowon, o ni oun ko le jẹ ki awọn ṣọja mu oun nibẹ ki ẹnikan ma  mọ, to ba fẹẹ mu oun, ki wọn waa gbe oun nile oun ni.Gowon fi i rẹrin-in ni, o ni bo ba ṣe pe oun fẹẹ fi ṣọja gbe e ni, oun ko ni i maa pe e mọ, ile rẹ naa ni wọn yoo ti gbe e. Ni Akindele ba lọọ ba Gowon. Nigba to de ọhun, Gowon ni iwadii awọn ti fi han pe ki i ṣe oun lo ba ẹnikẹni sọrọ lori ọrọ yii, pe oniroyin Daily Times kan to ti n gbọ hunrun-hunrun lori ohun to n lọ nileeṣẹ naa tẹlẹ wa nibẹ nigba ti Akindele n sọ fun akọwe rẹ pe wọn ti da oun duro fun igba diẹ na, oniroyin yii lo si fi eeji kun ẹẹta gẹgẹ bii ohun to ti gbọ tẹlẹ, oun lo sare lọọ gbe iroyin naa jade. O ni nitori bẹẹ, ki  Akindlee ma binu, ko maa pada lọ sile rẹ. O daju pe ki i ṣe nitori eleyii ni Gowon ṣe pe Akindele, nitori bo ba jẹ ohun to fẹẹ sọ fun un naa niyi, ko si ohun ti ko ṣe le sọ ọ ni ori tẹlifoonu, ṣugbọn lati fi ọgbọn tu Akindele ninu ni, ko si jẹ ko mọ pe ko si ohun toun le ṣe si ọrọ to wa nilẹ naa ju eyi ti oun ṣe yẹn lọ ni.Akindele pada si ile rẹ, aaye waa gba Muritala lati ṣe ohun ti wọn fẹẹ ṣe. Loju-ẹsẹ lo pada si ileeṣẹ rẹ, o si gbe igbimọ mi-in dide lati ṣe atunṣe awọn iwe ti wọn kọ lọjọsi lori ọrọ iṣẹ ti wọn fẹẹ gbe fun ITT yii kan naa, iṣẹ ti wọn tori rẹ le Akindele. Iyatọ to wa ninu igbimọ eleyii ni pe akọwe agba fun ileeṣẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Williams, ati olori ẹka eto ibanisọrọ, Ọgbẹni Lasọde, ni wọn wa nidii eto naa bayii, ohun ti wọn ba fẹ ni wọn si le ṣe. Gbogbo awọn ti wọn wa ninu igbimọ naa lọjọsi ti wọn tẹle Akindele lori ọrọ yii ni wọn ko pe sinu igbimọ naa mọ, nigba ti wọn si ṣepade wọn, kia ni wọn fi ọwọ si iṣẹ yii, wọn ni ki ITT ko irinṣẹ naa wa fawọn, nitori yoo wulo gan-an, yoo si mu eto ibanisọrọ awọn gbooro si i ni Naijiria. Iwe yii ni Muritala gbe lọ siwaju igbimọ awọn ologun apapọ pe ki wọn fọwọ si i ki ITT le bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn, nitori iṣẹ naa ti falẹ fun ọjọ pipẹ.Kia ni igbimọ awọn alaṣẹ ijọba apapọ ti fi ọwọ si iṣẹ naa nibi ipade wọn loṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 1975, nigba to si di ibẹrẹ oṣu keji, ijọba Naijiria ati ileeṣẹ ITT fọwọ si iwe adehun yii, wọn ni ki ITT bẹrẹ iṣẹ wọn. Gẹgẹ bi a ti wi tẹlẹ, miliọnu lọna irinwo ati aabọ o le ni owo iṣẹ yii, bẹẹ ni Akindele ṣe ẹkunrẹre alaye pe bii ilọpọ mẹwaa iye to yẹ ki wọn ṣe iṣẹ naa ni wọn kọ wa yii, iyẹn ni pe bii ogoji (40) miliọnu naira lo yẹ ki wọn fi ṣe iṣẹ yii, ṣugbọn ITT, ileeṣẹ awọn Abiọla, gba irinwo (400) miliọnu o le, ọọkan ibi yii ni owo Abiọla si ti yarọ, owo naa de digbidigbi ti oun naa ko si mọ ohun toun yoo fi i ṣe ni, owo naa ti pọ ju. Ọsẹ akọkọ ninu oṣu keji ni wọn gbe iṣẹ yii fun awọn ITT, ọsẹ yẹn naa ni wọn kọwe si Akindele pe to ba ti di ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu keji, ni 1975 kan naa, ko pada si ẹnu iṣẹ rẹ, ṣe wọn ti gbe iṣẹ fun ITT, ITT ti gbowo iṣẹ wọn, ọkan Muritala si ti balẹ. Nnkan nla gbaa ni!Ẹ maa ka a lọ lọsẹ to n bọ."},{"question":"Title: కరోనావైరస్: విశాఖలో పాజిటివ్ కేసు, నగరంలో హై అలర్ట్nGiven the above title of an imaginary article, imagine the article.n","answer":"విశాఖ-హైదరాబాద్- సౌదీఅల్లిపురం ప్రాంతానికి చెందిన 65 సంవత్సరాల వ్యక్తి మూడు రోజుల క్రితం హైదరాబాద్ నుంచి వచ్చారు. ఫిబ్రవరి 21న ఆయన గరీబ్ రథ్‌ ఎక్స్‌ప్రెస్ రైలులో హైదరాబాద్ వెళ్లారు. అక్కడ 25 వరకూ తన కుమార్తె ఇంట్లో ఉన్నారు. 26వ తేదీన మక్కా వెళ్లారు. అక్కడి నుంచి మార్చి 9న మదీనా వెళ్లారు. 10వ తేదీన తిరిగి హైదరాబాద్ చేరుకున్నారు. 11న రాత్రి హైదరాబాద్ నుంచి బయలుదేరి 12వ తేదీ ఉదయం విశాఖ వచ్చారు. దగ్గు, జలుబుతో బాధపడిన ఆయనకు మొదట స్థానికంగా ఉన్న ఓ వైద్యశాలలో చికిత్స చేశారు. ఆనంతరం మూడు రోజుల క్రితం విశాఖలోని చెస్ట్ ఆస్పత్రిలో చేర్చారు. ఆయన నుంచి శాంపిళ్లు సేకరించి హైదరాబాద్ పంపి పరీక్షించారు. ఆయనకు కరోనావైరస్ సోకినట్లు నిర్ధరణ అయ్యింది. దాంతో ఆయన్ను ఐసోలేషన్ వార్డులో ఉంచి చికిత్స అందిస్తున్నారు.ఆయనతో పాటు మరో ముగ్గురు కూడా అలాంటి లక్షణాలతోనే రావడంతో వారి నుంచి శాంపిళ్లు సేకరించి హైదరాబాద్‌లోని ల్యాబ్‌కు పంపించారు. ఆయన నివాసం ఉండే ప్రాంతంలో వైద్య బృందాలు సర్వే చేస్తున్నాయి. ఆయన ఈ వారం రోజుల్లో ఎవరెవరిని కలిశారు? ఎక్కడికి వెళ్లారు? తదితర వివరాల గురించి ఆరా తీస్తున్నారు. ముందు జాగ్రత్త చర్యలు కూడా చేపట్టారు.విశాఖలో ఆంక్షలుఅల్లిపురం చుట్టుపక్కల 5 కిలోమీటర్ల వరకూ రహదారులను మూసివేశారు. ఆశా వర్కర్లు, వాలంటీర్లతో కలిపి 141 ప్రత్యేక బృందాలను ఏర్పాటు చేశామని, మొత్తం 7,800 ఇళ్లను జల్లెడ పడుతున్నామని విశాఖ జిల్లా వైద్య ఆరోగ్య శాఖాధికారి తిరుపతిరావు చెప్పారు. శానిటైజర్లను స్ప్రేయింగ్ చేయడంతో పాటు వ్యాధి లక్షణాలున్న వారిని గుర్తిస్తామని తెలిపారు. ఇంతే కాకుండా, విశాఖలో కాల్ సెంటర్ ఏర్పాటు చేశారు. డీఎంహెచ్‌వో కార్యాలయంలో 24 గంటలూ పనిచేసే కాల్ సెంటర్‌లో సిబ్బంది అందుబాటులో ఉండేలా చర్యలు తీసుకున్నామని చెప్పారు. ఇప్పటికే రాష్ర్ట ప్రభుత్వ ఆదేశాలతో ఉత్తరాంధ్ర వ్యాప్తంగా సినిమా హాళ్లు, షాపింగ్ మాల్స్, జూ పార్కు, అన్నీ మూతపడ్డాయి. పర్యటక కేంద్రాలైన బొర్రా గుహలను కూడా మూసివేశారు. విశాఖ ఆర్కే బీచ్‌, రుషికొండ బీచ్, కైలాసగిరిలోనూ సందర్శకుల శాతం చాలా తక్కువగా ఉంది.ఉత్తరాంధ్ర వ్యాప్తంగా సీతంపేట ఏజెన్సీ, పార్వతీపురం ఏజెన్సీ, విశాఖ ఏజెన్సీలో వారాంతపు సంతలు, ప్రార్ధనా స్థలాలు వంటి వాటిని నిషేధించారు.ఉత్తరాంధ్రలో ప్రముఖ పుణ్యక్షేత్రాలు అయిన సింహాచలం దేవస్థానం, శ్రీకాకుళం జిల్లాలోని శ్రీకూర్మం, అరసవిల్లి సూర్యదేవాలయం,...కూడా. "},{"question":"રોટી/ચપાતીના ઘટકો શું છે?","answer":"ચપટીને રોટી, રુટી, રોટી રોટલી, રોટ્ટા, સફતિ, શબાતી, ફુલકા (મરાઠીમાં), ચાપો (પૂર્વ આફ્રિકામાં), સદા રોટલી (કેરેબિયનમાં), પોલિ અને રોશી (માલડાઇવ્સમાં) તરીકે પણ ઓળખાય છે, તે એક છેભારતીય ઉપખંડમાંથી ઉદ્ભવતા અને ભારત, નેપાળ, બાંગ્લાદેશ, પાકિસ્તાન, શ્રીલંકા, પૂર્વ આફ્રિકા, અરેબિયન દ્વીપકલ્પ અને કેરેબિયનમાં ઉદ્ભવતા ઉપેક્ષિત ફ્લેટબ્રેડ છે. [૨]ચપટીસ એટીએ તરીકે ઓળખાતા આખા ઘઉંના લોટથી બનેલા હોય છે, જે પાણી, તેલ (વૈકલ્પિક) અને મીઠું (વૈકલ્પિક) સાથે કણકમાં ભળી જાય છે, જેને પેરાટ કહેવામાં આવે છે, અને તાવા પર રાંધવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bunyi cempedak jatuh\\"?","answer":"bunyi jatuh yang kuat"},{"question":"வினா :சரியான விடையத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக. தமிழ்நாட்டில் பெட்ரோலியம் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ள இடம்A. திருநெல்வேலிB. திருச்சிC. தஞ்சாவூர்(நரிமணம்)D. மதுரை","answer":"விடை : தமிழ்நாட்டில் பெட்ரோலியம் கண்டறியப்பட்டுள்ள இடம்C. தஞ்சாவூர்(நரிமணம்)பெட்ரோலியம்  என்றால் பாறை எண்ணெய் அல்லது கல்லெண்ணெய் என்பது பொருளாகும். கிரேக்க மொழியில் பெட்ரா என்றால் பாறை அல்லது கல் என்று பொருளாகும். ஓலியம் என்றால் எண்ணெய் என்பது பொருள். இயற்கையில் நிலத்திலுள்ள பாறைகளிலிருந்து தோற்றம் பெற்று கிடைப்பதால் இப்பெயர் சூட்டப்பட்டுள்ளது.நீர்ம நிலையில் உள்ள பல ஐதரோகார்பன்களின் கலவை பெட்ரோலியம் ஆகும். இந்த ஐதரோகார்பன் மூலக்கூறுகள் வெவ்வேறு நீளங்கள் கொண்டவையாக உள்ளன. இவற்றில் பெரும்பாலானவை, ஆல்க்கேன்கள் ஆகும். இவற்றின் நீளம் C5H12 இல் இருந்து C18H38 வரை பொதுவாகக் காணப்படுகிறது. இதனினும் குறைந்த நீளமுடையவை எரிவளி அல்லது எரிவளி நீர்மமாக் கருதப்படுகின்றன. நீளமான ஐதரோகார்பன் தொடர்கள், திண்ம நிலையில் உள்ளன. மிக நீளமான ஐதரோகார்பன்கள் நிலக்கரி ஆகும்.இயற்கையில் கிடைக்கும் பாறை எண்ணெயில் உலோகமற்ற தனிமங்களான கந்தகம், ஆக்ஸிஜன், நைட்ரஜன் போன்றவையும் காணப்படலாம். பொதுவாக இது கறுப்பு அல்லது கரும்பழுப்பு நிறத்தில் காணப்படுகிறது."},{"question":"Qual cantor era conhecido entre outras coisas como 'The King of Pop' e 'The Gloved One'?","answer":"Michael Jackson"},{"question":"Scotland Yard stopt met het zoeken naar restanten van slachtoffers van de grote brand vorige maand in de Grenfell Tower. Het dodental staat nu op 81. Ten tijde van de brand waren er 350 mensen in het flatgebouw, van wie er 225 konden worden geëvacueerd. 14 bewoners waren niet thuis. Alle nog identificeerbare menselijke resten zijn inmiddels uit het gebouw gehaald. Er zijn tot nu toe niet meer dan 32 mensen formeel geïdentificeerd, bij een aantal van de overige dodelijke slachtoffers zal dit nooit meer lukken omdat hun resten door de verzengende hitte bij de brand te onherkenbaar zijn.Geef me een goede title voor dit artikel.","answer":"Natuurlijk, een mogelijke titel voor het artikel is \\"Scotland Yard zoekt niet langer naar overlevenden Grenfell Tower-brand\\"."},{"question":"கேள்வி :குஷானர்கள் எந்த நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்தவர்கள்அ. கிரேக்கம்ஆ. பாரசீகம்இ. இந்தியாஈ. சீனா","answer":"பதில் :ஈ. சீனா"},{"question":"Hvad er opskriften på pasta med kødsovs?","answer":"Her er en simpel opskrift på pasta med kødsovs. Opskriften er beregnet til 4 personer.Ingredienser400g hakket oksekød1 stort løg, hakket2 fed hvidløg, hakket1 dåse hakket tomat (ca. 400g)2 spsk tomatpuré2 tsk oregano1 tsk basilikum1 tsk sukkerSalt og sort peber efter smag2 spsk olivenolie400g pasta (for eksempel spaghetti)Frisk parmesan til serveringFremgangsmådeForbered ingredienserne: Hak løg og hvidløg. Mål krydderier og andre ingredienser op.Brun kødet: Varm en stor pande op med olivenolie over mellem-høj varme. Tilsæt hakket oksekød og brun det godt af. Bryd kødet op i små stykker med en træske undervejs.Tilsæt løg og hvidløg: Når kødet er brunet, tilsættes hakket løg og hvidløg. Steg i yderligere 5 minutter, eller indtil løgene er bløde.Krydderier og tomat: Tilsæt tomatpuré, hakket tomat, oregano, basilikum, sukker, salt og sort peber. Rør godt rundt.Lad det simre: Skru ned for varmen, og lad saucen simre i mindst 20 minutter. Jo længere tid, desto bedre smag.Kog pasta: Mens saucen simrer, kan du koge pastaen i en stor gryde med rigeligt saltet vand. Følg instruktionerne på pakken for kogning.Dræn pasta: Når pastaen er kogt, skal den drænes for vand.Samling: Tilsæt den drænede pasta til kødsovsen og rør rundt, eller server kødsovsen over pastaen, alt efter præference.Servering: Server med friskrevet parmesan og eventuelt lidt frisk basilikum.Nyd måltidet!"},{"question":"Sobre qual evento importante é esse texto: Em sua estreia na Fórmula 1, no dia 26 de julho de 2009, no Grande Prêmio da Hungria pela equipe Toro Rosso, Alguersuari completou a prova na 15ª posição. Os primeiros pontos na categoria foram conquistados no Grande Prêmio da Malásia, quando terminou a corrida na nona colocação.","answer":"Carreira do corredor de F1 Alguersuari, sua primeira corrida e seu primeiro ponto."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Kibokiboin'ny marina ka ...\\" ","answer":"\\" Kibokiboin'ny marina ka milaza tsy anontaniana. \\" "},{"question":"Miten keuhkoklamydia tarttuu?","answer":"Bakteeri tarttuu hengitysteitse pisaratartuntana ihmisestä toiseen. Keuhkoklamydia esiintyy usein useamman kuukauden mittaisina epidemioina. Itämisaika tartunnasta oireiden alkuun on noin kuukausi."},{"question":"Quem foi o primeiro brasileiro a conquistar um cinturão no UFC?","answer":"O primeiro campeão brasileiro foi Royce Gracie, em 1993, no primeiro torneio realizado na história da organização."},{"question":"问：《荒野大镖客2》可以在哪些平台上玩？","answer":"答：《荒野大镖客2》可以在PlayStation 4、Xbox One、Microsoft Windows以及Google Stadia等平台上玩。"},{"question":"රුලං යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"රුලං (Semolina) යනු ආහාර ද්‍රව්‍යයකි."},{"question":"සීගිරි බලකොටුව නිර්මාණය කල රජු සදහන් කරන්න.","answer":"සීගිරි බලකොටුව ඉදිකරනු ලැබුවේ කාශ්‍යප රජු විසිනි."},{"question":"北海道河西（かさい）郡芽室（めむろ）町が発祥地で、プレイヤーは１チーム５人である、ご年配の方に人気のスポーツは何でしょう？","answer":"ゲートボールです。"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny _ dia tantara an'ohatra nampiasain'i Jesosy mba hampianarana lesona ara-moraly.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Fanoharana nampiasain'i Jesosy mba hampianarana lesona momba ny fitondran - tena ny fanoharana."},{"question":"다음 맥락을 완성시켜주세요. 헝가리의 귀족들의 대부분은 라코치의 봉기가 농민 봉기와 다름없다며 지지하지 않았다. 그렇지만 라코치는 해방된 농민 전사 계층인 허이두크(Hajduk)를 자신들의 군대에 끌어들이는 데에 성공했다. 그가 지휘하는 군대는 한동안 헝가리 국토의 대부분을 지배했지만 합스부르크 군주국이 대대적인 반격에 나서면서 전쟁 상황은 불리해지게 된다. 특히 1704년 8월 13일에 일어난 블레넘 전투","answer":"(블렌하임 전투)에서 잉글랜드-스코틀랜드-신성 로마 제국-합스부르크 군주국 연합군이 프랑스-바이에른 연합군을 격파하면서 라코치는 큰 타격을 입게 된다."},{"question":"ગુજરાતી કવિ ભોજા ભાગત ની માહિતી આપો.","answer":"ભોજા અથવા ભોજોનો જન્મ ૧૭૮૫માં લેઉઆ કણબી જ્ઞાતિમાં ફતેહપુર અથવા દેવકી ગલોળ ગામમાં જેતપુર નજીક સૌરાષ્ટ્રમાં થયો હતો. તેમનાં પિતાનું નામ કરસનદાસ અને માતાનું નામ ગંગાબાઇ હતું. તેમની કૌટુંબિક અટક સાવલિયા હતી. ૧૨ વર્ષની ઉંમરે તેઓ તેમનાં ગુરૂને મળ્યાં જેઓ ગિરનારના સંન્યાસી હતી. જ્યારે તેઓ ૨૪ વર્ષના થયા ત્યારે તેમનું કુટુંબ અમરેલી નજીક ફતેપુર ગામમાં સ્થાયી થયું. તેઓ પછીથી ભોજા ભગત અને ત્યારબાદ ભોજલરામ તરીકે જાણીતા થયા.વ્યવસાયે તેઓ ખેડૂત હતા. અભણ હોવા છતાં તેમનાં ગિરનારી ગુરૂના આશીર્વાદથી તેમણે કવિતાઓ અને ગીતો લખ્યા જેમાં સામાજિક દૂષણો પરનો વિરોધ હતો, તે ભોજા ભગતના ચાબખાઓ તરીકે પ્રખ્યાત છે."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക ഏത് വിഷയത്തെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് സംസാരിക്കുന്നത്: \\"ഇന്ത്യയിലെ ഏറ്റവും മികച്ച കായികതാരങ്ങളിലൊരാളായിരുന്നു പി.ടി. ഉഷ. ഇന്ത്യ കണ്ട എക്കാലത്തെയും മികച്ച സ്പ്രിന്ററായാണ് പി.ടി. ഉഷ കണക്കാക്കപ്പെടുന്നത്. 1984-ൽ പത്മശ്രീയും അർജുന അവാർഡും നേടിയ ഉഷ ഇന്ത്യയ്ക്കുവേണ്ടി അന്താരാഷ്ട്ര മത്സരങ്ങളിൽ നിന്ന് വിരമിച്ചു. 2000-ൽ. നിലവിൽ കായിക പ്രതിഭകളെ പരിശീലിപ്പിക്കുന്നതിനായി ഉഷ സ്കൂൾ ഓഫ് അത്‌ലറ്റിക്‌സ് നടത്തുന്നു.\\"","answer":"മുകളിലെ ഖണ്ഡിക \\"പി.ടി. ഉഷ\\"യെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് പറയുന്നത്."},{"question":"Describe algunas estructuras de datos comunes utilizadas en la programación competitiva y sus aplicaciones.","answer":"En la programación competitiva, las estructuras de datos eficientes son fundamentales para resolver problemas de manera rápida y efectiva.  Las más comunes son:1. Arreglos o listas: Se usan para para mantener y manipular datos, como listas de valores de la entrada, resultados intermedios y datos de salida. En Python se puede utilizar \`list\`, y en C++ se puede utilizar tanto arreglos convencionales de C, como \`std:array\` (para arreglos de tamaño fijo) o \`std::vector\` (para arreglos dinámicos).2. Listas enlazadas: Consisten de nodos conectados entre sí de manera lineal. Son una abstración con la cual se pueden implementar otras estructuras de datos más específicas como colas, pilas, etc.3. Cola: Es una estructura de datos que permite insertar elementos por un lado y eliminar elementos por el otro. Usa el principio FIFO (first in-first out). Se puede implementar sobre una lista enlazada. En C++ existe una implementación en la clase \`std::queue\` y en Python existe \`Deque\` en \`collections\`.4. Pila: Permite insertar elementos por un lado y eliminarlos por el mismo lado. Usa el principio LIFO (last in-first out). Se puede implementar sobre una lista enlazada. En C++ existe una implementación en la clase \`std::stack\`.5. Montículos (Heaps). Son un árbol binario casi-completo que mantienen cierta propiedad de prioridad en cada nodo. Permiten insertar y eliminar elementos en tiempo logarítmico, así como obtener el menor o mayor elemento en tiempo constante. Son muy útiles para implementar colas de prioridad. En C++ se puede encontrar una implementación en la clase \`std::priority_queue\`, y en Python se puede encontrar una implementación en la clase \`heapify\`. 6. Tablas de Hash: Permiten insertar, eliminar y recuperar pares clave-valor en tiempo promedio constante. Son útiles para implementar arreglos asociativos y contar frecuencias. En C++ existen implementaciones como \`unordered_set\` y \`unordered_map\`, y en Python existen \`set\` y \`map\`. Notemos que en C++ también existen \`set\` y \`map\` pero están implementados con árboles binarios de búsqueda.7. Union-Find Disjoint Set: Se utiliza para resolver problemas relacionados a componentes conexas y conjuntos disjuntos. Es útil para detectar ciclos y para mezclar conjuntos de manera eficiente. Se utiliza en el algoritmo de Kruskal para encontrar el MST.8. Segment Tree: Es un árbol binario completo estático, en el cada nodo tiene información correspondiente a un rango de un arreglo. Con esta información se puede computar la información sobre cualquier rango en tiempo logarítmico. Es muy útil en problemas de preguntas y actualizaciones en rangos.9. Trie: Se usan para manipular cadenas, insertar y eliminar cadenas,  y hacer preguntas sobre prefijos de cadenas.Estas estructuras de datos son los componentes básicos de la programación competitiva, y comprender cuándo y cómo aplicarlas es esencial para resolver una amplia gama de problemas algorítmicos de manera eficiente. Los programadores competitivos exitosos son hábiles en seleccionar la estructura de datos más apropiada para un problema dado y en implementarla de manera óptima."},{"question":"-  Sheeg yaa ugu horeeyey Muslimiinta qof Maka Ka haajira oo u haajira Madiina?","answer":"Wuxu ahaa abuu Salaama Rc."},{"question":"පහත ගීතයේ පද රචනය කාගේද?රන් කෙන්දන් බැඳ අතැඟිලි එක්කළ ආදරයයි...පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.....පෙම් රැහැනෙන් බැඳසිතුම් වසඟ කළ ආදරයයි.......කිරිලිය සේ දුර පියාසලාලාඅත්තටු රිදුණා පමණයිදෑල විදාහළ දෑත මගේඔබටත් ඔහුටත් උරුමයිහිරු සඳු එකවර දෙපස නැඟේකළුවර ඇයි විජිතයම මගේ....කණාටු සුළඟේ දුහුළු මලකි අදවල්මත් වී පාවෙන්නේඔබගෙන් දෝඔහුගෙන් දෝමා හෙට දින සමුගන්නේ.....","answer":"ගීපද - අජන්තා  රණසිංහ"},{"question":"Karanta wannan rubutun sanna ka amsa tambayoyin dake ciki: A ranar 14 ga Oktoba, 2013, Dwayne Johnson ya kulla yarjejeniya don yin fim, a fim din yana taka rawar matukin jirgi mai saukar ungulu yana neman 'yarsa bayan girgizar kasa. A ranar 4 ga Fabrairu, 2014, Alexandra Daddario ta shiga cikin 'yan wasan. A ranar 12 ga Maris, 2014, Carla Gugino ta shiga cikin 'yan wasan, ta haɗu da Dwayne Johnson, wanda ta yi fim tare da shi a Race to Witch Mountain da Faster. A ranar 14 ga Maris, 2014, wasan kwaikwayo na Game of Thrones Art Parkinson ya shiga cikin fim din. A ranar 1 ga Afrilu, 2014, Archie Panjabi ya shiga fim ɗin girgizar ƙasa. A ranar 5 ga Afrilu, 2014, Todd Williams ya kuma shiga fim ɗin, don yin wasan Marcus Crowlings, tsohon abokin Soja na halin Johnson. A ranar 15 ga Afrilu, 2014, an kara Colton Haynes a cikin fim din fim din. A ranar 29 ga Afrilu, Ioan Gruffudd ya shiga cikin fim din. Gruffudd ya buga Daniel Reddick, wani attajiri mai haɓaka ƙasa wanda ke fita tare da matar da aka rabu da ita ta halin Johnson. A ranar 28 ga Mayu, Will Yun Lee ya shiga cikin 'yan wasan don taka rawar Dr. Kim Park, mai gudanar da aikin Lab na Caltech Seismology Lab a cikin fim din. A ranar 11 ga Yuni, mawaƙa da 'yar wasan Australiya Kylie Minogue sun shiga fim ɗin don yin' yar'uwar Gruffudd.  Tambaya: Wanene abokin wasan kwaikwayo na Will Yun Lee?","answer":"Kylie Minogue (Yar wasan kwaikwayo)"},{"question":"नेपाली चलचित्रको अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय मान्यताले विदेशी लगानी र सहकार्यलाई आकर्षित गर्ने उद्योगको क्षमतामा कस्तो प्रभाव पारेको छ ?","answer":"नेपाली चलचित्रको अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय मान्यताले विदेशी लगानी र सहकार्यलाई आकर्षित गर्ने उद्योगको क्षमतामा सकारात्मक प्रभाव पारेको छ । अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय फिल्म फेस्टिभलहरूमा प्रशंसाहरूले उद्योगको विश्वव्यापी स्थितिलाई बढाउँछ, सह-उत्पादन र साझेदारीको लागि ढोका खोल्छ।"},{"question":"యానాదులను చూసి మనం ఎందుకు గర్వపడాలి?","answer":"యానాదులు కష్టజీవులు. కష్టపడి బతుకుతారు. వనమూలికలు, కషాయాలతో వైద్యం చేసుకొంటారు. చిరునవ్వుతో ఆదరిస్తారు. అల్ప సంతోషులు, నిబ్బరంగా జీవిస్తారు. బాహ్య ప్రపంచానికి నీతిని నేర్పగలవారు. నేటి తరంలో యానాదులు సగౌరవంగా జీవిస్తున్నారు. వారి భాషను అభివృద్ధి చేసుకొన్నారు. విద్యావంతులయ్యారు. ఆంధ్ర దేశాభివృద్ధిలో వారూ భాగస్వాములయ్యారు. పరస్పర సహకారంతో జీవిస్తున్నారు. మన తెలుగు వారి పట్ల అభిమానంగా అందరూ నావాళ్లే అనే భావంతో ఉంటారు. సంఘశక్తిని పెంచడంలో భాగస్వాములయ్యారు. అత్యున్నత పదవులను పొందడంలో పౌరుషం, పట్టుదల, దీక్ష చూపించారు. ఇవన్నీ యానాదుల నుండి నేర్చుకొనతగినవి. గర్వించతగిన లక్షణాలు."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: \\"Gửi cho tôi cụm mật khẩu ví Pi, tôi sẽ hack hộ bạn 10.000 Pi miễn phí\\", anh Khánh nhận được đề nghị từ một tài khoản Facebook Messenger. Hai phút sau, anh tiếp tục nhận tin nhắn tương tự từ hai người lạ khác. Nghi ngờ lừa đảo, anh đăng lên một nhóm về tiền số Pi có hơn 100.000 thành viên. Dưới phần bình luận, một số người cho biết cũng nhận được tin nhắn như vậy, số ít thậm chí đã làm theo yêu cầu. \\"Tôi tò mò không rõ họ có hack được hay không nên đã đưa cụm từ khóa ví 12 ký tự. Trong ví này chưa có tiền nên tôi không lo\\", tài khoản Van Nguyen nói. \\"Nhưng không có đồng Pi nào được trả về cả\\". \\"Cụm mật khẩu\\" chính là mã khóa ví, còn gọi là cụm \\"hạt giống\\", thường gồm 12 hoặc tối đa 24 ký tự tùy chọn. Chỉ khi sắp xếp đúng, ví mới được mở khóa. Khác với mật khẩu hoặc mã PIN, người dùng không thể đặt lại hoặc khôi phục khóa của mình nếu bị mất dưới bất kỳ hình thức nào. Do vậy, việc giữ khóa an toàn và bảo mật rất quan trọng, vì mất chúng đồng nghĩa mất quyền truy cập vào tất cả các tài sản kỹ thuật số được lưu trữ trong ví đó. Pi Network hiện khởi chạy mạng chính thức (mainnet) \\"kín\\", do đó người chơi có thể chuyển Pi cho nhau qua ví trên ứng dụng từ giữa tháng 7. Còn trước đó, mạng này chỉ cung cấp ví dạng testnet, tức giao dịch thử nghiệm một lượng Pi nhất định và không có giá trị. Theo Lê Thành, quản trị viên một nhóm Pi Network có hơn 50.000 thành viên, lợi dụng một số người đã nhận được Pi về ví, kẻ gian đang tìm cách đánh cắp chúng dưới chiêu trò \\"hack giùm\\". \\"Thực chất, kẻ xấu muốn chiếm ví Pi của người dùng, sau đó chuyển hết số Pi nếu có sang ví khác\\", anh Thành giải thích. \\"Hoặc chúng cũng có thể chiếm ví trước, sau đó đợi tiền số Pi về ví để chiếm dụng\\". Theo anh, nếu lỡ cung cấp khóa ví cho kẻ gian, có hai trường hợp xảy ra. Nếu ví đã có Pi, người dùng nên nhanh chóng chuyển toàn bộ Pi sang một ví khác chưa bị lộ. Còn nếu trong ví chưa có Pi, tốt nhất nên khởi tạo một ví mới hoàn toàn. Thực tế, chiêu lừa đánh cắp mật khẩu ví khá phổ biến trong lĩnh vực tiền điện tử. Các chuyên gia khuyến cáo người dùng nên ghi cụm từ ra giấy và cất giữ cẩn thận. Một số có thói quen lưu trên trình duyệt, nền tảng đám mây hoặc trên máy tính, nhưng sẽ đối mặt với nguy cơ bị đánh cắp nếu chẳng may bị hacker tấn công. Hiện nay, tiền ảo Pi chưa có giá trị cụ thể và cộng đồng này chủ yếu định giá Pi dựa trên sự \\"đồng thuận\\", tức người mua và bán tự quy ước với nhau về giá trị của Pi và trao đổi hàng hóa tương ứng. Thời gian gần đây, một số cũng khoe đã mua được hàng hóa bằng Pi, dù giao dịch bằng tiền ảo tại Việt Nam chưa được pháp luật công nhận. Pi Network rộ lên từ năm 2019, được quảng cáo là \\"sở hữu tiền ảo mà không mất gì\\". Người dùng sau khi tải ứng dụng, mỗi ngày sẽ vào bấm điểm danh để nhận Pi. Ứng dụng từng nhiều lần nằm trong danh sách tải nhiều tại Việt Nam. Theo công bố hồi cuối tháng 6, dự án có hơn 35 triệu người dùng trên toàn cầu. Bảo Lâm","answer":"Đánh cắp ví tiền ảo Pi bằng chiêu 'hack giúp'"},{"question":"من هو النبي الذي سمي بخاتم الأنبياء؟","answer":"– النبي محمد صلى الله عليه وسلم."},{"question":"Улуу Турк кагандыгы качан түзүлгөн ?","answer":"Улуу Турк кагандыгы 552-жылдары түзүлгөн"},{"question":"வினா: உலகிலேயே  ஆழமான ஆழி எது?","answer":"விடை: மரியானா ஆழி"},{"question":"Байымбек Абдрахман уулу эмнеге “Тоголок Молдо” болуп калган.","answer":"Байымбет 18 жашка келгенде Музооке дүйнөдөн кайтат. Бул жоготуу чөбүрөгөн жетимдерди дагы кыйын күнгө дуушар кылат. Аргасы кетенде «эптеп кун өтөөр бекен» деген ой менен, Байымбет Жумгалдагы таякесиникине барып жашап, андан кийин Чуй өрөөнүндөгү «Жаңы Чек» айлына келип ар кимге жалданып, иштей баштайт. Токмок шаарындагы орус, дунган жана кыргыздардын байларына жалчы жүрдү, алардын оор жумуштарын аткарды. Он жыл чамалуу Чүйдө туруп агартуучулук, эмчилик, акындык, ишмердигинөркүндөтөт. Оокаттары тынып Тоголок Молдо Курткадагы туугандарына кайра көчүп барат. Ал Курткага келген кыргыздын жана казактын ырчыларына аралашат. Ошол кезде кыргыз айылдарында сапаттуу кат тааныган адамдарды «Молдо» деп аташчу. Байымбет чарчы бойлуу тогологураак келген жигит болгон. Анын ышкыбоздуулугун баамдаган манасчыТыныбек: «өзү тоголок, кат тааныган, сапаттуу экен. Муну «Тоголок Молдо» десе болот дейт. Мына ошол кундон баштап Байымбет -Тоголок Молдо аталып калат."},{"question":"ලොව ප්‍රථම ෆෝමියුලා වන් තරඟාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහකයා කවුද?","answer":"ලොව ප්‍රථම ෆෝමියුලා වන් තරඟාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහකයා වූයේ ඉතාලි ජාතික ෆෝමියුලා වන් කණ්ඩායමක් වූ ඇල්ෆා රෝමියෝ කණ්ඩායමෙන් තරඟ වැදි ඉතාලි ජාතික ජූසුප්පෙ ෆරිනායි."},{"question":"குமரகுருபரன் என்ற திங்கள் இதழை நடத்தும் மடம் எது?","answer":"குமரகுருபரன் என்ற திங்கள் இதழை நடத்தும் மடம் திருப்பனந்தாள் காசிமடம்."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Thói quen ăn uống \\"phá nát\\" dạ dày nhiều người Việt thường mắc phải","answer":"Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/thoi-quen-an-uong-pha-nat-da-day-nhieu-nguoi-viet-thuong-mac-phai-13...Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/thoi-quen-an-uong-pha-nat-da-day-nhieu-nguoi-viet-thuong-mac-phai-1382644.ngn "},{"question":"\\"මිනිසාමයි ලොව දෙවියන් වන්නේ\\" ගීතයේ මුල් ගායකයා කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"\\"මිනිසාමයි ලොව දෙවියන් වන්නේ\\" ගීතයේ මුල් ගායකයා මොහිදින් බෙග් මහතා ය."},{"question":"ما هو اسم العملة الرسمية في اليابان؟","answer":"العملة الرسمية في اليابان هي الين الياباني"},{"question":"🎶Эл сүйгөн обондордон \\"Махабатым\\"-ырынын сөзү кайсы? 🎧","answer":"🎧МАХАБАТЫМ 🎶Сөзү А.Кожокуловдуку,обону Т.БектеновдукуТатына жылмаясың,Талпынтып ыр канатын.Байланып кирпигиңе,Бакыттай бир карашын. Кайырма:Махабатым, махабатым,Гүл болуп ыргаласың.Күн болуп нурданасың,Жашоодо жакшы обондой.Тармал чач, мөл булагым,Тамчыдан көл курадың.Кумарлуу көл жээгинде,Кубанып мен турамын.Сен үчүн жандырамын,Сезимдин шам чырагын.Ыйбалуу наздыгыңды,Ырыма калтырамын."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة هجاء من بحر الطويل. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"وَفى بِمَواعيدِ الخَليطِ وَأَخلَفواوَكَم وَعَدوا القَلبَ المُعَنّى وَلَم يَفواوَما ضَرَّهُم أَن لَم يَجودوا بِمُقنِعٍمِنَ النَيلِ إِذ مَنَّوا قَليلاً وَسَوَّفواأَفي كُلِّ يَومٍ لَفتَةٌ ثُمَّ عَبرَةٌعَلى رَسمِ دارٍ أَو مَطيٌّ مُوَقَّفُوَرَكبٍ عَلى الأَكوارِ يَثني رِقابَهُملِداعي الصِبا عَهدٌ قَديمٌ وَمَألَفُفَمِن واجِدٍ قَد أَلزَمَ القَلبَ كَفَّهُوَمِن طَرَبٍ يَعلو اليَفاعَ وَيُشرِفُوَمُستَعبِرٍ قَد أَتبَعَ الدَمعَ زَفرَةًتَكادُ لَها عوجُ الضُلوعِ تَثَقَّفُقَضى ما قَضى مِن أَنَّةِ الشَوقِ وَاِنثَنىبِدارِ الجَوى وَالقَلبُ يَهفو وَيَرجُفُوَلَم تُغنِ حَتّى زايَلَ البُعدُ بَينَناوَحَتّى رَمانا الأَزلَمُ المُتَغَطرِفُكَأَنَّ اللَيالي كُنَّ آلَينَ حَلفَةًبِأَن لا يُرى فيهِنَّ شَملٌ مُؤَلَّفُأَلَمَّ خَيالُ العامِريَّةِ بَعدَماتَبَطَّنَنا جَفنٌ مِنَ اللَيلِ أَوطَفُيُحَيِّي طِلاحاً حينَ هَمّوا بِوَقعَةٍتَهاوَوا عَلى الأَذقانِ مِمّا تَعَسَّفواوَقيذينَ قَد مالَ النُعاسُ بِهامِهِمكَما أَرعَشَت أَيدي المُعاطينَ قَرقَفُأَعاريبَ لا يَدرونَ ما الريفُ بِالفَلاوَلا يَغبِطونَ القَومَ إِمّا تَرَيَّفوارَذايا هَوىً إِن عَنَّ بَرقٌ تَطاوَلواوَإِن عارَضوا الطَيرَ الغَوادي تَعَيَّفواتَوارِكَ لِلشَقِّ الَّذي هُوَ آمِنٌنَوازِلَ بِالأَرضِ الَّتي هِيَ أَخوَفُأَيا وَقفَةَ التَوديعِ هَل فيكِ راجِعٌإِشارَتَهُ ذاكَ البَنانُ المُطَرَّفُوَهَل مُطمِعي ذاكَ الغَزالُ بِلَفتَةٍوَإِن ثَوَّرَ الرَكبُ العِجالَ وَأَوجَفواعَشيَّةَ لا يَنفَكُّ لَحظٌ مُبَهَّتٌمُراقَبَةً مِنّا وَدَمعٌ مُكَفكَفُفَلِلَّهِ مَن غَنّى الحُداةُ وَراءَهُوَلِلَّهِ ما وارى العَبيطُ المُسَجَّفُوَسائِلَةٍ عَنّي كَأَنِّيَ لَم أَلِجحِمى قَومِها وَاليَومُ بِالنَقعِ مُسدِفُلَئِن كُنتُ مَجهولاً بِذُلِّيَ في الهَوىفَإِنّي بِعِزّي عِندَ غَيرِكِ أَعرَفُفَلا تَعجَبي أَنّي تَعَرَّقَني الضَنىفَإِنَّ الهَوى يَقوى عَلَيَّ وَأَضعُفُيُقَرَّعُ بِاِسمي الجَيشُ ثُمَّ يَرُدُّنيإِلى طاعَةِ الحَسناءِ قَلبٌ مُكَلَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَنغَلُّ في لَهَواتِهاوَفَحلُ الرَدى دوني بِنابَيهِ يَصرُفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَحمِل عَلى الضيمِ ساعِديوَقَد ثُلِمَ الماضي وَرُضَّ المُثَقَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَثنِ الأَعِنَّةَ ظافِراًتُحَدِّثُ عَن يَومي نِزارٌ وَخِندِفُوَحَيٍّ تَخَطَّت بي أَعَزَّ بُيوتِهِصُدورُ المَواضي وَالوَشيجُ المُرَعَّفُسَلي بي أَلَم أَصبِر عَلى الظَمءِ بَعدَماهَوى بِالمَهاري نَفنَفٌ ثُمَّ نَفنَفُوَكُلُّ غُلامٍ مِلءُ دِرعَيهِ نَجدَةٌوَلَوثَةُ أَعرابيَّةٍ وَتَغَطرُفُعَلى كُلِّ طاوٍ فيهِ جَدٌّ وَمَيعَةٌوَطاوِيَةٍ فيها هِبابٌ وَعَجرَفُوَقَد أُتبِعَت سُمرُ العَوالي زِجاجَهاوَحَنَّ مِنَ الإِنباضِ جَزعٌ مُعَطَّفُفَإِن تَسمَعوا صَوتَ المُرِنّاتِ تَعلَموابِمَن جَعَلَت تَدعو النَواعي وَتَهتُفُلَنا الدَولَةُ الغَرّاءُ ما زالَ عِندَهامِنَ الجَورِ واقٍ أَو مِنَ الظُلمِ مُنصِفُبَعيدَةُ صَوتٍ في العُلى غَيرُ رافِعٍبِها صَوتَهُ المَظلومُ وَالمُتَحَيَّفُوَنَحنُ أَعَزُّ الناسِ شَرقاً وَمَغرِباًوَأَكرَمُ أَبصارٍ عَلى الأَرضِ تَطرِفُبَنو كُلِّ فَيّاضِ اليَدَينِ مِنَ النَدىإِذا جادَ أَلغى ما يَقولُ المُعَنِّفُوَكُلِّ مُحَيّاً بِالسَلامِ مُعَظَّمٍكَثيرٍ إِلَيهِ الناظِرُ المُتَشَوِّفُوَأَبيَضَ بَسّامٍ كَأَنَّ جَبينَهُسَنا قَمَرٍ أَو بارِقٌ مُتَكَشِّفُحَيِيٌّ فَإِن سيمَ الهَوانَ رَأَيتَهُيَشُدُّ وَلا ماضي الغِرارَينِ مُرهَفُلَنا الجَبَهاتُ المُستَنيراتُ في العُلىإِذا اِلتَثَمَ الأَقوامُ ذُلّاً وَأَغدَفواأَبونا الَّذي أَبدى بِصِفّينَ سَيفَهُضُغاءَ اِبنِ هِندٍ وَالقَنا يَتَقَصَّفُوَمِن قَبلِ ما أَبلى بِبَدرٍ وَغَيرَهاوَلا مَوقِفٍ إِلّا لَهُ فيهِ مَوقِفُوَرِثنا رَسولَ اللَهِ عُلويَّ مَجدِهِوَمُعظَمُ ما ضَمَّ الصَفا وَالمُعَرَّفُوَعِندَ رِجالٍ أَنَّ جُلَّ تُراثِهِقَضيبٌ مُحَلّىً أَو رِداءٌ مُفَوَّفُيُريدونَ أَن نُلقي إِلَيهِم أَكُفَّناوَمِن دَمِنا أَيديهِمُ الدَهرَ تَنطِفُفَلِلَّهِ ما أَقسى ضَمائِرَ قَومِنالَقَد جاوَزوا حَدَّ العُقوقِ وَأَسرَفوايَضَنّونَ أَن نُعطى نَصيباً مِنَ العُلاوَقَد عالَجوا دَينَ العُلى وَتَسَلَّفواوَهَذا أَبي الأَدنى الَّذي تَعرِفونَهُمُقَدَّمُ مَجدٍ أَوَّلٌ وَمُخَلَّفُمُؤَلِّفُ ما بَينَ المُلوكِ إِذا هَفَواوَأَشفَوا عَلى حَزِّ الرِقابِ وَأَشرَفواإِذا قالَ رُدّوا غارِبَ الحِلمِ راجَعواوَإِن قالَ مَهلاً بَعضَ ذا الجَدِّ وَقَّفواوَبِالأَمسِ لَمّا صالَ قادِرُ مُلكِهِموَأَعرَضَ مِنهُ الجانِبُ المُتَخَوَّفُتَلافاهُ حَتّى سامَحَ الضَغنَ قَلبُهُوَأَسمَحَ لَمّا قيلَ لا يَتَأَلَّفُوَكانَ وَليُّ العَقدِ وَالعَهدِ بَينَهُوَبَينَ بَهاءِ المُلكِ يَسعى وَيَلطُفُوَلَمّا اِلتَقى نَجوى عُقَيلٍ لِنَبوَةٍوَمَدَّ لَهُم حَبلاً مِنَ الغَدرِ مُحصَفُلَوى عِطفَهُ لَيَّ القَنيِّ رِقابَهُموَلَو لِسِواهُ اِستَعطَفوا ما تَعَطَّفواوَسَل مُضَراً لَمّا سَما لِدِيارِهافَهَبَّ وَنامَ العاجِزُ المُتَضَعَّفُتَوَلَّجَها كَالسَيلِ صُلحاً وَعَنوَةًفَأَبقى وَرَدَّ البيضَ ظَمأى تَلَهَّفُلَهُ وَقَفاتٌ بَالحَجيجِ شُهودُهاإِلى عَقِبِ الدُنيا مِنىً وَالمُخَيَّفُوَمِن مَأثُراتٍ غَيرَ هاتيكَ لَم تَزَللَها عُنُقٌ عالٍ عَلى الناسِ مُشرِفُحَمى فاهُ عَن بُسطِ المُلوكِ وَقَد كَبَتعَلَيها جِباهٌ مِن رِجالٍ وَآنُفُزِمامُ عُلاً لَو غَيرُهُ رامَ جَرَّهُلَساقَ بِهِ حادٍ مِنَ الذُلِّ مُعنِفُجَرى ما جَرى قَبلي وَها أَنا خَلفَهُإِلى الأَمَدِ الأَقصى أُغِذُّ وَأوجِفُوَلَولا مُراعاةُ الأُبوَّةِ جُزتُهُوَلَكِن لِغَيرِ العَجزِ ما أَتَوَقَّفُحَذَفتُ فُضولَ العَيشِ حَتّى رَدَدتُهاإِلى دونِ ما يَرضى بِهِ المُتَعَفِّفُوَأَمَّلتُ أَن أَجري خَفيفاً إِلى العُلىإِذا شِئتُمُ أَن تَلحَقوا فَتَخَفَّفواحَلَفتُ بِرَبِّ البُدنِ تَدمى نُحورُهاوَبِالنَفَرِ الأَطوارِ لَبّوا وَعَرَّفوالَأَبتَذِلَنَّ النَفسَ حَتّى أَصونَهاوَغَيرِيَ في قَيدٍ مِنَ الذُلِّ يَرسُفُفَقَد طالَما ضَيَّعتُ في العَيشِ فُرصَةًوَهَل يَنفَعُ المَلهوفُ ما يَتَلَهَّفُوَإِنَّ قَوافي الشِعرِ ما لَم أَكُن لَهامُسَفسَفَةٌ فيها عَتيقٌ وَمُقرِفُأَنا الفارِسُ الوَثّابُ في صَهَواتِهاوَكُلُّ مُجيدٍ جاءَ بَعدِيَ مُردَفُ"},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa:An haifi Malam Aliyu Hammari a cikin garin Gombe a watan  Satumba 1984, a nan kuma jihar ya fara karatun addinin musulunci a wajen kakansa Sarkin Malamai Abubakar Baffa wanda ya dade da rasuwa, nan ya yi karatun Al-Kur'ani da wasu littafan Fiqhu. A hannun kakan nasa ya yi karatun littafan Kawa'idi da Ahlari kamar matakin nazire kenan, daga nan aka kai su makarantar da 'ya'yan kowa ke zuwa, wato makarantar Alhaji Umaru Tudun Wada da ke cikin garin Gombe, wajen Alaramma Yakubu Bara a nan suka sauke Al-Kur'ani mai tsarki. Daga nan shi ma ya ce ya kamata su matsa wata makarantar da ta fi wadda yake koyar da su, ya ba su zabin makarantu guda uku; Daga bisani aka daidaita kan su tafi makarantar Malam Abu Waile Kole, a hannunsa ya yi kashi 70 cikin 100 na littafa addini, wasu karance-karancen na da'awa da wa'azi a wajen Malam Muhammadu Basakkwace ya yi. Bangaren Tafsir wajen Murshid Usman Baba Liman da Malam Dahiru Isa Bolari. A bangaren karatun boko ya yi karatun firamaren a makarantar Karangara a cikin Gombe da karamar sakandare makarantar Pilot, sai babbar sakandare da ya yi a makarantar kimiyya da fasaha ta Gombe, sai ya yi Difloma a makarantar Legal inda ya karanci fannin Shari'a, daga nan jami'ar Maiduguri ya karanta Shari'a and Public Law, sai makarantar koyon aikin Lauya a Yola da ke jihar Adamawa. A shekarar 2019 aka tabbatar da shi a matsayin Lauya, ya sake komawa jami'ar Maiduguri inda ya ke yin digiri na biyu duk dai a fannin shari'a. Malam Aliyu ya ce baya ga kasar Saudiyya ya na fatan kai ziyara wasu kasashen da suka shafi aikin lauyanci, saboda ana amfani da dokokin Birtaniya, don haka burinsa ya je kasar Birtaniya inda zai gano ainahin tushen inda aka kafa dokokin da ake amfani Najeriya. Malamin ya ce ya sha wuya a bangaren karatun Alkurani saboda hadda ake son yi, shi kuma ba inda ya ba shi wuya kenan. ''Akwai bambanci sosai da koyarwar lokacinmu, domin mun sha bulala idan muka gagara ba da hadda amma duk da hakan, Alhamdulillah saboda mun yi karatu mai inganci. Sai kuma lokacin da muna makarantar koyon aikin Lauya, akwai abin da ake kira Presentaion, wato tsayawa gaban mutane ka yi bayani a kan wani maudu'i da aka bukaci ku yi bincike a kai, nan ma na sha wuya domin kusan kullum sai an yi. Lokacin da aka sanar da cewa na tsallake wannan siradin ba karamin farin ciki na yi ba,'' in ji Malamin. Malam Aliyu Hammari ya ce ya na jin dadin karanta Suratu Maryam, har ta kai ya na yawan karatanta a matsayin karatun sallah, sannan ta dauki hankalinsa saboda tattaro addinai guda biyu, wato addinin Musulunci da na Kirista.","answer":"Tabbas, ga kanun labarai don rubutun da aka bayar - Ku San Malamanku tare da Malam Aliyu Hammari Walama"},{"question":"સ્મિથેરેન્સ ગીતનો સારાંશ આપો.","answer":"સ્મિથેરેન્સ એ એક પોપ ગીત છે જે જોજી દ્વારા આવેલ છે. આ ગીત તેમના એલ્બમ \\"નેક્ટર\\" માટે બનાવવામાં આવ્યો છે અને તેમના સંગીતમાં વ્યક્તિગત ભાવનાઓ અને અનુભવોને સારીરીતે પ્રસ્તુત કરવામાં આવ્યો છે.ગીતમાં, સ્મિથેરેન્સ તેમના એક પ્રેમના ભાગ પર આધાર રાખે છે, જેમણે તે પ્રેમનો અનુભવ કરવાનો વર્ણન કરે છે. ગીતમાં તે વિવિધ ભાવનાઓનો અભિવ્યક્તિ કરતાં તમારા પ્રિયતમના પ્રતિનિધિ બનવાની ઇચ્છા સાથે જોજી પરસ્પરના અને ભાવનાત્મક વાતચીત્રોનો સંકલન પ્રદાન કરે છે.ગીતનો સાઉન્ડ વાંછનાને સુસંગતિથી બનાવવામાં આવે છે, જે શ્રાવકોને એક અનેકમોડની અનુભવાનો મૌકો આપે છે.સ્મિથેરેન્સ એ જોજીની વ્યક્તિગતતા અને વિચારશીલતાનો એક સુંદર પ્રતિષ્ઠાન પ્રદાન કરતો છે અને ગાયન, સંગીત, અને ગીતકારીના ક્ષેત્રે જોજીની સાકારાત્મકતાને ઉજાગર કરવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"\\"Ny fifanolanana ara-pahasalamana sy teknolojia dia niteraka fiakaran'ny sehatry ny fahasalamana nomerika. Ireo fitaovana azo ampiasaina, fampiharana ara-pahasalamana ary telemedicine dia manova ny fandefasana fitsaboana. Ity fanovana nomerika ity dia misy fiantraikany amin'ny fikarakarana ny marary, ny etika ara-pitsaboana ary ny fiarovana ny data.\\"","answer":"Ny lohahevitra tamin'ny andalana teo aloha dia ny Fahasalamam-pahasalamana nomerika sy fahasalamana"},{"question":"¿Cuál es la pregunta de: \\"\\"Black Velvet\\" es un verso de blues con un coro de rock escrito por los compositores canadienses Christopher Ward y David Tyson, grabado por la cantante y compositora canadiense Alannah Myles.\\"? El tema es Black Velvet (canción).","answer":"\\"¿Quién escribió y grabó Black Velvet?\\""},{"question":"Simba avy hatrany ve ny nify aorian'ny fihinanana siramamy?","answer":"Tsia, mazàna mipoitra mandritra ny fotoana maharitra ny fahasimban'ny nify aorian'ny fihinanana siramamy tsy tapaka."},{"question":"อัลลอฮุอักบัร เป็นภาษาอะไร มีความหมายว่าอะไร","answer":"อัลลอฮุอักบัรเป็นภาษาอาหรับ แปลว่า \\"อัลลอฮ์ (พระเจ้า) ผู้ทรงยิ่งใหญ่ที่สุด\\""},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ചോദ്യം:\\"റോമിയോ ആൻഡ് ജൂലിയറ്റ്\\" എന്ന നാടകം എഴുതിയത് ആരാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: റോമിയോ ആൻഡ് ജൂലിയറ്റ് നാടകം എഴുതിയത് ഷേക്സ്പിയറാണ്. ശത്രുക്കളായിക്കഴിയുന്ന രണ്ട് കുടുംബങ്ങളില്പ്പെട്ട റോമിയോയുടേയും ജൂലിയറ്റിന്റെയും പ്രേമവും, അവരുടെ അകാല മരണവും, അതിനേത്തുടർന്ന് അവരുടെ കുടുംബങ്ങൾ ഐക്യപ്പെടുന്നതുമാണ് ഇതിന്റെ കഥ. ഷേക്സ്പിയറിന്റെ ജീവിതകാലത്ത് ഏറ്റവും പ്രശസ്തി നേടിയ അദ്ദേഹത്തിന്റെ നാടകങ്ങളിലൊന്നാണിത്. റോമിയോ ആന്റ് ജൂലിയറ്റ്, ഹാംലറ്റ് എന്നിവയാണ് അരങ്ങിൽ ഏറ്റവുമധികം അവതരിപ്പിക്കപ്പെടുന്ന ഷേക്സ്പിയർ നാടകങ്ങൾ."},{"question":"வினா: அகநானூற்றில் பாடல் தொடரால் பெயர் பெற்ற புலவர்கள் யாவர்?","answer":"விடை:நோய்பாடியார், ஊட்டியார்"},{"question":" Sheeg Nabi Ismaaciil (CS) meesha uu ku aasan yahay?","answer":" Nabi Ismaaciil (CS) wuxu ku aasan yahay magaalada Makkah."},{"question":"السؤال: شيء يلبس قبعة على الرغم من عدم وجود رأس له، ما هو؟","answer":"الإجابة: الزجاجة (وغطاء الزجاجة)."},{"question":"స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం మధ్యగల సంబంధాన్ని గురించి వివరించండి.","answer":"వ్యక్తులకు గల స్వేచ్ఛ – సమానత్వాలపైనే రాజకీయ వ్యవస్థ విజయం ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది. రాజనీతి శాస్త్ర అధ్యయనంలో ఈ రెండు అంశాలు విశేషమైన ప్రాముఖ్యతను సంతరించుకొన్నాయి. వ్యక్తులు తమ సర్వ సమగ్రమైన అభివృద్ధి కోసం స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వాలను వాంఛిస్తారు.స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం మధ్య సంబంధం: స్వేచ్ఛ సమానత్వం మధ్యగల సంబంధం గురించి రాజనీతి తత్త్వవేత్తలు రెండు భిన్న అభిప్రాయాలను వెల్లడించారు. ఆ రెండింటి భావనలు రాజనీతిశాస్త్రం అధ్యయనంలో ముఖ్యమైనవిగా వారు అంగీకరించారు. అయితే కొందరు ఆ రెండింటి మధ్య సంబంధం ఉందని పేర్కొనగా, మరికొందరు అవి ఒకదానికొకటి వ్యతిరేకమైనవిగా పరిగణించారు.స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం పరస్పర సంబంధం కలిగి ఉంటాయనే భావనను రాజనీతి తత్త్వవేత్తలైన రూసో, టానీ, లాస్కీ, జి.డి. హెచ్. కోల్ వంటివారు ప్రతిపాదించారు. ఇక స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం అనేది పరస్పర వ్యతిరేకమైన భావనలని పేర్కొన్న వారిలో లార్డ్ మాధ్యూ, ఆర్నార్డ్, లార్డ్ ఆక్టన్, డి టాక్విల్లీ వంటి రాజనీతితత్వవేత్తలు ఉన్నారు. పైన పేర్కొన్న రెండు వాదనల గురించి కింది విధంగా తెలపడమైంది.1) స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం పరస్పర పోషకాలు:వ్యక్తి శ్రేయోవాదులు, అరాచకవాదులు, కమ్యూనిస్టుల దృష్టిలో స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం పరస్పర పోషకాలు.సమానత్వం లేని స్వేచ్ఛ అర్థరహితం, ‘సమానత్వం’ నెలకొల్పబడిన తరువాతే స్వేచ్ఛను గురించి ఆలోచించాలని కమ్యూనిస్టులు భావిస్తారు.సక్రమమైన, ఆదర్శమైన రాజ్యం స్థాపించబడాలంటే తప్పనిసరిగా సమానత్వ ప్రాతిపదికగా ప్రజలకు స్వేచ్ఛను ప్రసాదించాలి. ఈ రెండు విస్తృత పరిధిలో చూడబడాలి.స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం – ఈ రెండింటిలో దేన్నీ త్యాగం చేయడానికి ప్రయత్నించరాదు. సమానత్వం, స్వేచ్ఛ లోపించినట్లయితే అరాచకత్వం ప్రబలుతుంది. కావున ప్రభుత్వం శాసనాల ద్వారా ప్రజలందరికి ఎటువంటి జాతి, మత, కుల, వర్గ, వర్ణ, లింగ భేదము లేకుండా సమానంగా ‘స్వేచ్ఛను’ ప్రసాదించాలి.రాజకీయ స్వేచ్ఛ ద్వారా భావ ప్రకటనా స్వాతంత్ర్యం, ఓటుహక్కు, అర్హత ప్రాతిపదికగా పదవులకు పోటీచేసే హక్కు లభిస్తాయి. సాంఘిక, ఆర్థిక, రాజకీయ సమానత్వాలను ప్రజలందరూ కలిగి ఉండాలంటే వారందరూ స్వేచ్ఛను పొంది ఉండాలి. అందువలనే స్వేచ్ఛ లేకుండా సమానత్వం, సమానత్వం లేకుండా స్వేచ్ఛ ఉండవు.ఏ రాజ్యంలో ప్రజలు ఆర్థిక, సాంఘిక, రాజకీయ రంగాలలో స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వాలను సమానంగా పొంది ఉంటారో ఆ రాజ్యం బహుముఖంగా త్వరితగతిన అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుందని పరిశీలకులు భావిస్తారు.2) స్వేచ్ఛ-సమానత్వాలు పరస్పర విరుద్ధాలు: స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం పరస్పర శత్రువులు అని పేర్కొన్న వారిలో లార్డ్ ఆక్టన్ ముఖ్యుడు. రాజ్యముగాని, వ్యక్తులుగాని సమానత్వానికి ఎక్కువ ప్రాధాన్యతనిస్తే స్వేచ్ఛ మరుగున పడిపోతుంది అని ఆక్టన్ మహాశయుడు వాదిస్తాడు. ‘మితిమీరని ప్రభుత్వ పరిపాలననే స్వేచ్ఛ’ అని సీలీ మహాశయుడు పేర్కొన్నాడు. ప్రభుత్వ అధికారాలు మితిమీరడమంటే ప్రజలు తమ స్వేచ్ఛాస్వాతంత్ర్యాలను కోల్పోవటమేనని వీరు భావిస్తారు. ప్రజల వ్యక్తిగత వ్యవహారాలలో, కార్యకలాపాలలో ప్రభుత్వము జోక్యం కల్పించుకోరాదు అని ఆక్టన్ అభిప్రాయం. ప్రజలందరికి ఆర్థిక స్వేచ్ఛను ప్రసాదించినట్లయితే శక్తిసామర్థ్యాలు, తెలివితేటలు, విద్యా పరిజ్ఞానం కలిగినవారు అపారమైన సంపదను కూడబెడితే, అమాయకులు, నిరక్షరాస్యులు, సోమరిపోతులు తమతమ కనీస అవసరాలను కూడా సమకూర్చుకోలేరు. ఇది సమాజములో ఆర్థిక అసమానత్వానికి, వర్గతత్వానికి దారితీస్తుంది. కావున స్వేచ్ఛ-సమానత్వం పరస్పరం శతృ సంబంధాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటాయి. “ఎక్కడ స్వేచ్ఛ ఉంటుందో, అక్కడ సమానత్వం ఉండదు. ఎక్కడ సమానత్వం ఉంటుందో, అక్కడ స్వేచ్ఛ ఉండదు. స్వేచ్ఛ-సమానత్వం రెండు కత్తుల వంటివి. అవి ఒక ఒరలో ఇమడవు” అని ‘లార్డ్ ఆక్టివ్’, ‘డి టాక్వెల్లీ’, ‘సీలీ’ మొదలగు రాజనీతిజ్ఞులు వాదిస్తారు.పైన పేర్కొన్న రెండు రకాల వాదనలు పూర్తిగా నిజమైనవికావు. వాస్తవ అంశం ఆ రెండింటికీ మధ్య ఉంటుంది. స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వాలు రెండూ ఒకదానికొకటి పరస్పర పోషక, పరస్పర వ్యతిరేక స్వభావాన్ని కలిగి ఉండవు. ఈ సందర్భంలో ఆ రెండు భావనల మధ్య ఉండే వాస్తవిక సంబంధాన్ని క్రింది విధంగా వివరించడమైంది.సమానత్వానికి స్వేచ్ఛ అవసరం:i) స్వేచ్ఛ అంటే నిరపేక్షమైనదికాదు. దానికి కొన్ని పరిమితులు ఉంటాయి. కొన్ని నిబంధనలకు లోబడి సామాజిక సంక్షేమాన్ని సాధించేందుకై ఈ స్వేచ్ఛ అందరికీ అందుబాటులో ఉంటుంది.ii) స్వేచ్ఛ అంటే ఏ ఒక్కవ్యక్తి లేదా వ్యక్తుల సముదాయపు గుత్తాధికారంగా భావించరాదు.iii) ఒకానొక వ్యక్తి స్వేచ్ఛను అనుభవించడమనేది ఇతరులకు స్వేచ్ఛకు భంగం కలిగించేదిగా ఉండకూడదనే ఈ సూత్రాన్ని ఆమోదించారు. సమానత్వ సూత్రాన్ని గౌరవించవలసి ఉంటుంది. దాని అర్థం స్వేచ్ఛా ఫలాలు సమానత్వమనే వృక్షానికి చెందిన శాఖలలో ఉంటాయని పేర్కొనవచ్చు. కాబట్టి స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వాలు ఒకదానికొకటి పరస్పర పోషకాలుగా భావించడమైంది. సమానత్వ సూత్రం ఆధారంగా స్వేచ్ఛను వర్తింపజేస్తే, స్వేచ్ఛాలక్ష్యం వాస్తవానికి నెరవేరినట్లవుతుంది.స్వేచ్ఛకు సమానత్వం అవసరం: సమానత్వం అంటే ఒకే విధమైన ఆదరణ అని అర్థం కాదు. ఎందుకంటే అటువంటి సమానత్వం పౌర సమాజంలో సాధ్యంకాదు. అందుకు బదులుగా ఒకేరకమైన పరిస్థితులలో సమానమైన ఆదరణయే సమానత్వంగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు. పౌర సమాజంలో కొందరు ఇతరులతో సమానమైన హోదాను కలిగి ఉండరు. అయితే వారికి తమ వ్యక్తిత్వం, హోదాలను పెంపొందించుకొనేందుకై కొన్ని పరిస్థితులు, అవకాశాలను కల్పించాల్సిన అవసరం ఎంతైనా ఉంది. ప్రజలందరూ సమానంగా ఉన్నప్పుడు స్వేచ్ఛా, ఫలాలను వారందరూ అనుభవిస్తారని చెప్పవచ్చు.పైన పేర్కొన్న విధంగా స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం ఒకదానికొకటి పరస్పర పోషకాలుగా ఉంటాయి. ఆ రెండు భావనలు ఒకే ఉమ్మడి లక్ష్యాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటాయి. సమానత్వాన్ని విస్మరించినందునే స్వేచ్ఛ అనే అరాచకం, నియంతృత్వాలకు దారితీస్తుంది. అట్లాగే స్వేచ్ఛను పట్టించుకోకుండా, సమానత్వానికి ప్రాధాన్యత ఇస్తే, బానిసత్వం ఏర్పడే ప్రమాదం ఉంది. కాబట్టి వ్యక్తి, సమాజాల ఔన్నత్యానికి ఆ రెండు భావనలు ఆవశ్యకమైనవిగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు."},{"question":"Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: Sau Bỉ vỏ của nhà văn Nguyên Hồng, Thương nhớ mười hai của nhà văn Vũ Bằng, Tủ sách Văn chương và Mỹ thuật vừa trở lại bằng việc ra mắt ấn phẩm Gió đầu mùa & Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường của nhà văn Thạch Lam. Những áng văn ấn tượng nhất của Thạch Lam lần này có sự góp mặt của họa sĩ đương đại Đào Hải Phong, mang tới cho độc giả một cảm xúc mới, khi hội họa đồng hành cùng văn học. Nhà văn Thạch Lam (1910-1942) nổi tiếng trong nền văn học Việt Nam với những tác phẩm như Hai đứa trẻ, Nắng trong vườn, Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường, Gió đầu mùa… Chọn Gió đầu mùa - tập truyện ngắn và Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường - tập tùy bút nổi tiếng của nhà văn Thạch Lam, Đông A và Nhà xuất bản Văn học đã xếp chung trong một tập sách với tựa đề Gió đầu mùa & Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường. Trong ấn phẩm này, phần văn bản của tập truyện ngắn Gió đầu mùa được thực hiện theo bản in lần đầu năm 1937 của Nhà xuất bản Đời Nay, với Lời tựa do nhà văn Khái Hưng viết. Còn phần văn bản của tùy bút Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường được thực hiện theo bản in đầu tiên năm 1943 của Nhà xuất bản Đời Nay, cũng do Khái Hưng viết lời tựa. Vẽ minh họa cho các tác phẩm văn học nổi tiếng luôn là một thử thách với các họa sĩ đương đại, nhất là họa sĩ quen bảng màu, giá vẽ. Văn chương Thạch Lam càng có vẻ khó hơn. Bởi như Gió đầu mùa hay Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường vốn đầy ắp hình ảnh và mang nét duyên dáng rất riêng, vừa thâm trầm sâu lắng, vừa ý nhị, nhẹ nhàng. Hơn thế, đã có rất nhiều họa sĩ vẽ về Hà Nội và để lại dấu ấn sâu đậm trong người xem. Họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong được mời minh họa cho ấn phẩm lần này. Khi thấy họa sĩ nhận lời vẽ minh họa Gió đầu mùa và Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường, nhiều người nghĩ anh \\"liều\\". Bởi trong hội họa Việt Nam đương đại, họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong đã xây dựng một phong cách riêng với cách sử dụng màu sắc đầy ấn tượng. Thế nhưng, với lời mời này, họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong xem nó vừa như một cơ duyên nhưng đồng thời là một thử thách thú vị. Nếu trước đó, với Bỉ vỏ của nhà văn Nguyên Hồng, họa sĩ Hoàng Phượng Vỹ đã tạo được ấn tượng thẩm mỹ tốt, khi anh vắt kiệt sức mình trong một thời điểm để vẽ minh họa thì với bộ minh họa trong Gió đầu mùa & Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường, họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong dường như đã tìm lại được mình. Họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong cho biết, anh thực hiện các bức minh họa này trong thời gian giãn cách xã hội vì đại dịch Covid-19. Họa sĩ xem đây là cơ duyên, là may mắn khi được cùng nhà văn Thạch Lam xuất hiện trên cùng một cuốn sách. \\"Văn chương Thạch Lam có sự gần gũi, tương đồng với quan niệm nghệ thuật của tôi… Tôi vẽ những bức minh họa này bằng bột màu, là chất liệu đã làm nên tên tuổi của tôi những năm 90 của thế kỷ trước. Tôi có cảm giác nhà văn Thạch Lam gợi lại cho tôi những gì đã là giá trị của tôi, những gì mộc mạc, nhẹ nhàng nhưng mang lại nhiều điều thú vị\\", họa sĩ Đào Hải Phong chia sẻ. Dù không phải là họa sĩ có thế mạnh trong vẽ minh họa, nhưng với Gió đầu mùa và Hà Nội băm sáu phố phường có thể nhận ra sự hòa điệu nhịp nhàng. Đào Hải Phong đã \\"bắt\\" trúng tinh thần của văn chương của nhà văn Thạch Lam để vẽ. Những bức minh họa của Đào Hải Phong trong ấn phẩm này, ở chừng mực nào đó, có thể coi là những tác phẩm hội họa độc lập được gợi hứng từ những trang văn giàu cảm xúc của nhà văn Thạch Lam. Các bức vẽ trong bộ minh họa mang đến cho người xem điểm nhìn mới về những vết dấu cũ xưa. Hà Nội hiện ra trong tranh Đào Hải Phong vừa quen thuộc vừa mới lạ, thâm trầm nhưng cũng đầy kiêu sa. Minh họa của họa sĩ đồng điệu với văn chương Thạch Lam ở nét thanh lịch dịu dàng và tình yêu chân thành, tha thiết dành cho cảnh vật, con người, những giá trị đẹp đẽ và cao quý.","answer":"Đào Hải Phong 'tìm lại mình' trong văn Thạch Lam"},{"question":"Senaraikan planet dalam sistem suria. ","answer":"Utarid, Zuhrah, Bumi, Marikh, Musytari,  Zuhal, Uranus dan Neptun"},{"question":"آیا بوستان آب و آتش مکان تفریحی مناسبی برای کودکان است؟","answer":"اگر کودک شما از جمله کودکانی است که به فضای طبیعت علاقه زیادی دارد و می خواهید به یک محیط دلنشین ببرید، بوستان آب و آتش گزینه مناسبی است. در زمین بازی پارک آب و آتش کودکان شما می‌توانند از وسایل بازی نهایت لذت را ببرند و شاید با هم سن و سالان خود دوست شوند. این پارک بازی حدود ۲۴ هزار متر مربع مساحت دارد که قطعاً بخش های دیگری هم برای بازی در آن وجود دارد. آب نماهای متنوع و زیبا در این بوستان محیطی هستند که کودک شما می تواند در آن جا به آب تنی بپردازند. بنابراین اگر می خواهید کودک شما تجربه یک تفریح خنک را داشته باشد، بوستان آب و آتش گزینه بسیار مناسبی خواهد بود."},{"question":"මිලදීගැනීමට, ප්‍රසම්පාදන යන වදන සමාන පදයක් වනවාද? එසේනම් එකෙසේද?","answer":"ප්‍රසම්පාදනය කියන්නේ විශේෂයෙන් රජයේ හෝ එවැනි සම්මත ආයතන වල කෙරෙන ක්‍රමවත් මිලදී ගැනීම් වලට. Procurement කියන ඉංග්‍රීසි වචනය තමා සිංහලෙන් ප්‍රසම්පාදනය කියලා කියන්නේ"},{"question":"Gbólóhùn tó fi àsìkò afànámóní hàn ni...","answer":"Ó lọ sí Èkó."},{"question":"“百足之虫,死而不僵”这句话是什么意思呢？","answer":"\\"百足\\"即指虫名,又名马陆或马蚿,有十二环节,切断后仍能蠕动。这句谚语比喻势家豪族,虽已衰败,但因势力大,基础厚,还不致完全破产。"},{"question":"భాగస్వామ్యాన్ని నిర్వచించి, ప్రయోజనాలు, పరిమితులను చర్చించండి.","answer":"కొంత మంది వ్యక్తులు కలిసి ఉమ్మడిగా చేసే వ్యాపారాన్ని భాగస్వామ్య వ్యాపారము అని చెప్పవచ్చును. 1932 భారత భాగస్వామ్య చట్టం ప్రకారం భాగస్వామ్యాన్ని దిగువ విధముగా నిర్వచించినారు. – “అందరుకుగాని, అందరి తరపున కొందరుగాని వ్యాపారాన్ని నిర్వహిస్తూ అందులోని లాభాలను పంచుకోవడానికి వ్యక్తుల మధ్య ఏర్పరచుకున్న సంబంధమే భాగస్వామ్యము”.భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థ ప్రయోజనాలు:1. స్థాపనా సౌలభ్యము: భాగస్వామ్య వ్యాపారాన్ని స్థాపించడానికి చట్టబద్ధమైన లాంఛనాలు తక్కువ. నమోదు తప్పని సరికాదు. దీనిని స్థాపించడానికి వ్రాత పూర్వకమైన లేదా నోటిమాటల ద్వారా ఏర్పరచుకున్న సాధారణ ఒప్పందము సరిపోతుంది.2. అధిక నిధులు లభ్యము: భాగస్తులందరూ పెట్టుబడి పెడతారు కాబట్టి, సొంత వ్యాపారానికంటే భాగస్వామ్యానికి ఎక్కువ నిధులు లభిస్తాయి.3. సత్వర నిర్ణయాలు: భాగస్తులందరూ స్థానికులే కాబట్టి తరచూ కలుసుకుంటూ ఉంటారు. వ్యాపార నిర్ణయాలు జాప్యము లేకుండా తీసుకోవచ్చు. త్వరిత నిర్ణయాల వలన వ్యాపార లాభాలు పెరుగుతాయి.4. మార్పునకు అనుకూలము: అవసరాన్ని బట్టి వ్యాపారములో మార్పులు చేయడానికి న్యాయపరమైన అవరోధాలు తక్కువ. వ్యాపారస్వభావాన్ని, ప్రదేశాన్ని సులభముగా మార్చుకోవచ్చును.5. వ్యాపార రహస్యాలు: వ్యాపార రహస్యాలు భాగస్తులకు మాత్రమే తెలిసి ఉంటుంది. లాభనష్టాలను, ఆస్తి-అప్పుల వివరాలను బయటకు వెల్లడిచేయరు. రహస్యాలను జాగ్రత్తగా కాపాడతారు.6. నష్టాల పంపిణీ: భాగస్వామ్య వ్యాపారములో వచ్చిన నష్టాలను భాగస్తులందరూ అంగీకరించిన నిష్పత్తిలో పంచుకుంటారు. విడివిడిగా ఒక్కొక్క భాగస్తుడు భరించే నష్టము తక్కువ.7. వ్యక్తిగత శ్రద్ధ: భాగస్వామ్య వ్యాపారాన్ని ప్రత్యక్షముగాను, అతి సన్నిహితముగాని పర్యవేక్షణ చేస్తారు. అందువలన వృథాలు తగ్గి, వ్యాపారము విజయవంతము అవుతుంది.8. ప్రత్యేకీకరణ: భాగస్వామ్యములో మూలధనము, నిర్వహణా సామర్థ్యము, సాంకేతిక నైపుణ్యము తదితర లక్షణాలు గల భాగస్తుల కలయిక వలన ప్రత్యేకమైన సేవలను ఉపయోగించుకొని సంస్థ రాణిస్తుంది.9. ఆసక్తుల పరిరక్షణ: భాగస్వామ్యములో ప్రతిభాగస్తుని హక్కులు, ఆసక్తులు పూర్తిగా కాపాడబడతాయి. ఏ. భాగస్తుడైనా ఒక నిర్ణయం పట్ల అసంతృప్తి చెందితే, అతడు రద్దును కోరవచ్చు లేదా వైదొలగవచ్చు.పరిమితులు/లోపాలు: భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థలకు క్రింది పరిమితులున్నవి.1. పరిమిత మూలధనము: వాటాదారుల సంఖ్యకు పరిమితిలేని జాయింట్ స్టాకు కంపెనీలతో పోలిస్తే భాగస్వామ్య సంస్థ నిధులను సేకరించే శక్తి తక్కువ. భాగస్వామ్యములో 20 మందికి మించి భాగస్తులు ఉండరాదు.2. స్థిరత్వము లేకపోవుట: భాగస్తులలో ఎవరు మరణించినా, విరమించినా లేదా దివాలాతీసినా భాగస్వామ్యము రద్దు అవుతుంది. అసంతృప్తి చెందిన ఏ భాగస్తుడైనా సంస్థను రద్దుపరచడానికి ఏ సమయములోనైనా నోటీసు ఇవ్వవచ్చును.3. అపరిమిత ఋణబాధ్యత: భాగస్తుల ఋణ బాధ్యత పరిమితము. సంస్థ నష్టాలపాలై వ్యాపార అప్పులను సంస్థ ఆస్తుల నుంచేకాక భాగస్తుల సొంత ఆస్తుల నుంచి తీర్చవలసి ఉంటుంది.4. వాటాను బదిలీ చేయరాదు: ఏ భాగస్తుడు సహభాగస్తుల అంగీకారము లేకుండా తన వాటాను బయటవారికి బదిలీ చేయడానికి వీలులేదు. దీనికి ప్రత్యామ్నాయం సంస్థను రద్దు పరచడమే.5. భాగస్తుల మధ్య ఐక్యత లోపము: ప్రతి భాగస్తుడు నిర్వహణలో పాల్గొనవచ్చు. ఏ విషయములోనైనా తన అభిప్రాయాన్ని వెల్లడించవచ్చు. ఇది కొన్నిసార్లు భాగస్తుల మధ్య అభిప్రాయభేదాలు, తగాదాలకు దారితీయవచ్చును.6. ప్రచ్ఛన్న అధికారము: సంస్థ తరపున లావాదేవీలు జరపడానికి ప్రతిభాగస్తునకు హక్కు ఉంటుంది. ఇది ఆసరాగా తీసుకొని కొంతమంది భాగస్తులు నిర్లక్ష్యముగాను, ‘దురుద్దేశముతో వ్యవహరిస్తే సంస్థ నష్టాలపాలయ్యే అవకాశమున్నది.7. ప్రజలకు విశ్వాసము లేకపోవడం: భాగస్వామ్యములో లెక్కలను ప్రచురించరు. అంతాగోప్యముగా ఉంటుంది, కాబట్టి ప్రజలకు వీటిపై విశ్వాసము ఉండదు."},{"question":"கேள்வி : இந்தியாவில் உள்ள தஞ்சாவூர் பெரிய கோயிலைக் கட்டியவர்?1) கரிகால சோழன்2) பல்லவன்3) ராஜராஜ சோழன்4) சந்திரபோஸ்","answer":"பதில் :3) ராஜராஜ சோழன்"},{"question":"അന്താരാഷ്ട്ര മാരത്തണുകളുടെ ഒരു കൂട്ടം പട്ടികപ്പെടുത്തുക. ","answer":"ബോസ്റ്റൺ, ന്യൂയോർക്ക് സിറ്റി, ക്ലീവ്‌ലാൻഡ്, ചിക്കാഗോ, ബിഗ് സൂർ, റോഡ് ഐലൻഡ്. "},{"question":"සංවිධානයක ලක්ෂණ මොනවාද?","answer":"සංවිධානයකට සාමාන්‍යයෙන් ප්‍රධාන අංග කිහිපයක් ඇත, ඒවා අතර:1. ඉලක්ක සහ අරමුණු: සංවිධානවලට ඔවුන්ගේ ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සහ තීරණ ගැනීමේ ක්‍රියාවලීන් මඟ පෙන්වන නිශ්චිත ඉලක්ක සහ අරමුණු ඇත.2. ව්‍යුහය: සංවිධානවලට විධිමත් හෝ අවිධිමත් ව්‍යුහයක් ඇත. එය කාර්යයන් පැවරෙන ආකාරය සහ සංවිධානය තුළ සන්නිවේදනය ගලා යන ආකාරය නිර්වචනය කරයි.3. පුද්ගලයන්: පොදු අරමුණු සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා එකට වැඩ කරන පුද්ගලයින්ගෙන් සංවිධාන සෑදී ඇත.4. සම්පත්: සංවිධාන ක්‍රියාත්මක වීමට ප්‍රාග්ධනය, තාක්ෂණය සහ අමුද්‍රව්‍ය වැනි සම්පත් අවශ්‍ය වේ.5. සංස්කෘතිය: සෑම සංවිධානයකටම එහි වටිනාකම්, සම්මතයන් සහ විශ්වාසයන් නිර්වචනය කරන අද්විතීය සංස්කෘතියක් ඇත.6. ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි: තීරණ ගැනීම සහ හැසිරීම සඳහා මාර්ගෝපදේශ සපයන ප්‍රතිපත්ති සහ ක්‍රියා පටිපාටි සංවිධාන සතුව ඇත.7. උපාය මාර්ග: සංවිධාන තම අරමුණු සහ අරමුණු සාක්ෂාත් කර ගැනීම සඳහා උපාය මාර්ග සකස් කර ක්‍රියාත්මක කරයි.8. නායකත්වය: සේවකයින්ට මග පෙන්වීම, අභිප්‍රේරණය සහ සහාය ලබා දෙන නායකයින් සංවිධාන සතුව ඇත.9. කාර්ය සාධනය මැනීම: සංවිධාන ඔවුන්ගේ සාර්ථකත්වය ඇගයීමට සහ වැඩිදියුණු කළ යුතු ක්ෂේත්‍ර හඳුනා ගැනීමට ප්‍රමිතික සහ කාර්ය සාධන දර්ශක භාවිතා කරයි.මේවා ආයතනයක ප්‍රධාන ලක්ෂණ කිහිපයක් පමණක් වන අතර, එක් එක් ආයතනයට එහි අරමුණ, සංස්කෘතිය සහ මෙහෙයුම් පරිසරය පිළිබිඹු කරන සුවිශේෂී ලක්ෂණ තිබිය හැක."},{"question":"Sheeg Eey-Gii Galay Janada?","answer":"Wuxuu Ahaa Eey-Gii La-Socday Reer Asxaabu Kahfi"},{"question":"ما هي القارة التي تقع فيها فلسطين؟","answer":"تقع فلسطين في قارة آسيا."},{"question":"Orúkọ wo ni àwọn Yorùbá ń sọ ọmọ tí ó wà nínú àpò nígbà tí wọ́n bi? ","answer":"Ọ̀kẹ́"},{"question":"ਨਵੀਂ ਦਿੱਲੀ, 25 ਅਕਤੂਬਰਭਾਰਤੀ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਭੁਵਨੇਸ਼ਵਰ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਤੇ ਜਸਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਬਮਰਾਹ ਫੁਰਸਤ ਦੇ ਪਲਾਂ ’ਚਤੇਜ਼ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ ਭੁਵਨੇਸ਼ਵਰ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਤੇ ਜਸਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਬਮਰਾਹ ਨੂੰ ਵੈਸਟਇੰਡੀਜ਼ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਆਖਰੀ ਤਿੰਨ ਇਕ ਰੋਜ਼ਾ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਲਈ ਅੱਜ ਟੀਮ ’ਚ ਦਾਖ਼ਲੇ ਲਈ ਹਰੀ ਝੰਡੀ ਮਿਲ ਗਈ ਜਦੋਂਕਿ ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਸ਼ਮੀ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਚਰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਦੇ ਚਲਦਿਆਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਂਜ ਕੌਮੀ ਚੋਣ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਵੈਸਟ ਇੰਡੀਜ਼ ਤੇ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਕੁੱਲ ਛੇ ਟੀ-20 ਮੈਚਾਂ ਲਈ ਟੀਮ ਦੀ ਚੋਣ ਸ਼ੁੱਕਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਪੁਣੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਰੇਗੀ। ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਤਿੰਨ ਟੀ-20 ਮੈਚ ਉਸੇ ਦੀ ਸਰਜ਼ਮੀਨ ’ਤੇ ਖੇਡੇ ਜਾਣਗੇ। ਭਾਰਤੀ ਕਪਤਾਨ ਵਿਰਾਟ ਕੋਹਲੀ ਵੈਸਟ ਇੰਡੀਜ਼ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਟੀ-20 ਲੜੀ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੇਡੇਗਾ ਜਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਹ ਵੇਖਣਾ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਦਿਲਚਸਪ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਕੌਮੀ ਚੋਣ ਕਮੇਟੀ ਨੇ ਪੁਣੇ (27 ਅਕਤੂਬਰ), ਮੁੰਬਈ (29 ਅਕਤੂਬਰ) ਤੇ ਪੁਣੇ (ਪਹਿਲੀ ਨਵੰਬਰ) ਵਿੱਚ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਲਈ ਕੋਹਲੀ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ 15 ਮੈਂਬਰੀ ਟੀਮ ਦੀ ਚੋਣ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਪਹਿਲੇ ਦੋ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਲਈ ਚੁਣੀ ਗਈ ਟੀਮ ’ਚੋਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਸ਼ਮੀ ਨੂੰ ਹੀ ਬਾਹਰ ਦਾ ਰਾਹ ਵਿਖਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਦੋ ਇਕ ਰੋਜ਼ਾ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਿਆਂ ’ਚ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਮਹਿੰਗਾ ਸਾਬਤ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਹਾਲਾਂਕਿ ਉਮੇਸ਼ ਯਾਦਵ ਵੀ ਅਸਰਦਾਰ ਗੇਂਦਬਾਜ਼ੀ ਕਰਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਾਕਾਮ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਪਰ ਉਹ ਟੀਮ ’ਚ ਆਪਣੀ ਥਾਂ ਬਰਕਰਾਰ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਭੁਵਨੇਸ਼ਵਰ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਤੇ ਬਮਰਾਹ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਏਸ਼ੀਆ ਕੱਪ ਤੇ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਵੈਸਟ ਇੰਡੀਜ਼ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਦੋ ਟੈਸਟ ਮੈਚਾਂ ਦੀ ਲੜੀ ਲਈ ਆਰਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ, ਦੀ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਮਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਮਜ਼ਬੂਤੀ ਮਿਲੀ ਹੈ। ਚੋਣਕਾਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਕੇਦਾਰ ਜਾਧਵ ਦੀ ਚੋਣ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ, ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਦੇਵਧਰ ਟਰਾਫ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਜ਼ੋਰਦਾਰ ਵਾਪਸੀ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ 25 ਗੇਂਦਾਂ ’ਤੇ 41 ਦੌੜਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਾਰੀ ਖੇਡੀ ਸੀ। ਅਜਿਹੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ ਪ੍ਰਿਥਵੀ ਸ਼ਾਹ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਰੋਜ਼ਾ ਟੀਮ ’ਚ ਥਾਂ ਮਿਲੇਗੀ, ਪਰ ਦੇਵਧਰ ਟਰਾਫ਼ੀ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਹੱਥ ’ਤੇ ਲੱਗੀ ਸੱਟ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਹ ਬੱਲੇਬਾਜ਼ ਭਾਰਤ ਏ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਸੀ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਮੈਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਖੇਡ ਸਕਿਆ।ਟੀਮ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੈ:ਵਿਰਾਟ ਕੋਹਲੀ (ਕਪਤਾਨ), ਰੋਹਿਤ ਸ਼ਰਮਾ(ਉਪ ਕਪਤਾਨ), ਸ਼ਿਖਰ ਧਵਨ, ਅੰਬਾਤੀ ਰਾਇਡੂ, ਰਿਸ਼ਭ ਪੰਤ, ਮਹਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਧੋਨੀ (ਵਿਕਟ ਕੀਪਰ), ਰਵਿੰਦਰ ਜਡੇਜਾ, ਕੁਲਦੀਪ ਯਾਦਵ, ਯੁਜਵੇਂਦਰ ਚਹਿਲ, ਭੁਵਨੇਸ਼ਵਰ ਕੁਮਾਰ, ਜਸਪ੍ਰੀਤ ਬਮਰਾਹ, ਖਲੀਲ ਅਹਿਮਦ, ਉਮੇਸ਼ ਯਾਦਵ, ਕੇ.ਐਲ.ਰਾਹੁਲ, ਮਨੀਸ਼ ਪਾਂਡੇ।ਭਾਰਤੀ ਟੀਮ 'ਚੋਂ ਕਿੰਨੇ ਖਿਡਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਾਹਰ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਮੁਹੰਮਦ ਸ਼ਮੀ ਨੂੰ ਲੱਚਰ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਦੇ ਚਲਦਿਆਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Bleach\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay \\"manga\\" mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Bleach\\" dia Tite Kubo."},{"question":"እንቆቅልሽ፡- 13 ልብ ያለው ምንድን ነው ግን ሌላ የአካል ክፍሎች የሉትም? ","answer":"መልስ:- የመጫወቻ ካርዶች/ካርታ ።"},{"question":"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਵੱਧ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੁਝ ਦੱਸੋ:\\"ਰੂਸ ਦੇ ਸੰਘੀ ਕਸਬੇ\\"","answer":"ਰੂਸ ਦੇ ਸੰਘੀ ਕਸਬੇ ,ਇਹ ਉਹ ਕਸਬੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇੱਕ ਅਬਾਦ ਬਸਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਸੰਘੀ ਇਕਾਈ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਹੈਸੀਅਤ ਹਾਸਿਲ ਹੈ। "},{"question":"iza no vavy matoa?","answer":"ny vavy matoa dia I Ravo"},{"question":"Qual é a ferrovia mais longa do mundo?","answer":"A ferrovia mais longa do mundo liga Portugal à Singapura com 18.755 quilômetros de extensão. "},{"question":"...యని అన్నారు. మేం ఎలా ఉన్నామో అలా మమ్మల్ని వారెవరూ స్వీకరించరు. ఎప్పుడూ సందేహంగా చూస్తుంటారు” అని గరిమ చెప్పారు. పురుషులు చాలాసార్లు బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయిలను  కేవలం సెక్సువల్ ఫాంటసీకి సంబంధించి చూస్తుంటారు.“నేను నా లైంగికత గురించి బాహాటంగా మాట్లాడతాను. అందుకే జనం నా గురించి ఏవేవో ఊహించుకుంటారు. అబ్బాయిలు నాకు సోషల్ మీడియాలో అసభ్యంగా మెసేజులు పంపిస్తుంటారు. బహుశా బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయి ఎవరితో అయినా పడుకోడానిక సిద్ధమైపోతుందని వాళ్లకు అనిపిస్తుందేమో.. వారు సమ్మతి, ఇష్టాయిష్టాల గురించి అసలు ఆలోచించరు”... Write the rest of the article:","answer":"బైసెక్సువల్ అంటే పోర్న్, ఫాంటసీ కాదుఒక అమ్మాయి స్వయంగా తన బైసెక్సువల్ గుర్తింపును బహిరంగంగా అంగీకరించడం అనేది చాలా సాహసోపేత చర్య అవుతుందని సోనల్ చెప్పారు.“చాలాసార్లు బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయిలను పోర్న్ కు కలిపి చూస్తారు. వారి చరిత్ర గురించి ప్రశ్నలు లేవదీస్తారు. అలాంటప్పుడు అది ఆ అమ్మాయిల భద్రతకు సంబంధించిన సమస్యగా కూడా మారుతుంది. బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయిలు ఓపెన్‌గా బయటకు రాకపోవడానికి కారణం కూడా అదే” అన్నారుయవ క్వీర్ యాక్టివిస్ట్ ధర్మేష్ చౌబే మరో ముఖ్యమైన విషయం గురించి కూడా వివరించారు. బైసెక్సువల్ అయిన పురుషులు, మహిళల లైంగితను సమాజం తమ సౌలభ్యానికి తగ్గట్టు రకరకాల వాదనలతో కొట్టిపారేందుకు ప్రయత్నిస్తోందని ఆయన భావిస్తున్నారు.“బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయిల గురించి మాట్లాడే సమాజం.. వారు స్ట్రెయిటే, కాకపోతే కాస్త సెక్సువల్ అడ్వెంచర్ చేయాలని చూస్తున్నారు అంటుంది. అటు బైసెక్సువల్ పురుషుల గురించి మాత్రం, వారు గే, కానీ తమ స్వలింగ సంపర్కాన్ని దాచేందుకు హోమోసెక్సువల్ అయినట్లు నటిస్తున్నారని అంటుంది. అంటే పితృస్వామిక సమాజంలో మహిళ లైంగికతకు పెద్దగా ప్రాధాన్యం లేదు. మొత్తం మీద తాము గే కావడం వ్యాధి కాదని, దానికి నివారణలు వెతకవద్దని, వారి కోరికలను పట్టించుకోవాలని పురుషులు ఆశిస్తున్నారు” అని ధర్మేష్ చెప్పారు. టేక్ మీ యాజ్ అయామ్ఇన్ని కష్టాలు ఎదురైనప్పటికీ భారత్‌లో బైసెక్సువల్ అమ్మాయిలు మెల్లమెల్లగా అయినా బయటకు రావడం ప్రారంభమైంది. ముఖ్యంగా జూన్‌లో(ప్రైడ్ మంత్) చాలా మంది అమ్మాయిలు సోషల్ మీడియాలో ఎలాంటి సంకోచం లేకుండా తమ సెక్సువాలిటీని అంగీకరించారు.జూన్ నెలను ఎల్జీబీటీ సమాజం ప్రైడ్ మంత్‌గా భావిస్తోంది. ఈ నెలలో తమ సంఘర్షణ, కోరికలు, సాధించిన వాటి గురించి మాట్లాడుతోంది. ప్రస్తుత సమయంలో బైసెక్సువల్ యువతులు కూడా చాలా సామాజిక సంకెళ్లను తెంచుకున్నట్లు కనిపించడానికి కూడా ఇదే కారణం. వారు తమ బైసెక్సువాలిటీని అంగీకరించాలని కోరుతున్నారు. తాము ఎలా ఉన్నామో, అలాగే స్వీకరించమని చెబుతున్నారు. 2018 సెప్టెంబర్‌లో భారత సుప్రీంకోర్టు స్వలింగ సంపర్క సంబంధాలను నేరంగా చెప్పే ఐపీసీ సెక్షన్ 377ను నిర్వీర్యం చేసింది. అప్పటి సీజేఐ జస్టిస్ దీపక్ మిశ్రా కోర్టు తీర్పును చదువుతూ జర్మనీ రచయిత యోహన్ వాఫ్గాంగ్‌ మాటను గుర్తు చేసుకున్నారు. జస్టిస్ మిశ్రా అప్పుడు “అయాం వాట్ అయాం, సో టేక్ మీ యాజ్ అయాం”(I am what I am, so take me as I am) అన్నారు"},{"question":"inona no vato mafy indrindra?","answer":"ny diamondra no vato mafy indrindra"},{"question":"Atsakykite į šį klausimą. Kokia pavardės Roche kilmė?","answer":"Pavardė Roche yra normanų kilmės"},{"question":"自動車が止まっている状態でエンジンを空回りさせることをなんと言うでしょう？","answer":"アイドリングです。"},{"question":"Аргымактын  жакшысы чапса күлүк, сатса пул.","answer":"Аргымак аттын жакшысы. Аттын күлүгү. Жарышка салсаң озуп келет, кол карыштырып тизгинди созуп келет. Андай атты сатсаң пул болот."},{"question":" الحيوان المائي الاسرع في العالم؟","answer":" سمكة ابوشراع."},{"question":"සෑම වසරකම මිලියන ගණනක් නරඹන්නන් ආකර්ශනය කර ගන්නා ඉතාලියේ සුවිශේෂී ස්ථාන කිහිපයක් ඔබට නම් කළ හැකිද?","answer":"රෝමයේ කොලෝසියම්, වැනීසියේ ඇළ මාර්ග, පීසා හි ඇලෙන කුළුණ ට්‍රෙවි ෆවුන්ටන්"},{"question":"Seyrek saçlar sıklaşır mı?","answer":"Dökülen, seyrekleşen saçlar, doğru bakımlar yapıldığında hızla gürleşebilir. Gürleşmenin yanı sıra saçlarınız eskisinden çok daha güçlü ve sağlıklı bir hâle gelebilir."},{"question":"Демократия деген эмне ?","answer":"Демократия ( Гр. demos – эл, kratos – бийлик) – эл бийлигине негизделген саясий түзүлүштүн формасы. Демократияда эл бийликтин негизги булагы, аныктоочусу катары таанылат, мамлекеттик бийликтин негизги органдары шайланат, жарандардын тең укуктуулугу, чечимдерди кабыл алууда азчылыктын көпчүлүккө баш ийиши, азчылыктын укугунун корголушу жана башка нерселер менен камсыз болот. Демократиянын тарыхы байыркы батыш цивилизациясынын (өзгөчө грек жана рим) мезгилинен башталат. Батышта демократия түшүнүгү Байыркы Грециядагы шаар-мамлекеттердин өнүгүшү менен коштолот. Азыркы демократиянын калыптанышына жана бекемделишине адамдын табияттан берилүүчү жашоого, эркиндикке жана жеке менчикке болгон идеялары чоң түрткү болгон. Либералдуулукка негизделген азыркы демократия төмөнкүдөй принциптерди камтыйт: адам укугу жана аны мамлекеттин укугунан жогору коюу; эркин атаандаштык жана базар мамилелериндеги эркиндик, азчылыктын үстүнөн көпчүлүктүн бийлигин конституциялык жол менен чектөө; жеке ойго ээ болуу жана аны эркин айтуу боюнча азчылыктын укугун урматтоо жана башка. Либералдар жеке адамдын кызыкчылыгын жогору коюну көздөсө, демократияда тескерисинче эл бийлигин, атуулдардын саясий теңдигин, азчылыктын көпчүлүккө баш ийишин жогору коёт. Демократиянын ар кандай формалары жана институттары болушу мүмкүн. Бирок демократиянын талаптарына жооп берүүчү жалпы нормалары, баалуулуктары, принциптери бар. Алар биринчи кезекте адам укуктарын жогору коёт. Тең салмактуулукту кармап турган өз алдынча, бирок бири-бири менен байланыштуу болгон бийликтин 3 бутагы түзүлөт. Аларга мыйзам чыгаруучу, аткаруучу жана сот бийлиги ыйгарылат. Демократиянын негизги принциптеринин бири – ар бир атуул мыйзам алдында бирдей жооптуу жана тең укуктуу. Маалымдуулук принциби – демократиянын алмаштыргыс шарты. Азырынча демократиянын принциптерин толугу менен ишке ашырган бир да өлкө жок."},{"question":"ఉల్లిపాయి దొంగ గురించి కథ రాయండి ","answer":"ఒక అబ్బాయిని ఉల్లిపాయలు దొంగలిస్తుంటే ఊళ్ళో వాళ్ళు పట్టుకున్నారు. న్యాయమూర్తి దెగ్గిరకు   తీసుకుని వెళ్ళారు.  న్యాయమూర్తి ఆ అబ్బాయిని మూడు శిక్షలలో ఒకటి ఎంపిక చేసుకో మన్నాడు – ఒకటే ఒకసారి దొంగలించిన ఉల్లిప్పాయలన్నీ తినడమా; వంద కొరడా దెబ్బలు భరించడమా, జరిమానా చెల్లించడమా?  ఆ అబ్బాయి వెంటనే ఎక్కువ తక్కువ ఆలోచించ కుండా ఉల్లిపాయలు తినేస్తాను అన్నాడు.  ఉల్లిపాయలు తినడం మొదలుపెట్టాడు. కాని అది అనుకున్నంత సులువైన పని కాదు. ఒక్కటి కూడా పూర్తి గా తినకుండానే కళ్ళల్లోంచి, ముక్కు లోంచి నీళ్ళు కారడం మొదలైంది. ఐనా మొండి గా ఇంకో రెండు తిన్నాడు, కాని ఇక వీలు కాలేదు.  సరే ఇది కాదు, కొరడా దెబ్బలే తింటాను అని న్యాయమూర్తికి చెప్పాడు. సైనికులు కొరడాతో కొట్టడం మొదలు పెట్టారు. కొరడా దేబ్బాలంటే మాటలా? నొప్పి తట్టుకో లేక పోయాడు.  బాబోయి! బాబోయి! జరిమానా కట్టేస్తాను, ఆపండి! అని ఏడుపు మొదలెట్టాడు.  ఏడుస్తూనే జరిమానా చెల్లించాడు.  ఇప్పుడు ఆ అబ్బాయికి బాగా అర్ధం అయ్యింది. ఏదైనా తప్పు పని చేస్తే అది మనల్ని ముప్పు తిప్పలూ పెడుతుందని. ఆ తరువాత ఆ అబ్బాయి ఎప్పుడు దొంగతనం కాని, వేరే టప్పుడు పనులు కాని చేయలేదు.  కొంత మంది ఈ కథలో ఇంకో నీతి కూడా చెప్తారు. మనం ఏదైనా నిర్ణయం తీసుకునే ముందు బాగా ఆలోచించి, ప్రత్యామ్నాయాలు పరిశీలించాలీ. అప్పుడే నిర్ణయం తీసుకోవాలి."},{"question":"புதுமைப்பித்தனின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"பொதுவாக என்னுடைய கதைகள் உலகத்துக்கு உபதேசம் செய்யும் ஸ்தாபனம் அல்ல! பிற்கால நல்வாழ்வுக்கு சௌகரியம் பண்ணி வைக்கும் இன்ஷ்யூரன்ஸ் ஏற்பாடும் அல்ல. எனக்குப் பிடிக்கிறவர்களையும் பிடிக்காதவர்களையும் கிண்டல் செய்து கொண்டிருக்கிறேன். சிலர் என்னோடு சேர்ந்துகொண்டு சிரிக்கிறார்கள். இன்னும் சிலர் கோபிக்கிறார்கள்."},{"question":"Àwon Yorùbá máa ń lo ewé efinrin fún","answer":"jèdíjèdí"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada hati\\"?","answer":"Keinginan"},{"question":"Lateef Olúfẹ́mi Òkúnnù ","answer":"Lateef Olúfẹ́mi Òkúnnù Àdàkọ:Post-nominals tí wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún òṣù kejì ọdún 1933 jẹ́ agbẹjọ́rò àgbà ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà àti Alága àgbà fún ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ ọ̀gbìn University of Agriculture, Makurdi.Wọ́n bí Lateef Okunu ní ọjọ́ kọkàndínlógún òṣù kejì ọdún 1933 ní ìlú Èkó. Ó lọ sílé ẹ̀kó alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ ti Ansarudeen, tí ó wà ní Alakoro láàrín ọdún 1938 sí 1947. Tí ó sì tún lọ sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ Kings College láàrín ọdún 1938 sí 1953. Ní ọdún 1956, ó wọ ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ University of London níbi tí ó ti kẹ́kọ́ gbiyè akọ́kọ́ nínú ìmọ̀ òfin tí wọ́n sì gbàá wọlé gẹ́gẹ́ bí amòfin agbẹjọ́rò ní ọdún 1960, wọ́n sì tún fi jẹ Alákòóso ìjọba apápọ̀ fún iṣẹ́ àti ilégbèé. Ó ṣakóso gẹ́gẹ́ bí adarí ní ipò yí fún ọdún méje tí sáà rẹ̀ sì tẹnubepo ní ọdún 1974. Wọ́n t tún yàn án gẹ́gẹ́ bí olùgbani nímọ̀ọ̀ràn amòfin fún ẹgbẹ́ He served in this capacity for seven years, a tenure that ended in 1974 National Party of Nigeria (N.P.N.) ní ọdún 1981.Ìjọba yàn án gẹ́gẹ́bí agbẹnusọ fún orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà nínú àpérò Organisation of African Unity Consultative Committee nípa sísọ̀rọ̀ lórí ọ̀rọ̀ àlááfíà látàrí ogun abẹ́lé tí ó wáyé lórílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà láàrín ọdún 1968 àti ti ọdún 1969, Ìjọba tún yàn án gẹ́gẹ́bí agbẹnusọ fún orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà nínú àpérò O.A.U. Ministerial Conference. Ní ọdún 1980, òun ni ó ṣe agbẹnusọ fún orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà ní inú àpérò U.N.O. Lẹ́yìn náà ni wọ́n yàn án gẹ́gẹ́ bí Alákòóso àgbà fún ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ fáfitì University of Agriculture, Makurdi ní ọdún 1982."},{"question":"From 1944 to 1945, the Germans increased their troops surrounding the Ardennes Forest for what World War II battle and major counteroffensive? It gets its name from the rounded swelling of German troops in the region.","answer":"Battle of the Bulge"},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Sportpalast var en evenemangsbyggnad på Potsdamer Strasse, i hörnet av Pallasstrasse i stadsdelen Schöneberg i Berlin som stod klar 1910 och revs 1973. Här arrangerades flera olika evenemang och byggnaden blev även plats ","answer":"för politiska möten. Under 1920-talet upplevde Sportpalast en storhetstid med bland annat boxning och cykeltävlingen Sechstagerennen."},{"question":"ශුද්ධ වූ ත්‍රිත්ව පිළිබඳ ජනප්‍රිය නිදර්ශන මොනවාද?","answer":"ත්‍රිත්වය නිදර්ශනය කිරීම උදාර අරමුණක් වන නමුත් එය අවසානයේ නිෂ්ඵල භාවයේ ව්‍යායාමයකි. සියවස් ගණනාවක් පුරා දේවධර්මාචාර්යවරුන් විසින් ත්‍රිත්ව දෙවියන්වහන්සේ පිළිබඳ ධර්මනියාත්මක ශබ්දයක් සම්පුර්ණයෙන්ම තෘප්තිමත් කළ හැකි උපමාවක් සකස් කිරීමේ උත්සාහයේදී මොළය බිඳ දමා ඇත. ඔවුන්ගේ උත්සාහයන් බාධා කරන්නේ දෙවියන් වහන්සේ ලෝකෝත්තරව සිටීම සහ උන්වහන්සේගේ සමහර ගුණාංග නොදැන සිටීමයි. ශුද්ධ වූ ත්‍රිත්වය මුළුමනින්ම විදහා දැක්වීමට අපේ ලෝකයේ කිසිම දෙයකට නොහැකි වුවද, වසර ගණනාවක් පුරාවට ගුරුවරුන් සහ දේවධර්මාචාර්යවරුන් පැහැදිලි කළ නොහැකි දේ පැහැදිලි කිරීම සඳහා සොබාදහම සහ ගණිතය යන විෂයයන්ගෙන් උපුටා ගත් සමානකම් කිහිපයක් ඉදිරිපත් කර ඇත. මෙන්න නිදර්ශන කිහිපයක්:ත්‍රිත්වය පිළිබඳ එක් ජනප්‍රිය හා සරල නිදර්ශනයක් නම් බිත්තරයයි. කුකුළු බිත්තරයක කටුව, කහ මදය සහ බිත්තර සුදු වලින් සමන්විත නමුත් එය මුළුමනින්ම එක් බිත්තරයකි. කොටස් තුන මඟින් සමස්ථයක් නිර්මාණය වේ. මෙම නිදර්ශනයේ සහ වෙනත් ඒවාට ඇති අඩුපාඩුව නම් දෙවියන්වහන්සේව “කොටස්” වලට බෙදිය නොහැකි වීමයි. පියා, පුත්‍රයා සහ ආත්මය සාරයෙන් එකක් වන නමුත් බිත්තරයක කටුව, කහ මදය සහ සුදු පැහැය ගැන ද එයම කිව නොහැක.ඒ හා සමාන නිදර්ශනයක් ඇපල් භාවිතා කරයි: පියා, පුත්‍රයා සහ ආත්මය දෙවියන්වහන්සේගෙන් සමන්විත වනවාක් මෙන්, පළතුරු වල සම, මස් සහ බීජ සියල්ල ඇපල් වලින් සමන්විත වේ. මෙම නිදර්ශනයේ බිත්තර නිදර්ශනයේ ඇති දුර්වලකම ද ඇත, එනම් ස්වාධීනව සලකා බැලූ ඇපල් වල කොටස් ඇපල් නොවේ. ඊට වෙනස්ව, ස්වාධීනව ගත් ත්‍රිත්වයේ සෑම පුද්ගලයෙකුම තවමත් දෙවියන්වහන්සේ ය.ජ්‍යාමිතික මෝස්තර වලින් සමහර පුද්ගලයින් ත්‍රිත්වය පිළිබඳ උපමා උපුටා දක්වා ඇත. උදාහරණයක් ලෙස ත්‍රිකෝණයට එක් හැඩයක් සෑදීම සඳහා සම්බන්ධ වූ ස්වාධීන පැති තුනක් ඇත. කේන්ද්‍රයේ ත්‍රිකෝණයක් සෑදෙන සමකාලීන, එකිනෙකට බැඳී ඇති ආරුක්කු තුනකින් සමන්විත ත්‍රිකෝත්‍රාව තවත් මෝස්තරයකි."},{"question":"Mi a legkisebb prímszám?","answer":"Prímszámoknak pontosan két osztója kell, hogy legyen (1 és önmaguk). Az 1 nem lehet prímszám, tehát a legkisebb prímszám a 2, ami egyben az egyetlen páros prímszám is."},{"question":"フレンチカンカンでおなじみの曲『天国と地獄』の作曲者は誰でしょう？","answer":"オッフェンバック"},{"question":"Quem foi Celsius?","answer":"Anders Celsius foi um astrônomo, físico e geofísico sueco. Em 1742 propôs os graus Celsius de temperatura, escala que leva seu nome. A escala inicial de Celsius atribuía o valor de 0 °C ao ponto de ebulição da água e de 100 °C ao ponto de fusão da água. Em 1745, um ano após a morte de Celsius, Carl Linnaeus inverteu a escala para a sua forma atual: 0 °C para o ponto de fusão da água e 100 °C para o ponto de ebulição da água."},{"question":"Unsay English sa, Maayong buntag, sab?","answer":"Good morning too."},{"question":"”Awọn aṣẹwo gba ninu ounjẹ korona ta a pin l’Ondo, ko sẹni to ko ounjẹ pamọ”","answer":"Alaga ajọ to n ri si pinpin awọn ohun eelo tijọba pese fun awọn araalu lasiko Korona nipinlẹ Ondo, Akin Olotu, ti ṣalaye pe ki i ṣe pe awọn ko ṣuga tawọn eeyan ba ninu ile ẹru ti wọn si ji ko lọ pamọ, o ni awọn fẹẹ ko o fun awọn ileeṣẹ to n ṣe burẹdi nipinlẹ Ondo ni, ki awọn le fi ba wọn dunaa-dura lati din owo burẹdi ku. O ni gbogbo ounjẹ lawọn pin pata, awọn aṣẹwo paapaa gba ninu ounjẹ korona yii.O sọrọ yii lasiko ifọrọwerọ to ṣe pẹlu ileesẹ tẹlifiṣan Arise, ni Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii. Ọkunrin naa ṣalaye pe bii ṣuga ẹgbẹrun kan lawọn tọju pamọ sinu ile naa ki awọn janduku too ya lọ sibẹ lọọ ko o.Olotu sọ pe gbogbo ounjẹ iranwọ ti wọn fun awọn lasiko korona lawọn pin kaakiri ijọba ibilẹ mejidinlogun to wa nipinlẹ Ondo. Awọn opo, awọn aṣẹwo, awọn arugbo atawọn alaboyun lo ni awọn pin awọn ounjẹ iranwọ naa kan.O ni oun le fi gbogbo ẹnu sọ ọ pe ko si ounjẹ kankan ti awọn ṣẹku sibi kan, gbogbo ounjẹ to wa fun korona lawọn pin patapata. Bẹẹ ni fidio tawọn ya lasiko tawọn n pin in wa lati fi ṣe ẹri. O fi kun alaye rẹ pe ṣuga ti wọn ko wa fawọn nipinlẹ Ondo ti pọ ju lawọn fi tọju eyi ti awọn janduku lọọ ji ko ọhun. Ati pe ṣuga nikan lo wa ninu ile ẹru naa, ko si ounjẹ mi-in nibẹ.O ni awọn to wọle ko ṣuga tawọn tọju naa ti kuro ni awọn ti ebi n pa, bi ko ṣe awọn ọdaran ati janduku."},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങൾ നൽകിയിരിക്കുന്നു:വാക്യം 1: \\"പരീക്ഷയിൽ വിജയിക്കാൻ ഞാൻ എന്നെന്നേക്കുമായി ശ്രമിക്കുന്നു, അവസാനം ഞാൻ അത് ചെയ്തു.\\"വാക്യം 2: \\"വളരെയധികം പരീക്ഷണങ്ങൾക്ക് ശേഷം, എനിക്ക് ടെസ്റ്റ് വിജയകരമായി വിജയിക്കാൻ കഴിഞ്ഞു.\\"അവയ്ക്ക് ഒരേ അർത്ഥമുണ്ടോ?","answer":"അതെ, രണ്ട് വാക്യങ്ങളും ഒരേ കാര്യം അർത്ഥമാക്കുന്നു"},{"question":"வினா:சார்பெழுத்துகள் என்றால் என்ன? அதன் வகைகள் யாவை?","answer":" விடை:சார்பெழுத்துகள் :முதல் எழுத்துகளைச் சாா்ந்து வரும் எழுத்துகளைச் சாா்பெழுத்துகள் என்பர். இப்படி சார்பால் தன் இயல்புத்தன்மை மாறும் எழுத்துக்களை முன்னோர் சார்பெழுத்து என்றனர். 12-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் தோன்றிய நேமிநாதம் தொல்காப்பியர் வழியில் சார்பெழுத்துகள் 3 எனக் காட்டிச் செல்கிறது. 13-ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் தோன்றிய நன்னூல் சார்பெழுத்துகள் 10 என்கிறது. நன்னூலுக்குப் பின்னர் தோன்றிய பிரயோக விவேகம், இலக்கணக் கொத்து ஆகிய நூல்கள் நன்னூலை வழிமொழிகின்றன.சார்பெழுத்தின் வகைகள்:உயிர்மெய்                     க்+அ=க தொடக்கத்தனஆய்தம்                எஃகு தொடக்கத்தன முற்றாய்தம்உயிரளபெடை              கெடுப்பதூஉம் கெட்டார்க்குச் சார்வாய் மற்று ஆங்கே எடுப்பதூஉம் எல்லாம் மழை தொடக்கத்தனஒற்றளபெடை                 கண்ண் தண்ண் எனக் கண்டும் கேட்டும் தொடக்கத்தனகுற்றியலிகரம்               நாகு+யாது=நாகியாது தொடக்கத்தனகுற்றியலுகரம்               நாகு அன்று தொடக்கத்தனஐகாரக் குறுக்கம்               ஐப்பசி, வலையன், குவளைஔகாரக் குறுக்கம்               ஔவை என்பதை அவ்வை என ஒலிக்கும்போது ஔகாரக்குறுக்கம்மகரக் குறுக்கம்               வரும்வருவாய்ஆய்தக் குறுக்கம்                 அஃகடிய (அவை கடிய)"},{"question":"Kuris atsakymas teisingas? Kokia yra Saulės sistemos didžiausia planeta?a) Marsasb) Žemėc) Venerad) Jupiteris","answer":"Atsakymas: d) Saulės sistemos didžiausia planeta yra Jupiteris. Jupiteris yra penktoji planeta nuo Saulės ir didžiausia planetų sistema. Jo masė yra 2.5 karto didesnė nei visų kitų Saulės sistemos planetų masės suma."},{"question":"குறிப்புகளைப் பயன்படுத்திக் கட்டுரை ஒன்று தருக.முன்னுரை – இளமைப் பருவம் – கல்வி – கனவு நனவானது – முதல் பயணம் – கல்பனாவின் ஆர்வம் – இரண்டாம் பயணம் – முடிவுரை.","answer":"விண்வெளியும் கல்பனா சாவ்லாவும்முன்னுரை:விண்வெளிக்குப் பயணம் செய்த இந்தியாவின் முதல் பெண்மணி என்ற பெருமைக்குரியவர் கல்பனா சாவ்லா. நடுத்தரக் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்து உலகமே வியந்த விண்வெளி வீராங்கனையாக வாழ்ந்த கல்பனா சாவ்லா அமெரிக்காவின் கொலம்பியா ஓடத்தில் இருந்து விண்வெளிக்குப் பறந்து ஆராய்ச்சிகளை மேற்கொண்டவர்.இளமைப் பருவம்:இந்தியாவின் ஹரியானா மாநிலத்தில் 1961 ம் ஆண்டு ஜுலை ஒன்றாம் தேதி கர்னாஸ் என்ற ஊரில் பிறந்தார் கல்பனா. வீட்டின் நான்கு பிள்ளைகளில் அவர்தான் கடைக்குட்டி அவர் தந்தை ஒரு வியாபாரி, தாய் இல்லத்தரசி பொம்மை வைத்து விளையாடும் வயதில் கல்பனாவுக்குப் பிடித்த பொழுதுபோக்கு விமான ஓவியங்கள் தீட்டி அழகு பார்ப்பது விமானங்களின் சத்தம் கேட்டாலே வீட்டில் இருந்து தெருவுக்கு ஓடிவந்து அந்த அலுமினியப் பறவை, புள்ளியாக மறையும் வரை கண்கள் சுருக்கிப் பார்த்துக்கொண்டே நிற்கும் குழந்தைகளில் ஒருவர்தான் கல்பனாவும்.கல்வி :கர்னாவில் உள்ள அரசுப் பள்ளியில் ஆரம்பக் கல்வியை முடித்த கல்பனாவுக்கு அந்த வயதிலேயே விண்வெளி வீரராக வேண்டும் என்ற இலக்கு மனதில் பதிந்துவிட்டது. சண்டிகரில் உள்ள பஞ்சாப் பொறியியல் கல்லூரியில் விமானப் பொறியியல் பயில விரும்பினார். ஆனால் அது அப்போது ஆண்களின் படிப்பாக இருந்ததால் பெற்றோர் அனுமதிக்கவில்லை என்றாலும் கல்பனாவின் பிடிவாதத்தை அவர்களால் மாற்ற முடியவில்லை. அந்தக் கல்லூரியில் பொறியியல் பட்டம் பெற்ற கல்பனாவை 1982 ல் அமெரிக்கா வரவேற்றது. 1984 ஆம் ஆண்டு டெக்காஸ் விண்வெளி பொறியியல் துறையில் முதுகலைப்பட்டம் பெற்றார் கல்பனா. நான்கு ஆண்டுகள் கழித்துக் கொலோரடோ பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் விமானப் பொறியியல் துறையில் முனைவர் பட்டம் பெற்றார்.கனவு நனவானது:1993 ம் ஆண்டு ஒரு தனியார் நிறுவனத்தில் ஆய்வு விஞ்ஞானியாகச் சேர்ந்தார். அதற்கு அடுத்த ஆண்டே அவரின் விண்வெளி வீரர் கனவு நனவாகத் தொடங்கியது. நாஸாவில் விண்வெளி வீரர் பயிற்சி பெறுவதற்கு விண்ணப்பித்திருந்த சுமார் மூன்று ஆயிரம் பேரில் ஆறு பேர் மட்டும் தேர்வானார்கள். அவர்களுள் கல்பனாவும் ஒருவர். ஜான்ஸன் விண்வெளி தளத்தில் பல்வேறு உடல் மருத்துவ பரிசோதனைகள், கடுமையான நேர்காணல்கள் ஆகியவற்றைக் கடந்து வெற்றிகரமாகத் தேர்ச்சிப் பட்டியலில் இடம் பிடித்தார்.முதல் பயணம்:1995 ஆம் ஆண்டு பயிற்சிகள் முடிந்து விண்வெளி வீராங்கனையாகத் தகுதி பெற்ற கல்பனாவின் முதல் விண்வெளிப் பயணம் 1997 ஆம் ஆண்டு நவம்பர் பத்தொன்பதாம் தேதி நிகழ்ந்தது. ஆறு வீரர்களுடன் கொலம்பிய விண்வெளி ஊர்தியான எஸ்.டி.எஸ் எண்பத்தி ஏழில் பயணம் செய்வதற்குத் தேர்வு செய்யப்பட்ட கல்பனாவுக்கு அதில் ஆராய்ச்சி குறித்த முக்கியப் பொறுப்புகளும் தரப்பட்டன. பூமியை சுமார் இருநூற்று ஐம்பத்து இரண்டு தடவை சுற்றிய அந்த விண்கலத்தில் சுமார் பத்து மில்லியன் மைல் தொலைவு பயணித்த கல்பனா. சகவிண்வெளி வீரர்களுடன் வெற்றிகரமாகப் பூமிக்குத் திருப்பினார்.கல்பனாவின் ஆர்வம்:விமானம் மற்றும் கிளைடர்களை ஓட்டக் கற்றுக் கொடுக்க தகுதிச் சான்றிதழ் பெற்றதோடு மட்டுமல்லாமல் ஓட்டவும் அனுமதி பெற்றிருந்தார் கல்பனா. கொலம்பியா விண்வெளிப் பயணம் மேற்கொள்ளும் முன் கல்பனா முழுமனதோடு ஒரு காரியத்தில் ஈடுபடுபவர்களைப் பார்த்தால் எனக்கும் ஊக்கம் ஏற்படும் என்றார். ஆராய்ச்சியாளர்களின் சுயசரிதைகளை விரும்பிப் படிக்கும் அவர், தன் ஆசிரியர்களுக்கு எப்போதும் தன் நன்றிகளைத் தெரிவித்தபடி இருப்பார்.இரண்டாம் பயணம்:முதல் பயணத்தை வெற்றிகரமாக முடித்த கல்பனா. பிறகு அதே கொலம்பியா விண்கலத்தில் 2003 ஜனவரி பதினாறாவது தேதி ஆறு விண்வெளி வீரர்களுடன் மீண்டும் விண்ணுக்குப் பயணித்தார். பல விண்வெளி ஆராய்ச்சிகளை மேற்கொண்ட அவர்கள் பயணத்தை முடித்துக் கொண்டு வெற்றிகரமாக திட்டமிட்டபடி பிப்ரவரி ஒன்றாம் தேதி தரையிறங்க ஆயத்தமானார்கள். பூமியைத் தொட பதினாறு நிமிடங்களே இருந்த நிலையில் அந்த சோக சம்பவம் நிகழ்ந்தது. கொலம்பியா விண்கலம் வெடித்துச் சிதறியது நாற்பத்து ஒன்று வயது கல்பனா தேவதையாக விண்ணில் கலந்தார்.முடிவுரை:இந்திய அரசு கல்பனா சாவ்லாவின் சாதனைகளை நினைவு கூறும் வகையில் 2011 ம் ஆண்டு முதல் ஆண்டு தோறும் வீரதீரச் சாதனைகள் புரிந்த பெண்களுக்குக் கல்பனா சாவ்லா விருது வழங்கி கவுரவப்படுத்துகிறது. அந்த விண்வெளி தேவதை நம் வீட்டின் பல குட்டி தேவதைகளுக்குப் பிரியமான முன் உதாரணம்!"},{"question":"कौटिल्य हा कुटनितीज्ञ कोणत्या राजाचा गुरु होता ?","answer":"कौटिल्य हा कुटनितीज्ञ चंद्रगुप्त मौर्य राजाचा गुरु होता ."},{"question":" Waa maxay meeleeye? ","answer":" Meeleeye waxa uu ka mid yahay qaybaha hadalka. Waxa la isticmaalaa ka gadaal magaca ama magac-u-yaalka."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Chiều 31/7, ghi nhận tại Trạm thu phí cao tốc Pháp Vân – Cầu Giẽ (Liên Ninh, Thanh Trì, Hà Nội), nhiều tài xế đi ở làn thu phí không dừng phải phanh gấp để tránh barie. Tài xế Phan Huy Minh lái ô tô BKS 30E- 597.XX rất bức xúc khi barie tại trạm bất ngờ hạ xuống đập trúng ô tô. \\"Khi tôi qua trạm, trên bảng thông báo đã hiện biển số xe và mời qua thì bất ngờ barie hạ xuống đập trúng kính xe. Tôi đã phải phanh gấp để dừng lại, điều này vô cùng nguy hiểm, xe đằng sau có thể đâm trúng xe tôi\\", anh Minh nói. Không kìm nén được bức xúc, anh Minh đã xuống xe cự cãi với nhân viên tại trạm. Gặp lỗi tương tự, tài xế Nguyễn Xuân Thực điều khiển ô tô BKS 30G- 507.XX cho hay, trong tài khoản ePass của anh còn 606.000 đồng nhưng không hiểu sao barie tại trạm không mở. \\"Đây là lần đầu tiên tôi gặp phải lỗi này, không biết lý do làm sao nhưng phải phanh gấp thì khá nguy hiểm\\", tài xế Thực nói. Các lỗi này không chỉ gặp ở các xe ô tô con, xe khách 29 chỗ mang BKS 29B- 085.XX đã phải phanh gấp khi xe gần qua trạm thì barie hạ xuống. Tài xế Thế Anh (Bắc Giang) lập tức nhảy xuống xe bày tỏ bức xúc với nhân viên trạm thu phí. \\"Xe tôi đi qua trạm với tốc độ rất chậm, bảng thông báo đã hiện biển số xe để đi qua thì bất ngờ barie hạ xuống. Trên xe có mấy chục hành khách hò hét khi tôi phanh gấp, quá nguy hiểm\\", anh Thế Anh gay gắt. Còn tài xế Đào Xuân Tài phản ánh, tình trạng trên không chỉ xảy ra ở Trạm thu phí cao tốc Pháp Vân – Cầu Giẽ mà một số trạm cũng bị tương tự. \\"Ở trong tài khoản của tôi còn hơn 160.000 đồng, đi qua trạm thì không thấy báo lỗi gì nhưng barie cứ tự động hạ xuống. Tôi đã gặp lỗi tương tự ở Trạm thu phí này và ở cầu Thăng Long\\", anh Tài phản ánh. Ghi nhận trong khoảng 2 tiếng, tình trạng lỗi tương tự xảy ra với nhiều xe qua trạm. ","answer":"\\"Thu phí không dừng cao tốc liên tục gặp lỗi, tài xế đâm phải barie\\"."},{"question":"Is the tweet below expressing a positive, negative, or neutral sentiment?plzzzz adolph maglna thanina men l control zeft o daba nta 3iiiiiiiiiibb 3lik plzzz","answer":"The tweet is expressing negative sentiment."},{"question":"Akwai hamshakin attajiri a Najeriya?","answer":"Mujallar Forbes ta saka wasu ‘yan Najeriya uku, Aliko Dangote, Abdul Samad Rabiu, da Mike Adenuga a cikin hamshakan attajirin dan kasuwa da masu taimakon jama’a da suka yi kima a cikin jerin attajiran Forbes a duniya."},{"question":"ගැණු අයට සමහර ප්‍රදේශ වල බවලත් උදවිය කියලා  කියනවා.. හෙතුව?","answer":"බව \\" කියන්නෙ මාතෘ බව.. \\"ලත් \\" කියන්නෙ හිමිමාතෘ බවහිමි කියන එක තමයි බව ලත් කියන්නෙ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'buta hati'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bersikap kejam. Contoh ayat: Pencuri itu buta hati kerana sanggup membunuh orang tua yang tidak berdaya itu."},{"question":"漫画サザエさんで、サザエの妹といえば誰？","answer":"ワカメです。"},{"question":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mélòó ló wà ní ìpínlè Èkìtì?","answer":"Ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ mẹ́rìndínlógún ni."},{"question":"Sheeg Tiyaatarka Yaala Magaalada Moqdisho Wadankii Dhisay?","answer":"Tiyaatarka Ku Yaala Magaalada Moqdisho Waxa Dhisay Dalka Shiinaha (China) Waa Uu Ku Faani Jiray Xiligii Somaliya Ee Somaliya Eheed."},{"question":"சிவயோக சுவாமியின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"நீயே உனக்கு நண்பனும் பகைவனும்."},{"question":"Raha jerena ireto fehezanteny roa ireto:Fehezanteny A: \\"Rehefa avy nanao ezaka be aho dia afaka nandalo ny fanadinana.\\"Fehezanteny B: \\"Nandritra ny fitsapana maharitra dia nahavita fahombiazana aho tamin'ny nandalovana ny fitsapana.\\"Mitovy ve ny dikany?","answer":"Tsia tsy mitovy ny dikan' ireo fehezanteny roa ireo satria ilay Fehezanteny B dia efa milaza fahombiazana sahady anefa ilay Fehezanteny A tsy milaza fahombiazana. Noho izany tsy mitovy ny dikan' ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"اكتب سؤال عن الكتب مع الإجابة","answer":"ما اسم أطول رواية لستيفن كينج؟ The Complete and Uncut Edition of The Stand"},{"question":"كنت أقرأ في تويتر ووجدت الجملة التالية 'يعني \\"بموافقتنا\\" لأن دمشق صايرة موسكو'. هل التغريدة السابقة ساخرة أم غير ساخرة؟","answer":"التغريدة السابقة تعبر عن مشاعر ساخرة."},{"question":"كم عنصرا يحتوي الجدول الدوري؟","answer":"يحتوي الجدول الدوري على 118 عنصراً."},{"question":"Mikä on syyhy?","answer":"Syyhy eli scabies on kutiseva ihottuma, jonka aiheuttaa syyhypunkki (Sarcoptes scabiei). Syyhypunkkeja tavataan ihmisen lisäksi myös eläimillä kuten ketuilla, kissoilla ja koirilla. Eläinten syyhypunkit eivät kuitenkaan tartu herkästi ihmiseen tai päinvastoin, ja silloin kun näin käy, ne aiheuttavat korkeintaan lieviä ja itsestään paranevia oireita."},{"question":"Đặt tiêu đề cho đoạn văn sau: PARLACEN được thành lập cuối tháng 10.1991 gồm 6 thành viên ở khu vực Trung Mỹ là Guatemala, El Salvador, Honduras, Nicaragua, Panama và CH Dominica. Những thành viên này đều từng có thời công nhận ngoại giao với Đài Loan nhưng đến nay, trừ Guatemala, đều đã cắt đứt với Đài Loan và chuyển sang thiết lập quan hệ ngoại giao chính thức với Trung Quốc. Vì thế, việc PARLACEN buông bỏ Đài Loan và nghiêng hẳn về Bắc Kinh là diễn biến logic và không thể khác.Quyết định trên của PARLACEN khiến Mỹ và Đài Loan hậm hực bao nhiêu thì lại làm cho Trung Quốc hài lòng bấy nhiêu. Nó là bằng chứng về ảnh hưởng và vị thế ngày càng tăng của Trung Quốc ở vùng vốn từng được coi là \\"sân sau của Mỹ\\". Việc này diễn ra trong bối cảnh Mỹ và đồng minh tăng cường hậu thuẫn Đài Loan cũng như tăng cường hợp tác và liên kết đối phó Trung Quốc ở Ấn Độ Dương - Thái Bình Dương nói chung và trong vấn đề Đài Loan nói riêng.PARLACEN biện giải cho quyết định chấm dứt quy chế quan sát viên của Đài Loan bằng lý do LHQ ngay từ năm 1971 đã chuyển từ công nhận Đài Loan sang công nhận Trung Quốc. Quan điểm này của LHQ đã không cản trở PARLACEN dành cho Đài Loan quy chế quan sát viên nhưng bây giờ lại được viện dẫn làm lý do chính. Qua đó có thể thấy thực chất ở đây là vì lợi ích của PARLACEN trong quan hệ với Trung Quốc. ","answer":"Qua rồi thời thân ái"},{"question":"Eyi ni bawọn aṣaaju Hausa-Fulani ṣe ba Naijiria yii jẹ (16)","answer":"Mo ti mẹnuba ọrọ yii lẹẹkan, ṣugbọn bi a ba tun ṣe alaye ẹ nibi ta a de yii, ko ṣe nnkan kan. Awọn ọna ti awọn Hausa-Fulani gba lati fi mu awa to ku ni Naijiria, ti wọn si sọ wa di bọibọi wọn, ṣugbọn to jẹ nigbẹyin, gbogbo ohun to dara ni Naijiria ni wọn pada bajẹ pata. Mo ti ṣalaye fun yin bi wọn ti mu ipo oṣelu, nitori wọn sọ pe awọn ni idaji Naijiria, ti wọn si fi gbogbo agbara ja lati ri i pe ohun yoowu ti wọn ba fẹẹ pin ni Naijiria, titi dori awọn ọmọ ile-igbimọ aṣofin, awọn ni wọn yoo ko idaji. Nigba ti wọn ti le mu ipo oṣelu bẹẹ, ibi ti wọn tun dojukọ ni ileeṣẹ ologun ati awọn ọmọ ogun Naijiria, wọn nigbagbọ pe bi awọn ba ti ni eleyii, ohun gbogbo bo si awọn lọwọ pata niyẹn. N ni wọn ba bẹrẹ ète buruku, nigbẹyin gbẹyin, wọn ri kinni naa mu, oun naa lo si ba wa debi ti a de loni-in. Bi wọn ṣe ṣe e niyi:Ko too di ọdun 1960, ati ni ibẹrẹ 1960 ti Naijiria gba ominira, awọn Yoruba tiwa ati Ibo ni wọn ni awọn ọga to pọ ju lọ ninu iṣẹ ṣọja. Awọn ọga akọkọ ti wọn wa nigba yẹn ni Aguiyi Ironsi, Samuel Ademulẹgun, Babafẹmi Ogundipẹ, Ralph Ṣodẹinde ati Robert Adeyinka Adebayọ (awọn yii ti n lọ si ipo birigedia ati Mejọ-Jẹnẹra). Awọn ti wọn tẹ le wọn ni awọn ara Kanuri, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn jinna si awọn ti wọn wa niwaju yii diẹ, sibẹ awọn naa ni wọn tẹle wọn. Awọn yii ni Zakariya Maimalari, Umar Lawan ati Kur Muhammed (awọn yii ṣẹṣẹ n lọ si ipo konẹẹli ninu ṣọja nigba yẹn ni). Awọn ti wọn tẹle awọn yii lawọn Lẹfutẹnanti-Konẹẹli bii Emeka Ojukwu, David Ejoor, Yakubu Gowon, George Kurubo, ati awọn mi-in bẹẹ. Lẹyin eyi lo waa kan awọn mejọ (Major), awọn yii si ni alagbara.Ninu awọn mejọ bii mẹẹẹdọgbọn to wa lakọọkọ, mẹẹẹdogun ni ti awọn Ibo, ti Yoruba jẹ mẹjọ, ti ti awọn Hausa si jẹ meji pere. Iyẹn ni pe awọn Ibo lo ni ọga to pọ ju lọ ninu iṣẹ ṣọja ko too di pe Naijiria gba ominira. Igba ti mo n sọ yii, awọn oyinbo lo n ṣe olori ṣọja, wọn o ti i gbe ipo olori to ga ju lọ fawọn ọmọ tiwa. Ṣugbon bi a ti gbominira, to si jẹ awọn Hausa ni olori ijọba, eto ti wọn bẹrẹ ni bi wọn yoo ṣe yi nnkan pada, to fi jẹ awọn Hausa yii ni yoo pada di ọga ninu iṣẹ ologun, bo tilẹ jẹ pe iriri ati imọ wọn ko to ti awọn Yoruba ati Ibo ti wọn ti wa nibẹ tẹlẹ, ti wọn si kawe juwọn lọ. Bi a ti gba ominira, ti akoso awọn ologun bọ sabẹ awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba yii, ọna mẹta ọtọọtọ ni wọn gba lati ba gbogbo eto to wa nilẹ jẹ, ati lati ṣe e bi awọn ọmọ ilẹ Hausa naa yoo ṣe pọ ninu iṣẹ ṣọja yii.Muhammadu Ribadu ni minisita fun eto aabo ilẹ wa nigba naa, abẹ rẹ si ni eto ologun gbogbo wa, ohun to ba sọ lori ọrọ awọn ṣọja ni abẹ ge. Ribadu ti mo n wi yii, igbakeji Sardauna ni ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu wọn, ka ṣaa sọ pe oun gan-an laṣoju Sarduan l’Ekoo. Ki i ka iwe iroyin, ki i gbọ redio tabi ko feti si iroyin kan, kewu ati tira lo n ka, ohun ti oun ati Sardauna ba si ti fẹnu ẹ jona nikan lo n ṣe, tabi ohun to ba wa si i lọkan. Nigba  ti wọn ti ṣeto pe wọn maa gba ipo awọn ọga ṣọja kuro lọwọ awọn eeyan tiwa, ohun ti Ribadu dojukọ niyẹn, ọna mẹta ti wọn si la kalẹ naa lo lo lati ṣe nnkan ti wọn fẹ. Akọkọ ni pe wọn faake kọri pe ki i ṣe iwe nikan ni wọn yoo maa fi gbaayan sinu iṣẹ ṣọja mọ, bi eto oṣelu ṣe wa ni wọn aa maa lo.Eyi ni pe nigba tawọn ti wọn wa lati ilẹ Hausa ti le ko idaji ninu awọn aṣofin Naijiria, bi wọn ba fẹẹ gbaayan sinu iṣẹ ologun Naijiria naa, idaji lawọn gbọdọ ko. Iyẹn ni pe idaji awọn yoowu ti wọn ba fẹẹ gba sinu iṣẹ ṣọja, ilẹ Hausa ni wọn gbọdọ ti wa. Wọn fa ọrọ yii lọ, wọn fa a bọ, wọn pe orukọ eto jibiti ati irẹjẹ yii ni kota (Quota system), nigba to si ti jẹ awọn ni wọn pọ ju nileegbimọ aṣofin, kia ni wọn sọ ọrọ naa dofin. Ofin naa wa titi doni pe ti wọn ba fẹẹ gba ọgọrun-un ọmọ si ṣọja, ẹyin naa kuku mọ, aadọta lo maa wa lati ilẹ Hausa. Wọn tiẹ ti sun un siwaju debii pe o le jẹ ọgọta tabi aadọrin ni wọn maa rọ sinu iṣẹ naa, ti wọn aa fun Yoruba ati Ibo ni diẹ, nitori isọlẹnu lasan. Kota yii ni ibẹrẹ eto bawọn araabi yii ṣe ba iṣẹ ologun Naijiria jẹ titi di bi a ti n sọ yii.Ohun keji ti wọn ṣe ni lati din eto bi wọn ṣe maa gba wọn siṣẹ naa ku. Tẹlẹ, bi ẹnikẹni ba fẹẹ wọ iṣẹ ṣọja ti yoo di ọga nibẹ, yoo ti ka iwe mẹwaa rẹ jade, yoo si paasi daadaa ninu gbogbo idanwo to ba ṣe. Tẹlẹtẹlẹ, bi ọmọ kan ba yege ninu iṣẹ yii, o ni iye maaki to gbọdọ gba ninu idanwo to ba ṣe, ṣaaṣa awọn ọmọ Hausa yii ni wọn le de iru maaki naa, koda bo ti le wu ki wọn kọ wọn to. Meji ni iṣẹ to maa n ja wọn kulẹ ju lọ, iyẹn naa ni ede oyinbo ati iṣẹ iṣiro. Ẹnikẹni ti ko ba si ti gba to ọgọta ninu ọgọrun-un, iru ẹni bẹẹ ko ṣee mu lọ sinu iṣẹ ologun, awọn oyinbo ti wọn n dari wọn tẹlẹ ko tilẹ ni i jẹ ko wọle. Ṣugbọn nigba to kan awọn araabi yii, to jẹ Hausa ni minisita eto aabo, to jẹ akọwe agba fun iṣẹ ologun, Hausa naa ni, to jẹ minisita kekere fun iṣẹ ṣọja, Hausa naa ni, kia lawọn yi kinni naa pada, wọn si gbe maaki tiwọn jade.Wọn ni wọn o le fi maaki ọmọ ilẹ Hausa we ti awọn ọmọ ilẹ Yoruba ati ilẹ Ibo, pe ti ọmọ Hausa ba ti le gba maaki bii ogoji tabi marundinlogoji, ko sohun to de ti o le di ọọfisa ninu ṣọja, eyi ti ko ba ti i mọ, aa maa ka a bo ba de ile-ẹkọ awọn ologun. Bo ṣe di pe awon ọmọ ilẹ  Hausa ti wọn o le gboorun ipo ọọfisa ninu iṣẹ ṣọja laelae bẹrẹ si i di ọmọleewe ologun, ti wọn si n di ọọfisa ti wọn ba jade, lai mọ kinni kan. Oun la n ri loni-in yii, ẹyin naa kuku n ri i. Ọpọ awọn ọga ṣọja lati ilẹ Hausa, bi wọn ba sọ ede oyinbo bayii, eeyan yoo fẹrẹ sa lọ. Wọn ko fi ṣeka, nigba ti wọn o gbọ. Bẹẹ o yẹ ki wọn gbọ ki wọn too de iru ipo ti wọn wa, ṣugbọn eto irẹjẹ tawọn baba wọn ti ṣe silẹ fun wọn ko jẹ, ko sẹni to laya ninu awọn ti wọn n ṣejọba lati yi kinni naa pada, titi dori ẹgbọn tiwa, Bọọda Ṣẹgun, toun naa mọ pe kinni ọhun o daa.Ọna kẹta tawọn aṣaaju Hausa yii fi bẹrẹ si i ko awọn ọmọ wọn sinu iṣẹ ṣọja, ti wọn si n fi wọn ṣe ọga ni lati maa lọ sileewe girama kaakiri ilẹ Hausa, ki wọn si ni kawọn ọmọ ibẹ maa mura lati di ṣọja, bi wọn ti maa n ṣe kinni naa aa ya yin lẹnu bẹ ẹ ba gbọ. Nigba ti Yakubu Gowon ṣẹṣẹ jade nileewe awọn ṣọja, wọn maa n mu un lẹyin lọ sawọn ileewe yii, wọn aa ni ki wọn wo ohun tawọn naa le da bi wọn ba wọ iṣẹ sọja. Ni bii 1961 yẹn, nigba ti wọn fẹẹ gba awọn ọmọ si ṣọja, Tanko Galadima to jẹ minisita abẹle fun iṣẹ ṣọja nigba naa mu Gowon dani, wọn lọ si Government College, ni Bida, nibẹ ni wọn ti n sọ fawọn ọmọọleewe ibẹ pe ki wọn waa wọ iṣẹ sọja, ki wọn le da bii Gowon to ba ya. Awọn ti wọn ba nileewe nijọ naa, lara wọn ni Ibrahim Babangida, AbdulSalami Abubakar, Maman Vatsa, Garba Duba, Gado Nasko, Sani Bello, Muhammed Magoro, atawọn mi-in.Gbogbo awọn ti mo darukọ yii ni wọn pada waa di ọga ninu iṣẹ ologun, ti ninu wọn si di olori orilẹ-ede. Ohun ti ko jẹ ki awọn mi-in ninu wọn ni sabukeeti iwe mẹwaa ree, nitori wọn tẹle awọn ti wọn waa gba wọn yii lọ. Loootọ ni wọn ti fẹẹ jade, ṣugbọn wọn ko ṣedanwo oniwee mẹwaa jade. Bi nnkan ṣe buru to niyẹn. Bawọn eeyan yii ṣe fi ọbọ lọ wa to niyẹn. Bi awọn ti wọn lọ si Government College, Bida yii, ti n ṣe tiwọn, bẹẹ lawọn mi-in mu Zak Maimalari pe ko waa lọọ ba wọn sọrọ ni Barewa College, lara awọn ti wọn gbọ ọrọ lẹnu oun ni Muritala Muhammed. Bi wọn ba ti gbọ ọrọ bayii, wọn n lọ sinu iṣẹ ṣọja niyẹn. Bayii lawọn eeyan yii bẹrẹ si i rọ awọn ọmọ wọn sinu ṣọja lai kun oju oṣuwọn:  wọn mọwe wọn o mọwe, wọn paasi wọn o paasi, nibi ti ọrọ wa ti n dojuru si i niyẹn.E tun pade mi lọsẹ to n bọ si i"},{"question":"Манас эпосу 📚―Манас эпосун тарыхый жактан изилдөөчү, б. а. эпосто баяндалган жер суу, адам аттарын тарыхый окуялар менен байланыштырып изилдеп, Манастын прототиби 9-кылымда жашаган Яглакар хан деп божомолдогон советтик тарыхчы, этнограф?а) В. В. Радлов б) Арефьев Анатолийв) П. Н. Берков г) А. Н. Бернштам","answer":"Туура жообу г) А. Н. Бернштам варианты болот."},{"question":"中国有哪些著名的现代科技？","answer":"中国有高铁、航天、人工智能等著名的现代科技。"},{"question":"Аалы Туткучев ким?","answer":"Аалы Туткучев- төкмө акын. Таласта туулуп өскөн. Ырчылык жана комузчулук жайы бар. Кыргыздын эмгек сиңирген эл артисти."},{"question":"Dans quel pays la première bombe atomique a-t-elle été utilisée au combat ?","answer":"Au Japon"},{"question":"ليس لدي وقت لقراءة كل المقال التالي. إذا سمحت قم بتلخيصه: فالكثير من النوادي الرياضية يقوموا بتخصيص برامج متاحة للأطفال، ولكن عدد قليل منهم يوفرون برامج خاصة للبالغين والمراهقين. لذلك عليك أن تبحث عن شخص يمتلك الخبرة في العمل مع البالغين. كما أنه من المهم أن تتأكد أن شخصياتهم تتناسب مع شخصيتك. فسوف تكون بحاجة لشخص قادر على الاستماع وإعطائك الإرشادات اللازمة لتحسين سباحتك. فعلى سبيل المثال تعتبر مجموعة السباحين المحترفين بالولايات المتحدة الأمريكية بمثابة برنامجاً جيداً لمن فوق العشرين عاماً ويسعون للانضمام لمجموعة سباحة. كما يتنوع برنامجهم ما بين التعامل مع مبتدئين بشكل كامل لآخرين أكثر احترافاً.  ربما تقدم صالة الألعاب المحلية أو النادي الرياضي أيضاً شيئاً مشابهاً، وحينها من الممكن أن يكون ذلك بديلاً أفضل. فسوف تجد أن كثير من المنشآت القريبة منك بها مسابح. لذلك قم بجولة بحث لإيجاد المسبح الجيد الذي يقابل أسعاره مقدرتك المادية. فإذا كنت تلتزم بشيء يتطلب جهداً بدنياً ربما يكون من الأفضل لك لو استعنت بشخص يساعدك. ليس من الضروري لهذا الشخص أن يشاركك أداء التمارين، ولكن سيتمحور دورهم بوضوح حول تقديم التشجيع لك حينما يتملكك الإحباط. كما أن وجود شخص على استعداد للالتزام معك بروتين سباحة يعتبر إضافة رابحة من صديق جيد..","answer":"يسعدني مساعدتك في ذلك. هنا تلخيص للمقال: استعن بمدرب سباحة. انضم لمجموعة سباحين. انضم لصالة ألعاب بها مسبح. اطلب العون من أحد أصدقائك.."},{"question":"2023දී දැවයෙන් කරන ලද චන්ද්‍රිකාවක් ගුවන්ගත කිරීමට සූදානම් රට","answer":"ජපානය"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:“ఆహా !. యాదవవంశ శ్రేష్ఠుడగు శ్రీకృష్ణుడు తన సతీమణియగు సాక్షాత్తు లక్ష్మీదేవియైన రుక్మిణి ఏమనుకుంటుందో అని కూడ భావింపక, తాను ఎదురుగా వెళ్ళి సంతోషముతో మిత్రుడైన కుచేలుని కౌటిలించుకున్నాడు. సముచితమైన సేవలతో ఆయనను సంతృప్తిని కావించాడు. ఈ బ్రాహ్మణుడెంతగి అదృష్టవంతుడో కదా !” అని అంతఃపుర కాంతలు ఆశ్చర్యముతో భావించిరి.","answer":"చ. తన మృదుతల్పమందు పనితామణి యైన రమాలలాను సాందును నెదఁగాఁ దలంపక యడుప్రవరుం డెదురేఁగి మోచముందనుకంగఁ గౌఁగిలించి యుచితక్రియలం బరితుష్టుఁ జేయుచునవినయమునన్ భజించె; ధరణీసురుఁ దెంతటి భాగ్యవంతుదో ?"},{"question":"Айдаркан Алмамбетти ордого калтырмакчы болгон чечимди Көкчө кабыл алдыбы?а) Жок б) билбеймв) ооба г) кайдыгер болду","answer":"Айдаркан Алмамбетти ордого калтырмакчы болгон чечимди Көкчө кабыл алды. Туура жообу в) варианты болот."},{"question":"හැම්ල්ට් රචනා  කළේ කවුද?","answer":"\\"හැම්ලට්\\" ලියා  ඇත්තේ සුප්‍රසිද්ධ ඉංග්‍රීසි නාට්‍ය රචකයෙකු සහ කවියෙකු වන විලියම් ෂේක්ස්පියර් විසිනි. එය ඔහුගේ වඩාත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ හා නිතර රඟ දක්වන නාට්‍යවලින් එකකි. 1600 දී පමණ ලියා ඇති \\"හැම්ලට්\\" යනු හැම්ලට්ගේ පියා ඝාතනය කර, සිංහාසනය ලබා, හැම්ලට්ගේ මව සමඟ විවාහ වූ ඔහුගේ මාමා ක්ලෝඩියස්ට එරෙහිව හැම්ලට් කුමරු පළිගැනීමේ ගවේෂණයේ කතාව පවසන ඛේදවාචකයකි. මෙම නාට්‍යය ද්‍රෝහීකම, පළිගැනීම්, ව්‍යභිචාරය සහ සදාචාර දූෂණය යන තේමාවන් ගවේෂණය කරන අතර එහි සංකීර්ණ චරිත නිරූපණය සහ මනෝවිද්‍යාත්මක තීක්ෂ්ණ බුද්ධියේ ගැඹුර සඳහා සමරනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta casa'in da biyar a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 95"},{"question":"Ukuba awuhlali, ubuya kuyigcina phi ihempe yakho? Iinketho:  idrowa , isikhwama , phantsi , igumbi lokunxiba , ikhabhathi Hmmm- makhe ndicinge.","answer":"Umntu ugcina ihempe kwisutikheyisi. Iisutikheyisi zisetyenziselwa ukugcina iitshati xa zingahlali. Ngoko ke, impendulo yile, ibhegi."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Espen Arvesen (ur. 25 kwietnia 1980 r.) - norweski snowboardzista. Nie startował na igrzyskach olimpijskich. Zajął 46 miejsce w halfpipe'ie na mistrzostwach świata w ","answer":"Madonna di Campiglio. Najlepsze wyniki w Pucharze Świata osiągnął w sezonie 2000/2001 kiedy to zajął 65 miejsce w klasyfikacji generalnej. Jest brązowym medalistą mistrzostw świata juniorów w hlafpipe'ie z 1999 r."},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra sa mifanipa-kevitra sa tsy misy ifandraisany ireto fehezanteny roa ireto?Fehezanteny A: Matory any an-dakozia ny ankizy amin'izao.Fehezanteny B: Efa elaela ihany izay ny ankizy no natory tao an-dakozia.","answer":"Mitovy hevitra ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"नेपालको गढजी माई को बारेमा।","answer":"यो तीर्थस्थल हिन्दू देवीलाई समर्पित शक्ति (शक्तिपीठ) को धेरै सीटहरू मध्ये एक हो। बारा जिल्लाको महागडीमाई नगरपालिकामा रहेको मन्दिरमा पाँच वर्षमा एकपटक लाग्ने मेलामा ठूलो संख्यामा पशुबलि चढाइन्छ । एक महिना लामो मेला माघ शुक्ल सप्तमी (डिसेम्बर जनवरी) मा सुरु हुन्छ। गढी माईले मन्दिरमा भेटी चढाउँदा आफ्ना भक्तको मनोकामना पूरा हुने विश्वासका साथ नेपाल र भारतबाट हजारौं मानिसहरु मन्दिर दर्शन गर्न आउने गर्दछन् ।"},{"question":"ગુજરાતી કઢી કેવી રીતે બનાવવી રેસીપી જણાવો.","answer":"સામગ્રી:દહીં કે જાડી છાશ, ચણાનો લોટ કે બેસન, મેથીના દાણા, લીમડાના પાન કે કડી પત્તા, લીલું મરચું, હળદર (પીળો રંગ જોઈએ તો), મીઠું, હિંગ, લવીંગ, ગોળ.કૃતિ:દહીં માં પાણી ઉમેરી તેની ઘટ્ટ છાશ બનાવો.તેમાં ચણાનો લોટ ધીરે ધીરે ઉમેરો અને ઝેરવતા રહો જેથી ગઠ્ઠા ના રહી જાય.આ મિશ્રણને ગળણીથી ગાળી લો.એક જાડી તપેલીમાં ઘી લો અને મેથી, લવીંગ, રાઈ, હિંગ, લીમડા, લીલા મરચાંનો વઘાર કરો.તેમાં તૈયાર કરેલ છાશ ઉમેરો.મીઠું અને ગોળ ઉમેરી ઉભરા શરુ થવા દો. (ચમચાથી હલાવી ઉભરો શાંત પાડવો)દહીં એકરસ થઈ જાય અને ઉભરો શમી મિશ્રણ ખદબદે ત્યારે સમજવું કઢી તૈયાર થઈ."},{"question":"问：李白被誉为什么？","answer":"答：李白被誉为\\"诗仙\\"，因为他的诗才横溢，想象力丰富，语言优美。"},{"question":"س84 - من هو القائد الذي قاد المسلمين في معركة عينجالوت ؟","answer":"ج84 - سيف الدين قطز"},{"question":"U sheeg naftaada kheer?","answer":"U sheeg naftaada …..1. In Ujeedo cad laguu abuuray oo laguu keenay Aduunkan2. In Alle uu had iyo jeer kula jiro3. In aad tahay qof Muhiim ah4. In aad leedahay karti 5. In wax kasta ay hagaagayaan6. In culays kasta uu ka dambeeyo fudayd7. In aad u qalanto waxyaabo waaweyn8. In aad gaari karto meel sare9. In wax kasta Aduunkan ay yihiin ku meel gaar oo aysan waarayn10. In aad tahay qof degan oo dulqaad leh11. In aad noqon karto qofka aad rabto12. In wanaag badan kuu dambeeyo13. In aad wax qaban kartid, hal abuurna leedahay14. In aad Qurux badan tahay, Sharafna leedahay15. In aad tahay qof firfircoon oo Hawlkar ah16. In aad tahay qof adag oo go’aan leh17. In aad sameyn karto isbedel dhab ah18. In waqtigu yahay HADAQof kasta wuu isla hadlaa, Maskaxda bini’aadanku marnaba faaruq ma noqoto, mar kasta waxbaa ka dhex socda. Xusuusnow hadalada aad iskula hadasho, wixi aad u sheegto naftaada maalin kasta waxay kuu noqonayaan in ay kor kuu qaadaan ama hoos kuu dhigaan. Adigu ha is niyad jabin, Adigu hoos ha isu dhigin, Adigu nafta ha ku ridin rejo la’aan, Adigu ha is dhiibin. Waxaan Aaminaa wixi aan Nafteena u sheegno. U fakir si positive ah. Wax kasta ka eeg dhanka wanaagsan. U sheeg nafta wax wanaagsan.U sheeg nafta Kheyr. "},{"question":"විල්හෙල්ම් වුන්ඩ් කවුද?","answer":"විලියම් මැක්ස්මිලන් වුන්ඩ් (16 අගෝස්තු 1832 – 31 අගෝස්තු 1920) ජර්මන් ජාතික වෛද්‍යවරයෙකි.මෙතුමා මනෝ විද්‍යාඥයෙක් දාර්ශනිකයෙක් හා මහාචාර්‍යවරයෙකු ලෙසද ප්‍රකටය.මනෝ විද්‍යාවේ පියා යන විරුදාවලි නාමයෙන් මොහු හදුන්වනු ලබයි.ලොව පහලවූ ප්‍රතම මනෝ විද්‍යාඥයා විල්හෙල්ම් වුන්ඩ් ලෙස සැලකේ.එයට හේතුව මනෝ විද්‍යව නම් විෂය බිහිකිරීම හා මෙම විෂය නාමය හදුන්වා දෙන්නේ වුන්ඩ් විසින් බැවිනි. වුන්ඩ් විශාල සේවයක් මනෝ විද්‍යාවේ දියුණුව වෙනුවෙන් සිදු කළේය.එම නිසා පර්යේෂණාත්මක මනෝ විද්‍යාවේ පියා යනුවෙන් හදුන්වයි\\". 1876 දී ඔහු ප්‍රතම මනෝ විද්‍යා පර්යේෂණාගාරය ජ්මනියේ ලයිම්ෂිප් විශ්ව විද්‍යාලයේ දී ඇරඹීයˌමෙමගින් මනෝ විද්‍යාව ස්වාධින විෂයක් ලෙස වර්ධනය වීම ඇරඹින.මනෝ විද්‍යා පර්යේෂණාගාරයක් ඇරඹීම මගින් වුන්ඩ්ට ආගමික පිළිගැනීම් වල යථාර්තය සොයාබැලීමට මානසික රෝග හදුනා ගැනීමට අසාමාන්‍ය වර්‍යා හදුනා ගැනීමට මොළයට ඇතිවන හානි නිසා සිදුවන මානසික රෝග තත්වයන් ආදිය හදුනාගැනීමට ද ඒ පිළිබදව විද්‍යානුකූකූල අර්තකතනයන් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට හැකිවිය.තවද මනෝ විද්‍යාව ස්වාධින විෂයක් ලෙස වර්ධනය කිරීමට හැකිවිය.මීට පෙර දර්ශනය තුල පැවති උප විෂයක් ලෙස මනස පිළිබද දර්ශනය නමික් පැවති මනස පිළිබද අධ්‍යනය විධිමත් අධ්‍යනයක් වන්නේ වුන්ඩ්ගේ දායකත්වය නිසාය.වුන්ඩ් තම අධ්‍යන වලදී මනසේ ත්‍රියාකාරීත්වය සිතීම සංජානනය යනු කරුණු කෙරේ අවධානය යොමු කළේය.වර්තමාන ප්‍රජානන මනෝ විද්‍යාෙව් සාකඡ්චා වන ප්‍රධාන සංකල්පයන්ද මේවා වෙයි. වුන්ඩ් ගේ අදහස් පසුව ප්‍රජානන මනෝවිද්‍යාව බිහිවීමට පදනම්විය."},{"question":"Tinawag ng kaibigan ko ang sarili niya bilang isang \\"plantita\\". Ano ang ibig sabihin nito?","answer":"Ang \\"plantita\\" ay pagsasama ng salitang \\"plant\\" sa Ingles at \\"tita\\". Ginagamit ito upang sabihin na mahilig mag-alaga ng halaman ang isang kababaihan. Sumikat ang salitang ito noong kasagsagan ng COVID-19 Pandemic dahil dumami ang mga taong nag-alaga ng halaman habang nasa lockdown."},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية: وأنهى هنري مسيرته الكروية عام 2014، وهو كبير هدافي أرسنال على مر العصور برصيد 228 هدفا، بعد أن","answer":"خاض 123 مباراة دولية وأحرز 51 هدفا مع المنتخب."},{"question":"Kaggle nedir, kısaca açıkla? ","answer":"Yaklaşık olarak son 10 sene içinde ‘veri bilimi’ oldukça revaçta olan bir araştırma/çalışma alanı olarak ortaya çıkmıştır. Kaggle’da bu süreç içerisinde oluşmuş ‘Veri Bilimi Eviniz’ sloganıyla ortaya çıkmış bir platformdur.  Kaggle, ilk olarak makine öğrenmesi yarışmaları sunan bir platform olarak kurulmuştur. Genellikle yarışmalarda ilk N ekibe belli ödüller olabilir. Son gelişmeler ile birlikte Kaggle sadece yarışma değil aynı zamanda eğitim materyalleri de sunmaya başlamıştır. Eğer makine öğrenmesiyle ilgileniyorsanız hem yarışmalar hem de bu materyaller modelleme yetilerinizi güçlendirme konusunda oldukça faydalı olabilecek bir platform olarak kullanıcılara hizmet vermektedir."},{"question":"بحثت في الإنترنت عن إجابة لهذا السؤال ما هو الإسم الحقيقي للرئيس الجزائري السابق ((هواري بو مدين)) ؟. لكني لم أجد إجابة ، هل تستطيع الإجابة عليه؟","answer":"بالتأكيد الإجابة الصحيحة هي محمد بو خروبة."},{"question":"Recomiéndame un desayuno Colombiano muy tradicional.","answer":"Dependiendo de la región de Colombia, vas a tener muchas opciones. Te recomendamos uno de la región del eje cafetero, queso con chocolate (una bebida que se hace con chocolate y agua de panela) y arepa paisa con huevos revueltos."},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Liban?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Liban mu ngi tudd Beyrouth."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిముగింపు సరుకు విలువను ఎలా లెక్కగడతారు ?","answer":"కన్సైన్మెంటు మీద పంపిన సరుకులో కొంత భాగము అమ్ముడు కాకుండా మిగిలిపోవచ్చు. ముగింపు సరుకును విలువ కట్టడంలో అసలు ఖరీదు లేదా మార్కెట్ ధర ఏది తక్కువైతే ఆ ప్రకారం విలువ కట్టవలెను. సరుకు విలువను లెక్కించేటప్పుడు కేవలం కొన్న ధరకే కాకుండా సరుకుపై పెట్టిన పునరావృతం కాని ఖర్చులు లెక్కలోకి తీసుకోవాలి. వాటిని ముగింపు సరుకు విలువకు కలపాలి. పునరావృతం కాని ఖర్చులు అంటే కన్సైనార్ నుంచి కన్సైనీ గిడ్డంగికి చేరే వరకు పెట్టిన ఖర్చులు. ఉదా : రవాణా, ప్యాకింగ్, రవాణాలో భీమా, కస్టమ్స్ డ్యూటీ, ఆక్ట్రాయ్, బండి, కూలీ మొదలైనవి కన్సైనీ ఖర్చులను లెక్కలోకి తీసుకొనరాదు."},{"question":"Laburbildu artikulua.  Barack Obamaren atzean San Franciscon, gizon bat oihuka ari zaio lehendakariari: \\"Deportazioa geldiarazteko boterea duzu\\". Obamak, haserre, diskurtsoa eten zuen eta esan zuen ez zuela aginpiderik. Estatu Batuak \\"legezko nazio bat\\" direla. Nork du arrazoia? Immigrazio lege federalak hainbat egoeratan banandu edo deportatzeko eskubidea du, hala nola, herrialdean legez kanpo egotea, baimen legalaren iraupena gainditzea, estatutu penalak haustea edo beste hainbat delitu, prozesu judizialaren ondoren. Baina administrazioak eskubidea du arauak betearazteko. Nahiz eta lege-maisuek defentsa neurrigabekoak aitortzen dituzten. Obamak imigrazioa aipatu duenean, protestatu dute ez duela askorik egiten. Ju Hongek 24 urte ditu, Berkeleyko Kaliforniako Unibertsitateko graduatua da, eta Asiako Ikasleak dira, Hezkuntzaren Bidez Etorkinen Eskubideak Bultzatzen dituztenak, ASPIRE taldeko kidea. Asteleheneko bileraren ondoren, biltzarkideek botoa aldatzeko bozketa egin zuten. Hongek eta bere taldeak Obamaren atxiloketak geldiarazi nahi dituzte. Beldurra eragiten duen kultura bat sortzen ari omen da paperik gabekoen artean. Eta familia sakabanatuak daude. Josh Earnest lehendakariaren bozeramaileak esan du: \\"lehendakariak ez du eskumen hori\\". \\"Uste dut lehendakariak argi eta garbi esan zuela: ez dago gazte honen kezka asetuko duen agintzarik\\". Baina horrek ez du konbentzitzen May Liang, ASPIREren antolatzailea. CNNri asteartean esan zion uste zuela Obamak \\"gezurra esan zuela\\" deportatuak gelditzeko ahalmena ez zuela. Astelehenean, taldeak \\"analisi juridikoa\\" eskatu zion deportatuak ez geldiarazteko. Hala ere, Obamak eutsi egin zion. \\"Irteera errazena da oihu egitea eta zerbait egin dezakedala itxuratzea gure legeak hautsiz\\", esan zion Obama-k Hong-i astelehenean. Eta zer naiz ni?","answer":"San Franciscon, gizon bat oihu eginez protestatu zuen Barack Obamaren aurka, lehendakariari eskatuz deportazioa geldiaraztea. Obama erantzun zuen ez zuela horretarako aginpiderik eta Estatu Batuak \\"legezko nazio bat\\" direla aitortu zuen. Immigrazioaren legeak baimendu egiten du pertsonak deportatu edo herrialdetik kanporatu ditzakeela hainbat arrazoirengatik. Hala ere, administrazioak nola bete ditzaken arau horiek erabak dezake. Ju Hong, Berkeleyko Unibertsitateko ikasle bat, eta bere taldeak, ASPIRE, Obamak atxiloketak geldiarazi ditzakeela sinistu dute. Josh Earnest, lehendakariaren bozeramaileak, alde batera uzten du Obamak ez duela horretarako eskumenik. May Liang, ASPIREren antolatzaileak, alde kontrako iritzia du, esanez Obamak \\"gezurra esan zuela\\". Obama, berriz, legeen errespetua azpimarratu zuen protestatzaileari erantzunez."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Buah-buahan mengandungi __ yang penting kepada tubuh badan kita Pilihan:  A) langkah-langkahB) ciri-ciriC) wakil-wakil D)  zat-zat","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D)  zat-zat"},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Gần một thập kỷ đã trôi qua kể từ khi Chevrolet giới thiệu Colorado thế hệ thứ hai tại Triển lãm ô tô Los Angeles 2013. Tuy nhiên, mãi đến nay hãng xe Mỹ mới ra mắt thế hệ mới của mẫu bán tải cỡ trung này nhằm tăng sức cạnh tranh với đối thủ chính của nó là Ford Ranger mới – cũng là mẫu bán tải bán chạy nhất Việt Nam. Bước sang thế hệ thứ ba, Chevrolet Colorado mới sử dụng thiết kế lấy cảm hứng từ \\"người anh em\\" Silverado, tuy nhiên vẫn mang một số nét đặc trưng riêng. Phần đầu xe nổi bật nhờ những đường nét góc cạnh hơn, đi kèm toàn bộ cản trước gân guốc và cơ bắp. Lưới tản nhiệt sơn đen trong khi cản trước sử dụng nhiều khe và hốc hút gió để cải thiện khả năng làm mát động cơ.   Cụm đèn chiếu sáng trên xe bán tải Colorado nay đã gọn gàng hơn. Vòm bánh trước/sau bổ sung bộ ốp vòm có tính thẩm mỹ cao hơn. Chưa dừng lại ở đó, nắp ca-pô và hai bên sườn xe đều có các đường gân mang đến diện mạo thể thao, hầm hố hơn cho xe. Đuôi xe có cụm đèn hậu LED bắt mắt hơn, với hệ thống ống xả hướng sang bên phải thay vì hướng ra sau. Xe có kích thước dài x cao lần lượt là 5.410 x 1.795 mm và chiều dài cơ sở 3.337 mm, Chevrolet Colorado 2023 về cơ bản có kích thước không chênh lệch nhiều so với đối thủ Ranger 2023 khi mẫu bán tải của Ford có chiều dài 5.320 mm, cao 1.875 mm cùng trục cơ sở đạt mức 3.270 mm. So với thế hệ cũ, Colorado mới có nhiều lựa chọn bộ mâm thể thao và trẻ trung hơn.    Nội thất của Chevrolet Colorado mới nay đã hiện đại và có độ hoàn thiện cao hơn rất nhiều. Táp-lô thiết kế không cầu kỳ nhưng gây chú ý nhờ màn hình thông tin giải trí trung tâm kích thước 11,3 inch. Phía sau vô-lăng là màn hình thông số kỹ thuật 8 inch. Cửa gió điều hòa chuyển từ hình chữ nhật sang hình tròn lạ mắt hơn. Về trang bị, Chevrolet Colorado thế hệ mới sẽ khiến nhiều người dùng bất ngờ khi áp dụng nhiều công nghệ hơn. Phiên bản tiêu chuẩn có mở cửa không cần chìa khóa và hệ thống âm thanh 6 loa. Bản Z71 có ghế ngồi bọc vải giả da kèm đường chỉ khâu màu tương phản, riêng bản ZR2 có ghế trước sưởi và chỉnh điện 8 hướng ở ghế lái.    Một số tiện nghi khác dưới dạng tùy chọn gồm sạc điện thoại thông minh không dây, hệ thống điều hòa tự động hai vùng, cửa sổ trời,… Màn hình thông tin giải trí trung tâm còn có thể hiển thị hiệu suất Offroad của xe cùng các thông số chính giúp người lái đưa ra lựa chọn phù hợp với địa hình vận hành xe. Xe có ba tùy chọn động cơ khác nhau. Đầu tiên làn khối động cơ dầu 4 xy lanh, dung tích 2.7L tăng áp mới vốn được chia sẻ với chiếc Silverado, cho công suất 237 mã lực và mô-men xoắn 351 Nm. Mạnh mẽ hơn là bản Z71 có cho công suất 310 mã lực và mô-men xoắn 528 Nm. Cuối cùng là động cơ dầu, dung tích 2.7L tăng áp hiệu suất cao trên ZR2 nhưng các thông số vẫn tương tự bản Z71. Tất cả đều kết hợp với hộp số tự động 8 cấp.    Công nghệ an toàn của xe có thể kể đến như phanh khẩn cấp tự động, cảnh báo va chạm trước, phanh khẩn cấp với người đi bộ trước, hỗ trợ giữ làn, cảnh báo lệch làn,… Giá bán của Chevrolet Colorado mới hiện vẫn chưa được công bố. Hãng xe Mỹ cho biết, mẫu bán tải này sẽ có mặt tại các đại lý vào nửa đầu năm 2023. Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/xe-ban-tai-chevrolet-colorado-the-he-moi-lo-dien-1382588.ngnNguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/xe-ban-tai-chevrolet-colorado-the-he-moi-lo-dien-1382588.ngn ","answer":"Xe bán tải Chevrolet Colorado thế hệ mới lộ diện"},{"question":"Quem recebeu o primeiro transplante de coração no Brasil?","answer":"O primeiro transplante de coração no Brasil foi realizado, no lavrador mato-grossense, João Ferreira da Cunha. A cirurgia foi realizada pela Equipe do Cirurgião Euryclides de Jesus Zerbini, no Hospital das Clínicas da Universidade de São Paulo (HC-USP), em 26 de Maio de 1968. Este transplante também é considerado o primeiro transplante de coração da América Latina."},{"question":"Đơn vị thi công có gửi tôi phương án lắp đặt hệ tủ bếp chữ L. Tủ dưới cao 75 cm, sâu 40 cm, ngang 3m. Tủ trên làm kịch trần, khoảng cách giữa hai tủ là 60 cm. Tôi hơi phân vân về kích thước này, vì các thành viên trong nhà đều cao: tôi và các con cao trên 1m7, thấp nhất là vợ tôi - 1m6.Liệu có công thức tính kích thước tủ bếp để thuận tiện khi sử dụng không? Mong được tư vấn!","answer":"Chào bạn! Bếp là không gian rất quan trọng đối với một ngôi nhà. Khi thiết kế, thi công khu vực này cần đảm bảo các yếu tố như: thông thoáng, đủ sáng và tiện dụng. Trong đó, hệ tủ được coi là \\"linh hồn\\" của gian bếp, hỗ trợ đắc lực cho công việc nấu nướng.Tùy theo kiến trúc và công năng mà gia chủ mong muốn, tủ sẽ được bố trí sao cho phù hợp. Hệ tủ bếp thông thường có tủ trên và dưới: tủ trên được treo vào tường hoặc trần, tủ dưới đặt ở sàn nhà. Các kiểu thường thấy là hình chữ I, L, U... , vật liệu sử dụng cũng khá phong phú và đa dạng.Trong trường hợp câu hỏi của bạn, thì không có một công thức chung nào có thể tính ra kích thước tủ bếp phù hợp với mọi gia đình. Thay vào đó, mỗi không gian và người dùng khác nhau sẽ có cách bố trí và lắp đặt khác nhau."},{"question":"ఖడ్గ తిక్కనకు సంబంధించిన చాటు వృత్తాంతాన్ని తెలపండి.","answer":"కవి ఎవరో తెలియని ఉన్న ఖడ్గ తిక్కనకు సంబంధించిన వృత్తాంతం ఒకటి ఉంది. ఖడ్గ తిక్కన మనుమసిద్ధి పక్షాన నిలిచి కాటమరాజు నెదిరించిన మహావీరుడు. అతడు యుద్ధంలో భీకరంగా పోరాడి తన సేనలు చెల్లాచెదురై పారిపోగా యుద్ధాన్ని విరమించి ఇంటిముఖం పట్టాడు. అతడి భార్య నులకమంచాన్ని అడ్డుగా పెట్టి దానిమీద పసుపుముద్ద నుంచి ప్రక్కన నీళ్ళ చెంబు పెట్టిందట. ఇదేమిటని అడగ్గా“పగరకు వెన్నిచ్చినచోనగరేనిను మగతనంపు నాయకు లెందున్ముగురాడు వార మైతిమివగపేటికి జలకమాడ వచ్చిన చోటన్.అని ఎత్తిపొడుపు మాటలు మాట్లాడింది. ఆ తరువాత ఖడ్గతిక్కన తల్లి అన్నంలో విరిగిన పాలు పోసిందట. ఇదేమిటని ప్రశ్నిస్తేకసవున్ మేయగ బోయినపసులున్ విరిగినవి తిక్క ! పాలున్ విరిగెన్.అని ఆక్షేపించింది. ఆ మాటలకు సిగ్గుపడి లేచి యుద్ధమునకు పోయి వీర స్వర్గము నలంకరించాడు. ఈ చాటు పద్యాల వలన చరిత్రను తెలుసుకునే వీలు కలిగింది."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਠਾਕੁਰ ਕਾ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਆਗਿਆਕਾਰੀ ॥ਠਾਕੁਰ ਕਾ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਸਦਾ ਪੂਜਾਰੀ ॥ਠਾਕੁਰ ਕੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕੈ ਮਨਿ ਪਰਤੀਤਿ ॥ਠਾਕੁਰ ਕੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਕੀ ਨਿਰਮਲ ਰੀਤਿ ॥ਠਾਕੁਰ ਕਉ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਜਾਨੈ ਸੰਗਿ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕਾ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਨਾਮ ਕੈ ਰੰਗਿ ॥ਸੇਵਕ ਕਉ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਪਾਲਨਹਾਰਾ ॥ਸੇਵਕ ਕੀ ਰਾਖੈ ਨਿਰੰਕਾਰਾ ॥ਸੋ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਜਿਸੁ ਦਇਆ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਧਾਰੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸੋ ਸੇਵਕੁ ਸਾਸਿ ਸਾਸਿ ਸਮਾਰੈ ॥੩॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 285 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸਦਾ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪੂਜਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਹਸਤੀ ਦਾ) ਵਿਸ਼ਵਾਸ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਿੰਦਗੀ ਦੀ ਸੁੱਚੀ ਮਰਯਾਦਾ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।ਸੇਵਕ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਾਲਕ-ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ (ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਆਪਣੇ) ਨਾਲ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਮੌਜ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਪਾਲਣ ਦੇ ਸਮਰੱਥ ਹੈ, ਆਪਣੇ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੀ (ਸਦਾ) ਲਾਜ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਪਰ) ਸੇਵਕ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਬਣ ਸਕਦਾ) ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਤੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ; ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਅਜੇਹਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਦਮ-ਬ-ਦਮ ਯਾਦ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩।\\""},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పదానికి నానార్ధాలు ఇవ్వండి: రాజు","answer":"ప్రభువు, క్షత్రియుడు, ఇంద్రుడు, చంద్రుడు"},{"question":"Tòa nhà cao nhất thế giới ở nước nào?","answer":"Tháp Kingdom (hay Jeddah Tower) đang được xây dựng tại thành phố Jeddah thuộc Arab Saudi. Khi hoàn thành, tháp sẽ cao 1.000 m, là tòa nhà cao nhất thế giới. Tháp Kingdom có 167 tầng phía trên mặt đất, 4 tầng hầm, 57 thang máy và có 530 căn hộ, 200 phòng khách sạn và bãi đỗ xe 3.190 chỗ."},{"question":"வினா: பில்கிரிம்ஸ் புரோகிரஸ் நூலின் ஆசிரியர்?","answer":"விடை: ஜான் பன்யன்"},{"question":"Mumutambo weChess ndeipi ingava nhengo yechechi?","answer":"Mumutambo weChess, chine kukosha kwechitendero uye chinogona kuve nhengo yechechi ndiBhishopi. Mafambiro ayo ane anofamba achikirosa pachessboard anomutsa mufananidzo wegwara remufundisi."},{"question":"من هو النبي الذي راودته المرأة التي تربى في بيتها؟","answer":"الإجابة: يوسف عليه السلام."},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: \\"Sáng 31/7, theo thông tin PV Etime thu thập, UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi vừa có chỉ đạo cho Sở TNMT, BQL KKT Dung Quất và chính quyền các địa phương tăng cường công tác quản lý nhà nước về đất đai trên địa bàn. Tỉnh Quảng Ngãi nhìn nhận trong thời gian qua, trên địa bàn đã diễn ra tình trạng một số tổ chức, cá nhân tự ý triển khai san lấp mặt bằng; xây dựng công trình trên phần diện tích đất thực hiện dự án, khi chưa có quyết định giao (cho thuê) đất của cấp có thẩm quyền. Để nâng cao hiệu quả công tác quản lý nhà nước về đất đai trên địa bàn, UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi yêu cầu người đứng đầu BQL KKT Dung Quất và các KCN Quảng Ngãi; chính quyền các huyện, thị xã, thành phố và cơ quan, đơn vị liên quan triển khai thực hiện nghiêm túc nội dung văn bản chỉ đạo trước đó (Chỉ thị số 04/CT-UBND ngày 17/5/2022), của Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh. Chủ tịch UBND các huyện, thị xã, thành phố thực hiện đầy đủ trách nhiệm về quản lý đất đai; tuyệt đối không để xảy ra việc tổ chức, cá nhân tự ý triển khai san lấp mặt bằng, xây dựng công trình trên phần diện tích đất thực hiện dự án khi chưa có quyết định giao (cho thuê) đất của cấp có thẩm quyền.\\"","answer":"Trong quá theo dõi và kiểm tra, khi phát hiện những trường hợp (cá nhân, tổ chức) có hành vi vi phạm, phải tiến hành xử lý nghiêm khắc theo quy định của pháp luật về đất đai. UBND tỉnh Quảng Ngãi giao trách nhiệm cho Sở TNMT kiểm tra, rà soát; không tham mưu cho tỉnh giao (cho thuê) đất, đối với các tổ chức có hành vi vi phạm về đất đai. Được biết thời gian qua, dư luận người dân Quảng Ngãi tỏ ra bức xúc trước việc phát hiện hàng loạt sai phạm liên quan đất đai của Công ty Hà – Mỹ Á trong quá trình triển khai thực hiện 2 dự án khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận; dự án khu dân cư Nghĩa Thuận, ở huyện Tư Nghĩa. Cụ thể, đối với khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận, tại thời điểm khởi công vào tháng 4/2017, dự án vẫn chưa có ĐTM; chưa có (đến ngày 7/7/2022 mới có) quyết định chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng và cho thuê đất. Và đến thời điểm này, dù được hoàn thành và đưa vào hoạt động gần 3 năm, hiện khu du lịch sinh thái Nghĩa Thuận vẫn chưa có giấy phép xây dựng. Tương tự là dự án khu dân cư Nghĩa Thuận (cũng do Công ty Hà – Mỹ Á làm chủ đầu tư), dù mới được cấp quyết định đầu tư (vào ngày 22/5/2018) và đến thời điểm này, vẫn chưa được có quyết định chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng, giao đất nhưng chủ đầu tư, đã san lấp và thi công hoàn thành cơ sở hạ tầng đường giao thông nội bộ, điện…"},{"question":"கேள்வி: இசை மற்றும் நடனத்தை பற்றி கூறக்கூடிய வேதம் எது?","answer":"பதில்: இசை மற்றும் நடனத்தை பற்றி கூறக்கூடிய வேதம் சாம வேதம் ஆகும்."},{"question":"インダス文明の遺跡「ハラッパー」「モヘンジョ・ダロ」といえば、ともにどこの国にあるでしょう？","answer":"パキスタン"},{"question":"காலைல எழுந்து மதிய உணவு பெட்டி கட்டணுமா? ஒரு கைப்பிடி கொத்தமல்லி மட்டும் இருந்தால் பத்து நிமிடத்தில் சுவையான மல்லி சாதம் தயார் செய்வது எப்படின்னு தெரிஞ்சுக்கோங்க!","answer":"காலையில் எழுந்ததும் என்னடா மதிய உணவு பெட்டி கட்டி கொடுப்பது? என்று யோசித்துக் கொண்டிருப்பவர்களுக்கு, பத்தே நிமிடத்தில் செய்யக்கூடிய இந்த ஒரு மல்லி சாதம் உபயோகமாக இருக்கும். ருசியான மல்லி சாதம் வித்தியாசமான முறையில் ரொம்பவே சுலபமாக செய்யக்கூடிய இந்த கலவை சாதம் எப்படி செய்யப் போகிறோம்? என்பதைத் தான் இந்த சமையல் குறிப்பு பதிவின் மூலம் இனி தொடர்ந்து நாம் அறிந்து கொள்ள இருக்கிறோம்.மல்லி சாதம் செய்ய தேவையான பொருட்கள்: வடித்த சாதம் – மூன்று கிண்ணம், கொத்தமல்லி – ஒரு கைப்பிடி அளவு, பச்சை மிளகாய் – நான்கு, இஞ்சி – ஒரு அங்குலம், சீரகம் – ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி, எலுமிச்சை சாறு – ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி, தண்ணீர் – கால் கிண்ணம், சமையல் எண்ணெய் – தேவையான அளவு, கடுகு – ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி, உளுந்து – ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி, வரமிளகாய் – இரண்டு, கருவேப்பிலை – ஒரு கொத்து, முந்திரிப் பருப்பு – பத்து, மஞ்சள் தூள் – கால் தேக்கரண்டி, பெருங்காயத்தூள் – கால் தேக்கரண்டி, உப்பு – தேவையான அளவு.மல்லி சாதம் செய்முறை விளக்கம்: மல்லி சாதம் செய்வதற்கு முதலில் உதிரி உதிரியாக மூன்று கிண்ணம் அளவிற்கு சாதத்தை வடித்து தயார் செய்து கொள்ளவும். பின்னர் தேவையான எல்லா பொருட்களையும் தயாராக எடுத்து வைத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். ஒரு கை நிறைய மல்லித் தழைகளை நன்கு சுத்தம் செய்து கழுவி உலர்த்தி வைத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள்.இப்போது ஒரு சாணையில் கழுவி எடுத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். அதில் சுத்தம் செய்து வைத்துள்ள மல்லித்தழைகளுடன், உங்கள் காரத்திற்கு ஏற்ப பச்சை மிளகாய் சேர்த்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். பின்னர் இவற்றுடன் ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி சீரகம், ஒரு தேக்கரண்டி எலுமிச்சை சாறு சேர்த்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். ஒரு அங்குலம் அளவிற்கு இஞ்சியை தோல் நீக்கி சேர்த்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். இதை நன்கு பொடியாக அரைக்க கால் கோப்பை மட்டும் தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி அரையுங்கள். பின்னர் அடுப்பில் வாணலி ஒன்றை வைத்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். அதில் தேவையான அளவிற்கு எண்ணெய் விட்டு காய விடுங்கள். எண்ணெய் காய்ந்ததும் கடுகு போட்டு பொறிய விடுங்கள். கடுகு பொறிந்து வந்ததும் உளுத்தம் பருப்பு சேர்த்து பொன்னிறமாக வறுத்து இரண்டு வரமிளகாய்களை கிள்ளி போட்டு ஒரு கொத்து கருவேப்பிலையை உருவி போட்டு தாளித்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். இவற்றை தாளிப்பு செய்ததும் இதனுடன் நல்ல ஒரு சுவைக்கு முந்திரி பருப்புகளை பொடித்து சேர்த்துக் கொள்ளுங்கள். உங்கள் விருப்பம் போல வேர்க்கடலை, பாதாம் போன்ற எந்த பருப்பு வகைகளையும் நீங்கள் சேர்க்கலாம்.இவை சிவக்க வறுபட்டதும் மஞ்சள் தூள், பெருங்காயத்தூள் சேர்த்து, தேவையான அளவிற்கு உப்பு போட்டு அரைத்து வைத்துள்ள கலவையை சேர்த்துக் கலந்து கொள்ளுங்கள். இப்போது அடுப்பை மிதமான தீயில் வைத்து ஒரு ஐந்து நிமிடம் நன்கு பச்சை வாசம் போக கிளறி விடுங்கள். பிறகு நீங்கள் உதிரி உதிரியாக வடித்த சாதத்தை சேர்த்து எல்லா இடங்களிலும் படும்படி நன்கு பிரட்டி விட்டு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விடுங்கள். அவ்வளவுதான், பத்தே நிமிடத்தில் சுவையான மல்லி சாதம் தயார்!"},{"question":"उदहारणमा दिइए जस्तै तल दिइएका सङ्क्षिप्त शब्दको पूरा रूप लेख्नुहोस् ःजि.स.स. – जिल्ला समन्वय समिति(क) गो.प. –(ख) गा.पा. –(ग) न.पा. –(घ) जि.प्र.का. –(ङ) ने.बै.लि.  –","answer":"(क) गो.प. – गाउँ प्रशासन(ख) गा.पा. – गाउँ पालिका(ग) न.पा. – नगर पालिका(घ) जि.प्र.का. – जिल्ला प्रशासन कार्यालय(ङ) ने.बै.लि. – नेपाल बैंक लिमिटेड"},{"question":" فين كاين القبر ديال صلاح الدين الايوبي ؟","answer":"فدمشق فسوريا"},{"question":"Суроо: Мона Лизаны ким тарткан?","answer":"Жооп: Леонардо да Винчи."},{"question":"Sülük yaptırdıktan sonra nelere dikkat edilmeli?","answer":"Uygulama sonrasında 24 saat pansumanlar açılmamalıdır. Denize girilmemelidir ve 24 saat duş yapılmamalıdır. Tedaviden sonra ise tahıllı gıdalar, mercimek, aşırı tatlı veya aşırı ekşi tür gıdalar tercih edilememeli protein ağırlıklı beslenme ilk 24 saat tercih edilmelidir."},{"question":"จะซิงค์เพลงกับ iphone ได้อย่างไร?","answer":"ซิงค์เพลงกับ iPhone1. เชื่อมต่อ iPhone กับคอมพิวเตอร์2. เปิด iTunes3. คลิก iPhone ของคุณ4. คลิกเพลง5. ทำเครื่องหมายที่ช่อง \\"ซิงค์เพลง\\"6. คลิก ซิงค์"},{"question":"Ahoana no fomba fanantanterahana ny valin-tanana?","answer":"Ifandimbiasana ny olona anaovana ny asa. Ny olona avy niasana voalohany dia tsy iverenana intsony raha tsy tapitra niasana avokoa ny olona rehetra ( atero ko alao). "},{"question":"متى عبر المحيط الأطلسي بالطائرة لأول مرة ؟","answer":"1927"},{"question":" Sheeg maxaa loo-aqoon jiray caasimada Itoobiya (Ethiopia)?","answer":"Waxa loo-aqoon jiray Fin-Finaay."},{"question":"வினா: ”தோட்டத்தில் மேயுது வெள்ளைப் பசு” எனத் தொடங்கும் பாடலை இயற்றியவர்?","answer":"விடை: கவிமணி"},{"question":"Балдар тууралуу кызыктуу фактылар  жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"- Сиз билбесеңиз керек, Жапония сыяктуу өлкөлөрдө балдарга карата \\"жакшы\\" жана \\"жаман\\" деген түшүнүктөрдү колдонушпайт."},{"question":"Resume el siguiente texto con  una versión más simple: ¿Qué tienen en común el tren bala y el pájaro martín pescador?Sin embargo, la naturaleza, particularmente a través del proceso evolutivo conocido como selección natural, tiene el beneficio de millones de años de ensaño y error, perfeccionando su diseño. Por eso es lógico que los humanos recurran a ella para diseñar tecnología. Este tipo de innovación que emula a la naturaleza se llama diseño biomimético y ha inspirado muchas de nuestras mejores creaciones, desde trenes hasta edificios. A continuación nuestros seis ejemplos favoritos.Final de Quizás también te interese1. El tren pájaroJapón es famoso por la increíble velocidad y eficiencia de sus trenes. Sin embargo, cuando el famoso tren bala comenzó a circular, se dieron cuenta de que había un enorme problema: con su velocidad de 300 km/h, cada vez que emergía de un túnel generaba un estruendo que podía escucharse a 400 metros de distancia.El tren comprimía el aire en el túnel de tal forma que, al salir, producía una gran explosión de sonido.Viajando a 300 km/h, los trenes de Shinkansen comprimían el aire en los túneles y, al salir, producían un boom sónico.Los residentes locales protestaron por la contaminación sonora y las autoridades se vieron forzadas a solucionar el problema en la red ferroviaria de alta velocidad de Japón o Shinkansen.La respuesta llegó de la mano de Eiji Nakatsu, quien además de ser ingeniero, es aficionado a los pájaros.El tren de Nakatsu, que se inauguró en 1997, incluyó un rediseño de la parte frontal inspirada en el pico aerodinámico del martín pescador.Pero también implementó mejoras inspiradas en las plumas de las lechuza, aves conocidas por su vuelo silencios, y del abdomen del pingüino adelaida, que se desliza con un mínimo de resistencia en el agua.2. Turbinas de ballenaLa ballena jorobada pesa 36 toneladas, pero es uno de los nadadores, buceadores y saltadores más elegantes del mar. Tal como demostró hace 15 años el biomecánico Frank Fish, estas habilidades dinámicas se deben en gran medida..","answer":"Las pirámides, rascacielos y vuelos supersónicos son apenas algunas de las formas en que la humanidad ha demostrado su ingenio y habilidad técnica en los últimos milenios."},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"Misy ny milaza fa olona efa maty tamin'ny 5 taona mahery no mbola tafiditra ao anaty lisitry ny mpifidy\\"olona efa maty oviana no mbola tafiditra anaty lisi-pifidianana?","answer":"olona efa maty tamin'ny 5 taona mahery no mbola tafiditra ao anaty lisitry ny mpifidy"},{"question":"Em que país fica Praga?","answer":"A cidade se localiza na República Tcheca"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ആമസോൺ മഴക്കാടുകൾ ലോകത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലിയ ഉഷ്ണമേഖലാ മഴക്കാടാണ്, ഏകദേശം 5.5 ദശലക്ഷം ചതുരശ്ര കിലോമീറ്റർ വിസ്തൃതിയുണ്ട്. വൈവിധ്യമാർന്ന സസ്യങ്ങളുടെയും ജന്തുജാലങ്ങളുടെയും ആവാസ കേന്ദ്രമാണിത്, അവയിൽ പലതും ഭൂമിയിൽ മറ്റെവിടെയും കാണുന്നില്ല. ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ആമസോൺ മഴക്കാടുകൾ. തെക്കേ അമേരിക്കയിലെ ആമസോൺ പ്രദേശത്തു പടർന്നു കിടക്കുന്ന ഒരു വലിയ വനപ്രദേശമാണ് ആമസോൺ മഴക്കാടുകൾ. ഈ പ്രദേശത്തിന്റെ ആകെയുള്ള വ്യാപ്തിയായ 70 ലക്ഷം ചതുരശ്രകിലോമീറ്ററിൽ 55 ലക്ഷം ചതുരശ്ര കിലോമീറ്ററും ഈ വനം വ്യാപിച്ചു കിടക്കുന്നു. (കേരളത്തിന്റെ 138 ഇരട്ടി വലിപ്പം). 60 ശതമാനവും ബ്രസീലിലും 13 ശതമാനം പെറുവിലും 10 ശതമാനം കൊളംബിയയിലും ഉൾപ്പെടെ ആകെ 9 രാജ്യങ്ങളിലായി ആമസോൺ മഴക്കാടുകൾ സ്ഥിതിചെയ്യുന്നു."},{"question":" 2022 පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේදී ඉන්දියාව පදක්කම් කීයක් දිනා ගත්තාද?","answer":"2022 පොදුරාජ්‍ය මණ්ඩලීය ක්‍රීඩා උළෙලේදී ඉන්දියාව දිනාගත් මුළු පදක්කම් සංඛ්‍යාව 61 කි."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ny ranomasina lehibe indrindra eran-tany?a)Oseana Atlantikab) Oseana Indianinad) Oseana Pasifikae) Oseana Arktika","answer":"valiny d) :Ny anaran'ny ranomasina lehibe indrindra eran-tany dia ny Oseana Pasifika."},{"question":"Volgens de tekst van het lied 'Piraten-potpourri' zijn Samson en Gert op weg naar Timbuktu. In welk land ligt Timbuktu?","answer":"Het antwoord is Mali "},{"question":"Iyawo mi ni irawọ awọn to wa n ṣiṣẹ iṣegun lọdọ mi ni mo n lo, mi o fẹ ẹ mọ-Gbolagade","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ kọkọ-kọkọ kan to wa ni Ile-Tuntun, niluu Ibadan, ipinlẹ Ọyọ, ti tu igbeyawo ọdun mẹta ka laarin ọkunrin oniṣegun ibilẹ kan, Iṣọla Gbọlagade ati iyawo ẹ, Yetunde.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii ni ituka ọhun waye laarin Gbọlagade, ẹni ti wọn pe loniṣegun ibilẹ, ati Yetunde. Ẹsun ti ọkọ yii fi kan iyawo ẹ ni pe niṣe lo n rojọ oun kiri ilu Ibadan, to n pe oun ni oṣo to n lo irawọ awọn to waa ṣiṣẹ iṣegun lọdọ ẹ fi sowo loun.Gbọlagade tun fi kun un pe, obinrin naa ko bimọ kankan foun, bẹẹ lo n fi ọrọ ibajẹ le awọn onibaara lọdọ oun pẹlu ọrọ buruku to n sọ nipa oun kiri.“Orukọ buruku lobinrin yii ti sọ mi laarin ilu, niṣe lo n rojọ mi kiri pe irawọ awọn to n waa ṣiṣẹ iwosan lọdọ mi ni mo n lo, ti mo fi n ṣiṣẹ ọla funra mi, emi o ri iru Yetunde yii ri o, fun idi eyi, mi o fẹ ẹ mọ, ki kaluku maa ba tiẹ lọ. Nitori ti ko ba kuro lọdẹdẹ mi, o lewu o, mi o si fẹẹ lokuu eeyan kankan lọrun, oun gan-an ti sọ pe oun loun maa pa mi tẹlẹ.”Yetunde ni tiẹ naa ko jiyan si gbogbo ohun ti ọkọ ẹ ka silẹ yii, niṣe lo tẹnumọ ọn pe ika ati ọdaju lọkunrin naa n ṣe, to si maa n ko wahala ba oun lọpọ igba.Aarẹ ile-ẹjọ naa, Oloye Henry Agbaje, sọ pe ko si ohun ti oun le ṣe sọrọ awọn mejeeji, paapaa bi wọn ṣe fariga pe awọn ko fẹẹ jọ wa papọ mọ gẹgẹ bii lọkọ-laya.Ninu idajọ ẹ naa lo ti sọ pe Gbọlagade gbọdọ maa fun Yetunde ni ẹgbẹrun meje aabọ naira lati maa fi sanwo ile."},{"question":"\\"જોઈને જાણે, વાણીએ નહીં. \\" નો અર્થ શું છે?","answer":"જોઈને જાણે, વાણીએ નહીં. નો અર્થઉતર: દેખાવ પરથી અંદાજ લગાવી શકાય છે."},{"question":"కింది ప్రకృతి – వికృతి పదాలను జతపరచండి.1. విద్య\\tఅ) అంచ2. అగ్ని\\tఆ) విద్దె3. ధర్మము\\tఇ) మొగము4. హంస\\tఈ) అగ్గి5. ముఖము\\tఉ) దమ్మము","answer":"1. విద్య\\tఆ) విద్దె2. అగ్ని\\tఈ) అగ్గి3. ధర్మము\\tఉ) దమ్మము4. హంస\\tఅ) అంచ5. ముఖము\\tఇ) మొగము"},{"question":"Web Frameworks တွေမှာ Middleware နဲ့ Handler ဆိုတာ ဘယ်မျိုးလဲ","answer":"Laravel မှာ Middleware နဲ့ Handler က ကွဲပြားတဲ့ အရာ ၂ ခုဖြစ်ပြီး middleware တွေက native construct အနေနဲ့ သီးသန့်ပါဝင်တာဖြစ်တယ်။ ဒီအချက်ကို Http Kernel ရဲ့ http intelligence နဲ့ ပေါင်းစပ်လိုက်တဲ့အခါ Request ရဲ့ path နဲ့ query parameter တွေကို ဖတ်ပြီး dynamic routing လုပ်တာ၊ conditional middleware stack တာမျိုးတွေ လုပ်နိုင်စေပါတယ်။ Handler ကိုလည်း Controller အဖြစ် တွေ့ရပြီး Controller class ထဲမှာ Http verb ဖြစ်တဲ့ Get, Post လိုအပ်ချက်သလို Handler Method တွေရေးထားလို့ရပါတယ်။ExpressJS မှာတော့ Middleware concept မပါဝင်ပဲ Handler နဲ့ Middleware နှစ်ခုလုံးက Handler တွေအဖြစ်ပဲ ရှိကြတာဖြစ်တယ်။ Http intelligence လည်း မရှိတဲ့အတွက် handler ထဲမှာပဲ candidate မှန်မမှန် စိစစ်ရပြီး path နဲ့ query တွေကို စစ်ဆေးနိုင်မယ့် control flow logic တွေကို ရေးထားကြရပါတယ်။Laravel ရဲ့ တချို့ middleware တွေက တခါတည်း builtin ပါပြီးဖြစ်တဲ့အတွက် overhead မဖြစ်စေပဲ pipeline အစီအစဥ်ကို ပြင်ရခက်သလို ExpressJS ရဲ့ native middleware မပါတဲ့ အချက်က pipeline ဆောက်ရာမှာ ပိုလွတ်လပ်ခွင့်ရစေနိုင်ပါတယ်။"},{"question":"Let de volgende grap uit: Waarom ging het koekje naar het ziekenhuis? A: Hij voelde zich echt crumbly!","answer":"Uitleg: Kruimels zijn de kleine stukjes koekje of brood die op tafel vallen als je eet; de \\"b\\" in het woord kruimel is stil, dus het klinkt als \\"crum.\\" \\"Je slecht voelen\\" betekent je een beetje ziek voelen, niet al te goed, maar niet helemaal ziek. Deze grap speelt op de woorden crummy en crumb-ie (crumbie is geen woord maar zet het \\"ee\\" geluid aan het einde van het woord \\"crumb\\"). Dat is maar een grapje voor vandaag. Ik hoop dat je je goed voelt en niet slecht."},{"question":"നയാഗ്ര വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടം യുണൈറ്റഡ് സ്റ്റേറ്റ്സിന്റെയും കാനഡയുടെയും അതിർത്തിയിൽ സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്ന മനോഹരമായ പ്രകൃതിദത്ത അത്ഭുതമാണ്. അതിൽ മൂന്ന് വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടങ്ങൾ അടങ്ങിയിരിക്കുന്നു: ഹോഴ്സ്ഷൂ ഫാൾസ്, അമേരിക്കൻ ഫാൾസ്, ബ്രൈഡൽ വെയിൽ ഫാൾസ്. അതിശക്തമായ കാസ്കേഡുകളും അതിമനോഹരമായ സൗന്ദര്യവും കൊണ്ട്, നയാഗ്ര വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടം ഓരോ വർഷവും ദശലക്ഷക്കണക്കിന് സന്ദർശകരെ ആകർഷിക്കുന്നു. ബോട്ട് ടൂറുകളിൽ സന്ദർശകർക്ക് വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടം അടുത്ത് നിന്ന് അനുഭവിച്ചറിയാം അല്ലെങ്കിൽ നിരീക്ഷണ ഡെക്കുകളിൽ നിന്നുള്ള കാഴ്ച്ച കാണാൻ കഴിയും. നയാഗ്ര വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടം പ്രകൃതിയുടെ ശക്തിയും സൗന്ദര്യവും പ്രദർശിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ഒരു വിസ്മയം ഉണർത്തുന്ന സ്ഥലമാണ്.ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: നയാഗ്ര വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടം, അമേരിക്കയുടെയും കാനഡയുടെയും അതിർത്തിയിലുള്ള അതിന്റെ സ്ഥാനം, മൂന്ന് വെള്ളച്ചാട്ടങ്ങൾ - ഹോഴ്‌സ്‌ഷൂ ഫാൾസ്, അമേരിക്കൻ ഫാൾസ്, ബ്രൈഡൽ വെയിൽ ഫാൾസ്, ഒരു ടൂറിസ്റ്റ് ആകർഷണം എന്ന നിലയിലുള്ള അതിന്റെ ജനപ്രീതി, ശക്തിയുടെ പ്രാതിനിധ്യം എന്നിവയെക്കുറിച്ചാണ് ഈ ഭാഗം. പ്രകൃതിയുടെ സൗന്ദര്യവും."},{"question":"கேள்வி:உவமையால் விளக்கப்பெறும் பொருத்தமான பொருளைத் தேர்ந்தெழுதுக?.","answer":"பதில்: உவமையால் விளக்கப்பெறும் பொருத்தமான பொருளைத் தேர்தல்:அகழ்வாரை தாங்கும் நிலம் போல் – பொறுமை, பொறுத்தல்அச்சில் வார்த்தாற் போல் – ஒரே சீராகஅடியற்ற மரம் போல் – துன்பம், விழுதல், சோகம்அத்தி பூத்தாற் போல் – அறிய செல்வம்அரை கிணறு தாண்டியவன் போல் – ஆபத்துஅலை ஓய்ந்த கடல் போல் – அமைதி, அடக்கம்அவளை நினைத்து உரலை இடித்தாற் போல் – கவனம்அழகுக்கு அழகு செய்வது போல் – மேன்மைஅனலில் இட்ட மெழுகு போல் – வருத்தம், துன்பம்அனலில் விழுந்த புழுப்போல – தவிர்ப்புஇஞ்சி தின்ற குரங்கு போல் – துன்பம், வேதனைஇடி ஓசை கேட்ட நாகம் போல் – அச்சம், மருட்சி, துன்பம்இடி விழுந்த மரம் போல் – வேதனைஇணருழந்தும் நாறா மலரனையார் – விரித்துரைக்க இயலாதவர்இலைமறை காய் போல் – மறைபொருள்இழவு காத்த கிளி போல் – ஏமாற்றம், நினைத்தது கை கூடாமைஉடுக்கை இழந்தவன் கைபோல் – நட்பு, உதவுதல்உமி குற்றிக் கைவருந்தல் போல – பயனற்ற செயல்உமையும், சிவனும் போல் – நெருக்கம், நட்புஉயிரும் உடம்பும் போல் – ஒற்றுமை, நெருக்கம், நட்புஉள்ளங்கை நெல்லிக்கனி போல் – தெளிவு"},{"question":"नियमित डोडेकागन (१२-पक्षीय बहुभुज) को परिधिको गणना गर्नुहोस् जसमा प्रत्येक पक्ष १२ इन्च मापन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नियमित डोडेकागनको परिधि एक पक्षको लम्बाइको १२ गुणा बराबर हुन्छ। त्यसोभए, परिधि 12 * 12 इन्च हो, जुन 144 इन्च बराबर हुन्छ।"},{"question":"Où se trouve le volcan le plus actif au monde ?","answer":"Le volcan le plus actif au monde est généralement identifié comme étant le Kilauea, qui se trouve sur la grande île d'Hawaï, aux États-Unis. Le Kilauea fait partie de l'archipel hawaïen et est situé dans le parc national des volcans d'Hawaï. Ce volcan est en éruption continue depuis 1983, ce qui en fait l'une des éruptions les plus longues de l'histoire enregistrée."},{"question":"จงตอบคำถามต่อไปนี้: ปัญหาที่พบบ่อยที่สุดเกี่ยวกับร่างกายมนุษย์คืออะไร?","answer":"ปัญหาที่พบบ่อยที่สุดกับร่างกายมนุษย์ ได้แก่ ความเหนื่อยล้า ความเครียด วิตกกังวล ซึมเศร้า ปวดศีรษะ ปัญหาการย่อยอาหาร ภูมิแพ้ และปวดข้อ เป็นต้น"},{"question":"கேள்வி: ஆரிய இனத்தவர்களின் பூர்வீக இடம் எது?","answer":"விடை: மத்திய ஆசியா."},{"question":"Sunday Igboho yoo fara han nile-ẹjọ lorileede Benin","answer":"Bi gbogbo nnkan ba lọ bi wọn ti ṣeto rẹ, aarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee yii ni ajijagbara ọmọ Yoruba nni, Sunday Adeyẹmọ tiu gbogbo eeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho yoo fara han nile-ẹjọ kan, Judicial Service Benin, to wa ni Rue 447, Cotonou, Benin 02BP2004 ni orileede Benin. Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, lo ti yẹ ki igbẹjọ naa waye, ALAROYE gbọ pe iwọde ti awọn ọmọ Yoruba to wa lorileede Benin ṣe da igbẹjọ naa duro, eyi to mu ki wọn sọ ọ di oni, Tọsidee, Ọjọbọ.Agbẹnusọ Igboho, Koiki Ọlayẹmi, fidi eyi mulẹ ninu fidio kan to ṣe lati fi ṣalaye bi nnkan ṣe n lọ ni orileede Olominira Benin ti Sunday Igboho wa bayii.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, ni wọn mu ajijagbara ọmọ Yoruba naa ni orileede Benin, nigba to fẹẹ maa rin irinajo ọ si ilu oyinboLatigba naa ni ijọba Naijiria ti n wa gbogbo ọna lati gbe ọkunrin naa wa si Naijiria lati waa jẹjọ. ALAROYE gbọ pe gbogbo agbara ni ọga ṣoja ilẹ wa tẹlẹ to ti di aṣoju ilẹ wa lorileede Benin bayii, Turkur Buratai, n ṣa lati ri i pe wọn gbe Sunday Igboho wa si Naijiria. Sugbọn awọn alaṣẹ ilẹ Benin ni awọn ko le fi ọkunrin naa silẹ ni yajoyajo bẹẹ, afi ti wọn ba tẹle gbogbo alakalẹ, ti wọn si ṣe ohun gbogbo lọna ofin. Bẹẹ ni awọn agbẹjọro ọmọ Yoruba to ti pe jọ kaakiri agbaye n ja fitafita lati ri i pe ọkunrin naa mori bọ.Ile-ẹjọ kan, Judicial Service Benin, to wa ni Rue 447, Cotonou, Benin 02BP2004 ni ireti wa pe igbẹjọ naa yoo ti waye lonii ti i ṣe Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ചില ജനപ്രിയ കായിക വിനോദങ്ങൾ ഏതൊക്കെയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഫുട്ബോൾ, ബാസ്കറ്റ്ബോൾ, ടെന്നീസ്, സോക്കർ, ബേസ്ബോൾ, ഗോൾഫ്, നീന്തൽ, ക്രിക്കറ്റ്, റഗ്ബി, വോളിബോൾ"},{"question":"फिफा विश्वकपको बारेमा नेपालीमा जानकारी ","answer":" विश्व फुटबल कप फुटबलको सबैभन्दा महत्त्वपूर्ण खेल प्रतियोगिता हो। यसमा विभिन्न देशहरूका फुटबल टिमहरू एकत्र हुन्छन् र विश्वमा विजेता निर्धारित गर्ने लक्ष्यले खेल्छन्।विश्व फुटबल कप प्रत्येक चार वर्षमा एकपटक आयोजन गरिन्छ। यसले आफ्नो आयोजनस्थललाई नियन्त्रण गर्दछ, जसमा अनेक टिमहरूले प्रतियोगिता गर्दछन्। आफ्नो आयोजनबाट नयाँ फुटबल ग्राउन्ड, स्टेडियम र अन्य सुविधाहरूको विकास पनि भएको छ।यो विश्व फुटबल कप प्रतियोगिताको आयोजन विभिन्न राष्ट्रहरूमा भइरहेको छ। खेलकुद उद्धार गर्ने शानदार पर्यटन स्थलहरूमा यो कप आयोजन गरिन्छ।यसमा विश्वमा नै प्रमुख फुटबल खिलाडीहरूले खेल्ने अवसर पाउँछन् ।"},{"question":"Lietuvoje yra net du šiam įrankiui skirti muziejai – vienas Degučių kaime Vilkaviškio rajone, kitas Linkmenų kaime Ignalinos rajone. Koks tai įrankis?","answer":"Plaktukas."},{"question":"ፋሺሽት የተጠቀመበት ማስተርድ ጋዝ የኬሚካል መሳሪያ ምን ጉዳት ያስከትላል?","answer":"ህይወት ያለዉን ነገር ሁሉ የሚያጠፋ"},{"question":"Wọn ni ọkunrin ti wọn pa nibi ija awọn onimọto n’Ibadan n mura ilu oyinbo ni","answer":"Titi di ba a ṣe n sọ yii ni awọn eeyan adugbo Iwo Road, niluu Ibadan, nibi ti awọn onimọto ti lọọ kọju ija si awọn to n ta foonu ni Shopping Complex kan niluu naa lori pe wọn ko ja tikẹẹti.ALAROYE gbọ pe ọrọ tikẹẹti ti wọn ni awọn to n ta foonu nileetaja naa kọ lati ja ni awọn Park Management System, labẹ idari ọga awọn onimọto tẹlẹ, Ọgbẹni Mukaila Lamidi, ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Auxilliary fi bẹrẹ wahala pẹlu wọn.Asiko ti wahala naa n lọ lọwọ ni wọn ni ọmọkunrin yii, Rahmon Azeez, ti ko ju ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlogoji lọ ati ẹgbọn rẹ torukọ rẹ n jẹ Hammed jọ fẹẹ wa mọto wọle.Ṣugbọn awọn ti wọn n fa wahala naa ti fi mọto kan di oju ọna. Lasiko ti ọkunrin naa n sọ fun wọn pe ki wọn gbe mọto kuro loju ọna ki awọn le raaye wọ inu ọgba naa ni wahala bẹrẹ, ki awọn to wa nibẹ si too mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ, wọn ti yinbọn fun ọmọkunrin ti wọn ni ilu oyinbo lo ti kawe yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe ni nnkan bii ọdun mẹta sẹyin ni iyawo rẹ bi ibeji niluu oyinbo, ti wọn si ṣe ikomọ awọn ọmọ  naa ni Naijiria. Latigba naa ni ọmọkunrin yii ti n gbidanwo lati lọ siluu oyinbo ko le lọọ ba awọn mọlẹbi rẹ.Ọsẹ bii meji sẹyin ni awọn to mọ ọmọkunrin naa daadaa sọ pe wọn ṣẹṣẹ fun un ni fisa, to si ti n palẹmọ lati lọọ ri iyawo atawọn ọmọ rẹ ki wọn too fiku ojiji pa a yii.Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Seyi Makinde, ṣabẹwo si Iwo Road ti iṣẹlẹ naa ti waye l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ṣugbọn niṣe ni awọn eeyan fariwo bọnu, ti wọn n bu gomina naa, ti ọpọ si n pariwo pe awọn ko fẹ PMS, iyẹn ileeṣẹ ti gomina da silẹ pe ki wọn fi maa gbowo lọwọ awọn ọlọja, onimọto ati ọlọkada.Bakan naa ni wọn naka abuku si Mukaila ti gbogbo eeyan mọ si Auxilliary ti gomina fi ṣakoso ileeṣẹ naa, wọn ni ọkunrin naa lo ko awọn eeyan wa si awọn ṣọọbu ti wọn ti fa wahala naa."},{"question":"การปรับตัวแบบไหนจะเตือนสัตว์นักล่าไม่ให้กินสัตว์? ตัวเลือก: a) สีสันสดใส b) ดวงตาโผล่ c) รูปทรงเรขาคณิต d) สารพิษ","answer":"a) สีสันสดใสสัตว์ที่มีสีสันสดใส โดยธรรมชาติจะบ่งบอกว่าเป็นสัตว์มีพิษ สัตว์ที่ถูกล่านั้นอาจทำการเลียนแบบเพื่อให้สัตว์นักล่ากลัวพิษ"},{"question":"س88 - في أي عهد من عهود الخلفاء الراشدين كانتحروب الردة ؟","answer":"ج88 - في عهد سيدنا أبو بكر الصديق"},{"question":"Quando o Vitória foi fundado?","answer":"O Vitória foi fundado em 13 de maio de 1899."},{"question":"எல்லோரா கலைக்கோவில்கள் இருக்கும் இடம் எது?","answer":"எல்லோரா குகைகள், இந்தியாவின் மகாராஷ்டிராவின் ஔரங்காபாத் மாவட்டத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள, கி.பி. 6 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு காலத்தைச் சேர்ந்த கல்வெட்டுகளைக் கொண்ட பல மத பாறை-வெட்டு குகை வளாகமாகும்."},{"question":"Ing sawjining dina, kebo mlaku-mlaku nang pinggir kali. Kebo krungu suara baya njaluk tulung merga baya kebrukan wit. Kebo nulungi baya. Kebo nyrudug wit nganggo sungune. Baya sing ora duwe rasa matur nuwun malah nyokot sikile kebo. Baya arep mangan kebo. Ngerti niat elek baya, kebo nyuruk wit ben kebrukan baya neh. Bar kuwi kebo melayu ben iso selamet.Sebutno kewan sing dadi karakter ing crita.Jawaban:","answer":"Karakter utama crita ing ndhuwur iku ono loro (2), yaiku Kebo lan Baya."},{"question":"ගේම් ඔෆ් ත්‍රෝන්ස් කතා මාලාව විකාශය වූ කාල සීමාව කුමක්ද?","answer":"2011 - 2019"},{"question":"ஆஸ்கார் பரிசு பெற்ற முதல் இந்தியர் \\t1. பானு அத்தையா2. சத்யஜித்ரே3. நஸ்ருதீன் ஷா4. ராஜ் கபூர்","answer":"1. பானு அத்தையா"},{"question":"කෝපි භෝග ආරක්ෂණය ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"නෙමටෝඩාවන් සහ ගොළුබෙල්ලන් පැල තවාන්වලට හානි කරයි. ඊට අමතරව තවාන් පැලෑටිවල දියමලන් කෑම නම රෝගී තත්වය ඇතිවේ. මනා ජලාපවහනය එයට පිළියමයි.රෝගකෝපි මලකඩ රෝගය: කෝපි මලකඩ රෝගය යනු අතීතයේදී දරුණු රෝගයකි. නමුත් වර්තමානයේ මලකඩ රෝගයට ඔරොත්තු දෙන ප්‍රභේද හඳුන්වා දී ඇත. කෝපි මලකඩ රෝගයට 05% බොඩෝ මිශ්‍රණය යෙදීම නිර්දේශ කෙරේ. ඇරබිකා කෝපි අධික ලෙස මෙම රෝගයට ගොදුරු වේකළු දිලීර රෝගය: පත්‍ර මත කළු දිලීර වැඩීම නිසා ප්‍රභාසංශ්ලේෂණය අඩු වේ. කොළ පතනය සිදුවිය හැකිය. 1% පිටි යෙදීම නිර්දේශ කෙරේ.ඇන්ත්‍රැක්නෝස්: ගෙඩි සහ කොළ මත දුඹුරු වර්ණ ලප ඇතිවේ. ගස ක්‍රමයෙන් මිය යාම සිදුවිය හැකිය. 1% බොඩෝ මිශ්‍රණ යෙදීම නිර්දේශ කෙරේ. සෙවන අඩු කිරීම ද සුදුසු ය.පළිබෝධකයන්කෝපි ගෙඩි ගුල්ලා (Hypothenemus hampei ): ගැහැනු ගුල්ලා කෝපි  ගෙඩිය මුදුනේ සිදුරක් සාදා ගෙඩිය තුලට ඇතුල් වී බිත්තර   දමයි. බිත්තරවලින් බිහිවන කීටයන් ගෙඩියේ ඇතුලත කොටස් කා දමයි. කෝපි අස්වනු නෙලාගත් පසුවද ගබඩා කර ඇති ගෙඩි වලට ද මෙම ගුල්ලාගෙ හානිය සිදුවේ.   කෝපි ගෙඩි ගුල්ලා පාලනය කිරීම සදහා සෙවන 40% – 60% අතර පවත්වා ගත යුතු අතර,  ඒකාකාරීව ගෙඩි මෝරන ප්‍රභේද වගා කීරීම (අයි. එම්.වයි  සහ කටිමෝර් ප්‍රබේදය), පැල සිටුවීමේදී නිදේශිත පරතරය තබා ගැනීම, ප්‍රධාන  අස්වැන්න තුන් වතාවකට සීමා කර පාර්ශවික ශාක වල ඇති ඉතිරි ගෙඩි සියල්ල ඉවත් කිරීම සහ බිම වැටී ඇති ගෙඩි ඉවත් කර පොළව යට වළලා දැමීම හෝ ගිනි තබා විනාශ කිරීම කල යුතුය. පරිසරයේ සිටින කෝපි ගෙඩි ගුල්ලාගේ ස්වභාවික සතුරන් රැක ගැනීම සඳහා ක්‍රියා මාර්ග අනුගමනය කල යුතුය.කඳ ගුල්ලා (Xyleborus morstatti) :කලු පැහැති කුඩා ගුල්ලා ද්ව්තීක හා තෘතීයික අතු විදගෙන ඇතුල් වී අතු තුල කානු සාදා එහි  බිත්ති වල වර්ධනය වන දිලීරයක් ආහාරයට ගනිමින් වැඩේ. අතුවල කුඩා සිදුරු දක්නට ලැබෙන අතර මෙසේ අතු විදගෙන යන කෘමි හානිය නිසා හානියට ලක්වු අතුවල  අග්‍රස්ථය මැලවීම හා අතු කඩා වැටීම සිදුවේ. පාලනය සඳහා ආසාදනය වු අතු කපා පුලුස්සා දැමිම සහ ක්ෂේත්‍ර සනිපාරක්ෂාව සඳහා ක්‍රමෝපායන් අනුගමනය කල යුතුය.කෝපි වගාවේදී, මුල් කන කුරුමිණියන් සහ කොරපොතු කෘමින් සුළු හනිදායි පලිබෝධකයින් ලෙස සලකයි."},{"question":"Жаңы технологиялардын биздин жашоого кириши менен биз үчүн дүйнөнүн төртбурчу менен байланышуу бир мүнөттү талап кылган иш болуп калганы айдан ачык.Айтыңызчы, эгерде сиз эки-үч күн электрондук дарегиңизди текшербей калсаңыз,өзүңүздү ээн аралда калгандай сезим пайда болобу? Психологдордун айтымында,акыркы үч жылда “мейлоголия” деген жаңы дарт пайда болду. Аны менен электрондукдарексиз өз жашоосун элестете албай калган адамдар ооруйт экен. “Мындай көрүнүшадам өзүнө-өзү ишенбей калгандан улам пайда болот”, – дешет адистер.Жогорудагы тексттен кандай жыйынтык чыгарууга болот?(А) Адам өзүнө-өзү ишенбей калуудан улам “мейлоголия” дартына чалдыгышы мүмкүн.(Б) Жаңы технологиялар себептүү электрондук даректерди колдонобуз.(В) Электрондук дарексиз адамдар өз жашоосун элестете албайт.(Г) “Мейлоголия” дарты мурда эле пайда болгон.","answer":"Туура жооп - (А)Текстке ылайык, жашоосун электрондук дарексиз элестете албагандар “мейлоголия”дарты менен ооруйт, ал эми бул оору адам качан гана өзүнө-өзү ишенбей калганда пайдаболот. Демек, төмөнкүдөй жыйыктык чыгарсак болот: адам өзүнө-өзү ишенбей калууданулам “мейлоголия” дартына чалдыгышы мүмкүн."},{"question":"Huraikan kepentingan semangat kejiranan.","answer":"Semangat kejiranan dapat memupuk semangat kerjasama. dalam kalangan masyarakat sesuatu tempat melalui aktiviti kemasyarakatan seperti gotong-royong dan majlis sambutan perayaan atauperjumpaan bulan komuniti. Masyarakat akan menjadi lebih mesra dan saling membantu tanpa mengira bangsa danwarna kulit. Semangat kejiranan juga melahirkan masyarakat yang harmoni. Semua halo masyarakat memahami antara satu sama lain dan dapat mempelajari perbezaan budaya dan sistem sosial. Masyarakat yang bersatu padu seia sekata dapat mewujudkan suasana yang tenang dan aman dan menjamin keselamatan sesebuah kawasan. Kawasan perumahan perlu ditingkatkan keselamatannya supaya keamanan dalam masyarakat terjamin. Masyarakat harus meningkatkan keselamatan kawasan tersebut untukmengelakkan kejadian yang tidak diingini berlaku dan memastikan keselamatan penduduk terjamin."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أصغر بحر في العالم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: بحر سامار"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو عدد السجدات الموجودة في القرآن الكريم؟","answer":"الإجابة:  15 سجدة."},{"question":"એલેક્ઝાન્ડર ગ્રેહામ બેલ કોણ છે?","answer":"એલેક્ઝાન્ડર ગ્રેહામ બેલ (૩ માર્ચ, ૧૮૪૭ – ૨ ઓગસ્ટ, ૧૯૨૨) સુવિખ્યાત વૈજ્ઞાનિક, શોધક, એન્જિનીયર અને સંશોધનકાર હતા જેમને સૌપ્રથમ વ્યવહારુ ટેલિફોનની શોધનો યશ આપવામા આવે છે."},{"question":"సహకార సంఘాలను నిర్వచించి, దాని ముఖ్య లక్షణాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"ప్రజాస్వామ్య పద్ధతిలో లాభాపేక్షలేని పరస్పర సహాయము, సేవాశయాల కొరకు పరిమిత వనరులు గల వ్యక్తులు వ్యాపారము మరియు ఆర్థిక ప్రయోజనాలు పెంపొందించుటకే సమానత్వ ప్రాతిపదికపైన ఏర్పడిన స్వచ్ఛంద సంఘము సహకార సంఘము. సమిష్టి కృషికి, సాంఘిక శ్రేయస్సు దృష్టికి, సమాజ సేవకు పాటుపడుటయే ఈ సంస్థ లక్ష్యము. దీని ప్రధాన ధ్యేయము లాభార్జన కాదు. సభ్యులకు సేవ చేయుటయే. ఒకరికోసము అందరూ, అందరి కోసము ఒక్కరు అనేది ఆశయము. పరస్పర సహాయము ద్వారా స్వయం సహాయము దీని మార్గదర్శకమైన సూత్రము.1912 సహకార సంఘాల చట్టము ప్రకారము ‘సహకార సూత్రాలకు అనుగుణముగా సభ్యుల ఆర్థిక ప్రయోజనాలను పరిరక్షించే ధ్యేయముతో స్థాపించబడిన సంస్థను సహకార సంస్థ’ అంటారు.లక్షణాలు:1. స్వచ్ఛంద సంఘము: ఒక ప్రాంతానికి లేదా ఒక వర్గానికి చెందిన ప్రజలు తమంతట తాముగా స్వప్రయోజనాల కోసము ఏర్పాటు చేసుకున్న సంఘమే సహకార సంస్థ. ఈ సంస్థలో చేరడానికిగాని, వదిలివెళ్ళడానికి సభ్యులకు పూర్తి స్వేచ్ఛ ఉంటుంది.2. బహిరంగ సభ్యత్వము: సహకార సంఘములో చేరడానికి కులము, మతము, జాతి, రాజకీయ సిద్ధాంతాలు, విశ్వాసాలు మొదలైన వాటితో సంబంధము లేదు. సభ్యత్వము అందరికీ లభిస్తుంది.3. సభ్యుల సంఖ్య: సహకార సంస్థలను స్థాపించడానికి 10 మంది సభ్యులు కావలెను. రాష్ట్ర సహకార సంఘాలలో వ్యక్తులు 50 మంది కావలెను. గరిష్ట సభ్యులకు పరిమితి లేదు..4. ప్రభుత్వ నియంత్రణ: సహకార సంఘాల నమోదు తప్పనిసరి. వాటిపై ప్రభుత్వ అజమాయిషీ, నియంత్రణ ఉంటాయి. ఇవి ప్రభుత్వ నిబంధనలను పాటించాలి. ప్రతి సంవత్సరము వార్షిక నివేదికలను, లెక్కలను తయారుచేసి ప్రభుత్వానికి సమర్పించవలెను. సహకార శాఖ ఆడిటర్ వీటిని తనిఖీ చేస్తాడు.5. మూలధనము: సంఘాల మూలధనమును సభ్యులే సమకూరుస్తారు. మూలధనము పరిమితముగా ఉండటమువలన ప్రభుత్వము నుంచి ఋణాలు, రాష్ట్ర, కేంద్ర సహకార సంస్థల నుంచి గ్రాంటు, రాష్ట్ర, కేంద్ర ప్రభుత్వాల నుంచి సహయాన్ని పొందుతాయి.6. ప్రజాస్వామ్యబద్ధమైన నిర్వహణ: ఈ సంస్థ నిర్వహణ ప్రజాస్వామిక సూత్రాలమీద జరుగుతుంది. ప్రతి సభ్యునికి సంఘ నిర్వహణలో పాల్గొనే అవకాశము ఉంటుంది. సంఘములోని సభ్యులందరికి ఓటు హక్కు సమానము. ఒక మనిషికి ఒక ఓటు ఉంటుంది.7. సేవాశయము: సహకార సంస్థల ప్రధాన ధ్యేయము సభ్యులకు సేవచేయుటయే. లాభార్జన కాదు.8. పెట్టుబడిపై రాబడి సభ్యులకు తమ పెట్టుబడులపై డివిడెండు లభిస్తుంది.9. మిగులు పంపిణీ: సహకార సంస్థలు వ్యాపారము చేయగా వచ్చిన మిగులు నుంచి కొంత మొత్తాన్ని విరాళాలకు (విద్య, వైద్యం మొదలైనవి) మరికొంత మొత్తాన్ని రిజర్వు నిధులకు కేటాయించి, మిగిలిన దానిని సభ్యులకు పరిమితమైన లాభాంశాలుగా పంచుతారు.10. సహకార సంస్థల నమోదు: సహకార సంస్థను సహకార సంఘాల చట్టము 1912 క్రింద నమోదు చేయించవలెను. అప్పుడు దానికి కంపెనీ హోదా వస్తుంది. దాని వలన సంస్థకు న్యాయాత్మకమైన వ్యక్తిత్వము, నిర్దిష్టమైన న్యాయసత్వము కలుగుతుంది."},{"question":"கேள்வி :உலகின் மிகச் சிறிய சந்து எது?","answer":"பதில்:புனித ஜான் சந்து. ரோமில் உள்ளது. 48 செ.மீ. அகலம்."},{"question":"İngiliz düşünür John Locke en çok ne ile bilinir ve anılır?","answer":"John Locke, İngiliz klasik liberalizm düşüncesinin öncüsü olan filozoftur. Meşruti demokrasinin temel fikirlerini tutarlı bir şekilde toparlayabilen ilk yazardır ve 17. yüzyılın en önemli düşünürlerinden biridir. Düşünce özgürlüğünü, insan eylemlerini akla göre düzenlemek anlayışını en geniş ölçüde yayan ilk düşünür olduğu için Avrupa'daki aydınlanma ve Akıl Çağı'nın gerçek kurucusu olarak kabul edilir. John Locke'a göre insan zihni doğuştan boş bir levhadır (tabula rasa) ve zihin birey yaşadıkça tecrübe ile şekillenir."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਭਨਾ ਜੀਆ ਕਾ ਇਕੁ ਦਾਤਾ ਸੋ ਮੈ ਵਿਸਰਿ ਨ ਜਾਈ ॥੫॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਿਹੜਾ ਸਭਨਾਂ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਦਾਤਾਂ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਇਕ ਰੱਬ ਹੈ, ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਭੁਲਾ ਨਾ ਦਿਆਂ ।੫।\\""},{"question":"د اجنډا اساسي ټکي څه شی دي ؟","answer":"ځواب – د بحث وړ مسایلو ټاکل )تصمیم نیونه( ، د اجنډا لېږل )۷۲ ساعته مخکي( ، مشخصه نمونه ، د ټولو ګډون والو لپاره اجنډا او د معلومو او نامعلومو مسایلو تفکيک ده ."},{"question":"¿Cuál es el libro más conocido de la escritora chilena Marcela Paz?","answer":"Uno de los libros más conocidos de la escritora Marcela Paz es Papelucho. "},{"question":"lithetha ntoni elingama \\"Chabasa\\"","answer":"ukuChabasa kuthetha uku cotha "},{"question":"தமிழ் மொழியின் செயல்களாகக் கவிஞர் கூறுவன யாவை?","answer":"தமிழ் மொழியின் செயல்கள் :(i) பொய்மை அகற்றும், மனதில் உள்ள அறியாமை என்ற இருளை நீக்கும்.(ii) அன்பு உடையவருக்கு இன்பம் தரும். பாடல்கள் நிறைந்த மொழி. உயிர் போன்ற உண்மையைக் கற்பித்து அறத்தின் உயர்வை உணர்த்தும். இவ்வுலக மக்கள்வாழ்வதற்கு வழிகாட்டும்."},{"question":"வினா: புதுமைப்பித்தன் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை:புதுமைப்பித்தன் என்ற புனைபெயர் கொண்ட சொ. விருத்தாசலம் (ஏப்ரல் 25, 1906 - சூன் 30, 1948), மிகச்சிறந்த தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவர். நவீன தமிழ் இலக்கியத்தின் ஒரு முன்னோடியாக இவர் கருதப்படுகிறார்.கூரிய சமூக விமர்சனமும் நையாண்டியும், முற்போக்குச் சிந்தனையும், இலக்கியச் சுவையும் கொண்ட இவருடைய படைப்புகள், இவரின் தனித்தன்மையினை நிறுவுகின்றன. இவரது படைப்புகள் மிக அதிகமாக விவாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. அதுமட்டுமின்றி, 2002இல் தமிழக அரசு இவரது படைப்புகளை நாட்டுடமை ஆக்கியது.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்புமணிக்கொடி இதழ்புதுமைப்பித்தன் கடலூர் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள திருப்பாதிரிப்புலியூரில் பிறந்தார். தொடக்கக் கல்வியைச் செஞ்சி, திண்டிவனம், கள்ளக்குறிச்சி ஆகிய இடங்களில் பயின்றார். தாசில்தாராகப் பணி புரிந்த அவர் தந்தை ஓய்வு பெற்றமையால், 1918-இல் அவரது சொந்த ஊரான திருநெல்வேலிக்குத் திரும்பினார். அங்குள்ள ஆர்ச் யோவான் ஸ்தாபனப் பள்ளியில் பள்ளிப் படிப்பை முடித்தார். பின்பு நெல்லை இந்துக் கல்லூரியில் இளங்கலைப் (பி. ஏ) பட்டம்பெற்றார். 1932 சூலையில் திருவனந்தபுரத்தைச் சேர்ந்த கமலாவை மணந்தார்.இவரது முதல் படைப்பான குலோப்ஜான் காதல் காந்தி இதழில் 1933-இல் வெளிவந்தது. 1934-இலிருந்து மணிக்கொடியில் இவரது படைப்புகள் பிரசுரமாகத் துவங்கின. மணிக்கொடியில் வெளிவந்த இவரின் முதல் சிறுகதை ஆத்தங்கரைப் பிள்ளையார். இந்தக் காலகட்டத்தில் அவர் சென்னைக்குக் குடிபெயர்ந்தார். இவர் வாழ்ந்த இடங்களான திருநெல்வேலியையும் சென்னையையும் மையமாகக் கொண்டே இவரது படைப்புகள் அமைந்தன. இவரது சிறுகதைகள் கலைமகள், ஜோதி, சுதந்திரச் சங்கு, ஊழியன், தமிழ்மணி, தினமணியின் ஆண்டு மலர், நந்தன் ஆகிய பத்திரிக்கைகளிலும் பிரசுரமாயின. 1940ல் புதுமைப்பித்தனின் கதைகள் என்ற அவரது சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பு வெளியானது. சென்னையிலிருந்த காலத்தில் இவர் ஊழியன், தினமணி, மற்றும் தினசரியிலும் பணிபுரிந்தார்.இவர் திரைப்படத் துறையிலும் ஆர்வம் செலுத்தினார். ஜெமினி நிறுவனத்தின் அவ்வை மற்றும் காமவல்லி படங்களில் பணிபுரிந்தார். பின்பு திரைப்படத் தயாரிப்பு நிறுவனமான \\"பர்வதகுமாரி புரொடக்ஷன்ஸ்\\" -ஐத் துவங்கி வசந்தவல்லி என்ற படத்தைத் தயாரிக்க முயன்று தோல்வியுற்றார். எம். கே. தியாகராஜ பாகவதரின் ராஜமுக்தி திரைப்படத்திற்கு வசனம் எழுதுவதற்காகப் புனேவில் சில மாதங்கள் வாழ்ந்தார். அங்கு அவர் கடுமையான காச நோய்க்கு ஆளாகி சூன் 30, 1948-இல் காலமானார்.படைப்புகளும் சிந்தனைகளும்புதுமைப்பித்தன் எழுத்துப்பணியில் முழுவீச்சில் ஈடுபட்டது 15 ஆண்டுகளுக்கும் குறைவான காலம் தான். அக்குறுகிய கால அளவிலேயே அவர் நூற்றுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட சிறுகதைகள், கிட்டத்தட்ட அதே எண்ணிக்கையுள்ள கட்டுரைகள், 15 கவிதைகள், சில நாடகங்கள், புத்தக விமரிசனங்கள் என எழுதிக் குவித்தார். அவரது எழுத்துக்கள் அவரைப் புரட்சி எழுத்தாளராக அடையாளம் காட்டின. அவர் கையாண்ட விஷயங்களும் கதாபாத்திரங்களும் தமிழ்ப் புனைவு உலகுக்குப் புதியதாய் அமைந்தன. தமிழ் இலக்கிய உலகம் சில எழுதப்படாத விதிகளால் முடக்கப்பட்டிருப்பதாக அவர் கருதினார். தன் கட்டுரை ஒன்றில் இவ்வாறு கூறுகிறார்:“\\tஇலக்கியத்தில் இன்னதுதான் சொல்ல வேண்டும், இன்னது சொல்லக்கூடாது என ஒரு தத்துவம் இருப்பதாகவும், அதை ஆதரித்துப் பேசுவதாகவும் மனப்பால் குடித்துக்கொண்டிருக்கலாம். உண்மை அதுவல்ல; சுமார் இருநூறு வருஷங்களாக ஒருவிதமான சீலைப்பேன் வாழ்வு நடத்திவிட்டோம். சில விஷயங்களை நேர் நோக்கிக் பாக்கவும் கூசுகிறோம். அதனால் தான் இப்படிச் சக்கரவட்டமாகச் சுற்றி வளைத்துச் சப்பைக்கட்டு கட்டுகிறோம். குரூரமே அவதாரமான ராவணனையும், ரத்தக்களறியையும், மனக் குரூபங்களையும், விகற்பங்களையும் உண்டாக்க இடம் இருக்குமேயானால், ஏழை விபசாரியின் ஜீவனோபாயத்தை வர்ணிப்பதாலா சமூகத்தின் தெம்பு இற்றுப்போய் விடப்போகிறது? இற்றுப்போனது எப்படிப் பாதுகாத்தாலும் நிற்கப்போகிறதா?மேலும் இலக்கியம் என்பது மன அவசத்தின் எழுச்சிதானே? நாலு திசையிலும் ஸ்டோர் குமாஸ்தா ராமன், ஸினிமா நடிகை சீத்தம்மாள், பேரம் பேசும் பிரமநாயகம் - இத்யாதி நபர்களை நாள் தவறாமல் பார்த்துக்கொண்டிருந்து விட்டு, இவர்களது வாழ்வுக்கு இடமளிக்காமல், காதல் கத்தரிக்காய் பண்ணிக்கொண்டிருப்பது போன்ற அனுபவத்துக்கு நேர் முரணான விவகாரம் வேறு ஒன்றும் இல்லை. நடைமுறை விவகாரங்களைப் பற்றி எழுதுவதில் கௌரவக் குறைச்சல் எதுவும் இல்லை.”தனது சமகால எழுத்தாளர்களின் எதிர்விமர்சனங்களைப் புறந்தள்ளி பின்வருமாறு கூறுகிறார்:“வேதாந்திகள் கைக்குள் சிக்காத கடவுள் மாதிரிதான் நான் பிறப்பித்துவிட்டவைகளும். அவை உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களுக்குள் அடைபடாதிருந்தால் நானும் பொறுப்பாளியல்ல, நான் பிறப்பித்து விளையாடவிட்ட ஜீவராசிகளும் பொறுப்பாளிகளல்ல; உங்கள் அளவுகோல்களைத்தான் என் கதைகளின் அருகில் வைத்து அளந்து பார்த்துக்கொள்கிறீர்கள் என்று உங்களுக்குச் சொல்லிவிட விரும்புகிறேன்.”சிறுகதைகள்புதுமைப்பித்தனின் சிறுகதைகள் தான் அவருக்கு எழுத்துலகில் தனி இடத்தை அளித்தன. அவர் எழுதியதாகக் கணிக்கப்படும் 108 சிறுகதைகளில் 48 மட்டுமே அவர் காலத்திலேயே வெளியாகின. அவரது சிறுகதைகள் மணிக்கொடி, கலைமகள், ஜோதி, சுதந்திர சங்கு, ஊழியன், தமிழ்மணி, தினமணியின் ஆண்டு மலர், நந்தன் ஆகிய பத்திரிக்கைகளில் பிரசுரமாயின. மற்றவை அவர் மறைவுக்குப் பின்னர் வெவ்வேறு காலங்களில் பிரசுரமாயின. கடைசித் தொகுப்பு 2000ல் வெளியானது. புதுமைப்பித்தன் 1930களில் உருவாகிய மணிக்கொடி இயக்கத்தின் முக்கிய எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவராக விளங்கினார். கு. ப. ராஜகோபாலன், பி. எஸ்.ராமையா, வ. ராமசாமி ஆகியோர் மணிக்கொடி இயக்கத்தின் மற்ற புகழ்பெற்ற எழுத்தாளர்களாவர்.பெரிய மீன் சின்ன மீனைத் தின்னலாம், ஆனால் சின்ன மீன் அதற்கும் சின்ன மீனைத் தின்றால் பெரிய மீன் ‘குற்றம் செய்கிறாய்!’ என தண்டிக்க வருகிறது. இது தான் சமூகம்!சிறுகதைகள்புதுமைப்பித்தனின் சிறுகதைகள் தான் அவருக்கு எழுத்துலகில் தனி இடத்தை அளித்தன. அவர் எழுதியதாகக் கணிக்கப்படும் 108 சிறுகதைகளில் 48 மட்டுமே அவர் காலத்திலேயே வெளியாகின. அவரது சிறுகதைகள் மணிக்கொடி, கலைமகள், ஜோதி, சுதந்திர சங்கு, ஊழியன், தமிழ்மணி, தினமணியின் ஆண்டு மலர், நந்தன் ஆகிய பத்திரிக்கைகளில் பிரசுரமாயின. மற்றவை அவர் மறைவுக்குப் பின்னர் வெவ்வேறு காலங்களில் பிரசுரமாயின. கடைசித் தொகுப்பு 2000ல் வெளியானது. புதுமைப்பித்தன் 1930களில் உருவாகிய மணிக்கொடி இயக்கத்தின் முக்கிய எழுத்தாளர்களுள் ஒருவராக விளங்கினார். கு. ப. ராஜகோபாலன், பி. எஸ்.ராமையா, வ. ராமசாமி ஆகியோர் மணிக்கொடி இயக்கத்தின் மற்ற புகழ்பெற்ற எழுத்தாளர்களாவர்.மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள்புதுமைப்பித்தன் 50க்கும் மேற்பட்ட சிறுகதைகளைப் பிற மொழிகளிலிருந்து மொழிபெயர்த்துள்ளார். அவர் மொழிபெயர்த்த எழுத்தாளர்களில் சிலர்: மொலியர், கே பாயில், மேக்சிம் கார்க்கி, சின்கிளெயயர் லூயிஸ், எர்னஸ்ட் டோலர், வில்லியம் ஷேக்ஸ்பியர், இ. எம். டேலாஃப்ல்டு, வில்லியம் சரோயன், இ. வி. லூகாஸ், மோஷே ஸ்மிலான்ஸ்கி, ராபர்ட் லூயிஸ் ஸ்டீவன்ஸன், பிரட் கார்ட், ஜான் கால்ஸ்வொர்த்தி, அலெக்ஸாண்டர் குப்ரின், ஆன்டன் செக்கோவ், பிராண்ஸ் காஃப்கா, இல்யா எக்ரன்பர்க், கை டி மாப்பாசான், வலெரி பிர்யுசொவ், அனாடோல் பிரான்ஸ், லியோனிட் ஆண்டிரியேவ், ஹென்ரிக் இப்சன், நாத்தேனியல் ஹாத்தோர்ன், எட்கர் ஆலன் போ, ராபர்ட் முரே கில்கிரிஸ்ட், பிரான்ஸிஸ் பெல்லர்பி, லியோனார்ட் ஸ்ட்ராங், ஜேக் லண்டன், பீட்டர் எக்கி, மிக்கெயில் அலெக்ஸாண்ட்ரோவிச் ஷோலோகோவ், தாமஸ் வுல்ஃப் மற்றும் ஜேம்ஸ் ஹேன்லி ஆவர். அவருக்கு மொழிபெயர்ப்புகள், தழுவல்கள் குறித்து தெளிவான கருத்து இருந்தது. தழுவல்கள் இலக்கியத் திருட்டுக்குச் சமம் என்றும் பிறமொழி படைப்புகளைத் தமிழுக்குக் கொண்டுவர மொழிபெயர்ப்பே சிறந்த வழியெனவும் கருதினார். 1937ல் மொழிபெயர்ப்பா, தழுவலா என்ற பிரச்சனையில் அவருக்கும் கல்கி கிருஷ்ணமூர்த்திக்கும் இடையே காட்டமான இலக்கியச் சண்டையொன்று நிகழ்ந்தது.கவிதைகள்புதுமைப்பித்தன் 15 கவிதைகள் எழுதியுள்ளார். அவரது முதல் கவிதையான திரு ஆங்கில அரசாங்க தொண்டரடிப்பொடியாழ்வார் வைபவம், 1934ல் வெளிவந்தது. அவரது கவிதைகள் பெரும்பாலும் அவரது நண்பர் தொ. மு. சிதம்பர ரகுநாதனுக்கு வெண்பா வடிவில் எழுதப்பட்ட கடிதங்களாக அமைந்திருந்தன. அவரது 15 கவிதைகளும் அவர் இறந்த பின்பு தான் பிரசுரமாயின. அவரது சிறுகதைகளைப்போலவே அவரது கவிதைகளும் நையாண்டியும், நக்கலுமாக இருந்ததன. மூனாவருணாசலமே மூடா, அவரது கவிதைகளுள் புகழ் பெற்றது. அது மணிக்கொடி இயக்கத்தைப் பற்றிக் குறிப்பிடாமல் விட்டுவிட்ட ஒரு தமிழ் புத்தகத்தினைச் (மு. அருணாசலத்தின் இன்றைய தமிழ் வசன நடை) சாடும் விமரிசனமாக எழுதப்பட்டிருந்தது.அரசியல் புத்தகங்கள்புதுமைப்பித்தன் அடிப்படையில் சோஷியலிச கருத்துகளைக் கொண்டவர். அவரது அரசியல் கட்டுரைகள் மற்றும் புத்தகங்களில் குறிப்பிடத்தக்கவை நான்கு. அவை ஃபாசிஸ்ட் ஜடாமுனி, (முசோலினியின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு) கப்சிப் தர்பார், (ஹிட்லரின் வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு) ஸ்டாலினுக்குத் தெரியும் மற்றும் அதிகாரம் யாருக்கு (இரண்டும் கம்னியூசத்தையும் ஸ்டாலினின் கொள்கைகளையும் விவரிப்பவை). நான்கு புத்தகங்களுமே ஃபாசிசத்தை எதிர்த்தும் ஸ்டாலினிய கொள்கைகளுக்கு ஆதரவாகவும் எழுதப்பட்டன.எழுத்துநடைசென்னை, தஞ்சாவூர்த் தமிழ் அல்லாது பிற வட்டார வழக்குத் தமிழில் எழுதிய முதல் எழுத்தாளர் புதுமைப்பித்தன். பெரும்பாலும் இவரது கதாபாத்திரங்கள் நெல்லைத் தமிழில் பேசினர். அவரது கதைகள் அவர் வாழ்ந்த இடங்களான சென்னை மற்றும் திருநெல்வேலியைக் களமாகக் கொண்டிருந்தன. அவரது நடையில் பேச்சுத்தமிழ் மற்றும் செந்தமிழ் இரண்டும் கலந்திருந்தன. சிக்கலான விஷயங்களைக் கையாளும்போது கூட அவரது எழுத்துக்களில் நையாண்டி இழைந்தோடுவது அவரது சிறப்பு. கல்கி கிருஷ்ணமூர்த்தி போன்ற இலக்கிய எதிராளிகளுடன் விவாதம் செய்தபோது கடுஞ்சொற்களைப் பயன்படுத்தினார். நூல் விமரிசனங்களில் வசைபாடல்களையும் எழுதியுள்ளார்."},{"question":"A jọ n ta ko SARS ni, ṣugbọn mi o le maa sare kiri – Pasuma","answer":"Ni nnkan bii ọjọ meloo kan sẹyin lawọn ọdọ kan bu ẹnu atẹ lu Alaaji Wasiu Alabi Pasuma, ẹsun ti wọn si fi kan an ni pe ọkunrin olorin fuji naa ko darapọ mọ awọn ọdọ Naijiria lati ṣewọde ta ko gbogbo ohun ti ijọba n ṣe tawọn ko fẹ.Bi wọn ṣe sọrọ yii, bẹẹ niroyin ti gbe e, ṣugbọn ọkunrin onifuji yii naa ti sọrọ o, o ni awọn eeyan kan naa lo sọ pe gbogbo ẹni tọjọ ori ẹ ba ti ju aadọta ọdun lọ, kiru ẹni bẹẹ yee ṣe langbalangba bii ọdọ kiri.Nibi ayẹyẹ kan to ti lọọ kọrin laipẹ yii lo ti kọ ọ lorin pe oṣu to n bọ yii, iyẹn oṣu kọkanla, ọdun yii, loun yoo pe ẹni ọdun mẹtalelaaadọta looke eepẹ.Wasiu Alabi Pasuma sọ pe, “Gbogbo ohun ti awọn ọdọ ba ṣe pata lori ki Naijiria le dara, gbagbaagba ni mo wa lẹyin wọn, ko ṣẹṣẹ digba ti mo ba n sare tẹle wọn kiri. Gbogbo ori ẹrọ ayelujara mi, ‘officialpasuma’, la ti n ṣatilẹyin fun wọn.”O fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe bi oun ko tiẹ jade, awọn ọmọ toun bi tawọn naa ti toju u bọ ti to lati kopa nibi iwọde ọhun nitori ọdọ Naijiria lawọn naa i ṣe.“Laipe yii ni Wasilat, akọbi ọmọ mi yoo pe ọgbọn ọdun, bakan naa ni Barakat yoo pe ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlọgbọn, bẹẹ ni mo tun lọmọ mi-in to ti ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelogun. Fun idi eyi, lara awọn ọdọ Naijiria lawọn ọmọ mi yii wa, ti emi baba wọn ba si wa nile ti mo n fọkan ba wọn lọ, pẹlu awọn eyi ti mo ba le maa ṣe lori oriṣiiriṣii ikanni ayelujara ti mo ni, dajudaju a jọ n ṣe e ni.”Tẹ ọ ba gbagbe, bí iwọde ọhun ṣe n lọ kaakiri orilẹ-ede yii lawọn olorin atawọn oṣere tiata kaakiri Naijiria naa jade lati ta ko iwa buruku ti awọn SARS n hu, atawọn ohun mi-in tawọn ọmọ Naijiria sọ pe ijọba gbọdọ wa ojútùú si.Lara awọn oṣere to ti kopa daadaa tawọn eeyan n ri kiri ni Ṣeun Kuti, Eedris Abdulkareem, Saidi Osupa, Ọdunlade Adekọla, Davido, Small Doctor, Yọmi Fabiyi, Kikẹlọmọ Adéyẹmí, Rugged man ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ."},{"question":"Jaka  amerykańska wytwórnia filmowa założona w 1971 przez George’a Lucasa, została przejęta przez firmę The Walt Disney Company w 2012 r?","answer":"Jest nią studio Lucasfilm."},{"question":"ராமாயணத்தில் “சொல்லின் செல்வர்” என அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்  யார் ?","answer":"விடை: ராமாயணத்தில் “சொல்லின் செல்வர்” என அழைக்கப்பட்டவர்  அனுமன்.இலங்கையில் சீதையைக் கண்டதையும், சீதை கற்புநெறி தவறாமல் இருப்பதையும், இப்படி சுருக்கமாகச் கூறினார் ஆஞ்சநேயர். அதனால்தான் அவரை சொல்லின் செல்வர் என்றனர். ராமாயணத்தில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிப்பவர் ஆஞ்சநேயர்."},{"question":"Wọn fẹẹ da ija Yoruba ati Ibo silẹ ni o","answer":"Ẹgbẹ awon agbaagba ilẹ Ibo ti wọn n pe ni Ohaneze ti sọ pe ki ẹnikẹni ma ṣe gba ahesọ kan to n lọ nigboro gbọ lori iwọde SARS, iyẹn ariwo ti awọn kan n pa kiri pe awọn ọmọ Ibo lo fẹe ba ilu Eko ati lẹ Yoruba jẹ. Ẹgbẹ naa ni ko sohun to jọ ọ. Aarẹ ẹgbẹ awọn agba ilẹ Ibo yii, Oloye John Nwodo lo sọro naa jade fura ẹ.Baba naa ni oun ti n gbọ oriṣiriṣi ọrọ, bẹẹ ni awọn aṣaaju ilẹ Ibo paapaa n gbọ, bi awọn kan ti n gbe e kiri pe awọn Ibo lo wa nidii biba dukia Eko jẹ, nitori inu to n bi wọn si ilẹ Yoruba. O ni eyi ko le ri bẹẹ laye, nitori ipinlẹ Eko ati ilẹ Yoruba ni ọpọlọ ọmọ Ibo ti n ri jijẹ-mimu wọn, ti wọn si n gbe igbe-aye rere, bawo ni eeyan yoo waa ṣe ba ibi to ti n ri jijẹ ati mimu rẹ jẹ.Nwodo ni ajọṣe to ti wa laarin awọn Yoruba ati Ibo lati ayebaye ko ni i jẹ ki iru eleyii ṣẹlẹ, o ji ipa ti Yoruba ko ninu irin-ajo oṣelu Oloye Nnamdi Azikiwe ko kere bẹẹ naa ni won ṣe atilẹyin to yẹ fun Ibo lasiko ogun Ojukwu, nitori gbogbo diukia to jẹ ti awọn Ibo ni wọn pada waa ba nilẹ Yoruba lẹyin ti ogun pari, ti ko sẹni to sọ dukia kankan di tiẹ laarin awọn aṣaaju Yoruba gbogbo.Nwodo ni awom ti wọn n gbe ọrọ yii kiri mọ ohun ti wọn n ṣe, wọn kan fẹẹ fi da ija Ibo ati Yoruba silẹ lasan ni, bẹẹ ni ko si aṣaaju ilẹ Ibo kan to faramọ ọrọ ti Nnamdi Kanu, olori ẹgbẹ kan ti wọn n pe ara wọn ni ajijagbara ilẹ Biafra naa n sọ. O ni ki gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba gbọ o, ki awọn Ibo ti wọn wa nilẹ Yoruba naa si gbọ, pe ọrẹ nla ni wọn, ki wọn ma jẹ ki awọn ti wọn n gbe ahesọ kiri da aarin wọn ru, nitori awọn yẹn kan fẹe fi daja ẹlẹyamẹyaa silẹ ni."},{"question":"Tôi ở Hà Nội, cần chuyển khoản cho em gái trong Cần Thơ 600 triệu đồng nhưng nghe nói có quy định mới yêu cầu chuyển trên 500 triệu đồng phải lập báo cáo, có phải vậy không? Xin hỏi việc này chỉ áp dụng với ngoại tệ hay cả với tiền Việt Nam đồng? Người trong gia đình chuyển cho nhau có phải làm báo cáo không, hay chỉ các đối tác làm ăn?","answer":"Thông tư số 09/2023 của Ngân hàng Nhà nước, Hướng dẫn thực hiện một số điều của Luật phòng chống rửa tiền, quy định các trường hợp phải báo cáo cơ quan thực hiện chức năng, nhiệm vụ phòng chống rửa tiền khi thực hiện giao dịch chuyển tiền điện tử bao gồm:- Giao dịch chuyển tiền điện tử mà tất cả tổ chức tài chính tham gia giao dịch chuyển tiền điện tử cùng ở Việt Nam (chuyển tiền điện tử trong nước) có giá trị giao dịch từ 500 triệu đồng trở lên, hoặc bằng ngoại tệ có giá trị tương đương.- Giao dịch chuyển tiền điện tử mà có ít nhất một trong các tổ chức tài chính tham gia giao dịch chuyển tiền điện tử ở các quốc gia, vùng lãnh thổ ngoài Việt Nam (chuyển tiền điện tử quốc tế) có giá trị từ 1.000 USD trở lên hoặc bằng ngoại tệ khác có giá trị tương đương.Như vậy, giao dịch chuyển tiền trong nước giữa bạn và em gái, tuy có giá trị thuộc mức quy định nhưng được thực hiện giữa hai cá nhân nên không phải báo cáo."},{"question":"What initiatives are in place to promote sustainable tourism in Sri Lanka, balancing economic benefits with environmental conservation?","answer":"Sri Lanka has been actively promoting sustainable tourism by encouraging eco-friendly practices, community engagement, and wildlife conservation. Certification programs for eco-friendly accommodations and responsible tourism campaigns aim to ensure that tourism contributes positively to both the economy and the environment. Here are some key examples:1. Policy and Regulatory Framework:National Sustainable Tourism Policy 2018: This policy outlines a comprehensive framework for sustainable tourism development, including responsible visitor management, environmental protection, and community engagement.National Ecotourism Strategy: This strategy focuses on promoting eco-friendly tourism practices and experiences, such as wildlife conservation and sustainable agriculture.Regulations on plastic use and waste management: Bans on plastic bags and straws, along with initiatives to promote responsible waste disposal, are reducing pollution and protecting natural landscapes.2. Certification and Recognition Programs:Green Hotels Program: This program recognizes hotels committed to environmental sustainability, incentivizing eco-friendly practices like energy and water conservation.Sustainable Tourism Certification: This certification scheme assesses tourism businesses on their environmental, social, and economic sustainability practices, allowing tourists to choose responsible operators.Sri Lanka has recognized the need for sustainable tourism and implemented various initiatives to achieve this balance between economic benefits and environmental conservation. Here are some key examples:1. Policy and Regulatory Framework:National Sustainable Tourism Policy 2018: This policy outlines a comprehensive framework for sustainable tourism development, including responsible visitor management, environmental protection, and community engagement.National Ecotourism Strategy: This strategy focuses on promoting eco-friendly tourism practices and experiences, such as wildlife conservation and sustainable agriculture.Regulations on plastic use and waste management: Bans on plastic bags and straws, along with initiatives to promote responsible waste disposal, are reducing pollution and protecting natural landscapes.2. Certification and Recognition Programs:Green Hotels Program: This program recognizes hotels committed to environmental sustainability, incentivizing eco-friendly practices like energy and water conservation.Sustainable Tourism Certification: This certification scheme assesses tourism businesses on their environmental, social, and economic sustainability practices, allowing tourists to choose responsible operators.3. Community-Based Initiatives:Village Tourism: This initiative promotes tourism in rural areas, empowering local communities to benefit economically from tourism while preserving their culture and traditions.Homestays and eco-lodges: These accommodations offer tourists a more authentic experience while minimizing environmental impact and supporting local communities.Wildlife conservation projects: Tourists can participate in volunteer programs to protect endangered species and preserve natural habitats.4. Awareness and Education:Public awareness campaigns: These campaigns educate tourists and locals about the importance of responsible tourism and minimize negative impacts on the environment and culture.Sustainability training for tourism operators: Training programs equip tourism businesses with knowledge and skills to operate sustainably and minimize their environmental footprint.5. Technological Adoption:Online platforms for responsible tourism: Platforms like eco-tourism booking sites and sustainable travel blogs inform tourists about responsible options and encourage eco-conscious choices.Conservation technology: Drones for wildlife monitoring, apps for responsible waste management, and eco-friendly transportation options are being explored and implemented.Challenges and Opportunities:Balancing economic benefits with environmental conservation remains a challenge. Overcrowding at popular sites, pollution, and cultural appropriation are issues that need continued attention. However, Sri Lanka's commitment to sustainable tourism, coupled with growing awareness and technological advancements, offers promising opportunities for a thriving tourism industry that benefits both people and planet."},{"question":"د لاندې وینا په پام کې نیولو سره، پښتو ته یې ژباړئ:“John loves Jesica”","answer":"پښتو ته د جملې ژباړل داسې دي: \\"جان جیسیکا سره مینه لري\\""},{"question":"چند مکان دیدنی در جزیره قشم را معرفی کن.","answer":"از نقاط دیدنی جزیره قشم جنگل‌های حرا، تنگه چاهکوه، درهٔ ستاره‌ها، جزایر ناز، و غار نمکدان است. "},{"question":"أريد إيجاد عنوان مناسب للنص التالي: نفى طلعت زكي حافظ، أمين عام لجنة الإعلام والتوعية المصرفية والمتحدث باسم البنوك السعودية، صحة المعلومات الواردة في إحدى التقارير الصحفية المحلية، حيال زيادة البنوك لنسب أرباح التمويل العقاري على مستفيدي برنامج 'الدعم السكني' التابع لوزارة الإسكان، ومستفيدي برنامج 'التمويل المدعوم' بصندوق التنمية العقارية. وقال :' إن القطاع المصرفي يفرض نسبة موحدة على أصحاب التمويل العقاري الشخصي، و مستفيدي برامج الإسكان والصندوق العقاري'، وأضاف طلعت حافظ، بأن التقرير الصحفي، أشار إلى معدل الربح السنوي (APR) وقارنها بنسبة الأرباح الثابته (flat)، مؤكدا بأن هذه المقارنة 'غير سليمة' منطقيا، واقتصاديا. وطالب أمين عام لجنة الإعلام والتوعية المصرفية والمتحدث باسم البنوك السعودية، أفراد المجتمع بشكل عام والخبراء الاقتصاديين والعقاريين على وجه الخصوص، بأهمية تحري الدقة من الجهات المعنية بالأمر عند نشر وتحليل المعلومات للرأي العام..","answer":"«البنوك السعودية»: لا زيادة على نسب أرباح التمويل العقاري لمستفيدي الإسكان والعقاري."},{"question":"질문: 배우가 되려면 어떻게 해야 해요?답:","answer":"배우가 되는 방법에는 여러가지가 있습니다. 일반적으로는 연극영화과를 진학하여 체계적으로 배우면서 마이너리그, 메이저리그가 있는 것 처럼 저투자 작품부터 서서히 활동하면서 고투자 작품으로 올라가는 것입니다. 그 안에는 역시나 저투자 작품이라고 해도 단역부터 주연까지 그런 단계가 있다고 말할 수가 있습니다. 또한 십대 시절부터 기획사에 들어가서 가수로 데뷰 후 만능 엔터테이너로 배우 쪽으로도 동시에 영역을 확장하는 분들도 있습니다. 하지만 가수처럼 연습생으로 시작하는 분들은 상당히 적습니다. 지금 활동하는 배우들도 거의 바로 소속사에서 시작하거나 방송드라마 상업영화가 시작이 아니라는 부분을 참고하시길 바랍니다. 최근에는 모델로 캐리어를 시작했다가 배우로 전환하는 분들도 있습니다. "},{"question":"Kintana ao amin'ny rafi-masoandro misy antsika ny Masoandro. Inona no safidy heverina ho diso momba ny masoandro?1. Ny masoandro dia mamoaka hazavana.2. Ny masoandro dia vita amin'ny fromazy.3. Mafana be ny masoandro.","answer":"Ny safidy diso dia - 2. Ny masoandro dia vita amin'ny fromazy."},{"question":"Fim din James Bond na wace kasa ne?","answer":"Fim din James Bond na kasar Birtaniya ne. Jerin James Bond ya mayar da hankali kan James Bond, wani ɗan jarida mai ba da labari na Burtaniya wanda marubuci Ian Fleming ya kirkira a shekarata alif 1953, wanda ya nuna shi a cikin litattafai goma sha biyu da tarin gajerun labarai guda biyu. Tun mutuwar Fleming a shekarar alif 1964, wasu mawallafa takwas sun rubuta takardun shaida na Bond ko litattafai: Kingsley Amis, Christopher Wood, John Gardner, Raymond Benson, Sebastian Faulks, Jeffery Deaver, William Boyd, da Anthony Horowitz . Sabon labari shine Tare da Hankali don Kashe ta Anthony Horowitz, wanda aka buga a watan Mayu shekarata 2022."},{"question":"Naruuradee jacaylkeeLafoole","answer":"Naruuradee jacaylkeeLafooleNuurkii indhaha iyoNafta raaxadeedaayTaan nasiibka ku hamiyaayCalaf ineey u noqotaayKu nagaatay labtooNuudayaasha beerkiyo wadnahabaad ku nabantahayeeNaruuradii jacayl kaaySharka laga nasahayeeSidii nirigta maandeeqNaxariista eegmadaUgu soo noqnoqotaanBilaneey kuugu nugulahayNiyadeeydu gacalooyMideey naawishaad tahayTii nacab iblaysiyoNaxli laga fogeeyaayNoocii ijaabadaTii lagu nisbeeyaayNooci ijaabadaTii lagu nusbeeyaayNasteexadii IlaaheeyTii aan ka noogineeNaajax ku ahaydeeNugul laba u kala rooneeNaqa iyo abaartuyeSoow laabta umaad noqonDagarka iyo doogiiNacas lama amaaneeNaagaba adoo wacanNin raga saamigii siyeeNaruuradii jaceeylkeeSharta laga nasahayeeSidi nirigta maandeeqNaxariista eegmadaUgu soo noqnoqotaan bilaneeyKuugu nugulahayNiyadeeydu gacalooyMideey naawishaad tahay"},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે. આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો. \\"હું કહું છું કે રોજ દેવદર્શને જવું જઈએ.⁠બસ ચોરણી જ પહેર; મને ચોરણી પહેરે તે જ ગમે.⁠જોને, આમ તે વાળ ઓળાય ? આમ મારી જેમ ઓળ.⁠તે એમાં શું ? થોડું થોડું મરચું ખાતાં યે શીખવું જોઈએ.⁠જો ભા, એમ ન બેસાય. એમ બેસીએ તો ભૂંડા લાગીએ.⁠એમ તે હાથ ધોવાય ? કોણી સુધી ધોવા જોઈએ.⁠બાજરાના રોટલા ભાવવા જ જોઈએ; મને તો બહુ જ ભાવે છે.\\"","answer":"ભાઈ, જેને દેવદર્શને જવું હોય તે જાય.⁠તને ગમે તે પહેર; ચોરણી ગમે તો ચોરણી ને ઘાઘરી ગમે તો ઘાઘરી.​⁠તને ગમે તેમ વાળ તેં ઓળ્યા, ને મને ગમે તેમ મેં ઓળ્યા.⁠ભાવે તો મરચું ખા; નહિતર આ શાક છે તે જરા મોળું છે.⁠જો ભા, આમ બેસીશ ? એમ બેસે તે સૌને જરા જગા વધે. જો આમ ઘસીને હાથ ધો; બગડ્યા હોય તેટલા ધોઈએ.⁠બાજરાનો રોટલો ન ભાવે તો ઘ‌ઉંનો ખા; કોઈકને ન પણ ભાવે."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ਮਃ ੧ ॥ਕੂੜੁ ਬੋਲਿ ਮੁਰਦਾਰੁ ਖਾਇ ॥ਅਵਰੀ ਨੋ ਸਮਝਾਵਣਿ ਜਾਇ ॥ਮੁਠਾ ਆਪਿ ਮੁਹਾਏ ਸਾਥੈ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਐਸਾ ਆਗੂ ਜਾਪੈ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 139 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਝੂਠ ਬੋਲ ਕੇ (ਆਪ ਤਾਂ) ਦੂਜਿਆਂ ਦਾ ਹੱਕ ਖਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹੋਰਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿੱਖਿਆ ਦੇਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਕਿ ਝੂਠ ਨਾਹ ਬੋਲੋ),ਆਪ ਤਾਂ ਠੱਗਿਆ ਜਾ ਹੀ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਆਪਣੇ ਸਾਥ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਲੁਟਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਅਜੇਹਾ ਆਗੂ (ਅੰਤ ਇਉਂ) ਹੀ ਉੱਘੜਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Àpẹẹrẹ ọ̀rọ̀ àyálò níbi tí kọ́ńsónáńtì ti parí òrò ni:","answer":"Tọ́ọ̀gì (thug)."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Saya beraksi di atas pentas dengan memakai seluar pendek dan berkasut, saya juga bersarung tangan untuk berlawan dengan pencabar saya di atas pentas. Siapakah saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Ahli Tinju. Ahli sukan ini biasanya memakai seluar pendek dan berkasut dalam pentas pertarungan, sarung tangan juga dipakai dalam perlawanan."},{"question":"Tohizo ity : “ Ny fanahy no maha ________ “ .","answer":"“ Ny fanahy no mahaolona “."},{"question":"Generate a headline for the following text: Karin farashin man fetur da na hasken wutar lantarkin da aka yi a Najeriya sun sake jefa 'yan kasar a mawuyacin hali. Hakan na faruwa ne a yayin da suke cikin karin matsin tattalin arziki sakamakon annobar korona wacce ta tilasta wa duniya zama cikin dokar kulle. Sai dai gwamnatin kasar ta bayyana dalilai da suka sanya tsadar rayuwa a kasar. BBC Hausa ta yi nazari yadda 'yan Najeriya, wadda gwamnatin tarayyarta take biyan ₦30,000 a matsayin mafi karancin albashi, za su yi amfani da wannan adadi wajen gudanar da rayuwarsu a wannan mawuyacin hali da ake ciki.","answer":"Sure, here's a headline for the given text - Tsadar rayuwa a Najeriya: Shin ₦30,000 za ta iya magance matsalolinku?"},{"question":"Quando começou a preocupação com as regulações na área de recursos marinhos e áreas costeiras por parte do governo brasileiro?","answer":"Na década de 1970."},{"question":"第一句:学校还实施了新的CCE系统, 以对学生进行全面和持续的评估. 第二句:学校也实行了新的CCE系统, 以对学生进行持续和全面的评估. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":" 相同"},{"question":"Quel élément Joseph Priestley a-t-il découvert en 1774 ?","answer":"En 1774, Joseph Priestley découvre l'élément oxygène. Il a mené des expériences avec une substance qu'il a appelée « air déphlogistiqué », qui a ensuite été identifiée comme étant de l'oxygène. Les travaux de Priestley ont contribué à faire progresser la compréhension des gaz et de leur rôle dans la combustion et la respiration, jetant ainsi les bases d'une compréhension moderne de l'importance de l'oxygène dans le maintien de la vie et des processus chimiques."},{"question":"મને ગાયક આશિત દેસાઈ વિષે જણાવો.","answer":"આશિત દેસાઈ ગુજરાતી સુગમ સંગીત ગાયક - સંગીતકાર એક છે.તેઓ તેમના પત્ની હેમા દેસાઈ સાથે ગુજરાતી સુગમ સંગીતમાં એક લાંબી અને વૈવિધ્ય પૂર્ણ કારકિર્દી ધરાવે છે. આશિત દેસાઈની સ્વર રચનાઓમાં શાસ્ત્રીય સંગીતની બારીકાઈઓની સમજ ખાસ દેખાઈ આવે છે. તેઓ કવિ પણ છે. તેમણે લખેલી (કાવ્ય) રચનાઓ પ્રમાણમાં ઓછી છે અને તે કવિતાઓને સ્વાભાવિક રીતે આશિત દેસાઈની ઉત્તમ સ્વર રચનાઓનો સાથ સાંપડે છે. આશિત દેસાઈનો પુત્ર આલાપ દેસાઈ પણ એક ગાયક અને તબલા વાદક છે."},{"question":"1° Oración: Los resultados son altos cuando se pueden mantener tasas de flujo comparables.2° Oración: Los resultados son comparables cuando se pueden mantener altos caudales.Pregunta: ¿La oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2? ¿Sí o no?","answer":"Sí, la oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2. Ambas oraciones expresan la misma idea pero con una estructura gramatical diferente."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe haavon-toerana?","answer":"Ny haavon-toerana dia ny elanelan'ny toerana iray amin'ny teboka na velarana iaingana, ity dia ny an'ny ranomasina ifanarahana, izay 0 m (aotra metatra), raha ny toerana eto an-Tany no heverina. Refesina araka izany ny hahavon'ny tendrombohitra iray, ny haavon'ny toerana misy ny tanàna iray, ny toerana misy ny zavatra eny amin'ny habakabaka toy ny rahona, ny lalan'ny fiaramanidina, sns. Mety ho miabo na miiba ny haavon-toerana iray. "},{"question":"5 xikmadood?","answer":"5 xikmadood oo qaali ah1: Hadii aad riyadaada ku gaarka ah dhisanQofkale kushaqaalaysiin doonaInaad riyaddisa la dhisto2: Guulaystuhu maaha qofka aan waligii fashilmin ee waa qofka aan waligii aan quusan3: Ha joojin markaad daasho ee waxaad Joojisaa markaad si buuxda wax uqabato4:Markay caqabaduhu ku wada xidhaan waxaad soo xasuusata kuwa badan oo Ku faraxsan in ay arkaan guuldaradaada5:Looser laguu sheegayaa waa qofka aanWaxbaa isku dayin kabaqa isbadalka"},{"question":"வினா : மொரிசியஷியஸின் நாணயம் எது ? ","answer":"விடை : ரூபாய்"},{"question":"नेवार सभ्यताले काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा भूकम्प र मौसमी भिन्नता जस्ता वातावरणीय चुनौतिहरूसँग कसरी अनुकूलन र सामना गर्यो?","answer":"नेवार सभ्यताले काठमाडौं उपत्यकामा वातावरणीय चुनौतिहरूसँग अनुकूलन गर्दै, भूकम्प प्रतिरोधी वास्तुकला प्रविधिहरू कार्यान्वयन गर्दै र मौसमी भिन्नताहरूसँग सामना गर्न र लचिलोपन सुनिश्चित गर्न दिगो कृषि अभ्यासहरू विकास गर्दै।"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： ユニクロの会社が日本の社員の給料を上げる　多い場合約40％","answer":"ユニクロの会社は、日本で働く社員に払う給料を3月から上げることにしました。約8400人の1年の給料を、いちばん多い場合約40％多くします。例えば、新しく入った社員の最初の給料は、1か月25万5000円を30万円にします。会社に入って1年から2年で店長になった人は、1か月29万円を39万円にします。日本では物の値段が上がっています。会社は、社員のために給料を上げたと言っています。日本で働く人の給料を外国で働く人の給料と同じぐらいにして、世界の優秀な人たちに会社で働いてもらいたいと考えています。"},{"question":"Атлантика океаны аркылуу жалгыз учуп өткөн биринчи аял","answer":"Амелия Эрхарт"},{"question":"ਰਾਹੁਲ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦਾ PM ਮੋਦੀ 'ਤੇ ਵੱਡਾ ਹਮਲਾ, ਕਿਹਾ- ਮਣੀਪੁਰ 'ਚ ਹਿੰਦੂਸਤਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਤਲ- ਅਜੇ ਤੱਕ ਦੌਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਸਕਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਸੇਵਕ।","answer":"ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਵਜੋਂ ਮੈਂਬਰਸ਼ਿਪ ਬਹਾਲ ਹੋਣ ਮਗਰੋਂ ਅੱਜ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇਤਾ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਸਦਨ ਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਗਰਜ਼ੇ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਲੋਕ ਸਭਾ ਮੈਂਬਰ ਦੀ ਮੈਂਬਰਸ਼ਿਪ ਬਹਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਕੀਤਾ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਰਾਹੁਲ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮੋਦੀ ਤੇ ਵੱਡਾ ਹਮਲਾ ਕੀਤਾ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ, ਮਣੀਪੁਰ ਵਿਚ ਮੋਦੀ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਮਾਤਾ (ਮੇਰੀ ਮਾਂ) ਦਾ ਕਤਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਰਾਹੁਲ ਨੇ ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਾਇਆ ਕਿ, ਇਹ ਭਾਜਪਾ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਵਾਲੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇਸ਼ ਧ੍ਰੋਹੀ ਹਨ। "},{"question":"\\" චාගෝස් දූපත් \\" ලෙස අතීතයේදී හැඳින්වූ , ඉන්දියානු සාගරයේ පිහිටි භූමිය වර්තමානයේ හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද ?","answer":"\\" චාගෝස් දූපත් \\" ලෙස අතීතයේදී හැඳින්වූ , ඉන්දියානු සාගරයේ පිහිටි භූමිය වර්තමානයේ හඳුන්වන්නේ දියාගෝ ගාර්ෂියා යන නමිනි. "},{"question":"Voimistuvatko trooppiset hirmumyrskyt ilmastonmuutoksen vaikutuksesta?","answer":"Hirmumyrskyjen ensisijainen energianlähde on lämmin meri. Koska merivedet lämpenevät ilmastonmuutoksen vaikutuksesta, tällä on arvioitu olevan vaikutusta myös hirmumyrskyjen esiintymiseen ja voimakkuuteen. Trooppisen myrskyn intensiteetin todennäköisyyttä ei voida kuitenkaan yksistään arvioida meriveden pintalämpötilan perusteella. Mutta mitä enemmän merestä voi vapautua lämpöä hirmumyrskyn kehitykseen, sitä pidemmän ajan hirmumyrskyllä on mahdollisuus muuntua vuorovaikutuksessa ilmakehässä vallitsevien meteorologisten tekijöiden kanssa.Tällä hetkellä ilmastotutkimuksessa mallisimulaatioiden perusteella arvioidaankin, että kaikkein voimakkaimmat trooppiset myrskyt todennäköisemmin voimistuvat kuin eivät, mutta ei ole varmuutta siitä, millä aikataululla ja millä alueilla näin voi käydä."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਿਰੀਰਾਗੁ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਜਗਿ ਹਉਮੈ ਮੈਲੁ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਮਲੁ ਲਾਗੀ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ॥ਮਲੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਧੋਤੀ ਕਿਵੈ ਨ ਉਤਰੈ ਜੇ ਸਉ ਤੀਰਥ ਨਾਇ ॥ਬਹੁ ਬਿਧਿ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਵਦੇ ਦੂਣੀ ਮਲੁ ਲਾਗੀ ਆਇ ॥ਪੜਿਐ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਉਤਰੈ ਪੂਛਹੁ ਗਿਆਨੀਆ ਜਾਇ ॥੧॥ਮਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਗੁਰ ਸਰਣਿ ਆਵੈ ਤਾ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਥਕੇ ਮੈਲੁ ਨ ਸਕੀ ਧੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਮਨਿ ਮੈਲੈ ਭਗਤਿ ਨ ਹੋਵਈ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਪਾਇਆ ਜਾਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖ ਮੈਲੇ ਮੈਲੇ ਮੁਏ ਜਾਸਨਿ ਪਤਿ ਗਵਾਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਪਰਸਾਦੀ ਮਨਿ ਵਸੈ ਮਲੁ ਹਉਮੈ ਜਾਇ ਸਮਾਇ ॥ਜਿਉ ਅੰਧੇਰੈ ਦੀਪਕੁ ਬਾਲੀਐ ਤਿਉ ਗੁਰ ਗਿਆਨਿ ਅਗਿਆਨੁ ਤਜਾਇ ॥੨॥ਹਮ ਕੀਆ ਹਮ ਕਰਹਗੇ ਹਮ ਮੂਰਖ ਗਾਵਾਰ ॥ਕਰਣੈ ਵਾਲਾ ਵਿਸਰਿਆ ਦੂਜੈ ਭਾਇ ਪਿਆਰੁ ॥ਮਾਇਆ ਜੇਵਡੁ ਦੁਖੁ ਨਹੀ ਸਭਿ ਭਵਿ ਥਕੇ ਸੰਸਾਰੁ ॥ਗੁਰਮਤੀ ਸੁਖੁ ਪਾਈਐ ਸਚੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਉਰ ਧਾਰਿ ॥੩॥ਜਿਸ ਨੋ ਮੇਲੇ ਸੋ ਮਿਲੈ ਹਉ ਤਿਸੁ ਬਲਿਹਾਰੈ ਜਾਉ ॥ਏ ਮਨ ਭਗਤੀ ਰਤਿਆ ਸਚੁ ਬਾਣੀ ਨਿਜ ਥਾਉ ॥ਮਨਿ ਰਤੇ ਜਿਹਵਾ ਰਤੀ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਸਚੇ ਗਾਉ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮੁ ਨ ਵੀਸਰੈ ਸਚੇ ਮਾਹਿ ਸਮਾਉ ॥੪॥੩੧॥੬੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 39 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜਗਤ ਨੇ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ (ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਸਦਾ) ਦੁੱਖ (ਹੀ) ਸਹਾਰਿਆ ਹੈ (ਕਿਉਂਕਿ) ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਚੰਬੜੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸੌ ਤੀਰਥਾਂ ਉੱਤੇ (ਭੀ) ਇਸ਼ਨਾਨ ਕਰੇ ਤਾਂ ਭੀ (ਅਜੇਹੇ) ਕਿਸੇ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ (ਇਹ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਧੋਤਿਆਂ (ਮਨ ਤੋਂ) ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਲੋਕ ਕਈ ਕਿਸਮਾਂ ਦੇ (ਮਿਥੇ ਹੋਏ) ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਕੰਮ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਸਗੋਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਨਾਲੋਂ) ਦੂਣੀ (ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ ਆ ਲਗਦੀ ਹੈ (ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਆਦਿਕ) ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਨਾਲ ਭੀ ਇਹ ਮੈਲ ਦੂਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ, ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਪੜ੍ਹੇ ਹੋਏ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਪੁੱਛ ਲਵੋ (ਭਾਵ, ਪੜ੍ਹੇ ਹੋਏ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵਿੱਦਿਆ ਪੜ੍ਹਨ ਦਾ ਮਾਣ ਹੀ ਬਣਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੧। ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ! (ਜਦੋਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤਦੋਂ (ਹੀ) ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਰਾਮ ਰਾਮ ਆਖ ਆਖ ਕੇ ਥੱਕ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਫਿਰ ਭੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ) ਮੈਲ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਪਾਸੋਂ) ਧੋਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ। ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਮੈਲ ਨਾਲ ਭਰੇ ਹੋਏ ਮਨ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ, (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਾਸਲ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦਾ (ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ)ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਸਦਾ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਮਲੀਨ-ਮਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤੇ ਮਰੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਉਹ ਦੁਨੀਆ ਤੋਂ) ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਗਵਾ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਜਾਣਗੇਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਵੱਸ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦੀ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹਜਿਵੇਂ (ਜੇ) ਹਨੇਰੇ ਵਿਚ ਦੀਵਾ ਬਾਲ ਦੇਈਏ (ਤਾਂ ਹਨੇਰਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ਤਿਵੇਂ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਸਮਝ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਹਉਮੈ-ਰੂਪ) ਬੇ-ਸਮਝੀ (ਦਾ ਹਨੇਰਾ) ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਇਹ ਕੰਮ) ‘ਅਸਾਂ’ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ, ‘ਅਸੀ’ ਹੀ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਾਂ, (ਇਉਂ) ‘ਅਸੀ ਅਸੀ’ ਆਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਮੂਰਖ ਉਜੱਡ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਭੁੱਲਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪਿਆਰ ਪਾਈ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਵਿਚ) ਮਾਇਆ (ਦੇ ਮੋਹ) ਜੇਡਾ (ਹੋਰ ਕੋਈ) ਦੁੱਖ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਮੋਹ ਵਿਚ ਫਸ ਕੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ (ਮਾਇਆ) ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਭਟਕ ਭਟਕ ਕੇ ਖਪਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਮਤਿ ਉਤੇ ਤੁਰਿਆਂ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਾ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।੩। (ਪਰ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਭੀ ਕੀਹ ਵੱਸ ?) ਜਿਸ (ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ (ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਜੋੜਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ । ਮੈਂ ਅਜੇਹੇ ਬੰਦੇ ਤੋਂ ਕੁਰਬਾਨ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ ਹੇ ਮਨ ! (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਜੇਹੜੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਭਗਤੀ (ਦੇ ਰੰਗ) ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਨਾਮ ਹੀ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ‘ਆਪਣਾ ਘਰ’ ਲੱਭ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ ਉਸ ਆਤਮਕ ਟਿਕਾਣੇ ਤੇ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਜਿਥੋਂ ਮਾਇਆ ਦਾ ਮੋਹ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੰੂ ਧੱਕਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ) ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ-ਰੰਗ ਨਾਲ) ਰੰਗੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਜੀਭ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਵਿਚ ਮਸਤ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਕਦੇ) ਨਹੀਂ ਭੁੱਲਦਾ, ਉਹ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਵਿਚ ਲੀਨ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੪।੩੩।੩੧।੬੪।\\""},{"question":"भगवद्गीता नेपालीअध्याय ५, श्लोक ७","answer":"संस्कृत :योगयुक्तो विश‍ुद्धात्मा विजितात्मा जितेन्द्रिय: ।सर्वभूतात्मभूतात्मा कुर्वन्नपि न लिप्यते ॥ ७ ॥नेपाली:भक्तिमा संलग्न रहेको विशुद्ध आत्मा, आत्म संयमी व्यक्ति जसले आफ्ना मन तथा इन्द्रियहरू वशमा राखेको छ त्यो सबैको प्रिय हुन्छ र प्रत्येक व्यक्ति उसका लागि प्रिय हुन्छन् । यस्तो व्यक्ति सदा कर्ममा संलग्न रहे पनि कर्मबन्धनमा बाँधिदैन ।"},{"question":"ccual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuántos tipos diferentes de Materia hay en la original serie de Final Fantasy VII?","answer":"La respuesta correcta es videojuegos. "},{"question":" O que é um safári?","answer":"Um safári é uma forma de viagem que consiste em observar ou fotografar animais selvagens em seu habitat natural, geralmente em um veículo 4x4, a pé ou a cavalo. Um safári pode ser feito em diferentes regiões do mundo, mas é mais comum na África, onde se pode ver animais como leões, elefantes, girafas, zebras e rinocerontes. "},{"question":"Montevideo mooy gëblag man réew ?","answer":"Montevideo mooy gëblag réewum Uruguay."},{"question":"時計の長針は、短針の何倍の早さで進むでしょう？","answer":"12倍です。"},{"question":"句子1: 它有12个胸部软脊柱和15到17个背部线条. 第二句:它有12个背脊,和15到17个背脊软光线. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Какой знаменитый пример Стокгольского Синдрома?","answer":"Один такой пример случился во время ограбления на площади Норрмальмсторг, в Швеции. 23 августа 1973 года в Стокгольме двое грабителей, вооруженных автоматами, ворвались в банк. Они захватили четырех человек — трех женщин и одного мужчину — и удерживали их 131 час. Заложники находились в подвале, привязанные к динамиту, пока 28 августа их не освободили. Но во время осады заложники демонстрировали все возрастающую враждебность в отношении полиции. Пленники стали чувствовать, что преступники защищают их от полицейских. После освобождения они продолжали считать, что их захватчикам угрожают, жестоко с ними обращаются, и опасались за их жизни. Из интервью, взятого после освобождения, было ясно, что бывшие заложники поддерживали своих захватчиков и опасались властей, пришедших им на помощь. Одна из женщин впоследствии стала членом группы захватчиков, а другая организовала фонд их поддержки."},{"question":"inona ny volana  fahavalo anatin'ny taona?","answer":"ny volana  fahavalo anatin'ny taona dia aogositra"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిశృంఖల చర్య, ప్రత్యుత్పాదన గుణకం అనే పదాలను వివరించండి. ఒక శృంఖల చర్య ఎలా కొనసాగుతుంది?","answer":"శృంఖల చర్య :అత్యధిక శక్తి నిచ్చే స్వయం పరిపోషిత కేంద్రక విచ్ఛిత్తిని శృంఖల చర్య అంటారు.శృంఖల చర్యలో న్యూట్రాన్లు జ్యామితీయ శ్రేణిలో పెరిగి, పదార్థం అంతా విచ్ఛిత్తికి లోనవుతుంది. ఇదంతా అతి తక్కువ కాలంలో జరగడం వల్ల శక్తి పెద్దపెట్టున విడుదలవుతుంది.ప్రత్యుత్పాదన గుణకం(K) :ప్రస్తుత విచ్ఛిత్తిలో విడుదలైన న్యూట్రాన్ల సంఖ్యకు మరియు అంతకు ముందు విచ్ఛిత్తి విడుదలైన న్యూట్రాన్ల సంఖ్యకు మధ్య గల నిష్పత్తిని శృంఖల చర్య యొక్క న్యూట్రాన్ ప్రత్యుత్పాదన గుణకం (K) అంటారు.శృంఖల చర్య కొనసాగడానికి షరతులు :    1. శృంఖల చర్యను కొనసాగించడానికి కనీసం ఒక ఉష్ణన్యూట్రాన్ ఎల్లప్పుడు అందుబాటులో ఉండాలి.    2. న్యూట్రాన్ ప్రత్యుత్పాదన గుణకం K = 1 ఉండాలి."},{"question":"ગુજરાતના મશહૂર ગરબા ગાયકોની યાદી આપો.","answer":"ગુજરાતના મશહૂર ગરબા ગાયકોની યાદી:હેમંત ચૌહાણપ્રમોદ પ્રમોદકિરન ગઢવીમિતાલ ગઢવીઅતુલ પૂરીઅરવિંદ બારોટગુણીજ શાહપ્રશંત મહેતાકિરણ જગદેવફાલ્ગુણી પઠક"},{"question":"மழைமுகம் காணாப் பயிர்போல","answer":"தாயை இழந்த கருணையன் மழை முகம் காணாப் பயிர்போல வாடினான்."},{"question":"Що таке морфогенез?","answer":"Морфогенез - це процес виникнення нових структур і зміна їх форми в процесі онтогенезу. Морфогенез на клітинному рівні розпочинається з гаструляції. У хордових після гаструляції закладаються осьові органи. В цей період морфологічні перебудови охоплюють весь зародок. Потім відбувається закладка і розвиток окремих органів (органогенез). Це вже місцеві процеси, всередині кожного з яких відбувається дискретизація на окремі зачатки. Так послідовно в часі і в просторі перебігає індивідуальний розвиток, що призводить до формування організму із складною будовою і значно багатшою інформацією, ніж генетична інформація зиготи."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Air yang keras?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah air batu"},{"question":"வினா:முகமது கஜினி இந்தியாவை எத்தனை முறை தாக்கினார்?","answer":"விடை: 17 முறை"},{"question":"\\"පුණ්‍ය මහෝදදි ශාන්ත සමාධී\\"මෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"මහා උදධි = මහෝදධිමහා සාගරයපුණ්‍ය මහා සාගරය"},{"question":"س117 - من هو أول شهيد في غزوة بدر الكبرى ؟","answer":"ج117 - عمير بن الوقاص"},{"question":"Mina akukho muntu ongidukisayo. Indaba yokungenwa angiyifuni nje.Yayimbi-ke indaba kasisi.Kodwa uziphuthisele ngomuntu ophilayo makoti.Akaphileli mina.NoSipho wakho lowo ugula kabi ejele. Bheka nje le ngane yabantuesiboshwe ngenxa yakho.Indaba kaSipho ingiphethe kabi impela. Naye wagcina esengincengaethi angishintshe ngala. Sengathi bangasheshe bamdedele.Angiboni ukuthi uzosheshe aphume ejele. (Kungene uDumisani)Ake ngikuncenge okokugcina Thenjiwe.Ungazihluphi mntanami uhlanya lolu ngilubona kahle.(Ehwaqa) Wena Dumisani sengiyakuzonda nje. Uqale wafaka minaosizini nazo izihlobo zami. Umngani wami omkhulu uSipho, uboshiwengikhuluma nje.Ngigane phela, bazophuma bonke abantu osizini.Inkinga ukuthi asithandani Dumisani. Singaganana kanjani?Phela ngeke ubone ukuthi ngiyakuthanda ungakangithandi.Ngasuke ngathandwa kakhulu umfowenu, manje ngeke usalungawena ngoba ujabulisa abazali bakho manje.Usho ukuthini uma uthi ujabulisa abazali bakhe? Kanti uhlanyangempela?Kunjalo vele!Uhlushwa yinkani nje wena.Yehlisa umoya phela Thenjiwe.Nizongihlanganyela lapha. (Akhale) Lonke lolu sizi ludalwa yini.Wena asekulahlile amadlozi. Akusekho okuyokulungela.Kungcono ngiziyele kithi (Akhale)Angithi bakubuyisile ekhaya.Ngizoduka nezwe okungcono!1. Babunjani ubudlelwane phakathi kukaThenjiwe noDumisani ekuqaleni kwalomdlalo? Sekela impendulo yakho ngephuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"Ubudlelwane phakathi kukaThenjiwe noDumisani babubuhle ekuqalenikomdlalo. UDumisani wayemesekela futhi ezwelana naye kulesi simoayekusona sokushonelwa umyeni wakhe."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي الألوان التي ذكرت في سوره البقره ؟","answer":"الإجابة: الأصفر –الأبيض- الأسود"},{"question":": Waxaad sheegtaan ninkii dilay Xamsa ibnu Cadulmudhalib oo Nabiga adeerkiis ahaa?","answer":": waxaa dilay nin la oran jiray Waxshi.    "},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe hatsikana?","answer":"Ny hatsikana dia karazana tantara fohy  matetika atao an-tsehatra entina hampihomehezana  ny mpijery."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஜாதிகளைக் குறிக்கும் நெற்றிக்குறி, உடை, பூணூல் முதலிய சின்னங்களை சட்டப் பூர்வமாகத் தடுக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：美国的传统饮品有哪些？","answer":"答案：美国的传统饮品包括可乐、柠檬水、冰茶和根啤酒等。这些饮品在美国饮品文化中非常受欢迎，常作为休闲、聚会和餐饮场合的饮品选择。"},{"question":"Complete a seguinte frase:  Gabriel Radomir se casou duas vezes. Seu filho, Pedro Deliano, teve um papel fundamental na","answer":"primeira tentativa de restaurar a independência da Bulgária décadas depois."},{"question":"ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਵਾਕ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਨਾਂਵ ਚੁਣੋ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਵੀ ਦੱਸੋ ?ਸ਼ੇਰ ਜੰਗਲ ਦਾ ਰਾਜਾ ਮੰਨਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।","answer":"ਸ਼ੇਰ - ਆਮ ਨਾਂਵ ਜੰਗਲ - ਇਕੱਠਵਾਚਕ ਨਾਂਵ ਰਾਜਾ - ਆਮ ਨਾਂਵ"},{"question":"Lengkapi ukara ing ngisor iki:Bocah sregep bakal ... kancaneA. DiwenehiB. DigethingiC. DisenengiJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: C. Disenengi"},{"question":"腕時計や懐中時計で、ぜんまいを巻いたり、針を動かしたりするためのつまみを何というでしょう？","answer":"竜頭です。"},{"question":"Що таке мітоз? ","answer":"Мітоз (від грец. μίτος - нитка) - непрямий, або мітотичний поділ є переважаючим типом поділу еукаріотичних соматичних клітин і притаманний всім багатоклітинним організмам. При цьому відбувається точний рівномірний розподіл спадкового матеріалу. Внаслідок мітозу кожна дочірня клітина отримує повний набір хромосом із фіксованою кількістю ДНК і за їх складом ідентична материнській клітині."},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்திய மாநிலங்களில் புலிகள் பாதுகாப்பகம் இல்லாத இந்திய மாநிலம் எது ?","answer":"பதில்:சரியான பதில் ஜம்மு காஷ்மீர். இந்தியாவில் புலிகள் காப்பகங்கள் இல்லாத மாநிலங்கள் பின்வருமாறு. முக்கிய புள்ளிகள் இந்தியாவில் புலிகள் காப்பகங்கள் இல்லாத மாநிலங்கள். உலகில் உள்ள 80 சதவீத புலிகள் இந்தியாவில்தான் உள்ளன.இந்தியாவில் 54 புலிகள் காப்பகங்கள் உள்ளன, அவை புலிகள் பாதுகாப்புத் திட்டத்தின் மூலம் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகின்றன, இது தேசிய புலிகள் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையத்தால் நிர்வகிக்கப்படுகிறது.ந்தியாவில் தேசிய புலிகள் பாதுகாப்பு ஆணையத்தால் வழிகாட்டப்படும் புலிகள் திட்டத்தால் மேலாளப்படும் 54 புலிகள் காப்பகங்கள் உள்ளன.இந்தியாவின் புலிக் காப்பகங்கள் 1973 இல் அமைக்கப்பட்டு,புலிகள் திட்டத்தால் மேலாளப்படுகின்றன. இதற்கு, இந்திய அரசு, தேசியப் புலிகள் பேணுதல் ஆணையம் வழிகாட்டுகிறது. புலிக் காப்பகங்களாக 2018 இல் 50 பாதுகாப்புப் பகுதிகள் பெயரிடப்பட்டன.2022 இல் 53 ஆம் புலிக் காப்பகம் [ராணிப்பூர் கானுயிர் புகலிடம் இராணிப்பூர் கானுயிர் புகலிடம்]உத்தரப்பிரதேசத்தில் மாநிலத்தின் மூன்றாம் புலிக் காப்பகமாக அறிவிக்கப்பட்டது.உலகப் புலிகளில் 80% இந்தியாவில்தான் உள்ளன. 2006 இல் 1,411 புலிகள் இருந்த நிலையில் , 2011ஈல் 1,706 ஆகவும் , 2014ஈல் 2,226 ஆகவும் உயர்ந்தது.சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைச்சரின் அண்மைய அறிக்கையின்படி , 2016 ஆம் ஆண்டில் இந்த எண்ணிக்கை 2500 ஆக உயர்ந்தது.2006 இல், 1,411 ஆக இருந்த புலிகளின் தொகை 2022 இல் 3167 ஆக அதாவது, இருமடங்காக உய்ர்ந்தது என இந்தியா மதிப்பிட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"Côn Đảo từng thuộc địa phương nào?","answer":"Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu có một đơn vị hành chính hải đảo là huyện Côn Đảo. Đây là quần đảo, cách thành phố Vũng Tàu 97 hải lý và cách sông Hậu 45 hải lý, gồm 16 hòn đảo với tổng diện tích 76 km2.Côn Đảo hay Côn Sơn cũng hay dùng cho tên của hòn đảo lớn nhất trong quần đảo này. Sử Việt trước thế kỷ 20 thường gọi nơi này là đảo Côn Lôn hoặc Côn Nôn. Tên gọi cũ trong các văn bản tiếng Anh và tiếng Pháp là Poulo Condor.Theo tài liệu cổ, tên địa danh này có nguồn gốc Mã Lai từ chữ \\"Pulau Kundur\\" nghĩa là \\"Hòn Bí\\".  Năm 1977, Quốc hội quyết định tên gọi chính thức là Côn Đảo.Thời điểm mới được khai phá, Côn Đảo thuộc tỉnh Hà Tiên (nay là Kiên Giang). Dưới thời chính quyền Ngô Đình Diệm, Côn Đảo là một tỉnh. Ngày 1/5/1975, quân Mặt trận Dân tộc Giải phóng miền Nam Việt Nam tiếp quản Côn Đảo. Đến tháng 9/1976, tỉnh Côn Đảo bị giải thể, chuyển thành huyện Côn Đảo thuộc TP HCM. Tháng 1/1977, hải đảo này trở thành một huyện thuộc tỉnh Hậu Giang. Tháng 5/1979, Côn Đảo trở thành quận thuộc đặc khu Vũng Tàu-Côn Đảo. Địa phương này chính thức là huyện đảo thuộc tỉnh Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu từ tháng 10/1991."},{"question":"Ahoana no hanaovana koba pizza an-trano tsy misy mixer na sakafo processeur?","answer":"Azonao atao ny mampifangaro koba pizza amin'ny tanana amin'ny fampiasana lovia lehibe sy sotro hazo. Atambatra ireo akora ireo, avy eo mametafeta ny koba amin\`ny ambonin\`ny lafarinina mandra-masaka."},{"question":"ગુજરાત રાજ્યના બધાં શહેરોની યાદી આપો.","answer":"અમદાવાદવડોદરાસુરતરાજકોટભાવનગરજામનગરમોરબીગાંધીનગરભરૂચપાટણજૂનાગઢઅનંદખેડામહેસાણાનડીયાદસાબરકાંઠાઅરવલ્લીદાહોદપંચમહાલકચ્છમહીસાગરતાપીદેવભૂમિ દ્વારકામોરબી"},{"question":"Voltooi de zin: Tijdens de Dertigjarige Oorlog steunde haar echtgenoot de protestanten. Nadat de keizerlijke en Spaanse troepen in 1634 de Zweden versloegen in de","answer":"Slag bij Nördlingen, was Willem V zijn belangrijkste bondgenoot kwijt. In 1635 was hij een van de drie vorsten die de Vrede van Praag weigerden te erkennen en een alliantie sloten met koning Lodewijk XIII van Frankrijk. Tijdens het verdere verloop van de Dertigjarige Oorlog bevrijdde Willem op 13 juni 1636 Hanau, dat belegerd werd door de keizerlijke troepen. Later werd hij echter verslagen en moesten Willem V en Amalia Elisabeth naar hun bezittingen in Oost-Friesland vluchten. Een jaar later, in september 1637, overleed Willem V. In zijn testament stelde hij Amalia Elisabeth aan als regentes van Hessen-Kassel, in naam van hun minderjarige zoon Willem VI. Ook liet hij Amalia Elisabeth een goed opgeleid leger na, dat erin geslaagd was om naar Oost-Friesland te vluchten."},{"question":"Непалдын борбор шаары Катмандуда мышыктар дээрлик жокко эсе. Буга эмне себеб?","answer":"Себеби, бул маймылдардын кол салуусуна байланыштуу. Мышыктар айрым гана храмдарда кездешет. Шаарда мышыктар сейрек кездешкендиктен, аларды ыйык көрүшөт."},{"question":"Sarona lanezy ve ny tampon'i Everest?","answer":"Eny"},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri kanun labarai dan wannan labari mai zuwa:Malamin addinin Musulunci Sheikh Abdallah Usman Godon Kaya ya janye ikirarin da ya yi kan ma'aikatan lafiya na Najeriya cewa wasunsu na aikata masha'a yayin da suke aikin dare a asibitocin kasar. Cikin wani jawabi da ya yi da aka gani a wani bidiyo, malamin addinin Musuluncin ya zargi ma'aikatan lafiyan da mu'amular da ba ta dace ba, ciki har da zina da cin zarafin mata. Tun da farko jaridar intanet ta Sahelian Times ta ruwaito shehin malamin yana zargin ma'aikatan lafiya da aikata zina yayin wani shirin talabijin da aka haska a tashar talabijin ta Africa TV mai zaman kanta. Sai dai daga baya ta ce baya malamin ya janye kalaman nasa, bayan da ƙungiyar ma'aikatan jinyan ta ce kalaman nasa ɓata wa ƴaƴanta suna ne, tare da neman ya janye su. Ga abin da ya shaida wa BBC baya da aka tuntuɓe shi kan kalaman nasa. Ya gaya wa BBC cikin wani sakon murya da ya aika cewa \\"Ban yi niyyar cutar da kowa ba, kuma ya kamata mutane su zama masu kyautata tunanin alheri.\\" Sheikh Gadon Kaya ya shaida wa BBC cewa wasu ma'aikatan lafiya ne suka fara tuntuɓarsa kan wannan lamarin da ke ci gaba da jan hankalin jama'a. \\"Wasu ma'aikatan kiwon lafiya biyu, namiji da mace ne suka kira ni, muna karatu ne suka yi min fatawa, inda suka fadi matsalar da suke fuskanta ta haɗa mace da namiji, wani lokacin a cikin aiki na dare. \\"Suka koka, kuma na yi bayani a matsayina na almajiri, mai nusantar da mutane akan aikata daidai.\\" Ya ce ya yi bayani ne cewa matukar hakan na faruwa ya kamata a gyara: \\"Ya kamata a tsare mutunci matan nan da iyalanmu da 'ya'yanmu gaba ɗaya.\\" Sheikh Gadon Kaya ya ce bayan da kalaman nasa suka tayar da hankalin jama'a, musamman ma'ikatan lafiya, ya zauna da su, inda ya ce \\"sun warware min dukkan abubuwan da suka shige min duhu kan wannan lamarin.\\" Ya ce ma'aikatan lafiyan sun \\"yi gungu kuma sun ziyarce ni\\". Ya kuma ce sun sanar da shi cewa labarin da ya yada babu ƙamshin gaskiya cikinsa, kuma ya ce ya hujjarsa ita ce \\"wasu ma'aikatanku ne suka kira ni, suka tambaye ni a karatu kuma na bayar da jawabi, inda na ce a gyara\\". \\"Laifina shi ne na ce idan wannan abin yana faruwa, na ce a gyara.\\" Ya ce bayan da suka \\"yi min bayani, kuma na yi musu bayani, mun fahimci juna. Sai na ce mu su 'ba ku fahimci maganganun da ake yadawa ne ba'.\\" Ya kuma yi karin bayani, inda yace dalilinsa na biyu na furta wadannan kalaman masu tayar da hankali shi ne domin yana cikin masu yin kira ga al'umma da a rungumi karatun kiwon lafiya domin saboda akwai bukatar su cikin al'ummar kasar. Shehin ya ce bayanan da ma'aikatan lafiya suka yi kan batun, ya ƙaru da wasu abubuwan da a baya bai sani ba. Sai dai ya kare kansa inda ya ce bai ambaci sunan inda matar da ta yi masa tambayar ta fito ba. \\"Ban san daga wace jiha tambayar ta fito ba kuma ban ambaci sunan wata jiha ba, ballantana wasu suce da su nake wannan maganar.\\" Tun da farko shugaban ƙungiyar ma'aikatan lafiya na Jihar Kano, Kwamared Ibrahim Maikarfi Muhamad ya mayar da martani bayan da kalaman na Sheikh Gadon Gaya suka bayyana. Yayin wata hira da ya yi da mujallar Jarida Radio ta intanet, ya yi kira ga malamin addinin Islaman da ya gaggauta janye kalaman nasa, wanda ya ce na ɓatanci ne. \\"Cikin maganganunsa yana cewa ma'aikatan lafiya suna kwana a daki daya, har yana hasashe cewa wani mummunan abu yana faruwa tsakaninsu, inda ya kawo misalin wata mata mai shekara 50 da haihuwa kuma ya yi kwatanci kan wasu matasa 'yan matan da shekarunsu ba su kai 30 ba cewa suna kwana a daki daya, a bisa teburi daya a wurin da suke aiki na kwana.\\" Kwamared Muhammad ya yi kira ga ma'aikatan lafiya da su kwantar da hankalinsu kan munanan kalaman da Sheikh Gadon Kaya ya yi amfani da su, wadanda ya ce suna iya ɓata musu suna. \\"Muna gaggauta jan hankalin wannan malami da ya yi hanzarin janye wadannan kalaman da ya furta ya kuma ba ma'aikatanmu da al'ummar jihar Kano hakuri.\\" Shugaban kungiyar ma'aikatan lafiyan ya ce kalaman na iya tayar da hankalin magidantan da matansu ke tafiya aikin asibiti da dare. Ya kammala jawabin nasa da yin kira ga malamin addinin da ya gaggauta janye kalaman ko kuma su dauki matakin shari'a a kansa. Wannan batu dai ya jawo ce-ce-ku-ce sosai a Najeriya musamman daga masu amfani da shafukan sada zumunta. Mutane da dama na tsokaci da batun masu iya magana da ke cewa: \\"Iya ruwa fid da kai,\\" kuma \\"Baki shi kan yanka wuya\\". Wadannan karin maganar biyu sun shafi kowane fanni na zamantakewa da na rayuwar al'umma, musamman ma a bangaren da ya shafi addini. Malaman addinin a Najeriya na da karfin fada a ji, musamman ganin yadda 'yan kasar ke bin dukkan kalaman da suke furtawa sau da kafa. Lamarin bai tsaya kan malaman addinin Musulunci ko na Kirista ba, domin dukkan mabiya manyan addinan biyu na wa malamansu biyayya. Wannan ne yasa dukkan abin da suka fada ke jan hankulan jama'arsu sosai kuma kalaman ke yin tasiri kan yadda mabiyansu ke kallon batutuwan da malaman ke yin tsokaci akai. Wannan takaddamar da ke tsakanin Sheikh Abdallah Gadon Kaya da ma'aikatan kiwon lafiya misali ne na irin wadannan batutuwan da ya dace malamai su rika yin tsantseni akai gabanin bayyana wata matsaya, kuma ba wannan ne karo na farko da kalaman nasa ke tayar da hankulan al'ummar da yake ikirarin nusantarwa daga aikata laifuka ba. Idan ba a manta ba, a bara Sheikh Abdallah Gadon Kaya ya taba furta kalaman da wasu ke kallo a matsayin na ɓatanci, kuma wadanda ka iya taɓa mutuncin babban limamin masallanci kasa da ke Abuja, wato Sheikh Ibrahim Maqari. Sai dai rahotanni sun ce an shiga tsakani kafin aka kashe wutar rikicin da ta rika ruruwa bayan da kalaman Sheikh Gadon Kaya suka bayyana, inda daga baya Sheikh Gadon Kayan ya nemi afuwa daga Sheikh Maqari, amma sai bayan da ya shigar da ƙara a kotu a watan Agustan 2021. Kuma da alama, kamar sauran al'umma, malaman addinai ma na amfani da kafofin sada zumunta wajen yaɗa ra'ayinsu kan batutuwan da suka shafi rayukan 'yan kasa. Sauƙin hawa wannan mumbari na intanet ko na sada zumunta ya haifar da dubban masana kan kowane fanni na rayuwa, ciki har da na addinai. Sai dai a wasu lokutan, mutane da dama na ganin wasu malaman kan bayyana ra'ayinsu ne ba tare da sun yi cikakken bincike ba, kuma wasunsu ba sa tauna tasirin kalamansu kan al'umomin da suke yi wa jagoranci ta bangaren addini. Wannan ne yasa masu sharhi ke ganin yake da muhimmanci jagororin al'umma - musamman ma malaman addinai - su rika cizawa kuma suna hurawa kafin su yi sharhi kan kowane batu.","answer":"Tabbas ga kundun labarin: Ba a fahimci kalamai na kan ma'aikatan lafiya ba - Sheikh Gadon Kaya"},{"question":"自動車のギアの表示でバックを表すアルファベット１文字はなに？","answer":"Ｒです。"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Graham Rix. ","answer":"Is iarimreoir agus iar-thraenálaí peile é Graham Rix (r.23 Deireadh Fómhair, 1957), a bhí ina imreoir le cúig chlub - Arsenal F.C. ó 1975 go 1988, Cean ó 1998 go 1991, Le Havre ón tséasúr 1991-1992, Dundee United ó 1992 go dtí 1993. D'imir Rix le Chelsea F.C. don bhliain 1995. Bhí sé ina thraenálaí le Portsmouth F.C. ó 2001 go 2002 agus ansin le Oxford United agus Hearts ó 2004 agus 2005 go 2006."},{"question":"Mitovy hevitra ve ireto fehezanteny roa manaraka ireto?1. “Voavaliny tsara daholo ny fanontaniana rehetra.”2. \\"Namaly ny fanontaniana rehetra izy.\\"","answer":"Eny, mitovy ny hevitr’ireo fehezanteny roa ireo."},{"question":"Oògùn Àjẹsára","answer":"Oògùn àjẹsára tàbí Abẹ́rẹ́ Àjẹsára jẹ́ agbo kan tí a ṣe láti fúni ní ààbò tó péye kúrò lọ́wọ́kòkòrò , àrùn ati àìsàn tí ó fẹ́ wọlé sí agọ́ ara. Àwọn ohun tí wọ́n fi ńnṣe oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára yí ni díẹ̀ lára àwọn légbé-n-légbé tí ó lágbára jùlọ àmọ́ tí kò ní agbára mọ́ ní asìkò tí wọ́n fẹ́ ṣamúlò rẹ̀ tàbí kí wọ́n kúkú pa légbé-n-légbé yí ṣáájú kí wọ́n tó ṣamúlò rẹ̀. Àwọn légbé-n-légbé tí wọ́n ṣamúlò yí ni wọ́n yóò lò láti fi ṣe láti fi kún àwọn èròja mìíran tí yóò sì ma ṣiṣẹ́ ìdẹ́rùba fú èyíkéyí àìsàn àti àrùn tí ó fẹ́ fipá wọ inú àgọ́ ara ènìyàn tàbí ẹranko Fífún ènìyàn kan ní oògùn àjẹsára ni ìgbésẹ̀ tí a ń pè ní \\"gbígba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára\\". Lára àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí wọ́n múná dóko ni abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára fún àrùn rọpá-rosẹ̀, àìsàn òtútù ìta, òtútù àyà àrùn HPV àti bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Ọ̀gbẹ́ni Edward Jenner ni ó ṣe ìdásílẹ̀ gbólóhùn \\"abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ati gbígba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára \\" ni wọ́n fàyọ láti inú ọ̀rọ̀ (Veriolae).Gbígba abẹrẹ ajẹsara jẹ́ ohun tí kò léwu tí kò sì mú ìpalára dání láti fi kojú àrùn kárùn tàbí àìsàn èyíkéyí. Síbẹ agbára àwọn abẹ́rẹ àjẹsára yí ní àkùdé, bákan náà ni agbaára wọn gbára lé àwọn nka mélòó kan. Lára wọn ni: Àìsàn náà fúnra rẹ̀, ( abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lè má ṣiṣẹ́ nígbà tí a bá gbàá fún àrùn tàbí àìsàn tí kò bá mu). Bí wọ́n bá ń ṣe iṣẹ́ ìwádí lọ́wọ́ (àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí wọ́n ti pèsè sí lè má bá àrùn kan tabí òmíràn tí wọ́n ń ṣe ìwádí rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́). Títẹpẹlẹ mọ́ ìgba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lóòrè kóòrè fún àrùn tàbí àisàn kan, kódà bí àrùn bá ti kásẹ̀ nílẹ̀ tán pátá. Bí won tẹle iṣeto gbigba abẹrẹ ajẹsara daradara. Àdámọ́ ara ẹnì kòọ̀kan. Abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tún lè má ṣiṣẹ́ lára àwọn ènìyàn kan tàbí òmíràn látàrí àdámọ́ ara kálukú. Àwọn okùnfà míràn tún ni \\"ọjọ́-orí, ẹ̀yà ati àbùdá ara tí wọ́n ń pè ní (jẹ̀nẹ́tíìkì) àti bèé bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ.Bí ẹni tí a fún ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára bá sì tún lùgbàdì àìsàn tàbí àrùn tí wọ́n torí rẹ̀ fun ní abẹ́rẹ́ fun , ó dájú wípé àìsàn náà kò ní gbilẹ̀ lára onítòhún tó ẹni tí kò gba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára rárá.Àwọn akíyèsí wọ̀nyí ṣe pàtàkì nípa fífi ìmúná-dóko oògùn àjẹsára nínú ètò ìfúni lábẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára. Gbígbé ìlànà ìtọpinpin sí ìmúná-dóko iṣẹ́abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lára àwọn ènìyàn nígbà tí a bá ti fún wọ n gègẹ́ bí a ṣe ṣàláyé ré nínú ìpolongo wa gbogbo. Ìfojúsóde fún àwọn àrùn míran tó bá tún ṣẹ́ yọ lásìkò ìfúni ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára. Mí ma ṣe ìmúlò ìfúni ní abèrẹ́ àjẹsára lóòrè kóòrè, kódà bí àrùn bá kásẹ̀ nílẹ̀ tán.Ṣíṣàmúlò oògùn àjẹsára ma ń mú kí àdínkù tàbí kí àjakálẹ̀ àrùn èyíkéyí ó kásẹ̀ nílẹ̀ tán pátá pátá. Pàá pàá jùlọ, àwọn àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn bíi ìgbóná, rọpá-rọsẹ̀, òtútù ìta, rùbẹ́là, àìsàn ibà pọ́njú-pọ́ntọ̀ àti vẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ ti di ohun afìsẹ́yìn, yàtọ̀ sí bí wọ́n ṣe pọ̀ jántì-rẹrẹ ní nkan bí ọgọ́rùún ọdún sẹ́yìn Bí ọ̀gọ̀rọ̀ ènìyàn bá gba abẹrẹ àjẹsára, yóò nira púpọ̀ fún àìsàn kan láti bẹ́ sílẹ̀tàbí di ìtànkálẹ̀kiri. Ìgbésẹ̀ yí ni a ń pè ní àjẹsára tó gbópọn. Àwọn oògùn àjẹsára tún ma ń ṣe ìrànwọ́ fún ìdènà ìdàgbà-sókè àti ìgbèrú agbára àwọn kòkòrò tí wọ́n ma ń pa oògùn apa kòkòrò nínú ara. Fún àpẹrẹ, mímú àdínkù bá ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ àìsàn òtútù àyà tí Streptococcus pneumonia máa ń ṣokùnfà rẹ̀, àwọn ètò ìfúni labẹ́rẹ́ ajẹsara lóríṣríṣi ti mú àdínkù bá ìtànkálẹ̀ r, tí ó jẹ́ wípé Penisilini tàbí oògùn apa kòkòrò lásá lè gbọ. Abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára fún àrùn òtútù ìta ni wọ́n ti fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ wípé ó ti mú àdínkù bá ikú tí kò bá ti pa tó àwọn ènìyàn tí ó tó mílíọ́nù kan láàrín ọdún kan.Gbígba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ní ìgbà èwe kò léwu nínú rárá. Bí ewu bá tilé wà, ìwọ̀nba ni yóò mọ. Lára awọn eu tí ó lè ṣẹ́ yọ ni :ara gbífvóná, ìrora ojú abẹ́rẹ́ tí wọ́n fi gún oògùn náà, ati iṣan ríro. Ẹ̀wé, àwọn èròjà tí wọ́n fi pèsè abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lè fa ara ríro fún àwọn kọ̀ọ̀kan.Abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ní àwọn ohun-àrà kan tí wọ́n wà láàyè, èyí tótikú, èyí tí kòṣiṣẹ.(a) Èyí tí kò ṣiṣẹ́ Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára mìíràn ní àwọn ohun àrà tí kò ṣiṣẹ́ tí wọ́n fi kẹ́míkà, iná tàbí tí wọ́n sá sí Oòrùn láti lè jẹ́ kí ó kú. Àpẹrẹ irúfẹ́ àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ yí ni abẹ́rẹ àjẹsára àrùńrọpá-rọsẹ, ̀ abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára àrùn jẹ̀dọ̀jẹ̀dọ̀, abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára àrùn dìgbòlugi àti àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára àrùn òtútù àyà.(b) Èyí tí wọ́n dín kù Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára mìíràn ni àwọn kòkòrò alààyè tí wọ́n ti dín agbára wọn kù. Àwọn wọ̀yí ma ń jẹ́ kánká bí a bá lòó, ṣùgbọ́n ó ṣeé ṣe kí lílò wọn ó léwu fún ẹni tí ìlera mẹ́hẹ.(d) Èyí tí ó ní májèlé Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára onímájèlé tí wọ́n ṣe láti ara àwọn májèlé tí kò ṣiṣẹ́ mọ́ tí ó sì ń fa àrùn sí àgọ́ ara dípò kí ó ṣokùnfà ìlera tó péye. (e) Ẹlẹ́yọ-kékeré Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí ó bá jẹ́ ẹyọ kékeré ma ń lo àwọn légbé-n-légbé kékèké kan láti fi ṣẹ̀dá abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí ó ìmúná-dóko. (ẹ) Alásopọ̀ Àwọn kòkòrò bakitéríà kan ní èròjà \\"polisakaridi\\" tí wọ́n fi bo àwọn légbé-n-légbé kan tí wọn kò lágbé rárá láti ṣiṣẹ́ìdáàbò bo fún àwọn ọmọ ogun ara (hormone) nínú ẹ̀yà ara. (f) Àwọn àgbéyẹ̀wò Lọ́wọ́lọ́wọ́ báyí, oríṣiríṣi àgbéyẹ̀wò ati iṣẹ́ ìwádí ni ó ń lọ lọ́wọ́ láti ṣe àgbékalẹ̀ àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tuntun mìíràn tí wọn yóò ma lò káti fi kojú àìsàn tàbí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn. Púpọ̀ nínú àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ni wọ́n ti ṣẹ̀dá pẹ̀lú àwọn ohun-èlò tí kò ṣiṣẹ́ tàbí àwọn èyí tí wọ́n ti dín agbára wọn kù, àwọn ẹ̀yà sìntẹ́tíìkì ni wọ́n ma ń lò jùlọ láti fi ṣe abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára sìntẹ́tíìkì.Púpọ̀ nínú àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lè jẹ́ èy tí a ṣẹ̀dá léte àti fi kojú àìsàn kan gbòógì kan ṣoṣo, amọ́ kò ní lè ṣiṣẹ́ fún ìtọ́jú àrùn mìíràn yàtọ̀ sí àìsàn tí a ṣẹ̀dá rẹ̀ fún, àwọn ìsọ̀rí abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára yí ni wọ́n jẹ́ oníṣẹ́ ẹyọ kan ṣoṣo. Nígba tí àwọn irúfẹ́ abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ke jì jẹ́ abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára gbogbo-nìṣe. Irúfẹ́ àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára yí wà fún ìtọ́jú oríṣ àrùn méjì tàbí jù bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Àwọn ìsọ̀rí abẹ́rẹ́ yí ni wọ́n ń jẹ́ oníṣẹ́ púpọ̀ nígbà tí a bá fún àwọn ènìyàn.Àwọn irúfẹ́ abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí wọ́n wà ní ìsọ̀rí yí ni wọ́n fi ẹ̀yà ara àwọn légbé-n-légbé tí wọ́n ti kú tàbí àwọn èyí tí wọn kò lè fa àìsàn sí àgọ́ ara ènìyàn nígba tí wọ́n bá fúni.Àwọn ọmọ ogun ara(hormone) ma ń rí gbogbo ohun tí kò bá ti sí nínú ẹ̀jẹ̀ tẹ́lẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bí àlejò tàbí àtọ̀hún-rìn-wá, wọn sì ṣe tán láti pa wọ́n run kúrò nínú ara. Ìgbakúùgbà tí wọ́n bá ti kẹ́fín sí ìwọlé àrùn tàbí àìsàn ní inú ara, wọn yóò nti ṣe tán láti bá wọn wọ̀yá ìjà. Wọ́n ma ń gbógun ti àrùn nípasẹ̀: (1) Pípa àrùn náà ṣáájú kí ó tó inú àgọ́-ara.(2) Ṣíṣàwárí àti dídá àwọn apá ibi cẹ́ẹ̀lì tí àrùn náà wà mọ̀ nínú ara ṣáájú kí wọ́n tó di púpọ̀.Ọ̀nà ìtọ́jú oògùn àjẹsára Oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ma ń ní àwọn ohun-èlò kan tí ó lágbára, tí ó sì ma ń jẹ́ kí wọ́n tètè ṣiṣẹ́ míá nínú àgó-ara. Ẹ̀wẹ̀, wọ́n aì le fi nkan tí kìí jẹ́ kí nkan ó bàjẹ́ sínú rẹ̀ kí ó lè wà fún ìgba pípẹ́ Àgbékalẹ̀ oògùn àjẹsára Ó tọ́ mí àwọn ìkókó, òpónló, ọmọ ọ́wọ́ àti àwọn ògo wẹẹrẹ wa ó ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ń gba abẹ́rẹ́ oògùn àjẹsára láti ìgbà tí ara wọn bá ti gbó débi tí yóò ṣiṣẹ́gbe ààbò tó péye tí abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára fẹ́ fún wọn . nígbà tí àlékún ìdáàbò bó yóò tún mú kí àwọn ọmọ ogun ara wọn túbọ̀ jí pépé siwájú si. Àwọn ìgbésẹ̀ wọ̀nyí ni ó ń ṣokùnfà ìṣàgbékalẹ̀ gbígba a bẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lọ́nà tó lọ́ọ̀rìn fún àwọn ọmọdé láti ìgba èwe lóòrè-kóòrè. Àwọn oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára kan wà tí wọ́n yà sọ́tọ̀ fún àwọn ọmọ gẹ́gẹ́ bí ọjọ́-orí wọn bá ṣe pọ̀ sí, bẹ́ẹ̀ kẹ̀, àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára mìíràn náà tún wà tí wọ́n yà sọ́tọ̀ tí ènìyàn lè gbà ní ẹ̀mejì tàbí jù bẹ̀ẹ́ lọ láìmọye ìgbà kí onítọ̀hún ó tó jáde láyé láti lè kojú àwọn àìsàn kan tí wọ́n sábà m ń kọlu ènìyàn bí apẹẹrẹ́: Àìsàn kòkòrò tàtánọ́ọ̀sì, àrùn rọpá-rọsẹ̀, àrùn influenza, àrùn òtútù ìta ati bẹ́ẹ̀ bẹ́ẹ̀ lọ. Bákan náà, àwọn oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí a ṣàdáyanrí rẹ̀ fún àwọn àgbalagba ni ó dá lé àwọn àìsàn bíi: àrùn influenza, àrùn òtútù àyà.Kí wọ́n tó ṣàwárí oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára látarí ìbúrẹ́kẹ́ àrù cowpox àti small pox lára àwọn màlúù, ni wọ́n ti ri wípé àrùn yí ṣeé kojú nípa ṣiṣẹ́ ìyàsọ́tọ̀ àwọn kòkòrò tí ó ń fa àrùn yí, ní èyí tí wọ́n fìdí rẹ̀ múlẹ̀ ní nkan bí ọ̀rùndún mẹ́wàá (10th centuries) sẹ́yìn ní ilẹ̀ China. Ní ìparí ọdún 1760, Edward Jenner gbọ́ wípé àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ tí wọ́n ti ń pèsè wàra kan kò lùgbàdì àrùn smallpox nítorí wípé wọ́n ti kọ́kọ́ lùgbàdì àrùn cowpox tẹ́lẹ̀. Nígbà tí ó di ọdún 1796, ọ̀gbẹ́ni Jenner yí gbìyànjú, ó gba díẹ̀ lára ọyún ní àtẹ́lẹwẹ́̀ àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ ilé-iṣẹ́ wàrà tí wọ́n ti kó àrùn cowpox tẹ́lẹ̀ yí, ó wá gún ọmọdé kùnrin yí ní oògùn àjẹsára ti smallpox ní nkan bí ọ̀sẹ̀ mẹ́fà siwájú, lẹ́yìn èyí ó fi ọyún tí ó ti gba tí ó sì ní kòkòrò àrùn cowpox sí ara ọmọdé kùnrin ọmọ ọdún mẹ́jọ kan lásìkò àjakálé àrùn smallpox, àmọ́ ìyàlẹ́nu ibẹ̀ ni wípé ọmọdé kúnrin yí kò lùgbàdì àjàkẹ̀ àrùn lásìkò náà. Lẹ́yìn èyí, ọ̀gbẹ́ni Jenner kéde wípé oògùn àjẹsára tí òun ṣàwárí rẹ̀wípé ṣiṣẹ́ fún tọmọdé tàgba. Ìsọ̀rí oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ni ọ̀gbẹ́ni Louis Pasteur ní ọdún 1880. Lẹ́yìn èyí, oríṣiríṣi abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ni wọ́n tún ṣàgbékalẹ̀ tí ó sì ní àṣeyọrí rẹpẹtẹ, bíi abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ti àrùn gbọ̀fungbọ̀fun, àìsàn òtútù ìta, gẹ̀gẹ̀, ati aìsàn rùbẹ́là. Àṣeyọrí ùlá gbáà ni ìṣàwárí abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ati ìdàgbà-sókè tí ó níṣe pẹ̀lú àrùn rọpárọsẹ̀ tí wọ́n ń pè ní (polio) tí ó ma ń dàmú àwọn ọmọdé ní 1950 tí àrùn smaloox sì di ohun ìgbagbé ní ọdún 1960 àti 1970. Ní nkan bí ọ̀rùndún ogún (29th century), ọ̀gbẹ́ni Maurice Hilleman ni ó gbajúmọ̀ jùlọ nínú àwọn onímọ̀ tí wọ́n ṣe àwárí oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára. Púpọ̀ nínú iṣẹ́ ìwádí nípa lórí ìṣèwádí àti ìṣàwárí oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ni ó jẹ́ wípé ó gbára lé àtìlẹyìn owó láti ọ̀dọ̀ ìjọba, ilé ẹ̀kọ́ yunifásitì, àti àwọn ilé-iṣẹ́ aládàáni tí wọn kò ní ohun ṣe pẹ́lú ìjọba. kí ó tó kè jẹ́ àṣeyọrí. Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára kìí ṣe fún títà, ó wá fún ìlera gbogbo ènìyàn n Gbígba abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára gbèrú si ní ará tó kọjá. Ní àfikún, gígún abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára fún àwọn ẹranko ní ànfaní méjì : Àkọ́kọ́,fún ààbò àwọn ẹranko nípa àrùn àti ààbò fún àwọn ènìyàn nípa àkóràn àrùn lati ọ̀dọ̀ àwọnẹranko.Ìforúkọsílẹ̀ àwọn olùdásílẹ̀ ni ọnà tí ìdàgba-sókẹ̀ abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tún lè jẹ́ ìdènà fún ìdàgba-sókè àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tuntun. Lára awọn ìṣòro tí ìdàgbà-sókè abẹ́rẹ́ ajẹsára tún ń kojú gẹ́gè bí ̣bí àjọ̣ elétò Ìlera Agbáyé ti sọ, ìdènà ńlá tí ó lágbára jùlọ fún ìsọ di púpọ̀ ni agbègbè orílẹ̀-èdè tí kò tíì dagbà-sókè dára dára tí wọn kò sì ní owó tí wọ́n lè fi ṣe ìdàgba-sókè oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára láti fi kojú àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn.Ríṣiríṣi ọ̀na ni wọ́n ti là kalẹ̀ láti mú ìdàgbà-sókè bá àwọn ọnà tí a ń gba jẹ́ kí àwọn wnìyan ó ní ànfàní sí ètò ìfúni ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lọ́nà tí ó múná-dòko. Lára àwọn ọ̀na pàtàkì tí a fi ń fi àwọn oògùn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára yí jíṣẹ́ fún àwọn ènìyàn ni ìlò ìlanà ìmọ̀ ẹ̀rọ tẹkinọ́lọ́jì ti ìgbàlódé ti àtọ́lá (abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí a ń ẹ̀ sí ẹnu). Ìlana fífúni ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára sí ẹnu ma ń sisẹ́ púpò bí àwọn oníṣẹ́ ìlera tí wọ́n yọ̀nda ara wọn fún isẹ́ takun takun yí bá ti gba ìdánilẹ́kọ̀ọ́ dára dára. Nígbà tì ìwádí lórí lílo ìlànà ìfúni ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára pẹ̀lú abẹ́rẹ́ ṣì ń lọ lọ́wọ́.Orísirísi ọ̀nà ni Ìdàgbà-sókè nípa ìwádí abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tí ó n lọ lọ́wọ́, àwọn ni:Fún ìgbà díẹ̀ sẹ́yìn, àwọn ọmọdé nìkan ni wọ́n ń ṣe abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára fún, ṣùgbọ́n wọ́n ti ń ṣe fún àwọn ọ̀dọ́ àti àgbalagba láyé òde òní.Àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára ti ń di nkan tó wọ́pọ̀.Wọ́n ti ńnṣèwádí lórí àwọn ọnà tuntun tíbwọ́n ti lè ma fúní ní abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára.Won n ṣe awọn abẹrẹ ajẹsara lati mujade awon idahun ajẹsara abinibi, ati ti adaṣe.Wọ́n tún ń ṣe ìgbìyànjú lórí ìgbéjáde àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára to le woo aisan àwọn àrùn tó léwu.Wọn tún ń ṣíṣe lórí ìgbéjáde lórí àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára tó lè kojú àkọlù àwọn kòkòrò tí ń ṣekú pani.Àwọn onímò ìjìnlẹ̀ tún ń ṣègbìnyànjú lọ́wọ́ lọ́wọ́ láti gbé abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára sìntẹ́tíìkì jáde nípasẹ̀ àtúnṣe ètò àwọn kòkòrò tí ó ń fa àìsàn àti àrùn. Èyí yóò ṣe ìrÓ tó kí àwọn ògo wẹẹrẹ ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ń gbaànlọ́wọ́ láti dènà bí àwọn kòkòrò wọ̀nyí ṣe ń lágbára ju àwọn abẹ́rẹ́ àjẹsára lọ lọ́pọ̀ ìgbà."},{"question":"अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय चलचित्र महोत्सवहरूमा मान्यता प्राप्त गर्नमा नेपाली कलाकार र चलचित्र निर्माताहरूको योगदानको अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"नेपाली कलाकार र चलचित्र निर्माताहरूले अन्तर्राष्ट्रिय फिल्म फेस्टिभलमा मान्यता प्राप्त गर्न उल्लेखनीय योगदान गरेका छन्। \\"द ब्ल्याक हेन\\" जस्ता प्रदर्शन र चलचित्रहरूले नेपाली सिनेमाको विश्वव्यापी प्रोफाइललाई उचाल्दै प्रशंसा प्राप्त गरेका छन्।"},{"question":"Ahoana no iatrehana ny famoizana olon-tiana?","answer":"Ny fiatrehana ny famoizana dia midika hoe mamela ny tenanao halahelo, mitady fanohanana avy amin'ny hafa, ary manome voninahitra ny fahatsiarovana ny olon-tianao amin'ny fomba misy dikany."},{"question":"चित्रकलाको छोटो परिचय दिनुहोस् ।","answer":"चित्रकला एक कला हो जसले चित्र, रंग, आकृति, र मनोभावनालाई साझा गरेर विभिन्न विचार तथा भावनालाई अभिव्यक्त गर्दछ। यसले सामान्यतया चित्र, पेन्टिङ, ड्राइइङ, स्कल्प्चर, फोटोग्राफी, आदिको रूपमा देखा पाइन्छ। यो कला विविध शैली र विचारलाई अभिव्यक्त गर्दछ र विभिन्न समाजी तथा सांस्कृतिक पहिचानलाई प्रतिविम्बित गर्दछ। चित्रकला मानव सम्प्रेषण र व्यक्तित्वको एक महत्वपूर्ण साधन हो।"},{"question":"Tulis kelanjutan untuk paragraf ini - Hiyō terlibat dalam beberapa pertempuran antara lain Pertempuran Midway","answer":"pada bulan Juni 1942, lalu ia juga ikut berpartisipasi dalam Kampanye Guadalkanal pada bulan Oktober tahun yang sama. Hiyō ditorpedo pada pertengahan tahun 1943 dan menghabiskan tiga bulan dalam perbaikan. Dia tenggelam pada tahun 1944 akibat diserang oleh pesawat pembom tukik Sekutu, TBF Avenger dari kapal induk ringan , menyebabkan ledakan dan kebakaran yang masif di Pertempuran Laut Filipina."},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de uma pergunta de trívia da categoria: história.","answer":"A Estátua da Liberdade foi erguida antes de 1900? Sim, em 1886."},{"question":"பறவை காற்றலைகளின் பணி என்ன ?","answer":"பறவை காற்றலைகளின் பணி ,துணைச் சுவாசம் , மிதவைத்தனம் , வெப்பச் சீராக்கம் , இவை அனைத்தும்"},{"question":"Le mot « entrailles » a-t-il le même sens dans ces deux phrases ? Oui ou non ?Phrase 1: On l’a ouvert et on lui a trouvé toutes les entrailles fort saines.Phrase 2: En tête de toutes les vertus, elle place la justice et l’humanité ; mais cette justice est toute négative, et cette humanité n’a pas d’entrailles.","answer":"Réponse: non."},{"question":"PlayStation 5 ne zaman gelecek?","answer":"Beklenen gün geldi ve nihayet 20.11.2020 itibari ile PS5 stoklarda yerini aldı."},{"question":"हिन्दू पौराणिक कथामा कति देवता छन् ?","answer":"हिन्दू पौराणिक कथाहरू विविध छन्, र हिन्दू धर्म भित्र देवत्वको अवधारणा जटिल छ। हिन्दू धर्मले विश्वास, अभ्यास र परम्पराहरूको एक विस्तृत श्रृंखलालाई समेट्छ, र हिन्दू पौराणिक कथाहरूमा देवताहरूको कुनै निश्चित संख्या छैन।"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"விடை: மதக்குறி என்பது மாட்டு மந்தைக்காரன் தனது மாடுகளுக்குப் போடும் அடையாளம் போன்றதே."},{"question":"Kana iwe uchitumira hug chaiyo(virtual) , ndeipi emojis yaungashandisa?","answer":"🤗"},{"question":"Maari bang makuha ang square root ng isang negatibong numero?","answer":"Walang square root ang isang negatibong numero kung hindi natin isasama ang imaginary numbers. Ang square root ng isang numero ay ang factor ng numero na iyon na pwedeng imultiplika sa sarili upang makuha ang orihinal na numero. Maari lamang makakuha ng negatibong numero mula sa multiplikasyon kung positibo ang isang factor at negatibo ang isa pa. Ibig sabihin, hindi maaaring magkapareho ang dalawang factor ng isang negatibong numero."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਸੰਤ ਪ੍ਰਸਾਦਿ ਹਰਿ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇਆ ॥ਤਬ ਤੇ ਧਾਵਤੁ ਮਨੁ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਇਆ ॥੧॥ਸੁਖ ਬਿਸ੍ਰਾਮੁ ਪਾਇਆ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇ ॥ਸ੍ਰਮੁ ਮਿਟਿਆ ਮੇਰੀ ਹਤੀ ਬਲਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਚਰਨ ਕਮਲ ਅਰਾਧਿ ਭਗਵੰਤਾ ॥ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੇ ਮਿਟੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਚਿੰਤਾ ॥੨॥ਸਭ ਤਜਿ ਅਨਾਥੁ ਏਕ ਸਰਣਿ ਆਇਓ ॥ਊਚ ਅਸਥਾਨੁ ਤਬ ਸਹਜੇ ਪਾਇਓ ॥੩॥ਦੂਖੁ ਦਰਦੁ ਭਰਮੁ ਭਉ ਨਸਿਆ ॥ਕਰਣਹਾਰੁ ਨਾਨਕ ਮਨਿ ਬਸਿਆ ॥੪॥੫੦॥੧੧੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 189 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ) ਗੁਰੂ-ਸੰਤ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹਾਂਤਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ) ਦੌੜਨ ਵਾਲਾ (ਮੇਰਾ) ਮਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ) ਗੁਣ ਗਾ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ (ਉਹ) ਆਤਮਕ ਆਨੰਦ ਦਾ ਦਾਤਾ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਲੱਭ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ । (ਹੁਣ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਮੇਰੀ) ਦੌੜ-ਭੱਜ ਮਿਟ ਗਈ ਹੈ, (ਮੇਰੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਦੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ) ਬਲਾ ਮਰ ਮੁੱਕ ਗਈ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਭਗਵਾਨ ਦੇ ਸੋਹਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਧਿਆਨ ਧਰ ਕੇਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੀ (ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ) ਚਿੰਤਾ ਮਿਟ ਗਈ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ ! ਜਦੋਂ) ਮੈਂ ਅਨਾਥ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਆ ਗਿਆਤਦੋਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਉਹ ਸਭ (ਟਿਕਾਣਿਆਂ ਤੋਂ) ਉੱਚਾ ਟਿਕਾਣਾ ਪਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ।੩।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! (ਆਖ—ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ) ਸਿਰਜਣਹਾਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਹੁਣ ਮੇਰਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ) ਦੁੱਖ-ਦਰਦ, ਭਟਕਣ ਤੇ ਡਰ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ।੪।੫੦।੧੧੯।\\""},{"question":"Oración 1: El Modo 9 nació en Londres el 14 de junio de 1975 como el tercer hijo de sus padres, pero mantiene, (Estado de Osun) como su origen.Oración 2: El Modo 9 nació el 14 de junio de 1975 en Londres como el tercer hijo de sus padres, pero reclamó (el estado de Osun) como sus orígenes.Pregunta :¿la oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2?. ","answer":"Sí, la parafrasea. "},{"question":"ඔන්චිල්ලා  වාරම් කවියක් කියන්න ","answer":"ඔන්චිලි චිලි චිල්ල මලෝවැල්ල දිගට පුවක් මලෝනැන්දලාගෙ කොස් වත්තේඑක ගෙඩියයි පල ගත්තේඒක කන්ඩ ලුණු නැත්තේලුණු මිනිහා ගම නැත්තේගම කොතනද? කටු බැද්දේඔන්චිලි චිලි චිල්ල මලෝවැල්ල දිගට පුවක් මලෝ"},{"question":"Көзүнүн агы менен тең айлануу","answer":"1. Бирөөнүн ою менен болуу, айткан-дегенинен чыкпоо, көзүн кароо (көбүнчө аёо, жакшы көрүү, сыйлоо маанисинде) Бакма ата-энем менин көзүмдүн агы менен тең айланышчу. 2. Бирөөгө толук көз каранды болуп, айткан-дегенин аткаруу, анын каалаганын иштөө, жагынуу аракетин жасоо (көбүнчө баш ийүү, көз каранды болуу маанисинде) Айласы кеткенинен Жыргал Шадынын көзүнүн агы менен тең айланчу болду."},{"question":"இந்தியாவில் மதம் தொடர்பாக விதிக்கப்பட்ட ஜெசியா வரி எந்த மாகாணத்தில் விதிக்கப்பட்டது?","answer":"குஜராத்தின் ஆட்சியாளரான அஹ்மத் ஷா (1411-1442) 1414 இல் ஜிஸ்யாவை அறிமுகப்படுத்தினார், மேலும் அதை மிகவும் கண்டிப்புடன் சேகரித்தார், அதைத் தவிர்ப்பதற்காக பலர் இஸ்லாத்திற்கு மாறினார்கள். ஜிஸ்யா பின்னர் 1579 இல் மூன்றாவது முகலாய பேரரசர் அக்பரால் ஒழிக்கப்பட்டது."},{"question":"من القائل:إذا ضاق بال الرزق عنك ببلدةفثم بلاد رزقها غير ضيق؟","answer":"الخليل بن أحمد الجزي"},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：美国宪法的第一修正案保障了哪些自由？","answer":"答案：美国宪法的第一修正案保障了言论、宗教、新闻、集会和请愿的自由。"},{"question":"Berikan jawapan kepada soalan yang rumit ini: Dari daerah manakah Ron Teachworth berasal?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Oakland County."},{"question":"வினா: அடிக்குறிப்பு விளக்கம் தந்து ,  அடிக்குறிப்புகளால் சிறப்பு பெற்ற நூல்களை  எழுதுக. ","answer":"விடை: அடிக்குறிப்பு       ஆய்வறிக்கைக்கு அடிக்குறிப்பிடுதல் மிக இன்றியமையாத ஒன்றாகும்.  சான்றுகளின் வழி நடுநிலையோடு அறிவியலாய்வு என்பதைக் காட்டும் நெறி என்பதை மறக்கக் கூடாது.  மூலப் பகுதியில் காட்டப்படும் ஆதாரங்களுக்கான விவரங்கள் அடிக்குறிப்பில் இடம்பெற வேண்டும்.  அந்தந்தத் துறைகளில் உழைத்தவர்களின் பெயர்களை அடிக்குறிப்புக்கள் காட்டி விடுகின்றன.  ஆய்வாளர் பிறரிடமிருந்து பெற்றது என்பதை அடிக்குறிப்புகள் காட்டி விடுகின்றன. மறுப்பாளரிடமிருந்து காத்துக் கொள்ளவும் இஃது உதவும். அடிக்குறிப்புகளால் சிறப்பு பெற்ற நூல்கள் - ஐங்குறுநூறு,பதிற்றுப்பத்து"},{"question":"வினா :  காலத்தின் அருமையை அறிவோம் என்ற  தலைப்பில் சிறுகதை எழுதுக ","answer":"விடை : விஜயபுரி என்ற நாட்டை விவேகவர்மன் என்ற அரசன் ஆண்டு வந்தான். அவன் அரசவையில் நன்கு கற்றிருந்த அறிஞர்கள் இடம் பெற்றிருந்தனர். அரசன் ஒரு நாள் அந்த அறிஞர்களை பார்த்து, “அறிஞர் பெருமக்களே வாழ்க்கையில் மிகவும் மதிப்பு வாய்ந்த பொருள் எது?” என்று கேட்டான். இந்த கேள்வியை கேட்டதும், முதல் அறிஞர், “வாழ்க்கையில் மிகவும் மதிப்பு வாய்ந்த பொருள் உயிர்தான். உயிரில்லை என்றால் நம் வாழ்க்கையில் ஒன்றும் அனுபவிக்க முடியாது” என்றான். இரண்டாவது அறிஞர், “மன்னா, வாழ்க்கையில் மிகவும் மதிப்பு வாய்ந்தது அறிவுதான். அறிவில்லாமல் ஒருவரும் வாழ முடியாது” என்று பதிலளித்தார். மூன்றாவது அறிஞர் எழுந்து, “அரசே, வாழ்க்கையில் பொறுமை இன்றி நாம் ஒருகணம் கூட வாழ முடியாது. எனவே மிகவும் விலை உயர்ந்தது பொறுமை தான்” என்று பதில் அளித்தார்.நான்காவது அறிஞர், “அரசே, நம்ம பூமிக்கு வேண்டியஆற்றல் சூரியனிடமிருந்து தான் கிடைக்கிறது. சூரியன் இல்லை என்றால் பூமியில் உயிர்கள் கிடையாது. எனவே சூரியன்தான் உயர்ந்தது” என்றான். ஐந்தாவது அறிஞர், “வாழ்க்கையில் அனைத்தும் இருந்து அன்பு இல்லாவிட்டால் மனிதன் வாழ்ந்து ஒரு பயணும் இல்லை. எனவே அன்பு தான் மிக மதிப்பு வாய்ந்தது” என்றார். இறுதியாக ஓர் அறிஞர் எழுந்து, “அரசே, காலம் தான் அனைத்தையும் விட மிக மிக மதிப்பு வாய்ந்த பொருள். நமக்கு காலம் இல்லையானால் உயிர் இருந்து என்ன பயன்?. அறிவை பயன்படுத்த நமக்கு நேரம் எது?. பொறுமையாக இருக்க ஏது அவகாசம். சூரியனை பயன்படுத்த ஏது காலம்?. அன்பு காட்டை ஏது வாய்ப்பு? எனவே உலகிலேயே மிகவும் மதிப்பு வாய்ந்த பொருள் காலம்தான்”.ஆகவே, அதனை வீணாக்காமல் நம்முடைய ஆக்க பணிகளுக்கு எந்தெந்த வகையில் எல்லாம் அதனை பயன்படுத்திக் கொள்ள முடியுமோ? அந்தந்த வகையில் எல்லாம் பயன்படுத்திக்கொள்ள வேண்டும்” என்றார்.அரசர் அந்த ஆறாவது அறிஞர் கூறிய கருத்துதான் சிறந்தது என்று பாராட்டி அந்த கருத்தை ஏற்றுக் கொண்டார். காலத்தின் அருமையை குறித்து மிகவும் அழகாக விளக்கிய ஆறாவது அறிஞருக்கு அவர் மனம் விரும்பும் வகையில் எண்ணற்ற பரிசுகளை கொடுத்து பாராட்டினார். அது மட்டுமல்ல அவரை தனது அமைச்சராக நியமித்து கௌரவப்படுத்தினார். மற்ற ஐந்து அறிஞர்களும் அரசரின் செயலை பாராட்டினார். நீதி : காலம்தான் இவ்வுலகிலே விலைமதிக்க முடியாத பொருள். காலத்தை தவற விட்டவர்கள் வாழ்க்கையில் முன்னேற முடியாது. எனவே இளமையிலே நன்கு கற்க வேண்டும்.என்பதனை இச் சிறுகதை உணர்த்துகிறது ."},{"question":"ਚਾਰਵਾਕ ਝੀਲ ਬਾਰੇ ਦਸੋ। ","answer":"ਚਾਰਵਾਕ ਝੀਲ ( ਉਜ਼ਬੇਕ: Chorvoq  ; چهارباغ ਤੋਂ ਚਾਰ ਬਾਗ, ਫ਼ਾਰਸੀ ਵਿੱਚ \\"ਚਾਰ ਬਾਗ\\") ਉਜ਼ਬੇਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਤਾਸ਼ਕੰਦ ਖੇਤਰ ਦੇ ਉੱਤਰੀ ਹਿੱਸੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਸਟੋਨਲੀਕ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਪਾਣੀ ਦਾ ਸਰੋਵਰ , ਜੋ ਉਗਮ (ਉੱਤਰ), ਪਸਕੈਮ (ਪੂਰਬ) ਅਤੇ ਚਤਕਲ (ਦੱਖਣੀ) ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੱਖ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਸਰੋਵਰ ਨੂੰ 168 ਮੀਟਰ (551 ਫੁੱਟ) ਉੱਚੇ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ (ਚਾਰਵਾਕ ਹਾਈਡ੍ਰੋਪਾਵਰ ਸਟੇਸ਼ਨ) ਨੂੰ ਚਿਰਚਿਕ ਨਦੀ 'ਤੇ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਤਿਆਨ ਸ਼ਾਨ ਪਹਾੜਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪਸਕੈਮ, ਕੋਕਸੂਵ ਅਤੇ ਚਟਕਲ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਗਮ ਤੋਂ ਥੋੜ੍ਹੀ ਦੂਰੀ 'ਤੇ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਵੱਲ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਪਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਪ੍ਰਦਾਨ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ। ਵਰਤਮਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਿੰਨੋਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਗਮ ਨੂੰ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਹ ਤਿੰਨੋਂ ਨਦੀਆਂ ਸਿੱਧੇ ਚਾਰਵਾਕ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਸਰੋਵਰ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ 2 km3 (0.48 cu mi) ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"ਔਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਵ੍ਹੀਲਚੇਅਰ 'ਤੇ ਬਿਠਾਇਆ ਗਿਆ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਇੱਕ ਦੁਰਘਟਨਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਅਧਰੰਗ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਸਨੂੰ ਸਟਰੈਚਰ ’ਤੇ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਲਿਆਂਦਾ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਇੱਕ ਦੁਰਘਟਨਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸਨੂੰ ਅਧਰੰਗ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"වඩු බාස්, මැකනික් බාස්, මේසන් බාස්, කොත්තු බාස්බාස් යන වචනයේ ආරම්භය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ඉංග්‍රීසියෙන් boss කියන එක ලන්දේසි වලින් baas.ලොක්කා, ස්වාමියා  අදහස තියන නිසා මං හිතන්නේ ගොඩක් දුරට වැඩේට අත් උදව් දීපු අනිත් අය ප්‍රධානියා ට බාස් කියන්න ඇති."},{"question":"Formule uma resposta a esta pergunta elaborada: Qual revista tem mais publicações em mais países, Adventist World ou Baseball Digest?","answer":"Adventist World."},{"question":"问题：三星公司在半导体领域的发展如何？","answer":"答案：三星公司在半导体领域取得了重大突破和成就，成为全球领先的芯片制造商之一。"},{"question":"‘அகநானூற்றுப் பாடல்களைப் பாடிய புலவர்கள் எண்ணிக்கை……………..அ) 400ஆ) 145இ) 300ஈ) 140","answer":"ஆ) 145"},{"question":"Ndipe nzira 5 dzekuzorora kweawa?","answer":"“Heano mamwe mazano1. Famba-famba panze2. Bata hope3. Verenga bhuku4. Tarisa Netflix5. Fonera shamwari\\""},{"question":"Lee ya n'uju ebe aKama ọ bụrụ na ị chọrọ ya na nkenke, lee ihe ise gbara ọkpụrụkpụ o kwuru:1) Ụfọdụ ndị Pastor, ndị isi ndị agha na ndị ọgaranya ụfọdụ na-agba ya aka ahịa nke ọma, O kwuru sị \\"ndị isi ụka na-abịa chọtara m maka enyem aka, ha mechaa ha na-ekpere m ekpere\\".O kọwara n'ọnweghị ihe na-esere ya na ndi ụka.O kwuru sị \\"Ọ bụrụ na mụọ gi anabataghị ihe m na-eme, biko a zụla.2) O kwenyere n'ikikere si n'ala, mmiri n'ikuku.O kwenyere na ha na-ebute ihe ọmaỌ mara atụ sị n'ụfọdụ ndị na-eji ụkwụ ha gaharịa n'obodo ha batara ọhụru ma jiri ọnụ ha gwa ala ahụ ihe ha chọrọ.3) Angela Nwosu kwenyere na ọ bụghị okwu ọjọọ maọbụ ịkwa mmadụ emu ka mmadụ ga-eji ewebata ihe ọma na ndụ ya.4) O kwuru na ọ kwụsịri ịga ụlo ụka n'ihe dịka afọ 2015/2016.Ọ kọwara na ọ bụghị n'enwere ihe ọjọọ ọ hụru kama na ọ bụ na omasịghị ya.5) Nwosu kwuru na-agbanyeghị n'Nne ya n'ụmụnne ya akwadoghi ihe ọ na-eme, na ha na-ekpere ya ekpere.O kwukwara na dị ya kwadoro ihe ọ na-eme.Na mmechi, ọ gwara ndị mmadụ ka ha hapụ iji obi ọjọọ eso soshal Midịa, kama mgbe mmadụ hụru ihe ọma ka onye ahụ kelee Chineke ma kpee ekpere ka onweta nke ya. nnGive me a good title for the article above.","answer":"Angela Nwosu kwuru ihe ise a ga-atụ gị n'anya"},{"question":" Se uma pizza é dividida em 8 pedaços e você comeu 3 pedaços, quantos pedaços ainda restam?","answer":"Ainda restam 5 pedaços."},{"question":"Lengkapkan cerita berikut: Ketika aku pulang dari sekolah, aku ternampak seorang kanak-kanak sedang menangis di tepi jalan. Aku berasa simpati .....","answer":"Ketika aku pulang dari sekolah, aku ternampak seorang kanak-kanak sedang menangis di tepi jalan. Aku berasa simpati melihat budak itu.  Aku pun terus menghampiri budak itu sambil menuntun basikalku.Aku memujuknya supaya berhenti menangis. Aku menyuruh budak itu menceritakan apa yang telah berlaku. Rupa-rupanya, dia ketinggalan bas. Aku memujuknya dan berjanji akan menghantarnya pulang ke rumah. Dia berasa sungguh gembira.Selepas itu, aku pun mengayuh basikalku dengan berhati-hatinya menuju ke rumahnya. Aku berasa sangat gembira kerana dapat membantu budak itu.Apabila tiba di rumahnya, dia mengucapkan terima kasih kepadaku lalu berjalan masuk ke dalam rumahnya.  Selepas itu, aku pun terus mengayuh basikal pulang ke rumahku yang terletak berhampiran rumah budak itu.Setibanya di rumah, aku menceritakan peristiwa itu kepada ibu bapaku. Mereka memuji sikap baikku itu dan berasa sangat bangga mempunyai seorang anak yang berani dan baik hati seperti aku."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bunga dipetik, perdu ditendang'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud isteri dikasihi, mentua dibenci (gemar akan hak orang, tetapi orang itu dibenci)"},{"question":"መልስ ስጥ፦ የሰው ልጅ የማስወገጃ ሥርዓት ዋነኛ ሥራው ምንድን ነው? ከታች ካሉት ውስጥ ይምረጡ። (ሀ) የቆሻሻ ቁሳቁሶችን ማስወገድ፣ (ለ) ማነቃቂያዎች ምላሽ መስጠት፤ (ሐ) ምግብን በሜካኒካዊ መንገድ ማበላሸት፤ (መ) ከምግብ ውስጥ የሚገኘውን ንጥረ ነገር መሳብ፤","answer":"(ሀ) የቆሻሻ ቁሳቁሶችን ማስወገድ"},{"question":"Les remboursements mentionnes ci-dessus doivent etre fixes chaque mois; ils peuvent etre modifies dans l'intervalle .La phrase ci-dessus est très compliquée. Veuillez me fournir une version synonyme simplifiée composée de plusieurs phrases.","answer":"Voici les informations simplifiées, et présentées en plusieurs phrases: Ces remboursements doivent être fixés chaque mois mais modifiés entre-temps."},{"question":"Adajọ ti ran Kayode to fipa ba iyawo baba rẹ lo pọ l’Ekiti lẹwọn","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ Majisreeti kan to fi ilu Ado-Ekiti ṣe ibujokoo ti ni ki Durodọla Kayọde, ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelọgọta ati Ọwajulu Tobi, ẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgbọn, maa lọ sẹwọn fun igba kan na.Ninu ẹsun ọtọọtọ ti wọn fi kan awọn mejeeji, Durodọla Kayọde ni wọn fẹsun kan pe o fipa ba iya arugbo ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelogoji to jẹ iyawo baba rẹ laṣepọ pẹlu ipa, ni Ayetoro-Ekiti to wa nijọba ibilẹ Ido/Ọsin, nipinlẹ Ekiti.Owajulu Tobi to n ṣiṣẹ kafinta niluu Emure-Ekiti ni tiẹ, ladajọ ni oun naa tun fipa ba ọmọdebinrin kan to jẹ ẹni ọdun mẹtadinlọgbọn lo pọ niluu Emure-Ekiti kan naa.Ṣaaju ni ọlọpaa to n ṣoju ijọba, Inspẹkitọ Adejare Elijah, ti sọ pe oun ti ṣetan lati pe awọn ẹlẹrii meji-meji ọtọọtọ wa sile-ẹjọ naa lati waa jẹrii lori ipejọ naa. Ṣugbọn oun fẹẹ tọrọ aaye ranpẹ lọwọ ile-ẹjọ naa ki oun le fi akoko naa ko awọn ẹlẹri oun jọ. O tun ni oun yoo fi iwe ipẹjọ naa ranṣẹ si ileeṣẹ to n ṣeto ipẹjọ nileṣẹ awọn aṣofin ipinlẹ naa, koun le gba esi to daju lori ẹsun naa.Inspẹkitọ yii tun fi kun un pe eleyii yoo fun oun ni aaye lati ko awọn ẹlẹrii oun jọ, ati lati le ko wọn wa si ile-ẹjọ naa lati waa fi ẹri to daju mulẹ lori ẹsun naa.O ṣalaye pe awọn ọdaran naa ṣẹ ẹṣẹ yii lọjọ kẹtala ati ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu kefa, ọdun 2021, pẹlu bi awọn mejeeji ṣe fipa ba awọn obinrin mejeeji ọtọọtọ lo pọ. Ẹsun yii ni agbefọba ni o lodi si ofin ọtalelọọọdunrun o din meji ti ọdun 2012 ti ipinle Ekiti n lo.Ninu idajọ rẹ, adajọ ile-ọjọ naa, Mohammed Salau, fọwọ si ẹbẹ olupẹjọ yii, o si paṣẹ pe ki wọn ko awọn ọdaran mejeeji naa lọ si ọgba ẹwọn.Lẹyin eyi lo sun igbẹjọ naa si ọjọ karun-un, oṣu keje, ọdun yii."},{"question":"පුළිඟ හෝ  පුළිඟු ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන්නේ මොනවාද?","answer":"යමක් දැල්වෙන විට විසිවන ගිනි අඟුරු ."},{"question":"Rasao ity fehezanteny manaraka ity : \\"Tia mandeha tongotra ny mpianatra any ambanivohitra.\\" ","answer":"Tia ma nde ha to ngo tra ny mpi a na tra any am ba ni vo hi tra."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸਲੋਕੁ ਮਃ ੧ ॥ਖਤਿਅਹੁ ਜੰਮੇ ਖਤੇ ਕਰਨਿ ਤ ਖਤਿਆ ਵਿਚਿ ਪਾਹਿ ॥ਧੋਤੇ ਮੂਲਿ ਨ ਉਤਰਹਿ ਜੇ ਸਉ ਧੋਵਣ ਪਾਹਿ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਬਖਸੇ ਬਖਸੀਅਹਿ ਨਾਹਿ ਤ ਪਾਹੀ ਪਾਹਿ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 149 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਾਪਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨ (ਜੋ ਜੀਵ) ਜੰਮਦੇ ਹਨ, (ਇਥੇ ਭੀ) ਪਾਪ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ (ਅਗਾਂਹ ਭੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਕੀਤੇ ਪਾਪਾਂ ਦੇ ਸੰਸਕਾਰਾਂ ਕਰਕੇ) ਪਾਪਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਪ੍ਰਵਿਰਤ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।ਇਹ ਪਾਪ ਧੋਤਿਆਂ ਉੱਕਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਉਤਰਦੇ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਸੌ ਧੋਣ ਧੋਈਏ (ਭਾਵ, ਭਾਵੇਂ ਸੌ ਵਾਰੀ ਧੋਣ ਦਾ ਜਤਨ ਕਰੀਏ) ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਮਿਹਰ ਕਰੇ (ਤਾਂ ਇਹ ਪਾਪ) ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਜੱੁਤੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਪੈਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Qual é o segundo livro em As Crônicas de Gelo e Fogo?","answer":"A Clash of Kings"},{"question":"Ṣeyi Makinde atawọn agba ẹgbẹ PDP fẹẹ fi Gbenga Daniel ṣe adari ẹgbẹ naa nipinlẹ Ogun","answer":"Lati fopin sì oríṣiiríṣii wahala tó ní ṣẹlẹ nínú ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP nipinlẹ Ogun, Gomina Ṣeyi Makinde ti sọ pe yóò dara ti Ọ̀túnba Gbenga Daniel ba le máa ṣàkóso ẹgbẹ ọhun.Nibi ipade ti Makinde, gomina ipinlẹ Ọ̀yọ́, ṣe pẹlu Gbenga Daniel, gomina ipinlẹ Ogun tẹlẹ, nile ẹ niluu Sagamu lọrọ ọhun ti waye l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee.Koko ohun to fa iṣẹ nla ti wọn fẹẹ gbe fún ọkunrin oloṣelu yii ni lati wa ojuutu sí bí ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ṣe pin yẹlẹyẹlẹ bayii nipinlẹ Ogun. Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Gbenga Daniel ti sọ ọ tẹlẹ pé òun fẹẹ yẹra fún oṣelu, sibẹ oun ti Makinde atawọn àgbààgbà oloṣelu ninu ẹgbẹ PDP bíi Ọmọọba Ọlagunsoye Oyinlọla atawọn kan nilẹ Yoruba n wa bayii ni bi yóò ṣe gba ipò olórí ẹgbẹ naa nipinlẹ Ogun.Makinde sọ pe Ọtunba Daniel lo yẹ nipo ọhun latari awọn àmúyẹ to ni, ati pe oun yii kan naa lo le da alaafia pada saarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu ọhun ti wọn ti pin sí oríṣii mẹta bayii l’Ogun.Makinde loun mọ ipa nla to ko lori bi wọn ṣe fa oun kalẹ nipinlẹ Ọyọ lati dije dupo gomina, ati pe iru eeyan ti ẹnu ẹ tolẹ dáadáa bẹẹ ni yóò lè dari ẹgbẹ ọhun nipinlẹ Ogun, ti alaafia yoo si jọba pada laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ.Daniel sọ ni tiẹ pe ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan to dara ju fun awọn ọmọ Naijiria nipinlẹ Ogun ni PDP n ṣe.Bakan naa lo gba ẹgbẹ yìí níyànjú láti ṣatunto iru àwọn èèyàn tí yóò máa darí ẹgbẹ ọhun gẹgẹ bii ọna abayọri fún ẹgbẹ naa."},{"question":"Sheeg magaca naadigii uu u ciyaari jirey ciyaaryahan Max’ed Ismaaciil?","answer":"Maxamed Ismacil waxa uu u ciyaari jirey naadigii Horseed."},{"question":"كم تشكل المياه في الكرة الأرضية","answer":"نسبة 71 %."},{"question":"Расскажите мне о влиянии технологий на образование в будущем.","answer":"Разные технологии играют все более значимую роль в образовательном процессе. Очень вероятно, что технология продолжит влиять на образование в будущем. Например: 1) персонализированное обучение 2) доступность к образованию 3) виртуальная и дополненная реальность: VR и AR технологии 4) Коллаборативное обучение. Технологии способствуют развитию коллаборативного обучения, где учащиеся могут работать над проектами вместе."},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Trạm BOT ở TP.HCM đã sẵn sàng, nhiều xe chưa dán thẻ vẫn chạy vào làn ETC - Tuổi Trẻ Online","answer":"Theo ghi nhận, tại trạm BOT xa lộ Hà Nội, giao thông thông thoáng, xe có dán thẻ sử dụng ETC đi qua trạm rất nhanh. Phía đầu trạm, các nhân viên thu phí túc trực, hướng dẫn từ xa để điều tiết các xe chưa dán thẻ vào đúng làn theo quy định. Tuy nhiên, một số xe chưa dán thẻ vẫn chạy vào làn ETC, các nhân viên trạm yêu cầu lùi xe ra làn thu phí hỗn hợp. Ông Phan Công Bằng cho hay theo quan sát, hiện vẫn còn khá nhiều xe chưa dán thẻ. Các chủ xe cần sớm dán thẻ để đi lại, nhất là khi vào các tuyến cao tốc chỉ sử dụng làn ETC. Ngày mai 1-8 là ngày đầu tuần nên dự báo xe cộ rất đông, sở cùng các đơn vị liên quan đã lên phương án điều tiết và xử lý các trường hợp ùn tắc. Cũng trong ngày 31-7, tại điểm dán thẻ Etag của Công ty TNHH Thu phí tự động (VETC) gần trạm thu phí xa lộ Hà Nội, hướng từ cầu Rạch Chiếc đi Suối Tiên (TP Thủ Đức) tấp nập xe đến dán thẻ. Nhân viên tại đây cho hay đơn vị bố trí khoảng 30 nhân viên vào buổi sáng, buổi chiều có thêm khoảng 20 người tới hỗ trợ vì lượng xe đến đông. Anh Hiếu (ngụ TP Thủ Đức) cho biết hôm nay là ngày cuối nên anh cùng vợ đưa xe đi dán thẻ. Anh tranh thủ buổi sáng đi dán cho nhanh tránh buổi chiều đông đúc, chờ đợi rất mệt mỏi. Nói về lý do đợi đến sát ngày mới dán thẻ, anh Hiếu nói: \\"Tại tôi bận nhiều việc quá nên quên mất, hôm nay vợ nhắc mới hay\\". Tương tự, tại các điểm dán thẻ ở trạm thu phí cầu Phú Mỹ và trạm An Sương - An Lạc cũng khá tấp nập. Ở trạm BOT An Sương - An Lạc (quận Bình Tân), buổi sáng có khoảng 10 nhân viên thực hiện đăng ký dán thẻ nên các tài xế phải mất 15 - 20 phút chờ đợi. Các nhân viên dán thẻ cho hay khoảng một tuần trở lại đây xe tới rất đông, đặc biệt vào buổi chiều."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa qaababka jidhka & timaha loogu qurxin Karo timirta ?","answer":"Haddii aad hore ugu ogeyd timirta in ay tahay cuntooyinka aasaasiga ah ee bisha Ramadaan, maadaama oo ay si tayo badan leh ula dagaallanto mariidka, isla markaana ay leedahay faytamiinno ah noocyada E, B iyo A waxa aad ogaataa in isla faytamiinnadaas awgood ay sida oo kalana tahay dawo u fiican caafimaadka maqaarka iyo timaha. Qormadan waxa aynu ku eegaynaa qaabab kala duwan oo timirta loogu isticmaali karo qaabka kiriimada jidhka nafaqada iyo quruxda geliya.Timirtu waxa ay la gaar tahay waxtarka ah in ay maqaarka duxgeliso kana hortagto calaamadaha gabowga, sida oo kale waxa ay leedahay nafaqooyin si awood leh u daweeya dil-dillaaca maqaarka ku samaysa, waxa kale oo ay timirtu cusboonaysiisaa unugyada si ay u beddelaan unugyada dhintay ee maqaarka, waxa ay jilcisaa maqaarka waxa aanay la dagaallantaa coodhcoodhka.Marka dhinaca madaxa laga hadlayana waxa ay nafaqo gelisaa diirka madaxa, waxa ay gacan ka geysataa qarinta cirrada, waxa ay daweysaa toxobta, waxa aanay yaraysaa dhibaatada timo daadashada.Maqaarka:Afar xabbo oo timir ah ayaa lagu darayaa koob biyo diirran ah, habeen ayaa ay radsanaanaysaa, illaa ay jileec isu beddesho, kaidb waa la isku walaaqayaa illaa ay sida cajiinka noqdaan. Markaas kadib ayaa maqaarka wejiga la marinayaa, waxa aaanay khubaradu sheegeen in ay maqaarka geliso faytamiinno kala duwan, macadanno iyo cusbooyin uu jidhku u baahan yahay si uu dhalaalka iyo quruxda dabiiciga ah u ilaashado.Timir la cajiimay haddii lagu daro liin dhanaan la tuujiyey oo loo qiyaasay timirta la cajiimayo in ay si fiican u wada qoynayso, kadibna wajibka lagu dahaadho, muddo 30 daqiiqo kadib ahna laga maydho, muddo marka lagu wado, waxa isu ekaanaya midabka wejiga ee laga yaabo in uu kala noocnooc noqdo dadka qaar qorraxda iyo qabowga badan awgood, waxa aana tirtirma baraha madow iyo nabarrada.TimahaShan malqacadood oo ah timir la cajiimay ayaa lagu darayaa 4 malqacadood oo saliid saytuun ah iyo koob caano ah, kadibna iyada oo isku walaaqan ayaa timaha lagu dhoobayaa, muddo saacad ah ayaana lagu deynayaa. Kadib biyo diirran iyo shaamboo caadiya ayaa lagaga maydhayaa, waxa ay khubaradu ku taliyaan in qofku uu toddobaadkii hal mar isticmaalo timirta sidan ah."},{"question":"ทำไมต้องมีภาษี","answer":"ภาษี เป็นเครื่องมือในการหารายได้เข้ารัฐบาล เป็นการจัดเก็บรายได้ของประเทศ เพื่อนำไปบริหารประเทศและควบคุมกำกับระบบเศรษฐกิจ จึงทำให้จำเป็นต้องมีภาษีเกิดขึ้น"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:చందమామ ఆకాశానికి అందాన్నిస్తుంది. మిణుగురు పురుగుకాంతితో విద్యుత్ కాంతులు వ్యాప్తించవు. మనిషికి మార్పు తప్పనిసరి. అలా మారకపోతే విముక్తే లేదు మనిషికి.","answer":"అకాశానికి శోభ చందమామ.మిణుగురుతో విద్యుత్ కాంతులు ప్రసరించవు.ఘరాలి నేటి నాటు వ్యక్తికాకుంటే లేదెన్నటికి విముక్తి"},{"question":"கேள்வி : திருவாரூர் புராணம் பாடியவர்","answer":"பதில் :  ஞானக் கூத்தர்"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe anjerimanontolo?","answer":"Ny anjerimanontolo dia sekoly ambaratonga ambony"},{"question":"Кайсы орган инсулинди өндүрөт жана кандагы канттын деңгээлин жөнгө салат?","answer":"Уйку бези инсулин чыгарып, кандагы канттын деңгээлин жөнгө салат."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 最近、字の読み方などが個性的な「キラキラネーム」と呼ばれる名前が増えています。戸籍には名前の読み方が書いていないため、役所がコンピューターで手続きをすることが難しくなっています。このため法務省は2日、戸籍の法律を変える案を考えました。案では、名前にカタカナで読み方を書くことにします。そして、「名前に使う字は、一般に認められている読み方にしなければならない」という規則をつくります。例えば、「高」と書いて、漢字の意味と違う「ヒクシ」という読み方にするのは、認められません。「太郎」と書いて、「マイケル」という読み方にするのも、一般の読み方ではないため、認められません。法務省は、どんな読み方が認められないかを決めて、法律ができる前に知らせると言っています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"Alpha Beta: EFCC ti mu Fowler, ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ Bọla Tinubu","answer":"Ọfiisi ajọ EFCC ni ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu, iyẹn Ọgbẹni Babatunde Fowler, ti n sọ ohun to mọ bayii nipa ẹsun ọgọrun-un biliọnu naira, owo-ori ti ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta kọ lati san fun ijọba Eko.Ọgbẹni Babatunde Fowler yii ni ọga agba tẹlẹ fun ileeṣẹ to n pawo wọle fun ijọba Eko labẹle (IGR). Oun naa si tun ni ọga agba tẹlẹ fun ileeṣẹ ijọba apapọ to n pawo wọle (FIRS)Ohun ti wọn tori ẹ pe Fowler si ọfiisi wọn ni bi ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta ko ṣe san owo-ori to yẹ fun ijọba Eko, ati pe Fowler yii gẹgẹ bii ọga agba nileeṣẹ to n ba ijọba Eko gbowo nigba yẹn ni lati sọ ohun to mọ nipa ọrọ ọhun.Mọnde, ọjọ Aje, ọsẹ yii, ni Babatunde Fowler, lọọ yọju si ajọ EFCC, lẹyin ti wọn fiwe pe e.Ṣaaju asiko yii ni ọkan lara awọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta, Dapọ Apara, ti kọwe si ajọ EFCC, nibi to ti fẹsun kan Babatunde Fowler pe ki wọn mu ọkunrin naa daadaa, nitori oun naa ni ipa to ko lori bi ileeṣẹ Alpha Beta ko ṣe san owo to to  ọgọrun-un biliọnu naira to yẹ ko san gẹgẹ bii owo-ori fun ijọba Eko.Apara, sọ pe o pẹ ti ileeṣẹ to gbaṣẹ lati maa dari gbogbo bi ijọba Eko ṣe n pawo wọle ti n ṣe oriṣiiriṣi aṣemaṣe yii, ti awọn oloṣelu to ni in si n lo o lati maa fi kowo jẹ.Ọdun 2018 ni Apara ti kọwe yii ranṣẹ si EFCC, ṣugbọn ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ni Fowler lọọ yọju si wọn nibẹ. Agbẹnusọ fun ajọ EFCC, Wilson Uwujaren sọ pe Fowler wa nileese awọn bayii, nibi to ti n dahun awọn ibeere lori ohun to mọ nipa ẹsun ọgọrun-un biliọnu naira ti Alpha Beta jẹ ijọba Eko."},{"question":"السؤال: من هي ذات النطاقين؟","answer":"الإجابة: أسماء بنت أبي بكر"},{"question":"Wo kann man auf Safari gehen?","answer":"Beliebte Länder für Safari-Touren sind heutzutage Tansania, Südafrika, oder Kenya."},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 厚生労働省が去年10月に調べると、日本で働く外国人は182万2725人でした。前の年より約9万6000人増えました。日本で働く外国人は、2007年に調べ始めてから、増え続けています。新型コロナウイルスが広がったあとは、増える割合が少なくなっていましたが、戻りました。いちばん多いのはベトナム人で、約46万2000人です。次は中国人で約38万6000人、フィリピン人が約20万6000人です。技能実習生は前の年より2.4％減りました。2年続けて減っていて、新型コロナウイルスが原因のようです。厚生労働省は「ことばや習慣が違っていても、外国人が働きやすいように、会社や工場などと協力していきます」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。"},{"question":"Сагымбайдын Манас бөлүмү толугу менен канча сап болгон?а) 180378 б) 1 000000в) 500 000 г) 300 700","answer":"а) 180378 "},{"question":"Devletleştirme neyle yapılır?","answer":"Devletleştirme gerçek karşılığı üzerinden yapılır. Bu işleme karşı Anayasa Mahkemesi'ne başvurulabilir. Â Kamulaştırma idari işlem ile yapılırken, devletleştirme kanunla yapılır."},{"question":" Education is what remains after one has forgotten what one has learned in School. – Albert Einstein.மொழிபெயர்ப்பு செய்க","answer":"ஒரு பள்ளியில் கற்றுக்கொண்டதை மறந்து விட்டால், பள்ளியில் கற்ற கல்வியினால் பயன் என்னே!"},{"question":"“卡拉OK”的原義是?","answer":"無人樂隊"},{"question":" Education is what remains after one has forgotten what one has learned in School. – Albert Einstein.மொழிபெயர்ப்பு செய்க","answer":" பள்ளியில் கற்றுக்கொண்டதை மறந்து விட்டால், கற்ற கல்வியினால் பயன் ஏது?  "},{"question":"விலங்குகளின் பாதுகாப்பிற்காக எற்படுத்தப்பட்ட அமைப்பிற்கு பெயர் என்ன? ","answer":"விலங்குகளின் நெறிமுறை சிகிச்சைக்கான மக்கள் உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய விலங்கு உரிமைகள் அமைப்பாகும், மேலும் இது உலகளவில் 9 மில்லியனுக்கும் அதிகமான உறுப்பினர்கள் மற்றும் ஆதரவாளர்களைக் கொண்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"नेपालमा महाशिवरात्रि पर्वको सांस्कृतिक महत्व वर्णन गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"महा शिवरात्रि, भगवान शिवलाई समर्पित एक हिन्दू चाड हो। शिव मन्दिरहरूमा उपवास, प्रार्थना र रातभरि जागराम बसेर यो चाड मानाईन्छ।"},{"question":"జాతి – జాతీయవాదం మధ్య సంబంధాన్ని చర్చించండి.","answer":"ఆధునిక ప్రపంచ వ్యవహారాలలో జాతి, జాతీయవాదం అనేవి చాలా శక్తివంతమైన అంశాలు. ఈ రెండు భావనలు ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తంగా సర్వసత్తాక, సార్వభౌమాధికార రాజ్యవ్యవస్థలు ఏర్పరచుకొనేలా ప్రజలను ఉత్తేజపరిచాయి.అర్థం : జాతి, జాతీయవాదం అనే ఈ రెండు పదాలు ఒకదానికొకటి పర్యాయపదాలుగా వాడబడతాయి. ఈ రెండు పదాలు లాటిన్ భాషలోని “నేషియో” అనే పదం నుండి ఉద్భవించాయి. లాటిన్ భాషలో ఆ పదానికి జన్మతః పుట్టుక అనే అర్థం ఉంది.జాతి: ఈ ఆంగ్ల పదం ‘నేటస్’, నేషియో అనే లాటిన్ పదాల నుండి గ్రహించబడెను. దీనికి ‘పుట్టుక’ అని అర్థము కలదు. లార్డ్స్ ప్రకారము “స్వాతంత్య్రం పొందిన లేదా స్వాతంత్ర్యం పొందాలని కోరుకుంటూ, రాజకీయంగా వ్యవస్థీకృతమైన ప్రజలనే” జాతి అంటారు. బర్జెస్ ప్రకారం “భౌగోళిక ఐక్యత కలిగి ఉంటూ ఒక నిర్దిష్ట ప్రదేశములో నివసించే తెగకు సంబంధించిన జాతీయతయే జాతి”.జాతీయవాదం: జాతీయవాదం ఆధునిక రాజ్యానికి ఒక లక్షణం. ఇది ఒక మానసిక భావన. అంతర్గతంగా తమ హక్కులను పరిరక్షించుకునేందుకు, విదేశీ దండయాత్రల నుండి తమ దేశ స్వాతంత్య్రాన్ని రక్షించుకునేందుకు దేశ ప్రజలలో ఐకమత్యాన్ని ప్రేరేపించే మానసిక శక్తి ‘జాతీయవాదం’. దీనిని సంక్షిప్తంగా ‘ఐకమత్య ‘భావన’ అనవచ్చు. జాతుల స్వతంత్రానికి, దేశ అభివృద్ధికి ఇది అవసరం. కానీ సంకుచిత, మితిమీరిన జాతీయతా భావం హానికరము.జాతి, జాతీయవాదం మధ్య సంబంధం :-1) జాతీయవాదం ఒక మానసిక భావన. ఒక ప్రజా సమూహం స్వతంత్రంగా వేరుపడి, ప్రత్యేక రాజ్యం కలిగి ఉండటం అనే అంశం ఇందులో ఇమిడి ఉంటుంది.2) ఈ భావం ప్రజలలో బలంగా నాటుకుపోవటంతో ప్రజలు తమ జాతి మనుగడ కోసం వారి సమస్త ప్రయోజనాలను పణంగా పెడతారు.3) జాతీయత అనేది ప్రజల యొక్క ప్రగాఢమైన ఆకాంక్ష జాతిరాజ్య ఆవిర్భావానికి దోహదపడుటయే జాతీయవాదం.4) 16వ శతాబ్దంలో ఐరోపాలో ఆవిర్భవించిన సాంస్కృతిక పునరుజ్జీవనం జాతీయవాదానికి బీజాలు వేసింది.5) 1789లో సంభవించిన ఫ్రెంచ్ విప్లవం జాతీయవాదాన్ని ఐరోపాలో మరింత ఉన్నత స్థితికి తీసుకెళ్ళింది. దాని నినాదాలైన స్వేచ్ఛ, సమానత్వం, సౌభ్రాతృత్వం ఐరోపా జాతీయులలో తీవ్రమైన రాజకీయ చైతన్యాన్ని కలుగజేశాయి.6) వియన్నా సమావేశం (1815) ఐరోపాలో జాతీయవాదాన్ని మరింత బలపరచింది.7) ఇటలీ ఏకీకరణ మరియు జర్మనీ ఏకీకరణ జాతీయవాదానికి మరింత బలాన్నిచ్చాయి.8) 1774లో సంభవించిన అమెరికా స్వాతంత్ర్య యుద్ధం ప్రజలలో జాతీయవాద వ్యాప్తికి బాగా తోడ్పడింది.9) 1917లో నాటి అమెరికా అధ్యక్షుడు ఉడ్రోవిల్సన్ ప్రతిపాదించిన “జాతుల స్వయం నిర్ణయహక్కు” ప్రపంచ ప్రజలలో ప్రతి జాతీయ సముదాయం ఒక ప్రత్యేక రాజ్యంగా ఏర్పడాలనే భావాన్ని బలంగా నాటింది.10) రెండవ ప్రపంచ యుద్ధానంతరం ఆసియా, ఆఫ్రికా మరియు లాటిన్ అమెరికాలలోని దేశాలలో జాతిరాజ్య ఆవిర్భావం కోసం స్వాతంత్ర్యోద్యమాలు ఊపందుకున్నాయి.11) 1885 నుండి 1947 మధ్య సాగిన భారత జాతీయోద్యమం భారత్, పాకిస్థాన్లు స్వతంత్ర రాజ్యాలుగా ఆవిర్భవించటానికి దోహదం చేసింది.దీనిని బట్టి మనం అర్థం చేసుకోవలసింది ఏమిటంటే జాతీయవాదం అనే భావం ఎప్పుడైతే ఐక్యతను, స్వాతంత్ర్యాన్ని సాధిస్తుందో, అప్పుడు అది సార్వభౌమాధికార జాతిగా రూపొందుతుంది.కొంతమంది రాజనీతి శాస్త్రవేత్తలు ఈ రెండింటిని పర్యాయపదాలుగా పరిగణించారు."},{"question":"قم بتلخيص المقال التالي: إذا تركت القيام بما كنت تحب، فلن يضيف هذا إلا إلى حزنك وضيقك. احرص قدر ما تستطيع على أن تستمر فيما كنت تستمتع به من هوايات وأنشطة. إذا صار بعضها صعبًا بسبب الإعاقة، ففكر في طرق جديدة تمارسها بها. على سبيل المثال، إذا كنت تحب القراءة ثم تعذر ذلك، فجرب الكتب المسموعة. إذا أصبحت جليس كرسي متحرك وكنت تحب الرياضة، فابحث عن فرق رياضية لذوي الاحتياجات الخاصة في منطقتك.  فكر أيضًا في ممارسة هوايات جديدة. إذا أخذت دورات تدريبية لتعلم هواية جديدة، فستصبح أكثر اجتماعية بالإضافة إلى ممارسة أمر تحبه. الرياضة والغذاء السليم مهمان بشكل عام، لكن فائدتهما أكبر عند التأقلم مع الإعاقة. احرص على تناول وجباتك بانتظام وأن يكون طعامك غنيًا بمختلف الفواكه والخضراوات، حاول ممارسة الرياضة كل يوم وفقًا لما تحبه وتبرع فيه. سيقلل الحفاظ على هذين الأمرين أيضًا من فرص الاكتئاب والانعزال؛ لأنهما يزيدان من السيروتونين والدوبامين (المتعلقين بالسعادة والرضا) في الدماغ.  إذا دعت الحاجة، ففكر في القيام بالعلاج الطبيعي باعتباره تمرينًا رياضيًا. استشر طبيبك دائمًا قبل أن تحدث تغييرات في نظامك الغذائي. ستحافظ الرياضة على عضلاتك وتقوّيها مما يمكن أن يساعدك على التغلب على إعاقة جسدية. قد يصعب عليك بسبب الإعاقة أن تحافظ على وظيفتك السابقة أو أن تقوم بمهام كنت معتادًا عليها. لكي تحافظ على وضعك المالي وراحة معيشتك؛ ابحث عن وظيفة جديدة يمكنك النجاح فيها بغض النظر عن إعاقتك. ابدأ بتدوين قائمة بمهاراتك والمجالات المهنية المتعلقة بتلك المهارات، ثم ابحث في منطقتك عن وظيفة في تلك المجالات وانظر في المتاح أمامك. في بعض البلدان يجرم القانون على صاحب العمل أن يسألك حتى عن إعاقتك ما دمت قادرًا على أداء المهمة المطلوبة منك، دعك من أن يرفض تعيينك بسببها.  في بعض البلدان كذلك، يلزم القانون صاحب العمل بتهيئة بيئة عمل مناسبة لك طالما كان ذلك في حدود المعقول.  إذا لم يمثل الجانب المادي مشكلة لك، ففكر في التطوع بعمل ما على سبيل فعل الخير وباعتباره عملًا بنّاءً سيزيد من إحساسك بالرضا والسعادة..","answer":"هذا تلخيص للمقال: حافظ على هواياتك ونشاطاتك قدر الإمكان. حافظ على صحتك بشكل عام. ابحث عن وظيفة تخاطب قدراتك."},{"question":"Benedict Okey Oramah","answer":"Benedict Okey Oramah jẹ onimọ-ọrọ-aje ati oniṣowo lorilẹ-ede Naijiria, o si ti jẹ ààrẹ ati Alaga Igbimọ Awọn oludari ti African Export–Import Bank (Afreximbank), lati ọdun 2015.O ti ṣe atẹjade iwe kan, Awọn ipilẹ ti Isuna Iṣowo Iṣeto, o si ti kọ diẹ sii ju awọn nkan 35 lori ọpọlọpọ awọn ọrọ-aje, iṣowo ati iṣowo iṣowo Afirika.A bi Oramah sinu idile awọn agba lati Nnokwa, ni orilẹ-ede Igbo, guusu ila-oorun Nàìjíríà. Baba rẹ 'Olori' Lazarus A. Oramah jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ ti ijoye ibile agbegbe.Dokita Oramah di M.Sc. ati Ph.D. oye ninu eto oro aje ogbin, ti o gba ni 1987 ati 1991 lẹsẹsẹ, Yunifásítì Ọbáfẹ́mi Awólọ́wọ̀, Ile-Ife, Nàìjíríà. O gba B.Sc. oye, tun ni eto eto-ọrọ ogbin, lati Yunifásítì ìlú Ìbàdàn, Nàìjíríà, ni ọdun 1983.O ni Iwe-ẹri Isakoso Ilọsiwaju lati Yunifásítì Kòlúmbíà. Ni 22 Keje 2018, o jẹ Ọjọgbọn ti Iṣowo Iṣowo ati Isuna Kariaye nipasẹ Ile-ẹkọ giga Adeleke, Nàìjíríà.Dokita Oramah darapọ mọ Afreximbank gẹgẹbi Oluyanju Oloye ni 1994 ati pe o ni igbega si ipo Oludari Agba, Eto ati Idagbasoke Iṣowo ni 2007. Ṣaaju ki o darapọ mọ Afreximbank, o jẹ Alakoso Iwadi Iranlọwọ ni Ile-ifowopamọ Ijabọ-Iwọwọle Ilu Naijiria lati 1992. O ti jẹ Alakoso Igbakeji Alakoso tẹlẹ ni idiyele ti Idagbasoke Iṣowo ati Ile-ifowopamọ Ile-iṣẹ lati (Oṣu Kẹwa 2008 - Oṣu Kẹsan 2015).O ti ni iyawo o si bi ọmọ mẹta."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Afeganistão?","answer":"Cabul."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 沖縄県では第２次世界大戦で20万人以上が亡くなりました。これは、そのとき沖縄県に住んでいた人の25％です。沖縄県は、日本の軍が沖縄で戦いをやめた6月23日を「慰霊の日」にしています。78年前に激しい戦いがあった糸満市の平和祈念公園では、亡くなった人のために祈る式がありました。岸田総理大臣や沖縄県の玉城知事、亡くなった人の家族などが出席しました。糸満市にある「魂魄の塔」にも、亡くなった人の家族などが祈りに来ました。この塔には、近くで亡くなった約3万5000人の骨が埋めてあります。1946年に沖縄県で初めてできた、戦争で亡くなった人のための塔です。戦争で両親が亡くなった83歳の男性は「母の骨がないので、ここに母がいると思って来ています。撃たれて亡くなった母の背中をたたいて泣いていたことを覚えています」と話していました。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- 第２次世界大戦: 1）1939年から1945年まで、日本・ドイツ・イタリアが、イギリス・フランス・アメリカ・ソ連・中国などの連合国と戦った戦争。1945年（昭和二十年）八月十五日に日本が降伏して終わった。- 軍: 1）兵隊。兵隊の集まり。2）いくさ。戦争。- 戦い: 1）戦うこと。戦争。争い。2）試合。- 慰霊: 1）なくなった人のたましいをなぐさめること。- 激しい: 1）勢いが強い。2）ものごとの程度がきつい。- 総理大臣: 1）内閣総理大臣のこと。内閣の最高責任者で、国会議員の中から議員が選び、天皇によって任命される。首相。総理。- 知事: 1）都・道・府・県などの政治をとる、いちばん上の役目。また、その人。- 塔: 1）仏や死者をまつる高い建物。2）細長く立つ建物。- 約: 1）ちかう。取り決める。2）縮める。省く。簡単にする。3）おおよそ。ほぼ。だいたい。- 骨: 1）動物の体の中にあって、体を支えているかたいもの。2）物のしんにする細長い竹や金属。3）ものごとの中心。4）へこたれない強い性質。5）苦労なこと。- 埋め: 1）穴をほって物を入れ、土や砂をかぶせる。2）ふさいで平らにする。3）すき間なく、いっぱいにする。4）お湯に水を入れて、ぬるくする。5）足りない分を補う。- 撃た: 1）（鉄砲などを）発射する。- たたい: 1）ぶつ。なぐる。2）打って音を出す。3）悪口を言って、やっつける。4）やたらにしゃべる。5）値段をまけさせる。"},{"question":"\\"Misture em um recipiente: a farinha, o açúcar, o fermento e o sal. Em outro recipiente, misture os ovos, o leite e a manteiga. Acrescente os líquidos aos secos, sem misturar em excesso. O ponto da massa não deve ser muito líquido, deve escorrer lentamente. Aqueça e unte a frigideira com óleo, coloque a massa no centro, cerca de 1/4 xícara por panqueca. Vire a massa para assar do outro lado e está pronto!\\"Quais os ingredientes da receita?","answer":"Farinha, açúcar, fermento, sal, ovos, leite, manteiga e óleo. "},{"question":"\\"Tichifunga ndima idzi pamusoro peMultiomics, chii chinonzi single-cell multiomics? Multiomics, multi-omics, integrative omics, \\"\\" panomics\\"\\" kana \\"\\" pan-omics \\"\\" inzira yekuongorora biological iyo iyo data seti yakawanda \\"\\" omes\\"\\", senge genome, proteome, transcriptome, epigenome, metabolome, uye microbiome (kureva, meta-genome uye/kana meta-transcriptome, zvichienderana nekuti inotevedzana sei); nemamwe mazwi, kushandiswa kweakawanda omics. Nekubatanidza aya \\"omes\\", masayendisiti anogona kuongorora data rakakura rebhayoloji kuti awane hukama hutsva pakati pezvinhu zvipenyu, kunongedza akakodzera biomarker uye kuvaka akadzama mamaki echirwere uye physiology. Mukuita izvi, multiomics. inobatanidza data yakasiyana-siyana yeomics kuti iwane hukama hunoenderana ne geno-pheno-envirotype kana hukama.Sevhisi yeOmicTools inonyora anopfuura makumi mapfumbamwe nepfumbamwe esoftware ane chekuita nekuongororwa kwedata remultiomic, pamwe nemadatabase anodarika makumi mapfumbamwe nemapfumbamwe emusoro wenyaya.Maitiro eSystem biology anowanzo akavakirwa pakushandiswa kwepanomic yekuongorora data. IAmerican Society of Clinical Oncology (ASCO) inotsanangura panomics ichitaura nezve \\"\\" kupindirana kwezvinhu zvese zvipenyu mukati mesero uye nemamwe mabasa emuviri, kubatanidza data inounganidzwa neyakanangwa bvunzo ... uye pasi rose (senge genome sequencing) rumwe ruzivo rwemurwere.\\"Single-cell multiomicsBazi remunda we multiomics ndeyekuongororwa kweakawanda-sero-sero data, inonzi single-cell multiomics. Iyi nzira inotipa sarudzo isati yamboonekwa yekutarisa kuchinjika kwakawanda muhutano uye chirwere padanho resero rimwe chete. Chakanakira chine chekuita nekuwongorora kuwanda ndechekudzikamisa zvinokatyamadza zvinotorwa kubva kusero kuenda kune masero akasiyana, zvichibvumira kufumurwa kwehterogeneous tissue architecture.Nzira dzekuenzanisa-sero genomic uye transcriptomic ongororo inogona kuve yakavakirwa pakusimudzwa panguva imwe chete kana kupatsanurwa kwemuviri kweRNA uye genomic DNA. Vanobvumira maonero asingaunganidzwe chete kubva kuongororo yezvinyorwa, sezvo RNA data isina matunhu asina kukodha genomic uye ruzivo nezve kukopa-nhamba kusiyanisa, semuenzaniso. Kuwedzerwa kweiyi nzira ndeyekubatanidzwa kwe-single-cell transcriptomes kune imwechete-sero methylomes, kusanganisa single-sero bisulfite sequencing kune imwechete sero RNA-Seq. Mamwe matekiniki ekubvunza epigenome, seyo imwe-sero ATAC-Seq uye imwechete-sero Hi-C iripo.Imwe yakasiyana, asi ine hukama, dambudziko nderekubatanidzwa kweproteomic uye transcriptomic data. Imwe nzira yekuita kuyerwa kwakadai ndeyekupatsanura muviri-sero lysates muviri, kugadzira hafu yeRNA, uye hafu yemapuroteni. Protein yemukati yemalysates inogona kuyerwa neproximity extension assays (PEA), semuenzaniso, inoshandisa DNA-barcoded antibodies. Nzira yakasiyana inoshandisa musanganiswa weheavy-metal RNA probes neprotein antibodies kuti igadzirise mass cytometry yekuongorora kwemultiomic.Multiomics uye kudzidza muchinaMukufambirana nekufambira mberi kweiyo highthroughput biology, mashandisirwo ekudzidza muchina kune biomedical data kuongororwa ari kubudirira. Iko kubatanidzwa kweakawanda-omics data kuongororwa uye kudzidza muchina kwakatungamira mukuwanikwa kwetsva biomarkers. Semuenzaniso, imwe yenzira dzemusanganiswaOmics purojekiti inoshandisa nzira yakavakirwa pane sparse Partial Least Squares regression yekusarudzwa kwezvinhu (putative biomarkers).","answer":"Ongororo yeakawanda nhanho-sero data. Iyi nzira inotipa sarudzo isati yamboonekwa yekutarisa kuchinjika kwakawanda muhutano uye chirwere padanho resero rimwe chete."},{"question":"Wie was Jean Chot?","answer":"Jean Joseph Antoine Emile Chot (Thuin, 24 juni 1906 - Dinant, 24 november 1991) was een Belgisch senator, advocaat en Waals militant."},{"question":"ગુજરાતી ચંદ્ર મહિનાઓ જણાવો.","answer":"કારતકમાગસરપોશમહાફાગનચૈત્રવૈશાખજેઠઅષાઢશ્રાવણભાદરવોઆસો"},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر السريع.","answer":"وَقاريءٌ يُمعن في دَرسِهِنَفس المُحبين فَدا نَفسِهِمعجم يَشبَه بَدر الدُجىمُكور الشَمس عَلى رَأسِهِغُصن فُؤادي صارَ رَوضاً لَهُقَد أَبدَع الغارس في غَرسِهِ"},{"question":"2 torbada hangi takımlar var?","answer":"Kura çekimi 2 Aralık'ta Hamburg'ta yapılacak2. torbada Türkiye ile birlikte Danimarka, Macaristan, Arnavutluk, Romanya ve Avusturya yer aldı."},{"question":"Sheeg waxa ugu mac Adduunka ?","answer":"Adduunka waxaa ugu mac waa Candhuufta."},{"question":"নিন্মলিখিত উদ্দীপক অনুসারে প্রশ্নটির উত্তর দাও।নাইজারের অর্থনীতি সাধারণত ফসল, পশুসম্পদ ও কিছু বৃহত্তম ইউরেনিয়ামের খনি মজুদের উপর কেন্দ্র করে পরিচালিত হয়। ২০২১ সালে নাইজার ইউরোপে ইউরেনিয়ামের প্রধান সরবরাহকারী ছিল এবং এরপর রয়েছে কাজাখস্তান ও রাশিয়া। খরা চক্র, মরুকরণ ও ২.৯% জনসংখ্যা বৃদ্ধির হার এবং ইউরেনিয়ামের বিশ্ব চাহিদা হ্রাস নাইজারের অর্থনীতির হার কিছুটা কমিয়ে দেয়।প্রশ্ন: ২০২১ সালে ইউরোপের প্রধান ইউরেনিয়াম সরবরাহকারী দেশ ছিল কোনগুলো?","answer":"২০২১ সালে ইউরোপের প্রধান ইউরেনিয়াম সরবরাহকারী দেশ ছিল নাইজার, কাজাখস্তান ও রাশিয়া।"},{"question":"biblia ni nini?","answer":"biblia ni kitabu kitakatifu kinachotumiwa na wakristo kama msingi wa imani yao. biblia ina sehemu mbili ambazo ni agano la kale na agano jipya. biblia pia ina vitabu 66. kwa ujumla biblia ni kitabu chenye ukweli kuhusu wokovu wa maisha ya mwanamu. biblia inaeleza kisa cha ukombozi cha Yesu Kristo. biblia iliandikwa na watu takribani arobaini kwa nyakati tofauti na katika mazingira tofauti. wengine wao walikuwa wakulima, wafugaji wa kondoo, wavuvi wa samaki, madaktari na wasomi wa dini yankiyahudi kama vile Paulo. biblia ni kitabu ambacho mtu yeyote akikisoma atapata tumaini jipya, hasa tumaini la uzima wa milele."},{"question":"UMBHALO: Akazange athethe nto, kodwa uthi unento yokwenza nomfazi wakho.'' Ebenomdla kuyo nantoni na enento yokwenza nomfazi wakhe, wamamkela ngaphakathi eofisini yakhe. Imizuzwana kamva, uStephanie wayemi encumile.","answer":"uStephanie"},{"question":"Hai hòn đảo nào của Việt Nam bị cấm du lịch từ tháng 4/2022?","answer":"Ngày 22/4/2022, UBND TP Cam Ranh đã đề nghị Sở Du lịch, Sở Thông tin Truyền thông, Trung tâm Thông tin Xúc tiến du lịch tỉnh phối hợp thông tin, yêu cầu các doanh nghiệp \\"không được tiến hành, phát triển các loại hình du lịch và quảng cáo sản phẩm tại đảo Bình Ba và Bình Hưng (Hòn Chút)\\" để đảm bảo an ninh cho căn cứ quân sự tại Cam Ranh.Ngoài ra, các thông tin quảng bá du lịch về hai đảo này hiện có trên các website, mạng xã hội... cũng bị yêu cầu gỡ bỏ."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Izay teraka lahy avokoa.\\"","answer":"Valiny : lahin-jiro, lahin-taretra. Satria misy lahy ilay anarana."},{"question":"Quem disse a frase que virou meme \\"O que é isso, aiorriu?\\"","answer":"Mari Gonzales durante sua passagem no BBB20."},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réewum Marshall nekk ?","answer":"Réewum Marshall mu ngi nekk ci kembaar bi ñuy wax Oceanie."},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: Sundarban, Ganj Nehri'nin denize döküldüğü yerde bulunur. Bu nedenle bölgede bir sürü kanal, küçük ada ve bataklık bulunur. Bölgede deniz suyu çok tuzludur. Bu durum da bir takım su canlısının orada yaşamasına olanak tanır. Bölge Ramsar Sözleşmesi","answer":"ile korumaya alınmıştır."}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:S},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:C,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},B={class:"card-container"},P=["disabled"],K={key:0},O={key:1};function L(e,a,u,d,o,r){const k=b("PoemCard");return i(),t("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=s=>o.searchQuery=s),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,o.searchQuery]])]),n("div",B,[(i(!0),t(c,null,p(r.filteredPoems,(s,g)=>(i(),j(k,{key:g,poem:s},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),r.hasMorePoems?(i(),t("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:o.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...s)=>r.loadMore&&r.loadMore(...s))},[o.isLoading?(i(),t("span",O,"Loading...")):(i(),t("span",K,"See more"))],8,P)):f("",!0)])}const E=m(M,[["render",L],["__scopeId","data-v-6cabda1b"]]),H=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/2.md","filePath":"chatai/2.md"}'),D={name:"chatai/2.md"},V=Object.assign(D,{setup(e){return(a,u)=>(i(),t("div",null,[v(E)]))}});export{H as __pageData,V as default};
